<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure.microsoft.com/En-Us/Blog on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure.microsoft.com/En-Us/Blog on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing modern data governance for the era of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce a reimagined data governance experience within Microsoft Purview, available in preview April 8, 2024. This new software as a service (SaaS) experience offers sophisticated yet simple business-friendly interaction, integration across data sources, AI-enabled business efficiency, and actions and insights to help you put the ‘practice’ into your data governance practice. The post Introducing modern data governance for the era of AI appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Microsoft Intelligent Data Platform—Unleash your data and accelerate your transformation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Intelligent Data Platform is a suite of recommended AI, analytics, database, and security products and services. It includes our best offerings, delivering seamless data integration and real-time business intelligence required for powerful decision making, organizational performance, and innovation. The post The Microsoft Intelligent Data Platform—Unleash your data and accelerate your transformation appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/the-microsoft-intelligent-data-platform-unleash-your-data-and-accelerate-your-transformation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Microsoft Azure Virtual Network Manager to enhance network security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By using Azure Virtual Network Manager, the governance team can create and update these network baselines at the network manager level, and apply them to multiple NSGs at once, ensuring that some critical security policies are enforced across the organization. The post Using Microsoft Azure Virtual Network Manager to enhance network security appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/using-microsoft-azure-virtual-network-manager-to-enhance-network-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
