<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure.microsoft.com/En-Us/Blog on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure.microsoft.com/En-Us/Blog on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and OpenAI evolve partnership to drive the next phase of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to continue our strategic partnership with OpenAI and to partner on Stargate. Today’s announcement is complementary to what our two companies have been working on together since 2019. The key elements of our partnership remain in place for the duration of our contract through 2030, with our access to OpenAI’s IP, our The post Microsoft and OpenAI evolve partnership to drive the next phase of AI appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coldplay evolves the fan experience with Microsoft AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This fan remix experience was built with a collection of Azure AI services available in Azure AI Foundry, Microsoft’s unified AI platform announced a few months ago at Microsoft Ignite. It integrates advanced AI services like natural language processing, computer vision, and machine learning to help organizations across industries create AI-powered solutions that accelerate innovation and differentiate them in the market. The post Coldplay evolves the fan experience with Microsoft AI appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Global Acceleration Program for RISE with SAP on Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SAP and Microsoft are excited to announce a global program, the SAP RISE Acceleration Program. The post Announcing Global Acceleration Program for RISE with SAP on Microsoft Azure appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/announcing-global-acceleration-program-for-rise-with-sap-on-microsoft-azure/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
