<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 09:01:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #212</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 09:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #212 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Choosing Between Conditional Statements – If, Switch, and Switch Expression Performance in C# [dotnettips.wordpress.com] An age-old question – which one is faster and better: if or switch? Read this piece by David McCarter […] The post Code Maze Weekly #212 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images in C# Using ImageSharp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 06:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn about generating images in C# using ImageSharp. Let’s get started. What is ImageSharp? ImageSharp is a free and open-source cross-platform library for the .NET Ecosystem. It is designed to simplify the processing of images by providing a powerful yet simple API. ImageSharp is fully managed and can be used […] The post Generate Images in C# Using ImageSharp appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images in C# Using ImageMagick</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 05:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn about generating images in C# using ImageMagick. Let’s dive in. What is ImageMagick? ImageMagick is a free and open-source cross-platform library for displaying, creating, converting, modifying, and editing raster images. It is a popular choice for a wide range of image-related tasks, including web development, graphic design, scientific research, […] The post Generate Images in C# Using ImageMagick appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Kafka in an ASP.NET Core Web API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 05:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At its core, Kafka is a distributed streaming platform designed to handle large volumes of data in real-time. Its exceptional performance, fault tolerance, and scalability make it a pivotal component in event-driven architectures. In this article, we’ll learn how to integrate Kafka with an ASP.NET Core Web API using a custom Docker Compose setup and […] The post Using Kafka in an ASP.NET Core Web API appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 05:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about Server-Sent Events in ASP.NET Core. We will see what they are, their features, advantages, and implementation. So, let’s start. What Are Server-Sent Events The Server-Sent Events (SSE) protocol allows servers to send real-time, event-driven updates to clients over an HTTP connection without the client requesting these updates. It […] The post Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #211</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 09:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #211 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Unit testing BlobServiceClient with Azure blobs and NSubstitute [blog.elmah.io] If you rely on Azure Blob in your projects, here’s an excellent article by Thomas Ardal that can help you understand it better and […] The post Code Maze Weekly #211 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Zip File in Memory In C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will look at how we create In-Memory Zip files in C#. Previously, we discussed how to create and read Zip files in .NET in our Working With Zip Files in C#/.NET article, so we recommend taking a look at that to familiarize yourself with working with Zip files. Let’s delve in. […] The post How to Create a Zip File in Memory In C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
