<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 08:51:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #210</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 08:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #210 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Computing code coverage for a .NET project [www.meziantou.net] Computing code coverage without any dependencies is now possible in .NET. Check this article by Gérald Barré to learn how to do it. WHY and […] The post Code Maze Weekly #210 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Check the Total Number of Items Defined in an Enum</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 05:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we talk about enums and, more specifically, how to find the total number of items defined in the enum. But first of all, let’s define an enum. Let’s start. What is an Enum An enum, short for enumeration, serves as a lightweight data structure within a programming language. It encapsulates a set […] The post How to Check the Total Number of Items Defined in an Enum appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baseline Styling in BenchmarkDotNet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 05:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to set a baseline for our benchmark in BenchmarkDotNet and discuss styling the baseline results. As software developers, benchmarking the performance of our methods is a crucial part of our day-to-day activities. With the BenchmarkDotNet library, we can accurately perform this operation. When we use this library for […] The post Baseline Styling in BenchmarkDotNet appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Difference Between Invariance, Contravariance and Covariance in Generics in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 05:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore the role, significance, usage, and impact of invariance , contravariance and covariance in our C# generics programming. Generics in C# enable us to design flexible, reusable classes and methods, providing type safety without the need for excessive casting or the risk of runtime errors. However, […] The post The Difference Between Invariance, Contravariance and Covariance in Generics in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Strawberry Shake and GraphQL in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 05:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll get familiar with GraphQL and Strawberry Shake, a GraphQL tool that facilitates interaction with local and remote data. Subsequently, we will build an application using the .NET API, focusing on customers searching for available space in shipping containers using GraphQL. This article will not delve deeply into server-side implementation since we have […] The post Introduction to Strawberry Shake and GraphQL in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use HttpOnly Cookie in .NET Core for Authentication and Refresh Token Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 11:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will show you how to use HttpOnly Cookie in .NET Core apps to secure our JWT or JSON Web Tokens, when implementing the authentication and refresh token actions. So, let’s start. The Standard Flow for the Authentication Logic Using JWT When we follow the usual flow with the JWTs: We can […] The post How to Use HttpOnly Cookie in .NET Core for Authentication and Refresh Token Actions appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Detect if a Key is Pressed in a C# Console Application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2024/14_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 06:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2024/14_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We frequently read data from user input in our C# application. However, we sometimes need to detect a key press and continue the operation. In this article, we discuss how to detect if a key is pressed in a C# console application. By understanding the usage of these features, we can create interactive and responsive […] The post How to Detect if a Key is Pressed in a C# Console Application appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvements in the Using Directive for Additional Types in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_04_2024/13_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 05:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_04_2024/13_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The “using” directive in C# helps us reduce boilerplate code when referencing types and members that sit outside the context of our class. C# 12 further expanded on the using directive, allowing it to be used for additional types. In this article, we’ll start by looking at how “using” has been used so far in […] The post Improvements in the Using Directive for Additional Types in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #209</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_04_2024/12_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 08:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_04_2024/12_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #209 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks 6 Types of Constructors in C# [codingsonata.com] Let’s go over the basics and see which constructors we have available in C# with Aram Tchekrekjian. Can you name them all (think C#12 as well)? […] The post Code Maze Weekly #209 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Test gRPC Services in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_04_2024/12_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 05:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_04_2024/12_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            gRPC is a popular way to create fast and scalable API’s in the .NET world. In this article, we explore how to test gRPC Services in .NET applications, and set up both unit and integration tests to ensure the reliability and performance of gRPC services. So let’s start. What is gRPC? In general, gRPC is […] The post How to Test gRPC Services in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
