<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 05:56:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Handling Circular References When Working With JSON in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 05:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) in .NET applications, developers often encounter challenges related to circular references, where objects circularly reference each other. In this article, we’ll explore common scenarios involving circular references in .NET applications and discuss techniques for effectively handling them. We will use System.Text.Json for serialization and deserialization, one of the […] The post Handling Circular References When Working With JSON in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Way to Assign an Initial Value to Auto-Properties in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2024/07_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 07:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2024/07_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore auto-properties and various ways to assign an initial value to it in C#. The C# programming language supports the Auto-Properties feature from version 3.0. In almost every C# application we use auto-property because it enables a more concise way to declare the property. What Is an Auto-Property in C#? […] The post The Best Way to Assign an Initial Value to Auto-Properties in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Retrieve the Number of CPU Cores in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_04_2024/06_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 08:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_04_2024/06_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the realm of C# programming, understanding the underlying hardware can be crucial for optimizing performance. One fundamental aspect is knowing the number of CPU cores available. In this article, we will explore methods to retrieve the number of CPU cores in C#, delving into the System.Environment class and Windows WMI. Let’s start. Retrieve CPU […] The post How to Retrieve the Number of CPU Cores in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #208</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 09:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #208 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Responsive Images Crash Course for ASP.NET Core Developers [khalidabuhakmeh.com] Here’s something a bit different but important if you’re into web development. In this excellent article, Khalid Abuhakmeh goes through important concepts of responsive […] The post Code Maze Weekly #208 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Present a List of Files in a Directory With Directory Browsing in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 06:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In ASP.NET Core, directory browsing is a feature that allows a web application to present a list of files in a specified directory to the user. For security, however, directory browsing is disabled by default to prevent unauthorized users from accessing a website’s directory structure and files. But, there are times when enabling it can […] The post Present a List of Files in a Directory With Directory Browsing in ASP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Performance With Source-Generated RegEx in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 03:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look at source-generated RegEx and how it can improve performance in our .NET applications. Let’s dive in! How Does RegEx Work? Regular expressions are vital to the programming world, but do we know how they work in .NET? Let’s examine the example: public static class PasswordValidator { public static bool ValidatePasswordWithRegularRegEx(string […] The post Improve Performance With Source-Generated RegEx in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale Your Services With Service-Oriented Architecture in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 06:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss the Service-Oriented Architecture in .NET. We will cover what it is, how to implement it, how it differs from Microservice Architecture, and how we can use cloud computing platforms as a jump pad to quickly stand up services and infrastructural features. Let’s begin! What Is Service-Oriented Architecture Service-Oriented Architecture […] The post Scale Your Services With Service-Oriented Architecture in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Validate a GUID in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore several approaches to validate a string representation of a GUID in C#. So let’s dive in. What Does a GUID Look Like? The term “GUID” was first introduced by Microsoft as a specific version of the broader term “Universally Unique Identifier” (UUID). As time passed, these terms have become […] The post How to Validate a GUID in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Sortable Unique IDs With the NewId Library in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 06:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore why we might need sortable unique IDs in .NET and how to create them with the NewId NuGet Package. Let’s dive in! Why Might We Need Sortable Unique IDs in .NET We all know there are two main approaches when it comes to generating IDs for entities in our projects: […] The post Generate Sortable Unique IDs With the NewId Library in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
