<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 03:34:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Count the Number of Vowels in a String in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 03:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will take a closer look at the techniques we can use to count the number of vowels in a string in C#. We will go through the code and learn more about each approach. Let’s get started. Prepare Our Counters Application First, let’s create a VowelCounters console application and update the […] The post Count the Number of Vowels in a String in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Update an Item in a List in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 05:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look at how to update an item in a List in C#, using a simple library management system as an example. We’ll explore the intricacies of this common operation and learn how to manipulate lists in our C# applications effectively. Let’s start. Understand List in C# In the world of C#, […] The post How to Update an Item in a List in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between .NET and C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 10:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When diving into the programming world, distinguishing between .NET and C# can be puzzling. .NET is a framework, that provides a platform for building applications. In contrast, C# is a programming language used within this framework. Despite their close association, it’s crucial to understand that they serve distinct roles in the development process. In this […] The post Differences Between .NET and C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serialization and Deserialization with YamlDotNet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 06:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            YAML (YAML Ain’t Markup Language) is a human-readable data serialization language, while YamlDotNet is a .NET library that helps us serialize and deserialize YAML data. Due to its simple and intuitive syntax, programming languages frequently use YAML for configuration files and data exchange. Its flexibility in handling complex data structures has made YAML popular in […] The post Serialization and Deserialization with YamlDotNet appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fastest Way to Get a Dictionary Key by Value in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 05:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The C# language does not provide a built-in method that we can use to retrieve a key from our dictionary using its value. However, using other features of the language, we can create methods to perform this task. In this article, let’s implement and discuss several methods that we can utilize to get a dictionary […] The post Fastest Way to Get a Dictionary Key by Value in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Show Query Parameters in Swagger in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2024/05_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 10:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2024/05_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the .NET ecosystem, Swagger is a common way to define and document our APIs. In this article, we will look at how to show query parameters in Swagger. Let’s make a start. Swagger And Query Parameters Swagger is a framework for designing, documenting, and consuming RESTful Web APIs. It provides us with tools to […] The post How to Show Query Parameters in Swagger in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images in C# Using SkiaSharp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2024/04_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 05:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2024/04_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn about generating images in C# using SkiaSharp. Let’s dive in. What is SkiaSharp? The SkiaSharp library is a cross-platform 2D graphics API for .NET platforms based on Google’s Skia Graphics library, a comprehensive library for drawing text, geometries, and images. This library is the graphics engine used in various […] The post Generate Images in C# Using SkiaSharp appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #212</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 09:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #212 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Choosing Between Conditional Statements – If, Switch, and Switch Expression Performance in C# [dotnettips.wordpress.com] An age-old question – which one is faster and better: if or switch? Read this piece by David McCarter […] The post Code Maze Weekly #212 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images in C# Using ImageSharp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 06:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn about generating images in C# using ImageSharp. Let’s get started. What is ImageSharp? ImageSharp is a free and open-source cross-platform library for the .NET Ecosystem. It is designed to simplify the processing of images by providing a powerful yet simple API. ImageSharp is fully managed and can be used […] The post Generate Images in C# Using ImageSharp appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images in C# Using ImageMagick</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 05:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn about generating images in C# using ImageMagick. Let’s dive in. What is ImageMagick? ImageMagick is a free and open-source cross-platform library for displaying, creating, converting, modifying, and editing raster images. It is a popular choice for a wide range of image-related tasks, including web development, graphic design, scientific research, […] The post Generate Images in C# Using ImageMagick appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
