<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 05:51:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Filter a List Based on Another List In C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 05:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Lists in C# are one of the most ubiquitous data structures. We perform all kinds of operations on them, such as appending, inserting, removing, sorting, and filtering. In this article, we’ll focus on the latter – filtering. In particular, we’ll see how to use a list to filter other lists. We can achieve it in […] The post How to Filter a List Based on Another List In C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View-Based Authorization in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 06:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            View-based authorization is an authorization strategy that enables us to manage UI elements’ visibility based on the user’s identity. In this article, we’ll take a look at how we can achieve view-based authorization in an ASP.NET core application. Let’s begin. What Is Authorization? Before we dive deeper into the implementation of view-based authorization, let’s take […] The post View-Based Authorization in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a Cookie to an HttpClient Request/Response in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 04:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What are cookies? Websites send small pieces of text, known as internet cookies, to our browsers whenever we visit them. They help us have a personalized experience on that particular website and remember it for the next time we visit it. Our goal today is how to make that happen in ASP.NET Core. In this […] The post Add a Cookie to an HttpClient Request/Response in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Source Generators to Validate IOptions in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 02:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look at how to use source generators to validate IOptions and ensure they meet the required configuration expectations. Let’s dive in! Why We Need to Validate IOptions In ASP.NET Core we have ample choice when it comes to configuration providers. This gives us freedom when choosing a way to set our […] The post Using Source Generators to Validate IOptions in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Generate a Random Color Name in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 22:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to generate a random color name using the KnownColor enumeration. This enum is particularly useful in UI design and data visualization, as it provides a wide variety of preset colors. Let’s begin. Understanding the KnownColor Enumeration To understand why we would even need to generate a random color […] The post How to Generate a Random Color Name in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Default and per Request Timeout in HttpClient</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 03:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll demonstrate how to set a default request timeout for all requests and configure specific request timeout settings for individual requests using HttpClient. In modern software development, managing HTTP requests efficiently is vital for keeping our applications fast and reliable. The HttpClient enables us to effectively execute HTTP calls in .NET applications. […] The post Change Default and per Request Timeout in HttpClient appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Result Pattern in .NET Web API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 04:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the expanding world of APIs, meaningful error responses can be just as crucial as well-structured success responses, and here, the Result Pattern can help us greatly. To introduce the Result Pattern, we will go through a series of iterations, presenting different ways of passing information about the success or failure of a given operation. […] The post Using the Result Pattern in .NET Web API appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Call an Action From Another Controller in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 06:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to call an action from another controller in .NET MVC. We sometimes need to call an action method from another action method within the same controller or a different controller class. So, let’s see how to do that. Why We Need to Call the Action From Another Controller? […] The post How to Call an Action From Another Controller in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
