<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 05:37:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Run a Large Language Model(LLM) Like ChatGPT Locally With C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 05:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are quickly entering the era of AI in Tech and software development. AIs are no longer relegated to research labs. More recently, we have gained access to using AI on the web and even on our personal devices. Now, we can run AIs locally on our personal computers. This article will explore how we […] The post Run a Large Language Model(LLM) Like ChatGPT Locally With C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the Differences Between Onion Architecture and Clean Architecture in .NET?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 06:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to discuss the differences between onion architecture and clean architecture in .NET. These patterns are often used interchangeably, and while they are very similar, there are some key differences that we will highlight. First, let’s talk about the two architectures. What Is Onion Architecture? Onion architecture is a type […] The post What are the Differences Between Onion Architecture and Clean Architecture in .NET? appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing the Saga Pattern Using Rebus and RabbitMQ</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 05:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we provide a technical guide on implementing the Saga Pattern using Rebus and RabbitMQ in a .NET environment. Rebus is a .NET library designed to create distributed applications with messaging capabilities, simplifying the process of sending and receiving messages. Check out our detailed article for a deeper understanding of Rebus and its […] The post Implementing the Saga Pattern Using Rebus and RabbitMQ appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
