<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 05:41:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a URL Shortener in .NET Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 05:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with URLs in our applications, there are times when they may become too long, clunky, unreadable, and difficult to use. In such situations, we can employ a URL shortener to make them shorter, more readable, and easier to share. Essentially, a URL shortener takes our long URLs and provides a shorter URL that, […] The post How to Build a URL Shortener in .NET Applications appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-In Rate Limiting in ASP.NET Core Web API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 05:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’re going to discuss Rate Limiting in ASP.NET Core, specifically version 8, and explore some ways of implementing it. So, Let’s start. What is Rate Limiting? Rate limiting controls the rate at which requests or events are allowed within a given time frame. In today’s world, where information flows at unprecedented rates, […] The post Built-In Rate Limiting in ASP.NET Core Web API appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Represent the Relationship of Properties Using Property Mappings From AutoMapper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 05:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll take a look at what property mappings are and how to retrieve them from AutoMapper. AutoMapper is a free .NET library that streamlines object mapping, reducing manual coding to boost development speed and minimize the risk of errors. Additionally, it offers versatile configuration options and supports complex needs like conditional mapping, […] The post Represent the Relationship of Properties Using Property Mappings From AutoMapper appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Minimal APIs Endpoint Organization With Carter in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 09:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look closely at the Carter library and how we can use it in our ASP.NET Core projects. Let’s get started! What Is the Carter Library The Carter library is an open-source project providing an abstraction layer for ASP.NET Core applications. This layer serves as a way to manage our minimal APIs […] The post Better Minimal APIs Endpoint Organization With Carter in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #210</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 08:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #210 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Computing code coverage for a .NET project [www.meziantou.net] Computing code coverage without any dependencies is now possible in .NET. Check this article by Gérald Barré to learn how to do it. WHY and […] The post Code Maze Weekly #210 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Check the Total Number of Items Defined in an Enum</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 05:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we talk about enums and, more specifically, how to find the total number of items defined in the enum. But first of all, let’s define an enum. Let’s start. What is an Enum An enum, short for enumeration, serves as a lightweight data structure within a programming language. It encapsulates a set […] The post How to Check the Total Number of Items Defined in an Enum appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baseline Styling in BenchmarkDotNet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 05:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to set a baseline for our benchmark in BenchmarkDotNet and discuss styling the baseline results. As software developers, benchmarking the performance of our methods is a crucial part of our day-to-day activities. With the BenchmarkDotNet library, we can accurately perform this operation. When we use this library for […] The post Baseline Styling in BenchmarkDotNet appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Difference Between Invariance, Contravariance and Covariance in Generics in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 05:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore the role, significance, usage, and impact of invariance , contravariance and covariance in our C# generics programming. Generics in C# enable us to design flexible, reusable classes and methods, providing type safety without the need for excessive casting or the risk of runtime errors. However, […] The post The Difference Between Invariance, Contravariance and Covariance in Generics in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Strawberry Shake and GraphQL in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 05:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll get familiar with GraphQL and Strawberry Shake, a GraphQL tool that facilitates interaction with local and remote data. Subsequently, we will build an application using the .NET API, focusing on customers searching for available space in shipping containers using GraphQL. This article will not delve deeply into server-side implementation since we have […] The post Introduction to Strawberry Shake and GraphQL in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
