<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 09:16:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #208</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 09:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #208 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Responsive Images Crash Course for ASP.NET Core Developers [khalidabuhakmeh.com] Here’s something a bit different but important if you’re into web development. In this excellent article, Khalid Abuhakmeh goes through important concepts of responsive […] The post Code Maze Weekly #208 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Present a List of Files in a Directory With Directory Browsing in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 06:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In ASP.NET Core, directory browsing is a feature that allows a web application to present a list of files in a specified directory to the user. For security, however, directory browsing is disabled by default to prevent unauthorized users from accessing a website’s directory structure and files. But, there are times when enabling it can […] The post Present a List of Files in a Directory With Directory Browsing in ASP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Performance With Source-Generated RegEx in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 03:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look at source-generated RegEx and how it can improve performance in our .NET applications. Let’s dive in! How Does RegEx Work? Regular expressions are vital to the programming world, but do we know how they work in .NET? Let’s examine the example: public static class PasswordValidator { public static bool ValidatePasswordWithRegularRegEx(string […] The post Improve Performance With Source-Generated RegEx in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale Your Services With Service-Oriented Architecture in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 06:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss the Service-Oriented Architecture in .NET. We will cover what it is, how to implement it, how it differs from Microservice Architecture, and how we can use cloud computing platforms as a jump pad to quickly stand up services and infrastructural features. Let’s begin! What Is Service-Oriented Architecture Service-Oriented Architecture […] The post Scale Your Services With Service-Oriented Architecture in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Validate a GUID in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore several approaches to validate a string representation of a GUID in C#. So let’s dive in. What Does a GUID Look Like? The term “GUID” was first introduced by Microsoft as a specific version of the broader term “Universally Unique Identifier” (UUID). As time passed, these terms have become […] The post How to Validate a GUID in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Sortable Unique IDs With the NewId Library in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 06:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore why we might need sortable unique IDs in .NET and how to create them with the NewId NuGet Package. Let’s dive in! Why Might We Need Sortable Unique IDs in .NET We all know there are two main approaches when it comes to generating IDs for entities in our projects: […] The post Generate Sortable Unique IDs With the NewId Library in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Ways to Create a Generic List of Anonymous Types in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2024/31_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 06:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2024/31_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Knowing how to manipulate complex datatypes such as Lists is crucial when storing and manipulating data in C#. Sometimes, we may want to incorporate versatility by not having to define explicit classes and create generic lists of anonymous types in C#. In this article, we are going to learn some of the different ways we […] The post Different Ways to Create a Generic List of Anonymous Types in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fastest Way to Remove the Last Character of a String</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_03_2024/30_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 08:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_03_2024/30_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Creating and manipulating string objects can be useful when building applications. In the C# programming language, string objects contain text values stored as a sequential read-only collection of character objects. This means string objects are immutable and thus can’t be changed once created. Despite this, we often find ourselves needing to manipulate them. In this […] The post The Fastest Way to Remove the Last Character of a String appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #207</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 09:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #207 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks C# 12: Alias Any Type [www.thomasclaudiushuber.com] Aliasing types and namespaces has been around for the longest time. With C# that feature has been extended and now we can alias almost any type out […] The post Code Maze Weekly #207 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fastest Way to Check if a List is in Order in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 07:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll examine different techniques to check whether or not a list is in order in C#. We’ll begin by examining several techniques, including parallel processing. Finally, we’ll run a series of benchmarks to help us choose which option fits best in our use case. So, let’s begin! Initial Setup Before we start […] The post Fastest Way to Check if a List is in Order in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
