<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 05:38:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Change the ServiceLifetime of a Registered Service in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 05:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing dependencies is essential in modern application development. .NET provides a powerful Dependency Injection (DI) system, with ServiceCollection at its core. Typically, we register a service and use it as is. However, there are instances when we need to change the ServiceLifetime of services after registration. This article explores methods for changing ServiceLifeTime, providing practical […] The post Dynamically Change the ServiceLifetime of a Registered Service in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between Record Struct and Record Class in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 05:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll discuss the differences between record struct and record class in C#. First, we will shortly explain each of the types. Afterward, we’ll show and describe each difference between them. Let’s start. Record Struct and Record Class in C# C# is built upon two categories of types: value types and reference types. […] The post Differences Between Record Struct and Record Class in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Debugging in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 06:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll be talking about advanced debugging and inspecting data in C#. We’ll be using Visual Studio 2022 to demonstrate all the debugging techniques. For more information about general debugging, we have another article on the basics of debugging, so feel free to check it out. Let’s start by creating a project that […] The post Advanced Debugging in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
