<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 05:14:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using EF Core Interceptors in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 05:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core (EF Core) has many powerful features, with Interceptors being one of the most versatile. Interceptors allow us to plug in custom behavior at different stages of the EF Core operation pipeline, giving us enhanced control over data interaction processes. Moreover, by using interceptors, we can fine-tune our database operations, enforce business rules, […] The post Using EF Core Interceptors in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images Using OpenAI in an ASP.NET Core Application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 05:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to explore how to generate images in an ASP.NET Core application using OpenAI. Let’s get going. Introduction to OpenAI Models OpenAI has developed a range of specialized AI models, of which the GPT (Generative Pre-trained Transformer) series lays the groundwork for numerous natural language processing applications. Codex takes this […] The post Generate Images Using OpenAI in an ASP.NET Core Application appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Factory Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 04:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Abstract Factory design pattern is a creational pattern that handles object instantiations. It offers a framework to manage complex object creation scenarios and helps us achieve a more maintainable code structure. In this article, we’ll look into the Abstract Factory design pattern and how it helps us achieve modular and loosely coupled code. Let’s […] The post Abstract Factory Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
