<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 06:40:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Cancel an HTTP Request on Leaving a Blazor Component</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 06:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article explores how to cancel an HTTP request and the associated backend operation inside a Blazor component. After a brief introduction to the architecture for canceling backend operations, we will familiarize ourselves with cancellation tokens and how to utilize them to cancel an operation when the user navigates away. Let’s start. Setup a Blazor […] The post How to Cancel an HTTP Request on Leaving a Blazor Component appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Template Method Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 05:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about a behavioral design pattern, the Template Method Pattern. We are going to see how this pattern helps deal with certain design problems and how to implement it in C#. If you want to read more about design patterns in C#, you can inspect our C# Design Patterns page. Let’s start. […] The post Template Method Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The LINQ Where Method in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 05:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll focus on the use cases of the LINQ Where Method in C#. The LINQ Where Method offers a powerful tool that can manipulate data from various sources ranging from collections of objects in memory to relational database tables and XML files according to a specific criterion. It offers a simple, intuitive […] The post The LINQ Where Method in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
