<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 05:25:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Kafka in an ASP.NET Core Web API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 05:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At its core, Kafka is a distributed streaming platform designed to handle large volumes of data in real-time. Its exceptional performance, fault tolerance, and scalability make it a pivotal component in event-driven architectures. In this article, we’ll learn how to integrate Kafka with an ASP.NET Core Web API using a custom Docker Compose setup and […] The post Using Kafka in an ASP.NET Core Web API appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 05:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about Server-Sent Events in ASP.NET Core. We will see what they are, their features, advantages, and implementation. So, let’s start. What Are Server-Sent Events The Server-Sent Events (SSE) protocol allows servers to send real-time, event-driven updates to clients over an HTTP connection without the client requesting these updates. It […] The post Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #211</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 09:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #211 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Unit testing BlobServiceClient with Azure blobs and NSubstitute [blog.elmah.io] If you rely on Azure Blob in your projects, here’s an excellent article by Thomas Ardal that can help you understand it better and […] The post Code Maze Weekly #211 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Zip File in Memory In C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will look at how we create In-Memory Zip files in C#. Previously, we discussed how to create and read Zip files in .NET in our Working With Zip Files in C#/.NET article, so we recommend taking a look at that to familiarize yourself with working with Zip files. Let’s delve in. […] The post How to Create a Zip File in Memory In C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Show the Generated SQL Query in EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 06:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core has many useful features, and in this article, we will see how to use it to show a generated SQL query. EF Core is an open source Object-relational mapper that supports several databases like SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and also LINQ (Language Integrated Query). One key benefit to developers is the ability to […] The post How to Show the Generated SQL Query in EF Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HSTS Header Implementation in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 04:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to learn how to implement the HSTS header in ASP.NET Core applications. So let’s get going. What Is HSTS HTTP Strict Transport Security (HSTS) is a web security mechanism that forces browsers to access a website using only secure HTTPS connections. When enabled, the browser automatically upgrades any HTTP […] The post HSTS Header Implementation in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
