<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 06:59:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Call an Action From Another Controller in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 06:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to call an action from another controller in .NET MVC. We sometimes need to call an action method from another action method within the same controller or a different controller class. So, let’s see how to do that. Why We Need to Call the Action From Another Controller? […] The post How to Call an Action From Another Controller in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find the Latitude and Longitude of a Location in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 05:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to find the latitude and longitude of a location in C# using the Google Maps Geocoding API. We’ll introduce two different methods for obtaining the coordinates: using the GoogleMaps.LocationServices NuGet package, which simplifies the process but can be less flexible, and using HttpClient directly, which provides us more […] The post How to Find the Latitude and Longitude of a Location in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate QR Codes With QRCoder in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss how to generate QR codes, specifically with the .NET library QRCoder. We will generate basic QR codes that contain simple strings, discuss reading from and writing QR codes to a database, and try out real-life use cases, such as phoning numbers and opening web pages. Let’s first align on […] The post Generate QR Codes With QRCoder in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count the Number of Vowels in a String in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 03:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will take a closer look at the techniques we can use to count the number of vowels in a string in C#. We will go through the code and learn more about each approach. Let’s get started. Prepare Our Counters Application First, let’s create a VowelCounters console application and update the […] The post Count the Number of Vowels in a String in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Update an Item in a List in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 05:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look at how to update an item in a List in C#, using a simple library management system as an example. We’ll explore the intricacies of this common operation and learn how to manipulate lists in our C# applications effectively. Let’s start. Understand List in C# In the world of C#, […] The post How to Update an Item in a List in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between .NET and C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 10:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When diving into the programming world, distinguishing between .NET and C# can be puzzling. .NET is a framework, that provides a platform for building applications. In contrast, C# is a programming language used within this framework. Despite their close association, it’s crucial to understand that they serve distinct roles in the development process. In this […] The post Differences Between .NET and C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serialization and Deserialization with YamlDotNet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 06:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            YAML (YAML Ain’t Markup Language) is a human-readable data serialization language, while YamlDotNet is a .NET library that helps us serialize and deserialize YAML data. Due to its simple and intuitive syntax, programming languages frequently use YAML for configuration files and data exchange. Its flexibility in handling complex data structures has made YAML popular in […] The post Serialization and Deserialization with YamlDotNet appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fastest Way to Get a Dictionary Key by Value in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 05:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The C# language does not provide a built-in method that we can use to retrieve a key from our dictionary using its value. However, using other features of the language, we can create methods to perform this task. In this article, let’s implement and discuss several methods that we can utilize to get a dictionary […] The post Fastest Way to Get a Dictionary Key by Value in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
