<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code-Maze.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 06:01:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/code-maze.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manage Background Tasks With The IHostedLifecycleService Interface</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 06:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll describe the IHostedLifecycleService interface. We’ll see how it extends the IHostedService interface and enables finer control over the hosted service lifecycle. Finally, we’ll show some practical use cases for the IHostedLifecycleService interface. Let’s get started. What Is the IHostedService Interface The IHostedService interface is a powerful feature in .NET that enables […] The post Manage Background Tasks With The IHostedLifecycleService Interface appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIMD Accelerated Numeric Types in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 05:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, let’s explore the various SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) accelerated numeric types in .NET. We’ll start by examining what SIMD stands for and how it works in .NET. Then, we’ll look at the different SIMD accelerated numeric types available in .NET. To conclude, we’ll implement a benchmark to compare the performance of […] The post SIMD Accelerated Numeric Types in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Testing ASP.NET Core Web API With JMeter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 05:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to load test an ASP.NET Core Web API with JMeter. So let’s get going. Introduction to JMeter Load testing is crucial for ensuring that web applications perform well under heavy traffic. JMeter is a popular and robust open-source tool for measuring the performance and functionality of web applications. When […] The post Load Testing ASP.NET Core Web API With JMeter appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
