<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 05:16:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images in C# Using SkiaSharp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2024/04_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 05:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2024/04_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn about generating images in C# using SkiaSharp. Let’s dive in. What is SkiaSharp? The SkiaSharp library is a cross-platform 2D graphics API for .NET platforms based on Google’s Skia Graphics library, a comprehensive library for drawing text, geometries, and images. This library is the graphics engine used in various […] The post Generate Images in C# Using SkiaSharp appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing API Gateway Authentication With YARP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2024/04_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2024/04_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this newsletter, we&#39;ll explore how you can implement API gateway authentication using YARP (Yet Another Reverse Proxy), a powerful and flexible reverse proxy library for .NET applications.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/implementing-api-gateway-authentication-with-yarp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Checks Since Visual Studio 2022 17.8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 16:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The C++ team is committed to making your C++ coding experience as safe as possible. In the last couple of releases, we added new safety checks based on the requests of internal customers like the Windows group. Below is the overview of the new checks.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/new-checks-since-visual-studio-2022-17-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluid Framework: How SharedTree merges changes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 15:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SharedTree is a data structure that allows users to collaboratively edit hierarchical data, such as documents, spreadsheets, or outlines.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/fluid-framework-how-sharedtree-merges-changes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Software Integrity with Artifact Attestations in GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 15:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ensuring the integrity and security of software artifacts is extremely important. With the proliferation of supply chain attacks and the increasing complexity of software development environments, developers need robust tools to safeguard their code and build processes. Recognizing this need, GitHub has introduced Artifact Attestations, a feature designed to provide a verifiable way to link […] The article Enhancing Software Integrity with Artifact Attestations in GitHub Actions appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – May 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 14:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The May 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include a new Pylance code action and setting, removal of debugpy from the Python extension, socket disablement for testing scenarios, and Pylance performance updates. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-may-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Keyboard Shortcuts: Streamline Your Workflow in Data Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 14:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Working with databases just got a whole lot easier in Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer, thanks to some nifty new keyboard shortcuts. Now you can speed through your database tasks and manage your data with keyboard clicks. This update is about making your workflow smoother and faster.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/keyboard-shortcuts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles with a timeout, part 4: Building our own awaiter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To stop relying on unspecified behavior.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240503-00/?p=109725 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autofac ComponentRegistryBuilder in ASP.NET Core – How To Register Dependencies (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Autofac ComponentRegistryBuilder in ASP.NET Core – How To Register Dependencies (Part 3) appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how to use Autofac ComponentRegistryBuilder in ASP.NET Core! We&#39;ll see how we can move closer to getting the C# plugin architecture support we want! The post Autofac ComponentRegistryBuilder in ASP.NET Core – How To Register Dependencies (Part 3) appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/05/03/autofac-componentregistrybuilder-in-asp-net-core-how-to-register-dependencies-part-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Front Door: CNAME/alias record is not currently detected</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When configuring a custom domain with Azure Front Door, one common issue that users may encounter is the “CNAME/alias record is not currently detected” message. This can be a confusing and frustrating experience, especially when you’re sure you’ve followed all the steps correctly. In this article, we’ll explore why this issue occurs and provide a […] The article Azure Front Door: CNAME/alias record is not currently detected appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #212</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 09:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #212 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Choosing Between Conditional Statements – If, Switch, and Switch Expression Performance in C# [dotnettips.wordpress.com] An age-old question – which one is faster and better: if or switch? Read this piece by David McCarter […] The post Code Maze Weekly #212 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance Tip: Choosing Between Conditional Statements – If, Switch, and Switch Expression Performance in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article compares the performance of conditional if statements, switch statements, and switch expressions in C# code, with a focus on data retrieval.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/03/general-performance-tip-choosing-between-conditional-statements-if-switch-and-switch-expression-performance-in-c/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making an Application More Robust With Data Mapping</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to use data mapping to make your application more robust against unexpected third-party data schema changes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/data-mapping-for-more-robustness 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images in C# Using ImageSharp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 06:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn about generating images in C# using ImageSharp. Let’s get started. What is ImageSharp? ImageSharp is a free and open-source cross-platform library for the .NET Ecosystem. It is designed to simplify the processing of images by providing a powerful yet simple API. ImageSharp is fully managed and can be used […] The post Generate Images in C# Using ImageSharp appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Code Performance: Leveraging Essential Tools and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 19:35:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Experienced .NET developers rely on tools to quickly identify code issues, saving time and enabling focus on new features and customer satisfaction. Recommended tools address performance, code quality, and security, optimizing resource allocation.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/02/optimizing-code-performance-leveraging-essential-tools-and-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis for Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 16:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The articles provide performance tips for Microsoft .NET, focusing on code analysis and benchmark data. They demonstrate settings to enhance application performance with examples. All recommendations relate to .NET 8.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/02/microsoft-net-code-analysis-for-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionize Customer Satisfaction with tailored reward models for your business on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 16:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As more powerful large language models (LLMs) are used to perform a variety of tasks with greater accuracy, the number of applications and services that are being built with generative artificial intelligence (AI) is also growing. With great power comes responsibility, and organizations want to make sure that these LLMs produce responses that align with […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionize-customer-satisfaction-with-tailored-reward-models-for-your-business-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Personalize launches new recipes supporting larger item catalogs with lower latency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 15:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the general availability of two advanced recipes in Amazon Personalize, User-Personalization-v2 and Personalized-Ranking-v2 (v2 recipes), which are built on the cutting-edge Transformers architecture to support larger item catalogs with lower latency. In this post, we summarize the new enhancements, and guide you through the process of training a model and providing recommendations for your users.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-personalize-launches-new-recipes-supporting-larger-item-catalogs-with-lower-latency/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with Amazon Titan Text Embeddings V2: A new state-of-the-art embeddings model on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Embeddings are integral to various natural language processing (NLP) applications, and their quality is crucial for optimal performance. They are commonly used in knowledge bases to represent textual data as dense vectors, enabling efficient similarity search and retrieval. In Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), embeddings are used to retrieve relevant passages from a corpus to provide […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-started-with-amazon-titan-text-embeddings-v2-a-new-state-of-the-art-embeddings-model-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.34 is Out With AI Code Completion for Python and Kotlin, Smooth Caret Animation, Force Step Into, and Many More Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.34 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this latest version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights of this update. Download Fleet 1.34 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed a number […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/05/fleet-1-34-is-out-with-ai-code-completion-for-python-and-kotlin-smooth-caret-animation-em-force-step-into-em-and-many-more-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles with a timeout, part 3: Going beyond two</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generalizing what we learned last time.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240502-00/?p=109721 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring .NET Aspire: Building Cloud-Native Apps with Ease</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud-native application development, building scalable, observable, and production-ready distributed systems can be a challenging task. This is where .NET Aspire comes into play. .NET Aspire is an opinionated, cloud-ready stack designed to simplify the development of cloud-native applications by providing a collection of NuGet packages that handle specific cloud-native concerns. […] The article Exploring .NET Aspire: Building Cloud-Native Apps with Ease appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate 2024.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate offers an extensive set of features that go beyond the basics, providing access to AI-powered coding efficiency boosters, seamless integration with numerous frameworks and technologies, powerful database tools, and more. Download IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate 2024.1 In our latest release, version 2024.1, we’ve introduced a range of enhancements to elevate your coding experience. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/05/what-s-new-in-intellij-idea-ultimate-2024-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains .NET Days Online 2024 – Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On September 25 and 26, 2024, we’re hosting a free, live, virtual event where community speakers cover topics they are passionate about: JetBrains .NET Days Online! Talk topics could be C#, F#, .NET in general, performance, refactoring, open source projects, frameworks like MAUI and Blazor, and more. We are looking for speakers who are interested […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/02/jetbrains-dotnet-days-online-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the JetBrains Content Creators Program!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you passionate about creating engaging content for the tech community? Do you enjoy sharing your coding journey with others? If so, our new JetBrains Content Creators Program is just the thing for you! At JetBrains, not only do we work to provide an exceptional developer experience, but we also strive to inspire and support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/05/02/introducing-the-jetbrains-content-creators-program/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autofac ContainerBuilder in ASP.NET Core – What You Need To Know (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Autofac ContainerBuilder in ASP.NET Core – What You Need To Know (Part 2) appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how to use Autofac ContainerBuilder in ASP.NET Core to wire up dependency injection. I&#39;ll explore what we can and cannot do with this approach! The post Autofac ContainerBuilder in ASP.NET Core – What You Need To Know (Part 2) appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/05/02/autofac-containerbuilder-in-asp-net-core-what-you-need-to-know-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Roundup: K2 Compiler Updates, Ktor News, Kotlin for Data Analysis, and Other Ecosystem Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 11:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this roundup, let’s delve into the key recent developments in the Kotlin ecosystem. Did you know that the JetBrains team regularly publishes a newsletter featuring major Kotlin ecosystem news? Sign up to stay up to date with all things Kotlin.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/05/kotlin-roundup-april-24/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Performance Impact of Sealing Attributes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When designing custom attributes, Microsoft recommends sealing them to potentially enhance performance. Do sealing attributes indeed lead to improved performance? Check out this article to learn the answer.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/02/code-it-any-way-you-want-performance-impact-of-sealing-attributes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images in C# Using ImageMagick</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 05:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn about generating images in C# using ImageMagick. Let’s dive in. What is ImageMagick? ImageMagick is a free and open-source cross-platform library for displaying, creating, converting, modifying, and editing raster images. It is a popular choice for a wide range of image-related tasks, including web development, graphic design, scientific research, […] The post Generate Images in C# Using ImageMagick appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple guide to training Llama 2 with AWS Trainium on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 18:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) are making a significant impact in the realm of artificial intelligence (AI). Their impressive generative abilities have led to widespread adoption across various sectors and use cases, including content generation, sentiment analysis, chatbot development, and virtual assistant technology. Llama2 by Meta is an example of an LLM offered by AWS. Llama […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simple-guide-to-training-llama-2-with-aws-trainium-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Copilot for Azure: Your AI-Powered Cloud Companion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 18:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot for Azure, the innovative AI companion that is revolutionizing the way we interact with cloud infrastructure and services. In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud management, IT professionals in DevOps Engineer and SRE roles are constantly seeking ways to streamline their workflows and enhance productivity. Copilot for Azure will help you design, operate, optimize, […] The article Microsoft Copilot for Azure: Your AI-Powered Cloud Companion appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 18:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These articles delves into performance optimization for collections in .NET, covering topics like looping, sorting, and utilizing different types of objects. The author identified performance variations related to the object type in the collection and recommends conducting benchmark tests. All recommendations are specific to .NET 8.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/01/collection-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Globalization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 18:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Internationalization and localization are crucial for software projects, involving adapting to various languages, regions, and technical requirements. Delaying consideration until later stages can lead to significant costs and effort. The importance of addressing globalization from the outset is emphasized, along with a recommendation to explore the book &amp;quot;Rock Your Code: Coding Standards for Microsoft .NET&amp;quot; for comprehensive insights.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/01/mastering-globalization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune and deploy language models with Amazon SageMaker Canvas and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine harnessing the power of advanced language models to understand and respond to your customers’ inquiries. Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed service providing access to such models, makes this possible. Fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) on domain-specific data supercharges tasks like answering product questions or generating relevant content. In this post, we show how Amazon […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-and-deploy-language-models-with-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving inclusion and accessibility through automated document translation with an open source app using Amazon Translate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations often offer support in multiple languages, saying “contact us for translations.” However, customers who don’t speak the predominant language often don’t know that translations are available or how to request them. This can lead to poor customer experience and lost business. A better approach is proactively providing information in multiple languages so customers can […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improving-inclusion-and-accessibility-through-automated-document-translation-with-an-open-source-app-using-amazon-translate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing General Availability (GA) of Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the General Availability (GA) of Microsoft Entra External ID, a next-generation customer identity and access management (CIAM) solution. Introduced in May 2023, External ID provides improved security, scalability, and user experience for adding authentication to your external facing apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-id-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate chatbot for document and data retrieval using Agents and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Numerous customers face challenges in managing diverse data sources and seek a chatbot solution capable of orchestrating these sources to offer comprehensive answers. This post presents a solution for developing a chatbot capable of answering queries from both documentation and databases, with straightforward deployment. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-chatbot-for-document-and-data-retrieval-using-agents-and-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft RAN slicing solutions: Discover AI-assisted application service assurance capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RAN slicing is one of the important new features of 5G networks and Microsoft has researched and produced results, making it easier for operators to use in Azure. The post Microsoft RAN slicing solutions: Discover AI-assisted application service assurance capabilities appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/microsoft-ran-slicing-solutions-discover-ai-assisted-application-service-assurance-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap to empowering your workforce with AI: How Moody’s copilot ignited AI innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how you can quickly build your own custom copilot for Microsoft Teams leveraging best in class pre-built AI components from Azure OpenAI and Teams AI Library.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/roadmap-to-empowering-your-workforce-with-ai-how-moodys-copilot-ignited-ai-innovation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Conditional If Variable Does Not Exist (try function)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            They try function in HashiCorp Terraform allows values to be read from a Data Source, input variables, or some other attribute while providing a default value if the evaluation expression errors. This is particularly useful when data is retrieved from an external system in JSON or YAML format and then decoded. The decoded result may […] The article Terraform: Conditional If Variable Does Not Exist (try function) appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the VMware Rapid Migration Plan</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the era of AI upon us, the benefits of running your workloads in the cloud will grow in ways that you have not yet imagined. For your company to be a leader in its industry, your IT organization needs to be ready to meet new demands. The post Introducing the VMware Rapid Migration Plan appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/introducing-the-vmware-rapid-migration-plan/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles with a timeout, part 2: Continuing with two</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Giving it another try.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240501-00/?p=109718 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing SharePoint Framework 1.19 with updates on building enterprise extensibility within Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 13:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce a new public version of the SharePoint Framework, v1.19, with new features, capabilities and fixes for Microsoft Viva, Microsoft Teams and SharePoint.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-sharepoint-framework-1-19-with-updates-on-building-enterprise-extensibility-within-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Lightroom: Issues with Most Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article outlines the author&#39;s frustration with Adobe Lightroom Classic updates, citing issues like lost edits and export failures due to catalog format changes. They urge for better testing, maintenance of user setups, and swift bug resolution. Specific grievances include vanished settings, performance decline, and incompatibility with MacMini systems. The author emphasizes the need for Adobe to prioritize user experience to retain subscribers.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/01/adobe-lightroom-issues-with-most-updates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance Tip: Optimizing Enum Value Name Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article delves into the optimization of Enum value name retrieval in .NET, comparing three approaches. It demonstrates that one of these methods is 16.13 times more efficient, with no memory allocation.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/01/general-performance-tip-optimizing-enum-value-name-retrieval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Type &amp; Structure Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 20:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These articles delve into strategies for optimizing the performance of your reference types and structures, also known as user-defined types. Both exhibit distinct behaviors, given that reference types are instantiated on the memory heap, overseen by the Garbage Collector, while structures are created on the memory stack, offering potentially superior performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/30/reference-type-structure-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance customer service efficiency with AI-powered summarization using Amazon Transcribe Call Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 19:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the fast-paced world of customer service, efficiency and accuracy are paramount. After each call, contact center agents often spend up to a third of the total call time summarizing the customer conversation. Additionally, manual summarization can lead to inconsistencies in the style and level of detail due to varying interpretations of note-taking guidelines. This […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-customer-service-efficiency-with-ai-powered-summarization-using-amazon-transcribe-call-analytics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AIChatUI: Open Source AI Chat Sample with Azure OpenAI Service &amp; GPT-3 / GPT-4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 17:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since I’ve been working with Azure OpenAI Service from a developer perspective as well, I’ve decided to build a sample application to help demonstrate not just the IaC deployment of Azure OpenAI Service and GPT models, but also to demonstrate some basic use cases of integrating AI into your own enterprise applications. Here’s a screenshot […] The article Introducing AIChatUI: Open Source AI Chat Sample with Azure OpenAI Service &amp;amp; GPT-3 / GPT-4 appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure your container build and publish with .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 8 has new security features for containers, including non-root images and SDK tools. Discover how to create non-root container images, configure Kubernetes pods, and inspect images and containers for enhanced security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/secure-your-container-build-and-publish-with-dotnet-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the hype: Part 1, How trustworthy AI empowers US Government agencies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models’ (LLM) ability to transform mission workflows for US Government agencies is revolutionary and adoption is now starting to accelerate. As agencies begin to leverage LLMs, they unlock capabilities that promise to streamline processes and drive innovation forward. It also means that there’s more to be done in the near term to support the deployment of LLM applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/trustworthy-ai-empowers-us-gov-agencies-part1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2024 is Now Live!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++, our free one-day virtual conference for the whole C++ community, is now live! Check it out on YouTube: The sessions are: Automated Testing of Shader Code with Keith Stockdale (Rare) – 15:00 UTC Message Handling with Boolean Implication with Ben Deane (Intel) –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-cpp-2024-is-now-live 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Build – Community Testimonial Videos</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, Microsoft Build is approaching and will occur from May 21st-23rd, 2024. During our Semantic Kernel session – Bridge the chasm between your ML and app devs with Semantic Kernel, we are looking to feature videos from community members like yourself sharing what you like about Semantic Kernel!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/microsoft-build-community-testimonial-videos 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker and JFrog partner to further secure Docker Hub and remove millions of imageless repos with malicious links</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker and JFrog partner further secure Docker Hub by removing millions of imageless repos with malicious links.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-jfrog-partner-to-further-secure-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles with a timeout, part 1: Starting with two</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s see by seeing if we can do it with just two.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240430-00/?p=109710 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate software development and leverage your business data with generative AI assistance from Amazon Q</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 12:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We believe generative artificial intelligence (AI) has the potential to transform virtually every customer experience. To make this possible, we’re rapidly innovating to provide the most comprehensive set of capabilities across the three layers of the generative AI stack. This includes the bottom layer with infrastructure to train Large Language Models (LLMs) and other Foundation […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-software-development-and-leverage-your-business-data-with-generative-ai-assistance-from-amazon-q/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Q Business and Amazon Q in QuickSight empowers employees to be more data-driven and make better, faster decisions using company knowledge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 12:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we announced the General Availability of Amazon Q, the most capable generative AI powered assistant for accelerating software development and leveraging companies’ internal data. “During the preview, early indications signaled Amazon Q could help our customers’ employees become more than 80% more productive at their jobs; and with the new features we’re planning on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-q-business-and-amazon-q-in-quicksight-empowers-employees-to-be-more-data-driven-and-make-better-faster-decisions-using-company-knowledge/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Commit and Push Changes Back to Repository</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 11:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Actions are great at enabling you to automate workflows directly from within a GitHub repository. The workflows are stored in a YAML definition file located within the .github/workflows directory within the repository. GitHub Actions can be used to configure workflows that can perform a variety of actions to perform build and release steps. On […] The article GitHub Actions: Commit and Push Changes Back to Repository appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a .NET AsciiMath parser and using it in a Markdig extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how I ported a Ruby AsciiMath implementation to .NET, created the AsciiMath NuGet package, and used it to create a Markdig extension
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-dotnet-asciimath-parser-and-using-it-in-a-markdig-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Optimizing Span Operations – Clear vs. Fill</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article compares two key search methods in dictionaries: using Contains() on the Keys collection and ContainsKey() method directly on the dictionary. It demonstrates examples for both approaches, highlighting Microsoft&#39;s recommendation of using ContainsKey(). The article suggests further examination of the performance aspect of these methods.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/30/code-it-any-way-you-want-optimizing-span-operations-clear-vs-fill-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSTest SDK：.NET 8的测试配置与灵活性新篇</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 07:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Marco Rossignoli 和Amaury Levé 的Introducing MSTest SDK – Improved Configuration &amp;amp; Flexibility。 我们很高兴地宣布，基于 MSBuild Project SDK 系统构建的全新 MSTest SDK已推出。它旨在通过合理的默认值和灵活的选项使项目配置更加容易，从而为您提供更好的 MSTest 测试体验。 这种新体验是建立在最近推出的 MSTest 运行程序的基础上（请查看公告）https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-ms-test-runner/，以进一步提高您的体验。 这个新的运行程序是一种轻量级、可靠且高性能的运行 MSTest 测试的方式，作为 MSTest.TestAdapter NuGet 包的依赖项发布。该运行器及其扩展由多个 NuGet 包组成，以提供可扩展、灵活且可配置的测试运行体验。然而，可定制性可能会导致许多问题：推荐的扩展是什么？正确的默认值是什么？如何对齐版本？ 这就是 MSTest SDK 的用武之地。 MSTest SDK 入门 开始使用新的 MSTest SDK 非常简单。 只需创建一个 MSTest 项目（或更新现有的 MSTest 项目）并将 .csproj 文件的内容替换为以下内容： Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/mstest-sdk%ef%bc%9a-net-8%e7%9a%84%e6%b5%8b%e8%af%95%e9%85%8d%e7%bd%ae%e4%b8%8e%e7%81%b5%e6%b4%bb%e6%80%a7%e6%96%b0%e7%af%87 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>使用 .NET 为 Microsoft AI 构建可扩展网关</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 02:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Kara Saucerman的Building a scalable gateway with .NET for Microsoft AI – .NET Blog Microsoft AI 团队构建了全面的内容、服务、平台和技术，以便消费者在任何设备上、任何地方获取他们想要的信息，并为企业改善客户和员工的体验。我们的团队支持多种体验，包括 Bing、Copilot、广告、地图和 Edge，并通过 Edge 新标签页、Windows 10 和 11 等入口点呈现，这些入口点每月有超过 10 亿活跃用户。我们意识到需要一个高性能且可靠的网关作为 Microsoft AI 的前端和入口层。这将使多个团队能够利用我们开发的通用功能来帮助运营业务并专注于客户体验和功能。在本文中，我们将介绍在 .NET 8 上借助 YARP 构建网关（代号为 CETO）的过程。 反向代理 在开始编写 CETO 之前，我们必须决定使用反向代理。 我们应该使用外部的还是尝试自己制作？ 这些外部的能涵盖我们所有的用例吗？ 我们还必须考虑定制这些代理的高成本和持续维护。 我们的需求包括支持 HTTP/2、HTTP/3、WebSocket 等流协议、简单的可扩展性等等。 当我们开始了解 Microsoft 其他内部团队正在做的事情时，我们遇到了 YARP 项目。 YARP 代表：“又一个反向代理”。 该项目使用 ASP.NET 和 .NET（.NET 6 及更高版本）提供一个灵活的解决方案，可以通过 .NET 代码进行修改。这有多方便呢？ 事实证明这正是我们所需要的。 Bing 运行着世界上最大、高性能且可靠的 .NET 应用程序之一。 我们依赖于与 .NET 团队的密切合作关系，并且是每个 .NET 版本的早期采用者。 通过尝试并升级到每个新版本，我们可以向 .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filters in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 19:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s important to understand how the application behaves and have the ability to override that behavior in runtime based on some conditions. For example, we don’t want to send malicious prompt to LLM, and we don’t want to expose more information than needed to the end users.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/filters-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and train large models cost-efficiently with Metaflow and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 19:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-authored with Ville Tuulos (Co-founder and CEO) and Eddie Mattia (Data Scientist) of Outerbounds. To build a production-grade AI system today (for example, to do multilingual sentiment analysis of customer support conversations), what are the primary technical challenges? Historically, natural language processing (NLP) would be a primary research and development […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/develop-and-train-large-models-cost-efficiently-with-metaflow-and-aws-trainium/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to Accessible Apps: Keyboard Accessibility and .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are your apps keyboard accessible? Learn more about keyboard traps and find out how you can ensure your .NET MAUI apps are keyboard accessible.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/the-journey-to-accessible-apps-keyboard-accessible 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Managed RunCommand Artifacts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 18:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As most of you may know from the current Managed RunCommand documentation there are multiple ways your script may be specified. Through the Script parameter. You can inline your entire script in this manner, though we don’t recommend the practice if your script contains confidential information.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/introducing-managed-runcommand-artifacts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Command R and R&#43; are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 17:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is co-written with Pradeep Prabhakaran from Cohere. Today, we are excited to announce that Cohere Command R and R+ foundation models are available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. Command R/R+ are the state-of-the-art retrieval augmented generation (RAG)-optimized models designed to tackle enterprise-grade workloads. In this post, we walk through how […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cohere-command-r-and-r-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting secrets locally</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Keeping security folks happy (or less upset which is the best we can hope for)
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell-community/encrypting-secrets-locally 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing large language model training with Arcee and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post by Mark McQuade, Malikeh Ehghaghi, and Shamane Siri from Arcee. In recent years, large language models (LLMs) have gained attention for their effectiveness, leading various industries to adapt general LLMs to their data for improved results, making efficient training and hardware availability crucial. At Arcee, we focus primarily on enhancing […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-large-language-model-training-with-arcee-and-aws-trainium/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the April edition of PHP Annotated! We’ll recap the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, featuring handpicked news, articles, tools, and videos. Highlights PHP statement on glibc/iconv vulnerability The hype around CVE-2024-2961 in relation to PHP was extremely exaggerated. Many people were under the impression that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/04/php-annotated-april-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2024 is Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++ is our free one-day virtual conference for the whole C++ community. This year it will run on April 30th 15:00 UTC. Sign-up for free to get access to our five sessions on the day. The sessions are: Automated Testing of Shader Code with Keith Stockdale (Rare) –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-c-2024-is-tomorrow 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s easier thank you think.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240429-00/?p=109707 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phi-3: Microsoft Redefines Small Language Models (SLMs)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the area of artificial intelligence (AI), the quest for smaller yet powerful language models has been an ongoing pursuit. Microsoft has taken a significant leap forward with the introduction of Phi-3. These new models promise to redefine the landscape of Small Language Models (SLMs), offering unparalleled capabilities and cost-effectiveness. Phi-3 Unveiled Phi-3 emerges as […] The article Phi-3: Microsoft Redefines Small Language Models (SLMs) appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anything Session With the JetBrains Academy Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’d like to invite you to our very first free Ask Me Anything session on Discord with JetBrains Academy! Send us any questions you may have about JetBrains Academy courses, how to start a career in IT, teaching opportunities, our offline programs, or any other topic you’re interested in. We’ll kick off the chatting session […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/04/29/ask-me-anything-session-with-the-jetbrains-academy-team/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break into Big Tech – My Journey from Startup to Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Break into Big Tech – My Journey from Startup to Microsoft appeared first on Dev Leader.This article is a high-level view of my career journey going from startups to Big Tech -- landing a principal software engineering manager role at Microsoft. The post Break into Big Tech – My Journey from Startup to Microsoft appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/29/break-into-big-tech-my-journey-from-startup-to-microsoft/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Detecting Items in a ConcurrentBag&lt;&gt;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The comparison between using the Count property and the IsEmpty() method in a ConcurrentBag reveals that IsEmpty() is 2.95 times more efficient based on benchmark results. This indicates a significant performance advantage for utilizing IsEmpty().
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/29/collection-performance-detecting-items-in-a-concurrentbag/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.17 includes integration with Azure API Center</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 07:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to share the launch of Dev Proxy v0.17 to help you to build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-17-includes-integration-with-azure-api-center 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Cloud Engineer and How to Become one?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It was once a new concept that enterprises were trying to make sense of, but the term “cloud” has really become ubiquitous across the IT landscape. No matter the industry, your organization is likely depending on some cloud services; from Microsoft Azure, AWS, Microsoft 365, Slack, Teams, GitHub, to so many other services. Behind the […] The article What is a Cloud Engineer and How to Become one? appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Kafka in an ASP.NET Core Web API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 05:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At its core, Kafka is a distributed streaming platform designed to handle large volumes of data in real-time. Its exceptional performance, fault tolerance, and scalability make it a pivotal component in event-driven architectures. In this article, we’ll learn how to integrate Kafka with an ASP.NET Core Web API using a custom Docker Compose setup and […] The post Using Kafka in an ASP.NET Core Web API appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenTofu: Open Source Alternative to Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of cloud, hybrid, and on-premises Infrastructure as Code (IaC), where managing and provisioning infrastructure through code has become indispensable, tools like OpenTofu play a pivotal role. The evolutions of IaC tools continues with OpenTofu, as a fork of Terraform that offers a more open-source, community-driven alternative that is managed by the Linux […] The article OpenTofu: Open Source Alternative to Terraform appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Math Do You Need To Program? – Dev Leader Weekly 41</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How Much Math Do You Need To Program? – Dev Leader Weekly 41 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I answer the question of how much math do you need to program -- with help from Twitter. The post How Much Math Do You Need To Program? – Dev Leader Weekly 41 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 05:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about Server-Sent Events in ASP.NET Core. We will see what they are, their features, advantages, and implementation. So, let’s start. What Are Server-Sent Events The Server-Sent Events (SSE) protocol allows servers to send real-time, event-driven updates to clients over an HTTP connection without the client requesting these updates. It […] The post Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Response Messaging Pattern With MassTransit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building distributed systems with .NET, direct calls between services can create tight coupling. The request-response messaging pattern can allow distributed services to communicate in a loosely coupled way.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/request-response-messaging-pattern-with-masstransit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
