<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:44:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Context Is the Bottleneck in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Software development context is the real bottleneck, not writing code. AI can generate code fast, but without context, boundaries, and language, you get coupling and brittle systems. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content on Software Architecture &amp;amp; Design, including this video showing everything in this post. With AI, I think… Read More »Context Is the Bottleneck in Software Development The post Context Is the Bottleneck in Software Development appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI with Large Language Models in C# in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI became the fastest‑growing consumer technology in history, surpassing Instagram and TikTok, reaching 100 million users in under two months. At the end of 2022, OpenAI released a free preview of GPT‑3.5, delivered as a conversational chat client: ChatGPT. The model was fine‑tuned using Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedb
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/generative-ai-with-large-language-models-in-dotnet-and-csharp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | January 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? In C# default interface methods allow you to include a method implementation directly in an interface. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 🔗 Links Here’s the latest from the developer community. ☕ Coffee Break Take a break to catch some […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/05/dotinsights-january-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can you swap two non-adjacent blocks of memory using only forward iterators?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we looked at how you can swap two adjacent blocks of memory using only forward iterators and noted that we can try to use the same trick to develop a forward-only sol
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260105-00/?p=111962 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to 2026, A Growth Year for All of Us</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I always enjoy the quiet stretch between Christmas and New Year’s. It’s one of the few moments in the year when things slow down just enough to reflect on what actually resonated. While many of us were unplugging, our digital team was doing the opposite, editing and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/vs-live-2026-immersive-learning-for-vs2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set the amr claim when using passkeys authentication in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post shows how to set the correct amr value when authenticating using ASP.NET Core Identity and passkeys in .NET 10. When authenticating using OpenID Connect and passkeys authentication, the OpenID Connect Extended Authentication Profile (EAP) ACR Values 1.0 specification should be used for the implementation. The amr claim should return the pop value. Blogs […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2026/01/05/set-the-amr-claim-when-using-passkeys-authentication-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack and JasperFx Retrospective for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 02:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2026/05_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At least professionally, I tend to be mostly focused on what’s next on the road map or upcoming client work or long planned strategic improvements to the Critter Stack (Marten and Wolverine). One of the things I do every year is to write out a blog post stating the technical goals for the OSS projects … Continue reading Critter Stack and JasperFx Retrospective for 2025 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2026/01/04/critter-stack-and-jasperfx-retrospective-for-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Span-Based String Concatenation for Improved Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2026/04_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2026/04_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The excerpt from &amp;quot;Rock Your Code&amp;quot; emphasizes the importance of efficient string concatenation in .NET. It highlights the advantages of using the Span type over traditional methods, demonstrating that replacing Substring with AsSpan and leveraging the Concat function significantly enhances performance by 43 times while minimizing memory allocations.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/01/04/leveraging-span-based-string-concatenation-for-improved-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Years Resolutions For Developers - Dev Leader Weekly 121</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2026/03_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2026/03_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss 2026 New Years Resolutions and invite YOU to share yours!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/01/03/new-years-resolutions-for-developers-dev-leader-weekly-121 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2026-01-02</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2026/03_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2026/03_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/01/03/weekly-recap-20260102 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Urge to Build Something</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2026/03_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2026/03_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking at my contribution graph now, I can see the whole journey mapped out in squares of green. The startup dreams. The pivot to teaching. The thousands of commits that represent years of building, learning, and growing. Every cluster tells a story. What will your graph look like a year from now?
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-urge-to-build-something 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can you swap two adjacent blocks of memory using only forward iterators?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2026/02_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2026/02_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we noted that the std::rotate function requires only forward iterators. The algorithm we explored last time involved a clever sequence of reversals, but reversals require bidirectional iterators (one to iterator forward from the beginning and another to iterate backward from the end).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260102-00/?p=111958 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bug-Fix Releases Are Available for MPS – 2025.2.2, 2025.1.2, 2024.3.5, and 2024.1.6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2026/02_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2026/02_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released updates for multiple major MPS versions that fix several additional issues. Check out all the updates in each particular version below: MPS 2025.2.2 Download MPS 2025.2.2 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. MPS 2025.1.2 Download MPS 2025.1.2 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. MPS 2024.3.5 Download MPS […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2026/01/new_bugfix_releases_mps-2025-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OpenAI Grove Cohort 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2026/02_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2026/02_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications are now open for OpenAI Grove Cohort 2, a 5-week founder program designed for individuals at any stage, from pre-idea to product. Participants receive $50K in API credits, early access to AI tools, and hands-on mentorship from the OpenAI team.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-grove 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swapping two blocks of memory that reside inside a larger block, in constant memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2026/01_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2026/01_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Suppose you have a large block of memory, and you want to swap two blocks that reside inside that large block. For concreteness, say you have a block of memory of the form A1, A2, B1, B2, C1, C2, D1, D2, D3, E1, and you want to swap the B&#39;s and D&#39;s, producing A1, A2, D1, D2, D3, C1, C2, B1, B2, E1.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260101-00/?p=111955 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2026: Regressions, Reliability Issues, and Missed Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2026/01_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2026/01_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2026 has regressed by removing or disabling key code-quality features, making development more difficult. The Analyze tool suffers from inconsistencies and lack of reliability, while various testing functionalities are also flawed. AI tools like Copilot cannot replace essential code-quality features. Greater MVP involvement and thoughtful updates are needed to enhance the IDE.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/01/01/visual-studio-2026-regressions-reliability-issues-and-missed-opportunities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock Your Code: Code &amp; App Performance for Microsoft .NET (5th Edition)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2026/01_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2026/01_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The fifth edition of David McCarter&#39;s book, &amp;quot;Röck Yöur Cöde: Code &amp;amp; App Performance for Microsoft .NET,&amp;quot; is now available on Amazon. It offers practical techniques for enhancing .NET application performance, including coding patterns, memory insights, and benchmarking. This definitive guide is essential for modern .NET developers aiming for speed and scalability.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/01/01/rock-your-code-code-app-performance-for-microsoft-net-5th-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java at Microsoft: 2025 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A breakthrough year for modernization, AI‑assisted development, Agentic AI development, and platform innovation 2025 was one of the most significant years yet for Java at Microsoft. From the arrival of OpenJDK 25 as the newest Long‑Term Su
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-at-microsoft-2025-year-in-review 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top .NET Videos &amp; Live Streams of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It has been an absolutely outstanding year of content for .NET from creators around the globe sharing their passion for .NET and the .NET team giving insight into the latest and greatest in the world of .NET. From events, live streams, and plenty of on-demand content dropping on the .NET YouTube nea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/top-dotnet-videos-live-streams-of-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing PDF Diff: Compare PDFs Privately in Your Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey friends! I&#39;m super excited to share a new tool I&#39;ve been working on that solves a problem I bet many of you have faced: how do you quickly compare two PDF documents to see what changed? Enter PDF Diff!Landing page for PDF Diff
Link to article: https://montemagno.com/introducing-pdf-diff-compare-pdfs-privately-in-your-browser/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 year-end link clearance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Closing the door on another year. Here are some random links. Mesmerizing: Wintergatan - Marble Machine, a musical instrument that uses 2000 marbles. It&#39;s like that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251231-01/?p=111952 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and mitigating a stack overflow in our task sequencer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was using the v2 task_sequencer class we developed some time ago. (Here&#39;s the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251231-00/?p=111950 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2025/31_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Happy Christmas and happy new year! I know it&#39;s been a while since I last posted anything here, but thought I&#39;d revive my tradition of writing another year in review post. Pluralsight Part of the reason for me not having as much time for blogging is that I created three new Pluralsight courses this year, bringing my total to 29. First up was a course about refactoring and optimizing code with GitHub Copilot.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top .NET Blog Posts of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2025/30_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2025/30_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2025 was a big year for .NET developers. We kicked things off with early .NET 10 previews, kept momentum with steady tooling and runtime improvements, and wrapped it all up with the launch of .NET 10 in November. 🚀 .NET 10 .NET 10 was the headline event of the year: the latest Long Term Support (L
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/top-dotnet-blogs-posts-of-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional notes on color-keyed overlays as a way of doing smooth video rendering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2025/30_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2025/30_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A little while ago, I wrote about the use of color-keyed overlays to render video smoothly. The idea is that the CPU itself p
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251230-00/?p=111944 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Oh My Posh Visual Configurator: Finally, a Drag-and-Drop Terminal Theme Builder! ✨</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 19:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A web-based drag-and-drop builder for oh-my-posh that makes creating beautiful terminal prompts actually fun!
Link to article: https://montemagno.com/introducing-oh-my-posh-visual-configurator-finally-a-drag-and-drop-terminal-theme-builder/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate MLflow tracking servers to Amazon SageMaker AI with serverless MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to migrate your self-managed MLflow tracking server to a MLflow App – a serverless tracking server on SageMaker AI that automatically scales resources based on demand while removing server patching and storage management tasks at no cost. Learn how to use the MLflow Export Import tool to transfer your experiments, runs, models, and other MLflow resources, including instructions to validate your migration&#39;s success.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI-powered website assistant with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to solve this challenge by building an AI-powered website assistant using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ai-powered-website-assistant-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gävle Goat (Gävlebocken) succumbs in 2025 to a new menace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Regular readers of this blog may remember the giant traditional Swedish Yule Goat erected annually in the Swedish town of Gävle. The Gävle Goat (
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251229-01/?p=111929 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect that the system is running low on memory? Or that my job is running low on memory?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to write a process that could detect that it is nearing its job memory limit. Now, if you were asking about system memory limits rather than job memory limits, you would use the Create­Memory­Resource­Notification to create a &amp;quot;low memory&amp;quot; notification. As noted in the documentation, this notificatio
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251229-00/?p=111927 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce GitHub Actions runner CPU usage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you&#39;re using self-hosted GitHub Actions runners, you might have noticed they can be surprisingly CPU-intensive, even when idle. A closer look reveals that a single runner can peg a CPU core at 100% utilization. This isn&#39;t a bug in your workflow; it&#39;s a deliberate design choice in the runner&#39;s sleep mechanism. The problem: Busy-waiting Instead of using standard, efficient sleep functions provided by the…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/reduce-github-actions-runner-cpu-usage.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
