<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 18:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure AI Foundry: Create an MCP Server with Azure AI Agent Service (TypeScript Edition)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 18:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to integrate Azure AI Foundry&#39;s Agent Service with Claude Desktop using the Model Context Protocol (MCP) for powerful integration for MCP clients.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/integrating-azure-ai-agents-mcp-typescript 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AIOps chatbot with Amazon Q Business custom plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use custom plugins for Amazon Q Business to build a chatbot that can interact with multiple APIs using natural language prompts. We showcase how to build an AIOps chatbot that enables users to interact with their AWS infrastructure through natural language queries and commands. The chatbot is capable of handling tasks such as querying the data about Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) ports and Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) buckets access settings.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Revolutionize Business Automation with AI: A Guide to Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel Process Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Revolutionize Business Automation with AI: A Guide to Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel Process Framework Step-by-Step guide on creating your first process with AI Microsoft’s AI Framework, Semantic Kernel, is an easy-to-use C#, Java, and Python-based AI framework that helps you quickly build AI solutions or integrate AI capabilities into your existing app. Semantic Kernel provides various […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-revolutionize-business-automation-with-ai-a-guide-to-microsofts-semantic-kernel-process-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How TransPerfect Improved Translation Quality and Efficiency Using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes how the AWS Customer Channel Technology – Localization Team worked with TransPerfect to integrate Amazon Bedrock into the GlobalLink translation management system, a cloud-based solution designed to help organizations manage their multilingual content and translation workflows. Organizations use TransPerfect’s solution to rapidly create and deploy content at scale in multiple languages using AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-transperfect-improved-translation-quality-and-efficiency-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racing beyond DeepRacer: Debut of the AWS LLM League</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS LLM League was designed to lower the barriers to entry in generative AI model customization by providing an experience where participants, regardless of their prior data science experience, could engage in fine-tuning LLMs. Using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart, attendees were guided through the process of customizing LLMs to address real business challenges adaptable to their domain.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/racing-beyond-deepracer-debut-of-the-aws-llm-league/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Microsoft Graph PowerShell 2.26&#43; compatibility issues with Azure Runbooks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 15:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We know how important Azure Automation workflows and appreciate the critical role played by automation runbooks. Some customers have experienced issues with the release of 2.26.1 of the Microsoft Graph PowerShell SDK, particularly when running PowerShell 7.2 runbooks in Azure Automation. The core challenge is a conflict around .NET 6 where fixing Runbooks would break […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/resolving-microsoft-graph-powershell-2-26-compatibility-issues-with-azure-runbooks 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the UI thread that hung in a kernel call</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I did tell you not to do that.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250411-00/?p=111066 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Scott Hanselman – Empowering Developer Community Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Few voices in the Microsoft and .NET space rise above the rest as much as Scott Hanselman. He’s a developer, teacher, speaker, and currently the Vice President of Developer Community at Microsoft. For over two decades, Scott has been a connecting force in the tech world, linking developers to tools, platforms, and to each other. […] The article Big Thinkers: Scott Hanselman – Empowering Developer Community Worldwide was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting insights from changes to items in Azure Cosmos DB just got easier!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB’s change feed provides a view of changes to data in your container. This enables patterns like event sourcing, auditing and synchronizing downstream systems. Change feed can be read in real time or on demand, giving you the most flexibility for processing and reprocessing changes. Change feed is available in two modes, latest […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/getting-insights-from-changes-to-items-in-azure-cosmos-db-just-got-easier 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Docker Extension for Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Speed up development with Docker DX extension with real-time feedback, smarter linting, and intuitive Bake/Compose file support in VS Code.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-dx-extension-for-vs-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 3 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out about the new features in .NET 10 Preview 3 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, C#, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce ML training costs with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the challenges of large-scale frontier model training, focusing on hardware failures and the benefits of Amazon SageMaker HyperPod - a solution that minimizes disruptions, enhances efficiency, and reduces training costs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/reduce-ml-training-costs-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Variables &amp; Methods are Evil?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 19:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You might have heard the recommendation to steer clear of static variables or methods. But is that really good advice? Let’s dive into why people say that, with a little nuance, and clarify the topic with some examples. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video… Read More »Static Variables &amp;amp; Methods are Evil? The post Static Variables &amp;amp; Methods are Evil?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Increase Code Quality in GitHub With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 17:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago we shared a post on how to integrate Qodana with Github Actions on the .NET Community – but a lot has changed since then. Qodana self-hosted has been released, with analysis that can make your code more secure by detecting hardcoded passwords and running taint analysis for JVM. The new Android Linter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/code-quality-in-github/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft at PyTexas 2025: Join Us for a Celebration of Python and Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 17:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft is thrilled to announce our participation in PyTexas 2025, taking place this year in the vibrant city of Austin, Texas! At this year’s event, Microsoft is proud to contribute to the community’s growth and excitement by hosting a booth and delivering an engaging talk.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/pytexas-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Language Support in ReSharper and Rider 2025.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our release for ReSharper and Rider 2025.1 is just around the corner, and we have lots of exciting features shipping for the current and next version of C#! This will be a really long post (blame our awesome devs!), so make sure to use the table of contents on the right. Oh, and of course… […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/10/csharp-language-support-in-resharper-and-rider-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model customization, RAG, or both: A case study with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The introduction of Amazon Nova models represent a significant advancement in the field of AI, offering new opportunities for large language model (LLM) optimization. In this post, we demonstrate how to effectively perform model customization and RAG with Amazon Nova models as a baseline. We conducted a comprehensive comparison study between model customization and RAG using the latest Amazon Nova models, and share these valuable insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/model-customization-rag-or-both-a-case-study-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate user-personalized communication with Amazon Personalize and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Personalize and Amazon Bedrock to generate personalized outreach emails for individual users using a video-on-demand use case. This concept can be applied to other domains, such as compelling customer experiences for ecommerce and digital marketing use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-user-personalized-communication-with-amazon-personalize-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating regulatory compliance: A multi-agent solution using Amazon Bedrock and CrewAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how AI agents can streamline compliance and fulfill regulatory requirements for financial institutions using Amazon Bedrock and CrewAI. We demonstrate how to build a multi-agent system that can automatically summarize new regulations, assess their impact on operations, and provide prescriptive technical guidance. You&#39;ll learn how to use Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon Bedrock Agents with CrewAI to create a comprehensive, automated compliance solution.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 – Help Shape the Future of Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since 2017, we’ve been checking in with developers around the world to better understand how the industry is evolving and how we can build better tools to support you. Now, the Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 is live, and we’d love for you to be part of it. This annual survey is a community milestone that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2025/04/10/developer-ecosystem-survey-2025-help-shape-the-future-of-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire 9.2 is Now Available with New Ways to Deploy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Aspire 9.2 is now available with cool new dashboard features and introducing the publishers feature
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-aspire-92-is-now-available-with-new-ways-to-deploy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixtral Large is now available in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to get started with the Pixtral Large model in Amazon Bedrock. The Pixtral Large multimodal model allows you to tackle a variety of use cases, such as document understanding, logical reasoning, handwriting recognition, image comparison, entity extraction, extracting structured data from scanned images, and caption generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pixtral-large-is-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Context Parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Context parameters are an upcoming feature in Kotlin, with a variety of use cases including more powerful extension methods and better tools for DSL development. Kotlin 2.2.0 will feature context parameters in Beta, and dedicated IntelliJ IDEA support will be available from 2025.1. Context parameters replace another experimental feature in the language, namely context receivers. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/update-on-context-parameters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 14:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Microsoft 365 Certification ensures ISVs use the latest privacy and personally identifiable information (PII) management controls to protect customer data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-privacy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Function overloading is more flexible (and more convenient) than template function specialization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can change more things in an overload.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250410-00/?p=111063 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bug-Fix Releases Are Available – MPS 2024.3.2 and MPS 2024.1.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 11:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released updates for MPS 2024.1 and MPS 2024.3 that fix several additional issues. Check them out and see what you think. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3.2 Download MPS 2024.3.2 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Download MPS 2024.1.3 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/04/mps-2024-3-2-has-been-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown in Java Docs? Shut Up and Take My Comments!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 07:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you’re building a cutting-edge Java library, optimizing every method, and writing the most efficient algorithms. At some point, you’ll need to document your code because well-documented code increases adoption (a fact backed by various surveys). Including documentation comments within a Java class ensures that the documentation evolves with the code, keeping it relevant. Using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/markdown-in-java-docs-shut-up-and-take-my-comments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using an MCP Server in GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot is continuing to evolve very rapidly, with the recent launch of &amp;quot;agent mode&amp;quot;, and the ability to connect to &amp;quot;Model Context Protocol&amp;quot; servers which gives you access to a vast array of tools, essentially allowing your agent to access any data, and perform any actions you like. In this post, I&#39;ll walk you through the steps to configure Visual Studio Code to connect to an MCP Server and make use of it in agent mode.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Hybrid Search with Semantic Kernel for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 19:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re thrilled to announce support for Hybrid search with Semantic Kernel Vector Stores for .NET. What is Hybrid Search? Hybrid search performs two parallel searches on a vector database. The union of the results of these two searches are then returned to callers with a combined rank, based on the rankings from each of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-hybrid-search-with-semantic-kernel-for-net 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement human-in-the-loop confirmation with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 19:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus specifically on enabling end-users to approve actions and provide feedback using built-in Amazon Bedrock Agents features, specifically HITL patterns for providing safe and effective agent operations. We explore the patterns available using a Human Resources (HR) agent example that helps employees requesting time off.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-human-in-the-loop-confirmation-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework April 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 19:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for April 2025.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-april-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we ended up rewriting NuGet Restore in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the journey that led to a full rewrite of the NuGet Restore algorithm in .NET 9, achieving break-through scale and performance.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/rewriting-nuget-restore-in-dotnet-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost team productivity with Amazon Q Business Insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 16:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Q Business Insights capabilities and its importance for organizations. We begin with an overview of the available metrics and how they can be used for measuring user engagement and system effectiveness. Then we provide instructions for accessing and navigating this dashboard.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-team-productivity-with-amazon-q-business-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-LLM routing strategies for generative AI applications on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 16:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are increasingly using multiple large language models (LLMs) when building generative AI applications. Although an individual LLM can be highly capable, it might not optimally address a wide range of use cases or meet diverse performance requirements. The multi-LLM approach enables organizations to effectively choose the right model for each task, adapt to different […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multi-llm-routing-strategies-for-generative-ai-applications-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Together: .NET Aspire, Azure Functions, and Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever struggled with integrating serverless technology into your existing .NET projects? The new update in Visual Studio has got you covered. Say hello to the powerful integration of .NET Aspire with Azure Functions, making your development process smoother than ever before. With this release of Visual Studio, Azure Functions developers can enlist in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//net-aspire-and-azure-functions-integration-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Real-Time Insights: Power BI Integration with vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB Now in Public Preview!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 14:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to introduce Power BI integration for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB. This certified solution brings your operational data to life through real-time dashboards, directly in the Power BI interface that your analytics teams already love. You can now connect Power BI Desktop directly to your vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/unlock-real-time-insights-power-bi-integration-with-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-vcore-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: A Comprehensive Guide to Agentic AI with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to welcome Arafat Tehsin, who’s a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for AI. back as a guest author on the Semantic Kernel blog today to cover his work on a Comprehensive Guide to Agentic AI with Semantic Kernel. We’ll turn it over to Arafat to dive in further. The world of AI is evolving […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-a-comprehensive-guide-to-agentic-ai-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the agent debugging experience in Microsoft 365 Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:58:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to debug your agents within Microsoft 365 Copilot to streamline your workflow using the agent debugging experience, now generally available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-the-agent-debugging-experience-in-microsoft-365-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Gemma 3 with Docker Model Runner: Fully Local GenAI Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how to run Gemma 3 models locally using Docker Model Runner, alongside a Comment Processing System as a practical case study.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-gemma-3-locally-with-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Docker Model Runner: A Better Way to Build and Run GenAI Models Locally</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Model Runner is a faster, simpler way to run and test AI models locally, right from your existing workflow.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2025: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 12:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the April 2025 edition of our monthly developer update, summarizing the latest news and developments in Microsoft Entra. This month, we bring you feature updates, public previews, announcements, and other important updates. Read on to learn more and make the most of Microsoft Entra.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-apr-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire and Azure Functions integration preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever struggled with integrating serverless technology into your existing .NET projects? The new update in Visual Studio has got you covered. Say hello to the powerful integration of .NET Aspire with Azure Functions, making your development process smoother than ever before. With this release of Visual Studio, Azure Functions developers can enlist in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/net-aspire-and-azure-functions-integration-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of LLM Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The journey of Large Language Models (LLMs) is moving fast—from understanding language to driving real-world enterprise workflows. But to truly… The post The Evolution of LLM Integration appeared first on Daily .NET Tips.
Link to article: https://dailydotnettips.com/the-evolution-of-llm-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate is ready for you to try! The upcoming stable release delivers initial support for .NET 10 and C# 14 Preview features. It also brings the new Files view for repository-wide visibility, a Roslyn syntax tree visualizer, and numerous enhancements for debugging both .NET and C++ solutions. If you’re ready to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/rider-2025-1-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.1 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper and .NET tools 2025.1 RCs are now available. This ReSharper update delivers initial support for .NET 10 Preview and C# 14 features, along with expanded inspections, smarter refactorings, and noticeable performance improvements. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the next release, you can download the RC build from our website […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/resharper-2025-1-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Retry Logic Made Easy with Spargine’s ExecutionHelper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a collection of open-source .NET assemblies and NuGet packages designed for enhanced functionality, featuring the ExecutionHelper methods: ProgressiveRetry() and ProgressiveRetryAsync(). These methods manage transient operation failures with retry logic and progressive delays. Additionally, proactive resource checks like IsNetworkAvailable() improve application reliability by checking resource availability before retrying.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/09/boost-your-net-projects-retry-logic-made-easy-with-spargines-executionhelper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Box subscriptions and licensing requirements demystified: What You Need and Why</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 22:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thinking of deploying Microsoft Dev Box service but want to understand the licensing and subscription requirements first? Then, you have come to the right place. This blog post breaks it all down—clearly and simply—so you know exactly what you need and why, whether you’re an IT admin, platform engineer, developer, or a decision-maker. Microsoft Dev […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/microsoft-dev-box-subscriptions-and-licensing-requirements-demystified 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April Patches for Azure DevOps Server and Team Foundation Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 19:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing patches that impact our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server, as well as Team Foundation Server 2018.3.2. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can download the latest version of the product, Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 from the Azure DevOps […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/april-patches-for-azure-devops-server-and-team-foundation-server-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 18:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Release Candidate is available for download, so we’re one step away from the major release! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. To use this build, an active subscription to IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate is required. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 RC […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/intellij-idea-2025-1-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (March 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 18:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.03.19 registry release, 2025-03-13 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout March. This release includes two new commands for our continuous integration system PR reviews, minor bugfixes, a new documentation article on authenticating to NuGet feeds, and a […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-march-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How iFood built a platform to run hundreds of machine learning models with Amazon SageMaker Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 17:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how iFood uses SageMaker to revolutionize its ML operations. By harnessing the power of SageMaker, iFood streamlines the entire ML lifecycle, from model training to deployment. This integration not only simplifies complex processes but also automates critical tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-ifood-built-a-platform-to-run-hundreds-of-machine-learning-models-with-amazon-sagemaker-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an enterprise synthetic data strategy using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Bedrock for synthetic data generation, considering these challenges alongside the potential benefits to develop effective strategies for various applications across multiple industries, including AI and machine learning (ML).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-enterprise-synthetic-data-strategy-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Tools for JetBrains IDE Plugin Development: Livestream Recording and Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The recording of our livestream is available on JetBrains TV! In the recent session, IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Yann Cébron and Jakub Chrzanowski explored some of the most helpful tools for developing plugins for JetBrains IDEs. From plugin creation to UI debugging, the session covered practical tips and tricks to enhance your workflow. Let’s take […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/essential-tools-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-development-livestream-recording-and-key-takeaways/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Process CPU Usage Analysis in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Streamlined Performance Insights Across Processes The Visual Studio Profiler’s CPU Usage tool and Instrumentation tool now supports multi-process analysis, providing a unified view of CPU activity across multiple processes. With performance graphs featuring distinct, color-coded stacked swim lanes for each process, diagnosing and optimizing CPU usage is now more efficient than ever. Tackling Multi-Process Complexity […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/multi-process-cpu-usage-analysis-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Vector Store Connectors update: Faiss, Azure SQL Server and Pinecone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 14:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing New Vector Stores: Faiss, SQL Server, and Pinecone We are thrilled to announce the availability of three new Vector Stores and Vector Store Record Collections: Faiss, SQL Server, and Pinecone. These new connectors will enable you to store and retrieve vector data efficiently, making it easier to work with your own data and data […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/python-vector-store-connectors-update-faiss-azure-sql-server-and-pinecone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Goldilocks zone of software stability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not too new, not too old.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250408-00/?p=111057 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Terminal: A New Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 13:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce our reworked terminal architecture, which is available in Beta starting with the 2025.1 versions of JetBrains IDEs. It now runs on a stable, standards-compliant core and uses the IDE’s editor for UI rendering. This change lets us introduce new features while preserving compatibility and performance across various platforms, whether local or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/jetbrains-terminal-a-new-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write AI Prompts That Output Valid JSON Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 12:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with LLMs, an extremely valuable use case is generating structured data as the output response of the AI prompt. Whether you’re building an app, prototyping a data pipeline, or performing data extraction or transformation, receiving structured outputs like JSON saves time and makes downstream processing seamless. But there’s a challenge: these models are […] The article How to Write AI Prompts That Output Valid JSON Data was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verifying tricky git rebases with git range-diff</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at the git range-diff feature, show what it&#39;s for and how it works, explain the output format, and demonstrate it with a toy scenario
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/verifiying-tricky-git-rebases-with-range-diffs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing JSON Serialization in .NET: Newtonsoft.Json vs. System.Text.Json</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 08:19:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JavaScript Object Notation (JSON) is a popular data storage and transmitting format. Whether you are a front-end or back-end developer, you must be familiar with it. As a.NET developer, you don&#39;t need an introduction to this text-based data format. The two most prominent libraries are Newtonsoft.Json
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/optimizing-json-serialization-in-net-newtonsoft-json-vs-system-text-json/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Llama 4 family of models from Meta are now available in SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 22:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce the availability of Llama 4 Scout and Maverick models in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. In this blog post, we walk you through how to deploy and prompt a Llama-4-Scout-17B-16E-Instruct model using SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/llama-4-family-of-models-from-meta-are-now-available-in-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-tenancy in RAG applications in a single Amazon Bedrock knowledge base with metadata filtering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 21:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases can help you scale your data management effectively while maintaining proper access controls on different management levels.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multi-tenancy-in-rag-applications-in-a-single-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-base-with-metadata-filtering/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectively use prompt caching on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 21:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Prompt caching, now generally available on Amazon Bedrock with Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Haiku and Claude 3.7 Sonnet, along with Nova Micro, Nova Lite, and Nova Pro models, lowers response latency by up to 85% and reduces costs up to 90% by caching frequently used prompts across multiple API calls. This post provides a detailed overview of the prompt caching feature on Amazon Bedrock and offers guidance on how to effectively use this feature to achieve improved latency and cost savings.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Semantic Kernel and Copilot Studio Usage Series – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 18:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today on the Semantic Kernel blog we’re excited to welcome a group of guest authors from Microsoft. We’ll turn it over to Riccardo Chiodaroli, Samar El Housseini, Daniel Lavve and Fabrizio Ruocco to dive into their use cases with Semantic Kernel and Copilot Studio. In today’s fast-paced digital economy, intelligent automation is no longer optional—it’s […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-semantic-kernel-and-copilot-studio-usage-series-part-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced tracing and evaluation of generative AI agents using LangChain and Amazon SageMaker AI MLFlow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 17:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, I show you how to combine LangChain&#39;s LangGraph, Amazon SageMaker AI, and MLflow to demonstrate a powerful workflow for developing, evaluating, and deploying sophisticated generative AI agents. This integration provides the tools needed to gain deep insights into the generative AI agent&#39;s performance, iterate quickly, and maintain version control throughout the development process.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advanced-tracing-and-evaluation-of-generative-ai-agents-using-langchain-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to build a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server using the C# SDK to enable seamless communication between AI models and applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/build-a-model-context-protocol-mcp-server-in-csharp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Golang Still Growing? Go Language Popularity Trends in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 15:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a fast-growing language with a wide range of applications, Go has become increasingly relevant to both new and existing developers. In this blog post, we will share our overview of the current state of Go, its position in the programming landscape, and the strategies for the future of Go. Following an analysis of its […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/04/is-golang-still-growing-go-language-popularity-trends-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Search Capabilities in SQL Server and Azure SQL with Hybrid Search and RRF Re-Ranking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 15:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-driven world, delivering precise and contextually relevant search results is critical. SQL Server and Azure SQL Database now enable this through Hybrid Search—a technique that combines traditional full-text search with modern vector similarity search. This allows developers to build intelligent, AI-powered search experiences directly inside the database engine. Funny enough one of the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/enhancing-search-capabilities-in-sql-server-and-azure-sql-with-hybrid-search-and-rrf-re-ranking 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On priority inversion in the use of a spinlock to ensure atomic access to a shared_ptr</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Priority inversion may be rare, but correctness doesn&#39;t care about rarity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250407-00/?p=111054 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2025 Talks Announced</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 13:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++ is our free, one-day, virtual conference for the whole C++ community. This year, it is running on the 30th April. We’re pleased to announce four of our five live sessions for the day: Welcome to v1.0 of the meta::[[verse]]! with Inbal Levi Proxy: Next Generation Polymorphism with Mingxin Wang Making unfamiliar C++ […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-cpp-2025-talks-announced 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Code Smarter, Not Harder: AI-Powered Dev Hacks for All</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 07:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Dan Vega, where we’ll explore the Stream Gatherer API in JDK 24 and how to use it effectively in your applications. Date: April 17, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In today’s fast-paced software development landscape, AI has become a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/new-livestream-code-smarter-not-harder-ai-powered-dev-hacks-for-all/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Type Checking Methods in .NET: Performance vs. Readability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_04_2025/06_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_04_2025/06_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In .NET, type checking methods include GetType(), the is keyword, IsAssignableFrom(), and the as keyword. Each method varies in readability and performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/06/comparing-type-checking-methods-in-net-performance-vs-readability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make the Most of Your One on Ones - Dev Leader Weekly 90</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to approach one on ones with your software engineering manager.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/04/05/make-the-most-of-your-one-on-ones-dev-leader-weekly-90 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removal of deprecated DISCO &amp; WSDL aspx pages from SharePoint Online</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 11:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are removing DSICO and WSDL pages from the SharePoint Online by mid September 2025.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/removal-of-deprecated-disco-wsdl-aspx-pages-from-sharepoint-online 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-04-04</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 06:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/04/05/weekly-recap-20250404 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI agents with Python in #AgentsHack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft is holding an AI Agents Hackathon, and we want to see what you can build with Python! We&#39;ll have 20+ live streams showing you how to build AI agents with Python using popular agent frameworks and Microsoft technologies. Then, you can submit your project for a chance to win prizes, including a Best in Python prize!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/agentshack-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MediatR and MassTransit Going Commercial: What This Means For You</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2025/05_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Popular .NET libraries MediatR, AutoMapper, and MassTransit are transitioning to commercial licenses after over a decade of free open-source availability. This article examines the reasons behind these changes, what they mean for your projects, and the practical options available to developers moving forward.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/mediatr-and-masstransit-going-commercial-what-this-means-for-you 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run LLMs Locally with Docker: A Quickstart Guide to Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 20:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is quickly becoming a core part of modern applications, but running large language models (LLMs) locally can still be a pain. Between picking the right model, navigating hardware quirks, and optimizing for performance, it’s easy to get stuck before you even start building. At the same time, more and more developers want the flexibility […]
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-llms-locally/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompting for the best price-performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 20:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog, we discuss how to optimize prompting in Amazon Nova for the best price-performance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/prompting-for-the-best-price-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – April 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 17:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The April 2025 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code is now available. This update introduces enhancements to the Copilot experience in Notebooks, improved support for editable installs, faster and more reliable diagnostics, and the addition of custom Node.js arguments with Pylance, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-april-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boards Integration with GitHub Enterprise Cloud and Data Residency (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 17:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in January, we launched a private preview of our Boards integration with GitHub Enterprise Cloud with data residency. If you’re unfamiliar with GitHub’s data residency option and what it means for your organization, you can learn more in the original announcement. Since the private preview launch, we’ve gathered valuable feedback from early adopters, and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/boards-integration-with-github-enterprise-cloud-and-data-residency-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel Agents are now Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 16:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The time is finally here, Semantic Kernel’s Agent framework is now Generally Available! Available today as part of Semantic Kernel 1.45 (.NET) and 1.27 (Python), the Semantic Kernel Agent framework makes it easier for agents to coordinate and dramatically reduces the code developers need to write to build amazing AI applications. What does Generally Available […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-agents-are-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate models or RAG systems using Amazon Bedrock Evaluations – Now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 15:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce the general availability of these evaluation features in Amazon Bedrock Evaluations, along with significant enhancements that make them fully environment-agnostic. In this post, we explore these new features in detail, showing you how to evaluate both RAG systems and models with practical examples. We demonstrate how to use the comparison capabilities to benchmark different implementations and make data-driven decisions about your AI deployments.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune large language models with reinforcement learning from human or AI feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 14:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce a state-of-the-art method to fine-tune LLMs by reinforcement learning, reviewed the pros and cons of RLHF vs. RLAIF vs. DPO, and saw how to scale LLM fine-tuning efforts with RLAIF. We also see how to implement an end-to-end RLAIF pipeline on SageMaker using the Hugging Face Transformer and TRL libraries, and using either off-the-shelf toxicity reward models to align responses during PPO or by directly prompting an LLM to generate quantitative reward feedback during PPO.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Lumi streamlines loan approvals with Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 14:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Lumi is a leading Australian fintech lender empowering small businesses with fast, flexible, and transparent funding solutions. They use real-time data and machine learning (ML) to offer customized loans that fuel sustainable growth and solve the challenges of accessing capital. This post explores how Lumi uses Amazon SageMaker AI to meet this goal, enhance their transaction processing and classification capabilities, and ultimately grow their business by providing faster processing of loan applications, more accurate credit decisions, and improved customer experience.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From BASIC to Copilot: 50 Years of Microsoft Technology Innovation and Leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 14:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are few companies in the history of technology — or business, for that matter — that can say they changed the world. Even fewer can say they did it more than once. As Microsoft marks its 50th anniversary, it’s hard not to marvel at just how much of our modern digital life bears its […] The article From BASIC to Copilot: 50 Years of Microsoft Technology Innovation and Leadership was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding delays to our task sequencer, part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Waiting more cheaply.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250404-00/?p=111046 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Fuzz Testing to Kotlin with kotlinx.fuzz</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 13:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Identifying edge cases for testing can be a challenging task, often leaving hidden bugs and vulnerabilities undetected. Fuzz testing (fuzzing) addresses this challenge by automatically generating tests with random or invalid inputs, enabling developers to uncover unexpected exceptions and failure scenarios. Thanks to its effectiveness in detecting critical software flaws, fuzzing has gained widespread use […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/04/kotlinxfuzz-kotlin-fuzzing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Anders Hejlsberg – The Architect Shaping the Cloud’s Programming Future from C# to TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 12:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Few names carry as much respect and recognition among software developers as Anders Hejlsberg. As the creator of Turbo Pascal, the chief architect of Delphi, the original designer of C#, and now the lead architect of TypeScript, Hejlsberg has shaped the way millions of developers write code daily. While his earlier work transformed client-side and […] The article Big Thinkers: Anders Hejlsberg – The Architect Shaping the Cloud’s Programming Future from C# to TypeScript was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure AI Foundry Extension for Visual Studio Code is Available in Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 09:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use Azure AI Foundry capabilities directly in VS Code with the Azure AI Foundry extension for Visual Studio Code, now available in public preview. Deploy Large Language Models, develop AI applications, and configure agents seamlessly within your favorite VS Code setup.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/azure-ai-foundry-vscode-extension-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AI Red Teaming Agent: Accelerate Your Trustworthy AI Journey with Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 09:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI Red Teaming Agent, integrated into Azure AI Foundry, enhances the safety and security of generative AI systems by providing automated scans, evaluating probing success, and generating detailed scorecards to guide risk management strategies.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/ai-red-teaming-agent-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of Agentic Applications: New Evaluation Metrics for Quality and Safety</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 09:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            New evaluation metrics in Azure AI Foundry help developers assess the quality and safety of agentic applications. These metrics enhance AI red teaming capabilities, enabling automated risk and safety evaluations through streamlined campaigns and regular assessments.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/evaluation-metrics-azure-ai-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – April 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 07:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the April edition of Java Annotated Monthly! Java 24 has landed, and we’ve got plenty to say about it. From fresh language features to smart tricks and must-try tutorials, there’s something for every curious developer. The cherry on top? Mala Gupta joins us as this month’s featured guest – don’t miss her insights! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/java-annotated-monthly-april-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Improve .NET Performance by Reusing Constant Arrays</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In optimizing the Spargine project, I improved performance by avoiding constant arrays as method arguments. Instead, using static readonly fields reduced memory allocations significantly. This change enhanced execution speed, yielding a 1.34x performance gain. I recommend enabling CA1856 warnings in .editorconfig to maintain performance-focused coding practices.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/04/microsoft-net-code-analysis-improve-net-performance-by-reusing-constant-arrays/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
