<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Compose to Kubernetes to Cloud: Designing and Operating Infrastructure with Kanvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker has long been the simplest way to run containers. Developers start with a docker-compose.yml file, run docker compose up, and get things running fast. As teams grow and workloads expand into Kubernetes and integrate into cloud services, simplicity fades. Kubernetes has become the operating system of the cloud, but your clusters rarely live in...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/compose-to-kubernetes-to-cloud-kanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Made Simple: A Guide for JVM Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was written by an external contributor. Kubernetes is a container orchestration system for deploying, scaling, and managing containerized applications. If you build services on the Java virtual machine (JVM), you likely know that most microservices run on Kubernetes. Kubernetes has become the de facto standard for running containerized microservices at scale. However, Kubernetes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/kubernetes-made-simple-a-guide-for-jvm-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie Now Integrated Into the AI Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’re always listening closely to our users, ensuring that the products we ship provide a consistent and intuitive user experience. One area for improvement that we both noticed is the presence of two separate UIs – one for Junie, the coding agent by JetBrains, and one for the JetBrains AI chat. We’ve now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/junie-now-integrated-into-the-ai-chat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2025.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2025.3 brings a set of powerful upgrades designed to help you write cleaner and more efficient code. This release introduces on-the-fly resource leak detection, bundled Terraform support, smoother single-file editing, updates to golangci-lint integration, and performance boosts everywhere in the IDE. Early resource leak detection GoLand now helps you catch resource leaks – situations […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/12/08/goland-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.3 Is Here, and It’s Epic: Faster Language Engine, Unique Constexpr Debugger, DAP Support, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is one of our largest updates ever, featuring advanced capabilities and refinements to deliver a smoother workflow. CLion 2025.3 represents one of our most ambitious releases yet. Beyond the extensive feature additions and workflow improvements, this version marks a fundamental shift in how we approach C and C++ language support – prioritizing speed and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/12/2025-3-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2025.3: Multi-Agent AI Chat, Rails-Aware MCP Server, Faster Multi-Module Projects Startup, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2025.3 is out! This blog post briefly goes over the highlights of the latest release. For a detailed description, check out our What’s New page. You can get the new build from our website or via the free Toolbox App. AI Assistant Multi-agent experience: Junie and Claude Agent With the addition of Claude Agent, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/12/rubymine-2025-3-multi-agent-ai-chat-rails-aware-mcp-server-faster-multi-module-projects-startup-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Is Out Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 has arrived! This version brings significant updates designed to streamline your productivity and help you confidently adopt the latest innovations across the Java ecosystem. You can download this latest release from our website or update to it directly from inside the IDE, via the free Toolbox App, or using snap packages for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Overload Ambiguity with Collection Expressions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OverloadResolutionPriority allows you to specify which method overload should be preferred by the compiler when multiple overloads are applicable. This can be useful in scenarios where you have multiple methods with types that can be implicitly converted to each other, and you want to control which overload is chosen. I&#39;ve found this feature particularly useful when having existing overloads that take…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/resolving-overload-ambiguity-with-collection-expressions.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2025.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scala 3 Support Scala 3.8 introduces several significant changes, including a new into modifier, the standard library now being compiled with Scala 3, and the minimum required JDK version being updated to 17. Given that the next Scala version, 3.9 LTS, will focus on stabilization, it was important for us to support these new changes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2025/12/08/scala-plugin-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unified IntelliJ IDEA: More Free Features, a Better Experience, Smoother Flow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA is now a unified product! As we announced back in July, starting from this release (2025.3), there is one IntelliJ IDEA, replacing the separate IntelliJ IDEA Community Edition and IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate to keep things simple and convenient. All the functionality of the Community Edition remains free for non-commercial and commercial use. We’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-unified-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Islands Theme – The New Default Look for JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Islands theme is now the default look across JetBrains IDEs starting with version 2025.3.This update is more than a visual refresh. It’s our commitment to creating a soft, balanced environment designed to support focus and comfort throughout your workflow. We began introducing the new theme earlier this year, gathering feedback, conducting research, and testing it hands-on with developers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/12/meet-the-islands-theme-the-new-default-look-for-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Fixed in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the overview of fixes and improvements in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3. In this release, we have resolved over 800 bug reports and usability issues throughout the IDE, with the highlights including improvements to the developer experience, Spring support, build tools, version control, the terminal, and more. Below are the most impactful changes that will […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/what-s-fixed-in-intellij-idea-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2025.3: Enhanced Monorepo Support, Framework Improvements, Vitest 4 Support, Multiple Agents in AI Assistant, Remote Debugging, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WebStorm 2025.3 is now available!After months of development, this release brings a host of new features and improvements. Highlights include: This release also includes numerous fixes and quality‑of‑life enhancements for TypeScript, Angular, Vue, Astro, Prettier, and more. You can update to WebStorm 2025.3 via the Toolbox App or download it directly from our website. We […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/12/webstorm-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instacart and OpenAI partner on AI shopping experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Instacart are deepening their longstanding partnership by bringing the first fully integrated grocery shopping and Instant Checkout payment app to ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/instacart-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of enterprise AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Key findings from OpenAI’s enterprise data show accelerating AI adoption, deeper integration, and measurable productivity gains across industries in 2025.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/the-state-of-enterprise-ai-2025-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immutable Collection Add() Trap: Don’t Get Burned — Use a Builder Instead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_12_2025/07_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_12_2025/07_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When using immutable collections in .NET, remember that the Add() method creates a new instance rather than mutating the original. Ignoring the return value leads to ineffective loops. Instead, use a builder for efficiency, as it offers faster performance and lower memory allocation while still ensuring immutability in the final result.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/12/07/immutable-collection-add-trap-dont-get-burned-use-a-builder-instead/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senior Engineers Spend Less Time Coding - Dev Leader Weekly 118</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2025/06_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2025/06_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss balancing time coding as a senior software engineer.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/06/senior-engineers-spend-less-time-coding-dev-leader-weekly-118 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-12-05</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2025/06_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2025/06_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/06/weekly-recap-20251205 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DbContext is Not Thread-Safe: Parallelizing EF Core Queries the Right Way</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2025/06_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2025/06_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to safely parallelize EF Core queries to improve performance by using IDbContextFactory to create isolated contexts, avoiding the thread-safety exceptions caused by sharing a single DbContext instance.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/dbcontext-is-not-thread-safe-parallelizing-ef-core-queries-the-right-way 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us for AI Dev Days - December 10-11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2025 was a year of incredible progress for AI and our industry as a whole. At Microsoft and GitHub, we&#39;ve innovated beyond isolated chats and prompts to building systems that collaborate with connected workflows and operational intelligence. This shift can be seen across the stack, from Microsoft Foundry, to GitHub Copilot in
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/join-us-for-ai-devdays 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker, JetBrains, and Zed: Building a Common Language for Agents and IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As agents become capable enough to write and refactor code, they should work natively inside the environments developers work in: editors. That’s why JetBrains and Zed are co-developing ACP, the Agent Client Protocol. ACP gives agents and editors a shared language, so any agent can read context, take actions, and respond intelligently without bespoke wiring...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-jetbrains-and-zed-building-a-common-language-for-agents-and-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can my process read its own standard output?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to know how their C# program could read its own standard output. They tried this: // Get my process Process p = Process.GetCurrentProcess(); // Make sure my standard output is not redirected p.StartInfo.UseShellExecute = false; p.StartInfo.RedirectStandardOutput = false; // Now read it -- fails string o
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251205-00/?p=111843 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing vLLM v0.12.0, Ministral 3 and DeepSeek-V3.2 for Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Docker, we are committed to making the AI development experience as seamless as possible. Today, we are thrilled to announce two major updates that bring state-of-the-art performance and frontier-class models directly to your fingertips: the immediate availability of Mistral AI’s Ministral 3 and DeepSeek-V3.2, alongside the release of vLLM v0.12.0 on Docker Model Runner....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-vllm-ministral-deepseek/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring your own AI agent to JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey! Here at JetBrains, we’re always happy to bring our users the best and most popular tools available on the market. This has been true for decades with conventional dev tooling: compilers, debuggers, build tools, etc; in the past several years, we’ve shipped all the newest LLMs in the same manner, and we want the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/bring-your-own-ai-agent-to-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.3 Release Candidate Is Ready!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the last step on our way toward the final release, the Release Candidate for MPS 2025.3 is now available for you to download! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 RC 1 To find out what features to expect in this release, check out the earlier updates from the EAP 1 and EAP 2 builds. The full list […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/12/the-mps-2025-3-rc1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Manage Configuration Drift in Your Jenkins Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Rajkumar Venkatasamy, draft.dev. Jenkins is still one of the most popular tools for continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD). People love it for its flexibility, vast plugin ecosystem, and the fact that it’s open source. It can automate just about any build, test, or deployment you throw at it, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/jenkins-configuration-drift/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month brings significant developments throughout the Java ecosystem. Java has begun announcing JEPs targeted for the upcoming release, while Spring has unveiled major updates with Spring Framework 7 and Spring Boot 4. As always, we’ve curated the most interesting articles, videos, and podcasts covering Java, Kotlin, Spring, AI, and other relevant topics in technology […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/java-annotated-monthly-december-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Classic” .NET Domain Events with Wolverine and EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was helping a new JasperFx Software client this week to best integrate a Domain Events strategy into their new Wolverine codebase. This client wanted to use the common model of using an EF Core DbContext to harvest domain events raised by different entities and relay those to Wolverine messaging with proper Wolverine transactional outbox … Continue reading “Classic” .NET Domain Events with Wolverine and EF Core →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Conf 2025 Recap - Celebrating .NET 10, Visual Studio 2026, AI, Community, &amp; More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At .NET Conf 2025 we celebrated the official launch of .NET 10 and Visual Studio 2026. The event provided a deeper dive into the world of .NET for developers worldwide and there were many announcements across the entir
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-conf-2025-recap 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking New Possibilities: Microsoft Azure Hyperscale AI Computing with H200 GPUs Accelerates Secure AI Innovation in Azure for U.S. Government Secret and Top Secret</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As artificial intelligence continues to reshape industries and redefine the boundaries of innovation, Microsoft is proud to announce a leap forward in secure, high-performance computing in our Secret and Top Secret clouds: the integration of NVIDIA H200 Tensor Core GPUs into Azure’s AI infrastructure. This advancement helps unlock unpreceden
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/h200-gpus-in-azure-government-secret-and-top-secret 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locking Down MCP: Create a Private Registry on Azure API Center and Enforce It in GitHub Copilot And VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever since MCP launched, every customer has asked the same thing:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/locking-down-mcp-create-a-private-registry-on-azure-api-center-and-enforce-it-in-github-copilot-and-vs-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I read the standard output of an already-running process?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to know if they could read the standard output of an already-running process. They didn&#39;t explain why, but my guess is that their main process launches a helper process (not written by them) to begin some workflow, and eventually that helper process launches a console process, which produces the desired output. But they wa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251204-00/?p=111841 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of Web with Copilot Chat’s New URL Context</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are many scenarios whereÂ Copilot ChatÂ canÂ feelÂ limited byÂ theÂ built-inÂ modelÂ training data.Â Maybe youÂ want guidance on the latest web framework, documentation, or project-specific resourcesâ€”but Copilotâ€™s responses justÂ arenâ€™tÂ specific enough. For developers who rely on up-to-dateÂ or esotericÂ
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/unlocking-the-power-of-web-with-copilot-chats-new-url-context 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Deprecation of K1 Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the next step in the evolution of K2 mode, with the IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 release we are officially deprecating its predecessor, K1 mode. In this post, we’ll give some background about K2 mode and discuss its current state, including adoption numbers, performance test results, and feature parity and stability. As always, we recommend updating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/the-deprecation-of-k1-mode/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v2.0 with improved AI telemetry, and small breaking changes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the release of Dev Proxy v2.0. Following semantic versioning (SemVer), we&#39;re bumping the major version due to breaking changes in this release. While these changes are small, they improve Dev Proxy&#39;s accuracy and behavior - and we want you to be aware of them. This release also br
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v2-0-with-improved-ai-telemetry-and-small-breaking-changes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock GitHub Copilot’s Full Potential: Why Every Repo Needs an AGENTS.md File</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Supercharge Your AI Pair Programming Experience with Project-Specific Context and Control AI-assisted development has rapidly transformed how engineers write code, collaborate, and ship software. GitHub Copilot, powered by OpenAI’s Codex and now evolving with GPT-5 capabilities, is at the center of this revolution — quietly sitting in your IDE, turning natural language prompts into working […] The article Unlock GitHub Copilot’s Full Potential: Why Every Repo Needs an AGENTS.md File was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoMapper 16.0.0 and MediatR 14.0.0 Released with .NET 10 Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of .NET, we&#39;ve released updated packages of AutoMapper and MediatR targeting .NET 10 (and all supported versions of .NET and 4.x of .NET Framework).From this release forward, we&#39;re aligning to major release cadences of .NET since this also means upping our
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/automapper-16-0-0-and-mediatr-14-0-0-released-with-net-10-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Foundry MCP Server (preview) in the cloud, speeding up AI development with Microsoft Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MCP (Model Context Protocol) is a standard protocol that enables AI agents to securely connect with apps, data, and systems, supporting easy interoperability and seamless platform expansion. At Ignite, Microsoft Foundry introduced Foundry Too
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/announcing-foundry-mcp-server-preview-speeding-up-ai-dev-with-microsoft-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Data Ingestion Building Blocks (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building AI applications, context is key. AI models have a knowledge cutoff and do not have access to your personal or company data by default. To generate high-quality answers, AI apps need two things: Access to high-quality data The ability to surface the right information at the right time
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-data-ingestion-building-blocks-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio November Update – Visual Studio 2026, Cloud Agent Preview, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-november-update-visual-studio-2026-cloud-agent-preview-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why changing keyboard shortcuts in Visual Studio isn’t as simple as it seems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A straight look at what’s behind the keys We’ve all tried unlearning a keyboard shortcut - it feels like forgetting how to breathe. Muscle memory doesn’t mess around. We wrestle with this every time someone suggest a “quick” shortcut change. It’s not just editing a keybinding but navigating a history that makes Visual Stu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/why-changing-keyboard-shortcuts-in-visual-studio-isnt-as-simple-as-it-seems 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I check whether the user has permission to create files in a directory?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to accept a directory entered by the user and verify that the user has permission to create files in that folder. The directory itself might not even be on a local hard drive; it could be a DVD or a remote network volume. They tried calling Get­File­Attributes, but all they were told was that it was a direct
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251203-00/?p=111836 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipe dreams to pipeline realities: an Aspire Pipelines story</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Liked this blog post? It was originally posted on Safia Abdalla&#39;s blog, https://blog.safia.rocks/, check out more content there! OK, sit down folks, because this one is gonna be a long one. This is the all-encompassing blog post about the thing I&#39;v
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspire-pipelines 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing the Docker MCP Catalog: Commit Pinning, Agentic Auditing, and Publisher Trust Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trust is the most important consideration when you connect AI assistants to real tools. While MCP containerization provides strong isolation and limits the blast radius of malfunctioning or compromised servers, we’re continuously strengthening trust and security across the Docker MCP solutions to further reduce exposure to malicious code. As the MCP ecosystem scales from hundreds...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/enhancing-mcp-trust-with-the-docker-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Us Anything During JetBrains AMA Week</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains will be hosting a series of open Ask Me Anything (AMA) sessions on Reddit December 9–12. On scheduled days, our product teams will join r/jetbrains to talk directly with developers who use our tools every day. We’ll be there for honest conversations about what’s working, what’s not, and where your priorities lie. Your feedback […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/03/ask-us-anything-during-jetbrains-ama-week/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How confessions can keep language models honest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI researchers are testing “confessions,” a method that trains models to admit when they make mistakes or act undesirably, helping improve AI honesty, transparency, and trust in model outputs.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/how-confessions-can-keep-language-models-honest 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI to acquire Neptune</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is acquiring Neptune to deepen visibility into model behavior and strengthen the tools researchers use to track experiments and monitor training.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-to-acquire-neptune 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Stories Of Developers Using JetBrains Rider to Create, Collaborate, and Have Fun</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago, we introduced a free non-commercial use license option for JetBrains Rider, hoping to remove barriers for developers who code with no financial objective in mind for their projects. Recently, we put out a call for your stories – curious to learn how you’ve been using Rider throughout this year. What came back […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/03/5-stories-of-developers-using-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the initial People-First AI Fund grantees</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The OpenAI Foundation announces the initial recipients of the People-First AI Fund, awarding $40.5M in unrestricted grants to 208 nonprofits supporting community innovation and opportunity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/people-first-ai-fund-grantees 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.5-1 and 1.24.11-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-5-1-and-1-24-11-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>⭐Upcoming Virtual Event⭐ AI Dev Days, Level-Up Your AI Skills with Microsoft Reactor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 03:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/ai-dev-days-december-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Interaction Changes Everything: Treating AI Agents as Collaborators, Not Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft Ignite 2025, I joined Amanda Silver (CVP, Apps &amp;amp; Agents + 1ES GM) and Karl Piteira (1ES PM lead) on stage to talk about Microsoft&#39;s transformation into an AI-driven engineering organization. The big narrative was about agents as partners in the development lifecycle, moving from tools that assist, to intell
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/the-interaction-changes-everything-treating-ai-agents-as-collaborators-not-automation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single File Test Suites in Dotnet Csharp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:16:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction One of my favorite new features in .NET 10 is C# file-based apps (or file-based C# programs if you prefer). With this feature, we can create individual .cs files and then run them using dotnet run &amp;lt;file.cs&amp;gt;. On Unix OSes you can go even further and mark the files as executable and include a shebang (#!) directive as the first line to tell the OS what to run it with and then you can run the files directly without even calling dotnet run.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DirectX Graphics Samples Updated to Agility SDK &#43; Enhanced Barriers examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share all DirectX Graphics Samples have been updated to use the latest DirectX 12 Agility SDK. What’s New: Agility SDK Integration: All samples now leverage the latest Agility SDK for improved compatibility and faster adoption of new DirectX capabilities. Enhanced Barrie
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directx-graphics-samples-updated-to-agility-sdk-enhanced-barriers-examples 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Sensitive Mobile Operations with Device-Bound Request Signing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mobile security goes beyond verifying user identity. If an attacker steals a valid token, how will your backend distinguish a legitimate request from one reproduced in an emulator or cloned environment? This is a gap in traditional authentication flows when applied to the mobile environment. By linking each request to hardware-backed keys g
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/securing-sensitive-mobile-operations-with-device-bound-request-signing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress on TypeScript 7 - December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this year, the TypeScript team announced that we&#39;ve been porting the compiler and language service to native code to take advantage of better raw performance, memory usage, and parallelism. This effort (codenamed &amp;quot;Project Corsa&amp;quot;, and soon &amp;quot;TypeScript 7.0&amp;quot;)
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/progress-on-typescript-7-december-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use cd - in Powershell 7 to Return to Previous Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:16:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction A command that many shells have had forever and that PowerShell has had for a long time as well is ‘cd -’ which means “change directory to previous folder”. This means you could do something like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6
cd c:\dev c:\dev cd c:\temp c:\temp cd - c:\dev
This is quite handy in many situations. In particular, since I’ve modified my PowerShell Profile to NOT start in my users folder but instead to start in my c:\dev folder (from which I can easily get to any repo I may be working from), I very often find myself using cd - whenever I create a new terminal in the folder I want to be in such as when using VS Code.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grok Models Come to the AI Chat in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re expanding our AI offering with xAI’s Grok family of LLMs: Grok 4, Grok 4.1 Fast, Grok 4.1 Fast (Non-Reasoning), and Grok Code Fast 1. With the addition of these models in the AI chat across all JetBrains IDEs, you now have even more flexibility to choose the model that best fits your workflow. How […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/grok-models-come-to-the-ai-chat-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tata Neu delivers personalized shopping experiences for millions of users with Azure DocumentDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Azure DocumentDB, Tata Neu delivers seamless authentication for millions of users, accelerates credit card onboarding across partners, unifies loyalty programs for hundreds of millions of members, and powers AI-driven support experiences across more than 60 brands.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/tata-neu-delivers-personalized-shopping-experiences-for-millions-of-users-with-azure-documentdb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiler Agent - Delegate the analysis, not the performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Visual Studio 2026 we introduced Copilot Profiler Agent, a new AI-powered assistant that helps
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/delegate-the-analysis-not-the-performance 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI agents shouldn’t be hard. According to theCUBE Research, Docker makes it easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For most developers, getting started with AI is still too complicated. Different models, tools, and platforms don’t always play nicely together. But with Docker, that’s changing fast. Docker is emerging as essential infrastructure for standardized, portable, and scalable AI environments. By bringing composability, simplicity, and GPU accessibility to the agentic era, Docker is helping developers...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-ai-agents-shouldnt-be-hard-according-to-thecube-research-docker-makes-it-easy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: Big rocks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recall that Microspeak is not merely for jargon exclusive to Microsoft, but it&#39;s jargon that you need to know to survive at Microsoft. The term big rocks was introduced by Stephen Covey in the book The Seven Habits of Highly Effective People, which I suspect is very popular among senior executives, because senior execu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251202-00/?p=111830 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip 2025.3: Migration From Consoles to Query Files, Connection to Cloud Providers, Introspection Levels for Amazon Redshift, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2025.3, the final major update of the year, is here! Let’s take a look at what it has to offer. Download DataGrip 2025.3 Migration from query consoles to query files Previously, when referring to the SQL files that are attached to a data source by default, we used the term query console, and their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/02/datagrip-2025-3-migration-from-consoles-to-query-files-connection-to-cloud-providers-introspection-levels-for-amazon-redshift-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? Calling GC.Collect() explicitly forces the garbage collector to run and reclaim memory from unreachable objects. However, it’s generally discouraged to use this method in most applications because the garbage collector is highly optimized to run automatically. Forcing it can lead to performance issues by interrupting the normal optimization process. Welcome to dotInsights […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/02/dotinsights-december-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a custom MSBuild SDK to reduce boilerplate in .NET projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is part of The C# Advent Calendar 2025, a series of 50 posts about C#. Be sure to check out the rest of the blog posts in the calendar! Over the years, I&#39;ve relied on Meziantou.DotNet.CodingStandard, a NuGet package, to establish a consistent baseline across all my .NET projects. This approach includes style enforcement, essential analyzers, sensible build defaults, and additional tooling.…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/creating-a-custom-msbuild-sdk-to-reduce-boilerplate-in-dotnet-projects.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Achieve Significant Build Performance Gains With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is brought to you by Mdu Sibisi, draft.dev. Long build times interfere with developer momentum, disrupt flow states, and negatively impact productivity. While seemingly minor gaps in work rate may appear negligible in the moment, they quickly accumulate into significant increases in release cycle times and infrastructure costs. (There’s a reason high-performance development […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/build-performance-gains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent updates to NetEscapades.EnumGenerators: [EnumMember] support, analyzers, and bug fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe some recent changes to the NetEscapades.EnumGenerators source generator, including support for [EnumMember] and new analyzers
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/recent-updates-to-netescapaades-enumgenerators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering owned entities in EF Core: Cleaner complex types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:12:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not all data in your application should live as a standalone table with its own ID and lifecycle. Sometimes you need a tightly coupled dependent object that exists alongside its parent, like a movie&#39;s budget, a survey&#39;s questions, or a customer&#39;s address. If you
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/mastering-owned-entities-in-ef-core-cleaner-complex-types/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AppendSelected parameter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Background The Property parameter introd
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/entrapowershell/appendselected-parameter 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claude Code &#43; Microsoft Foundry: Enterprise AI Coding Agent Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 01:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide covers setting up Claude Code CLI and VS Code extension with Microsoft Foundry, configuring CLAUDE.md for project context, integrating Spec Kit for structured development, and running Claude Code in GitHub Actions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/claude-code-microsoft-foundry-enterprise-ai-coding-agent-setup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain-Driven Design Misconceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Domain-Driven Design misconceptions often come from treating DDD like a checklist of patterns. Have you ever looked into Domain-Driven Design and thought, “Wow, this is totally overkill”? Well, you’re not alone. And I kind of agree, but not for the reasons you might think. I say you’re not alone because of this meme I did… Read More »Domain-Driven Design Misconceptions The post Domain-Driven Design Misconceptions appeared first on CodeOpinion.
Link to article: https://codeopinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data API builder’s &#34;request-body-strict&#34; Simplifies Client Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data API builder (DAB) provides REST and GraphQL endpoints over SQL Server, Azure Cosmos DB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and SQL Data Warehouse.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/data-api-builder-request-body-strict 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Platform Age Verification in .NET MAUI Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you&#39;re building apps that need to comply with upcoming age verification requirements in Texas (January 1, 2026), Utah (May 7, 2026), or Louisiana (July 1, 2026), you might be wondering how to handle age verification across Android, iOS, and Windows. The good news? Each platform provides its own age verification APIs, and we&#39;ve put togeth
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/cross-platform-age-verification-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the OSS AI Summit: Building with LangChain Event</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            December 10, 2025 8 am - 10 am Pacific Registration: https://aka.ms/OSSAISummitRegistration
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/join-the-oss-ai-summit-building-with-langchain-event 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#34;Golden Triangle&#34; of Agentic Development with Microsoft Agent Framework: AG-UI, DevUI &amp; OpenTelemetry Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the explosive era of Agentic AI, we&#39;re not just seeking more powerful models—we&#39;re searching for a development experience that lets developers actually get some sleep. When building Agents locally, we&#39;ve traditionally faced three major challenges:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/the-golden-triangle-of-agentic-development-with-microsoft-agent-framework-ag-ui-devui-opentelemetry-deep-dive 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade MSVC, improve C&#43;&#43; build performance, and refactor C&#43;&#43; code with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2026 introduces new GitHub Copilot capabilities to support C++ developers in three development tasks:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/upgrade-msvc-improve-c-build-performance-and-refactor-c-code-with-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I get my edit control text to be autoselected when I choose it to be the default focus in my dialog?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer had a Win32 dialog with a bunch of edit controls inside. In their WM_INIT­DIALOG message handler, they filled those edit controls with information and then decided which one should get initial focus when the dialog is shown to the user. To set the focus, they did SetFocus(GetDlgItem(hDlg, initialCon
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251201-00/?p=111825 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcoming Babu Annamalai to JasperFx Software</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting today, Babu Annamalai is taking a larger role at JasperFx Software (LLC) to help expand our support coverage to just about every time zone on the planet. Babu is a long time member of the Marten and now Critter Stack core team. In addition to some large contributions like the Partial API in Marten … Continue reading Welcoming Babu Annamalai to JasperFx Software →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/12/01/welcoming-babu-annamalai-to-jasperfx-software/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Engineers Talk About Spring Boot 4, Life, and Other Stuff</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us as we welcome the Spring team and Evgeny Borisov for a new IntelliJ IDEA livestream, where we’ll discuss what’s new in Spring Boot 4 and how all the new updates work in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: December 11, 2025 Time: 4:00–5:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this livestream, we’ll explore […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/new-livestream-engineers-talk-about-spring-boot-4-life-and-other-stuff/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Through the Noise: Smarter Context Management for LLM-Powered Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you’re working on a project and jotting down every single idea, experiment, and failure. After a while, your notes pile up so high that finding what’s useful takes more time and energy than the work itself. A similar problem faces users of software engineering (SE) agents: the agents “take notes” on every generated output, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/12/efficient-context-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Embedding Models and Unlock Semantic Search with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Embeddings have become the backbone of many modern AI applications. From semantic search to retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) and intelligent recommendation systems, embedding models enable systems to understand the meaning behind text, code, or documents, not just the literal words. But generating embeddings comes with trade-offs. Using a hosted API for embedding generation often results in...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-embedding-models-for-semantic-search/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating AI Development with GitHub Copilot: Real-World Use-Cases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Written by Destiny Hillis (Software Engineer II), Rachel Johnson (Software Engineer II), Tempest van Schaik (Principal Data Scientist), and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/accelerating-ai-development-with-github-copilot-real-world-use-cases 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and NORAD team up to bring new magic to “NORAD Tracks Santa”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and NORAD are bringing new magic to “NORAD Tracks Santa” with three ChatGPT holiday tools that let families create festive elves, toy coloring pages, and custom Christmas stories.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/norad-holiday-collaboration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accenture and OpenAI accelerate enterprise AI success</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Accenture and OpenAI are collaborating to help enterprises bring agentic AI capabilities into the core of their business and unlock new levels of growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/accenture-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI takes an ownership stake in Thrive Holdings to accelerate enterprise AI adoption</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI takes an ownership stake in Thrive Holdings to accelerate enterprise AI adoption, embedding frontier research and engineering directly into accounting and IT services to boost speed, accuracy, and efficiency while creating a scalable model for industry-wide transformation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/thrive-holdings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
