<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Gävle Goat (Gävleboken) succumbs in 2025 to a new menace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Regular readers of this blog may remember the giant traditional Swedish Yule Goat erected annually in the Swedish town of Gävle. The Gävle Goat (
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251229-01/?p=111929 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect that the system is running low on memory? Or that my job is running low on memory?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to write a process that could detect that it is nearing its job memory limit. Now, if you were asking about system memory limits rather than job memory limits, you would use the Create­Memory­Resource­Notification to create a &amp;quot;low memory&amp;quot; notification. As noted in the documentation, this notificatio
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251229-00/?p=111927 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce GitHub Actions runner CPU usage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you&#39;re using self-hosted GitHub Actions runners, you might have noticed they can be surprisingly CPU-intensive, even when idle. A closer look reveals that a single runner can peg a CPU core at 100% utilization. This isn&#39;t a bug in your workflow; it&#39;s a deliberate design choice in the runner&#39;s sleep mechanism. The problem: Busy-waiting Instead of using standard, efficient sleep functions provided by the…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/reduce-github-actions-runner-cpu-usage.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging Application Performance with Intelligent Client-Side Caching</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_12_2025/28_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_12_2025/28_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This excerpt discusses enhancing Microsoft .NET application performance by minimizing network calls. The author emphasizes client-side caching with Spargine’s InMemoryCache, which drastically improves responsiveness and scalability for costly operations like reflection. While significant speed gains are noted, developers are advised to benchmark changes, as caching may not always be beneficial.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/12/28/supercharging-application-performance-with-intelligent-client-side-caching/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a High-Performance Cache Without External Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_12_2025/27_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_12_2025/27_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to build a high-performance cache from scratch in .NET, moving from a simple ConcurrentDictionary to an optimized keyed-locking system. This deep dive explores how to master concurrency patterns like double-checked locking to protect your APIs and improve application scalability.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/how-to-build-a-high-performance-cache-without-external-libraries 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Is Now Part of TeamCity Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2025/26_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2025/26_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We introduced TeamCity Pipelines in March 2024 to make CI/CD setup simpler and more intuitive, without limiting what teams can build and automate. Pipelines brought a new workflow focused on a more guided configuration experience, including a visual editor with drag-and-drop dependencies, YAML for defining building routines from scratch, and a set of practical configuration […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/pipelines-sunset/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are we worried about memory access semantics? Full barriers should be enough for anybody</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2025/26_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2025/26_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Commenter Shawn wondered why we are so worried about memory access semantics. Back in my day, we just used full barriers everywhere, and I didn&#39;t hear nobody complainin&#39;.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251226-00/?p=111919 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Azure Naming Conventions at Scale with Terraform and Build5Nines/naming/azure (AzureRM &#43; Region Pairs)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2025/26_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 05:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2025/26_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Azure resource naming conventions are one of those “small” DevOps and cloud infrastructure management disciplines that quietly determine whether your cloud estate stays governable at 50 resources—or collapses into entropy at 5,000 resources. In this article, you’ll build a repeatable, region-aware naming strategy using HashiCorp Terraform and the Build5Nines/naming/azure module (which wraps Microsoft’s Azure/naming/azurerm module) to generate compliant […] The article Implementing Azure Naming Conventions at Scale with Terraform and Build5Nines/naming/azure (AzureRM + Region Pairs) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading the fine print, episode 4: Holiday promotions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2025/25_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2025/25_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I ran across a promotion from a hotel. Join us for the holidays with this promotion code. But if you read down to the fine print, it also says Limited number of rooms available for each date. May not be valid during holiday
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251225-01/?p=111916 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is the last letter of my string not making it to the clipboard?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2025/25_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2025/25_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just to see what happens, a customer called Set­ClipboardData(CF_TEXT) and passed a memory block that was intentionally not null-terminated. They found that when they subsequently pasted the string (say, into Notepad), the last character didn&#39;t get pasted. As a second experiment, they over-allocated the buffer b
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251225-00/?p=111914 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Turns 30: A Celebration of Code, Community, and Creativity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2025/25_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 09:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2025/25_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Created by Yukihiro “Matz” Matsumoto and first released in 1995, Ruby arrived with a purpose that was simple but profound: to make coding more human, more intuitive, and more enjoyable. Its object-oriented model, dynamic typing, and elegant syntax offered a fresh alternative to the heavier and more complex languages of that era. As Ruby marks […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/12/ruby-turns-30-a-celebration-of-code-community-and-creativity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmatically creating an IDP solution with Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to programmatically create an IDP solution that uses Strands SDK, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Base, and Bedrock Data Automation (BDA). This solution is provided through a Jupyter notebook that enables users to upload multi-modal business documents and extract insights using BDA as a parser to retrieve relevant chunks and augment a prompt to a foundational model (FM).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/programmatically-creating-an-idp-solution-with-amazon-bedrock-data-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI agent-driven browser automation for enterprise workflow management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enterprise organizations increasingly rely on web-based applications for critical business processes, yet many workflows remain manually intensive, creating operational inefficiencies and compliance risks. Despite significant technology investments, knowledge workers routinely navigate between eight to twelve different web applications during standard workflows, constantly switching contexts and manually transferring information between systems. Data entry and validation tasks […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-agent-driven-browser-automation-for-enterprise-workflow-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic QA automation using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser and Amazon Nova Act</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how agentic QA automation addresses these challenges and walk through a practical example using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser and Amazon Nova Act to automate testing for a sample retail application.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/agentic-qa-automation-using-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-browser-and-amazon-nova-act/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing LLM inference on Amazon SageMaker AI with BentoML’s LLM- Optimizer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to optimize large language model (LLM) inference on Amazon SageMaker AI using BentoML&#39;s LLM-Optimizer to systematically identify the best serving configurations for your workload.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-llm-inference-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-with-bentomls-llm-optimizer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Complete FIRE Calculator App with GitHub Copilot in One Chat Session</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 30 minutes with GitHub Copilot, VS Code, and Claude Opus 4.5 I built my ultimate FIRE calcultor app that is private, secure, and free!
Link to article: https://montemagno.com/building-a-complete-fire-calculator-app-with-github-copilot-in-one-chat-session/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does my &lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt;&#43;&lt;kbd&gt;M&lt;/kbd&gt; accelerator key activate when I press the &lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt; key?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer didn&#39;t understand why their Win32 accelerator key for Ctrl+M was triggering spuriously. Specifically, it was triggering when the user hit the Enter key, which is nothing like the Ctrl+M two-key combination. They defined their accelerator table like this: IDA
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251224-00/?p=111908 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the zero operator access design of Mantle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 22:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Mantle, Amazon&#39;s next-generation inference engine for Amazon Bedrock, implements a zero operator access (ZOA) design that eliminates any technical means for AWS operators to access customer data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/exploring-the-zero-operator-access-design-of-mantle/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Wanted to Ask About Rust – Answered by Herbert Wolverson</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disclaimer: This article was created using AI-based writing and communication companions. With its help, the core topics of this rich and nuanced livestream were conveniently distilled into a compact blog post format. In our recent JetBrains livestream, Vitaly Bragilevsky sat down with Rust expert and educator Herbert Wolverson (Ardan Labs) to talk about everything Rust […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/12/23/everything-you-wanted-to-ask-about-rust-answered-by-herbert-wolverson/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS AI League: Model customization and agentic showdown</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the new AWS AI League challenges and how they are transforming how organizations approach AI development. The grand finale at AWS re:Invent 2025 was an exciting showcase of their ingenuity and skills.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-ai-league-model-customization-and-agentic-showdown/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Enterprise AI Development using Weights &amp; Biases and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Foundation Models (FMs) from Amazon Bedrock and the newly launched Amazon Bedrock AgentCore alongside W&amp;amp;B Weave to help build, evaluate, and monitor enterprise AI solutions. We cover the complete development lifecycle from tracking individual FM calls to monitoring complex agent workflows in production.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-enterprise-ai-development-using-weights-biases-weave-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How dLocal automated compliance reviews using Amazon Quick Automate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how dLocal worked closely with the AWS team to help shape the product roadmap, reinforce its role as an industry innovator, and set new benchmarks for operational excellence in the global fintech landscape.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-dlocal-automated-compliance-reviews-using-amazon-quick-automate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing ADHD diagnosis: How Qbtech built a mobile AI assessment Model Using Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Qbtech streamlined their machine learning (ML) workflow using Amazon SageMaker AI, a fully managed service to build, train and deploy ML models, and AWS Glue, a serverless service that makes data integration simpler, faster, and more cost effective. This new solution reduced their feature engineering time from weeks to hours, while maintaining the high clinical standards required by healthcare providers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advancing-adhd-diagnosis-how-qbtech-built-a-mobile-ai-assessment-model-using-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating your marketing ideation with generative AI – Part 1: From idea to generation with the Amazon Nova foundation models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, the first of a series of three, we focus on how you can use Amazon Nova to streamline, simplify, and accelerate marketing campaign creation through generative AI. We show how Bancolombia, one of Colombia’s largest banks, is experimenting with the Amazon Nova models to generate visuals for their marketing campaigns.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-your-marketing-ideation-with-generative-ai-part-1-from-idea-to-generation-with-the-amazon-nova-foundation-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Visa Intelligent Commerce on AWS: Enabling agentic commerce with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how AWS and Visa are partnering to enable agentic commerce through Visa Intelligent Commerce using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore. We demonstrate how autonomous AI agents can transform fragmented shopping and travel experiences into seamless, end-to-end workflows—from discovery and comparison to secure payment authorization—all driven by natural language.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-visa-intelligent-commerce-on-aws-enabling-agentic-commerce-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When irate product support customers demand to speak to Bill Gates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A colleague of mine who used to work in product support told me that they had a procedure if a customer became irate and demanded to speak with Bill Gates. (This was, of course, back in the days when Bill Gates still ran the company.) The product support technician would apologize for not resolving the problem to the customer&#39;s sati
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251223-00/?p=111896 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Framework (SPFx) roadmap update – December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we close out 2025, we want to pause and reflect on what has been an extraordinary year for the SharePoint Framework (SPFx). We continue to be humbled by the momentum of the platform and the scale of impact it enables across Microsoft 365. Tens of millions of users
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/sharepoint-framework-spfx-roadmap-update-december-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thread Dumps and Project Loom (Virtual Threads)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:14:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve been keeping up with Java virtual threads, you already know that this hot new feature significantly improves hardware utilization for parallel I/O-bound operations. Virtual threads map multiple concurrent I/O operations to a single OS thread without blocking. The novel aspect of this approach is that it requires minimal changes to the codebase, as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/thread-dumps-and-project-loom-virtual-threads/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code in Rust: Winners and Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you to everyone who joined Advent of Code 2025 in Rust! It was inspiring to see many Rustaceans solving algorithmic puzzles, and celebrating the holiday coding season with the community. Before the Advent began, Vitaly Bragilevsky published a blog post on how to use AI in Advent of Code challenge responsibly and effectively. This […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/12/22/advent-of-code-in-rust-winners-and-highlights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Beyond Chain-of-Thought with Chain-of-Draft on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores Chain-of-Draft (CoD), an innovative prompting technique introduced in a Zoom AI Research paper Chain of Draft: Thinking Faster by Writing Less, that revolutionizes how models approach reasoning tasks. While Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has been the go-to method for enhancing model reasoning, CoD offers a more efficient alternative that mirrors human problem-solving patterns—using concise, high-signal thinking steps rather than verbose explanations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/move-beyond-chain-of-thought-with-chain-of-draft-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Mistral AI’s Voxtral on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate hosting Voxtral models on Amazon SageMaker AI endpoints using vLLM and the Bring Your Own Container (BYOC) approach. vLLM is a high-performance library for serving large language models (LLMs) that features paged attention for improved memory management and tensor parallelism for distributing models across multiple GPUs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-mistral-ais-voxtral-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance document analytics with Strands AI Agents for the GenAI IDP Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To address the need for businesses to quickly analyze information and unlock actionable insights, we are announcing Analytics Agent, a new feature that is seamlessly integrated into the GenAI IDP Accelerator. With this feature, users can perform advanced searches and complex analyses using natural language queries without SQL or data analysis expertise. In this post, we discuss how non-technical users can use this tool to analyze and understand the documents they have processed at scale with natural language.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a multimodal generative AI assistant for root cause diagnosis in predictive maintenance using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to implement a predictive maintenance solution using Foundation Models (FMs) on Amazon Bedrock, with a case study of Amazon&#39;s manufacturing equipment within their fulfillment centers. The solution is highly adaptable and can be customized for other industries, including oil and gas, logistics, manufacturing, and healthcare.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-multimodal-generative-ai-assistant-for-root-cause-diagnosis-in-predictive-maintenance-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AI fixed my procrastination</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I struggled to get started. For ages, I kept putting off building this website, creating a new programming language for Visual Studio, and coming up with fresh color themes. Each project looked overwhelming, and I couldn’t find the time or motivation to jump in. It all just felt like too much at once. But when a national holiday gave me a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-ai-fixed-my-procrastination 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the other cool languages have &lt;code&gt;try&lt;/code&gt;...&lt;code&gt;finally&lt;/code&gt;. C&#43;&#43; says &#34;We have &lt;code&gt;try&lt;/code&gt;...&lt;code&gt;finally&lt;/code&gt; at home.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many languages¹ that have exceptions also have a finally clause, so you can write try { ⟦ stuff ⟧ } finally { always(); } A quick checks shows that this control structure exists in Java, C#, Python, JavaScript, but not C++. C++ says, &amp;quot;We have try...finally at home.&amp;quot;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251222-00/?p=111890 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Test Run Hub is Going Generally Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Delivering high-quality software requires clarity, speed, and collaboration. That’s why we introduced the New Test Run Hub in Azure Test Plans. A modern, streamlined experience designed to make test execution and analysis fast and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/the-new-test-run-hub-is-going-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Managing Mark of the Web in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is Mark of the Web? Mark of the Web (MOTW) is a Windows security feature that protects users from potentially unsafe files downloaded from the internet. When you download a file, Windows automatically adds a special metadata tag indicating the file originated from an untrusted source and may contain harmful content. Windows components such as Microsoft Edge and Windows Explorer use MOTW to determine…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/understanding-and-managing-mark-of-the-web-in-dotnet.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuously hardening ChatGPT Atlas against prompt injection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is strengthening ChatGPT Atlas against prompt injection attacks using automated red teaming trained with reinforcement learning. This proactive discover-and-patch loop helps identify novel exploits early and harden the browser agent’s defenses as AI becomes more agentic.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/hardening-atlas-against-prompt-injection 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One in a million: celebrating the customers shaping AI’s future</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            More than one million customers around the world now use OpenAI to empower their teams and unlock new opportunities. This post highlights how companies like PayPal, Virgin Atlantic, BBVA, Cisco, Moderna, and Canva are transforming the way work gets done with AI.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/one-in-a-million-customers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
