<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 06:12:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scale Your Services With Service-Oriented Architecture in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 06:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss the Service-Oriented Architecture in .NET. We will cover what it is, how to implement it, how it differs from Microservice Architecture, and how we can use cloud computing platforms as a jump pad to quickly stand up services and infrastructural features. Let’s begin! What Is Service-Oriented Architecture Service-Oriented Architecture […] The post Scale Your Services With Service-Oriented Architecture in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS and Mistral AI commit to democratizing generative AI with a strengthened collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 04:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, Mistral AI is bringing its latest and most capable model, Mistral Large, to Amazon Bedrock, and is committed to making future models accessible to AWS customers. Mistral AI will also use AWS AI-optimized AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia to build and deploy its future foundation models on Amazon Bedrock, benefitting from the price, performance, scale, and security of AWS. Along with this announcement, starting today, customers can use Amazon Bedrock in the AWS Europe (Paris) Region.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 智能组件简介 – AI 驱动的 UI 控件</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 02:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Daniel Roth的Introducing .NET Smart Components – AI-powered UI controls AI的最新进展有望彻底改变我们与软件交互和使用软件的方式。然而，将AI功能集成到现有软件中可能面临一些挑战。 因此，我们开发了新的 .NET 智能组件，这是一组真正有用的AI支持的 UI 组件，您可以快速轻松地将其添加到 .NET 应用程序中。 您不必花费数周的开发时间来重新设计用户体验或研究机器学习和提示工程。 .NET 智能组件提供了预构建的端到端 AI 功能，您可以将其放入现有的应用程序 UI 中，以提高用户的工作效率。 目前，.NET智能组件仍处于试验阶段，最初可用于 .NET 6 及更高版本的 Blazor、MVC 和 Razor 页面。 我们计划为其他 .NET UI 框架（例如 .NET MAUI、WPF 和 Windows Forms）提供组件，但首先我们很想知道您对这些组件可用性的反馈，以及您希望增加哪些额外的功能。 观看 Steve Sanderson 演示 .NET 智能组件的功能： 它包含什么 .NET智能组件目前包括以下智能功能： 智能粘贴 只需单击按钮，智能粘贴就会自动使用用户剪贴板中的数据填充表单。 您可以将其与Web应用程序中的任何现有表单一起使用。 这有助于用户从外部源添加数据而无需重新输入。 了解更多：智能粘贴文档 智能文本区域 对于传统文本区域的智能升级。您可以配置它如何使用您自己喜欢的语气、策略、URL 等自动完成整个句子。这有助于用户更快地输入，而不必记住 URL 等。 了解更多：智能文本区域文档 智能组合框 通过基于语义匹配的建议来升级传统的组合框。这可以帮助用户找到他们想要的东西。 了解更多：智能组合框文档 运行示例 您可以使用 GitHub 上的 .NET 智能组件示例程序来尝试使用 Blazor 或 MVC/RazorPages 的 .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and deploying a .NET 8 App on an ARM64 processor using Azure Pipelines and AWS ECS Fargate. Part 2: Demo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 22:19:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this two-part series, I’m going to show you how to build and deploy a .NET 8 app container image that targets an ARM64 processor. In part 2, we will attempt to perform an end-to-end process. This will involve building a .NET 8 API, containerizing the app targeting an ARM64 processor using Azure Pipelines, and deploying it on AWS ECS Fargate. Furthermore, a benchmark will also be conducted to compare the performance of the application running on an ARM64 Fargate container versus an AMD64 Fargate container.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should .terraform.lock.hcl file be added to .gitignore or committed to Git repo?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with Terraform, one common question that arises is whether to include the .terraform.lock.hcl file in the Git repository or leave it out by adding it to .gitignore. This decision impacts the version control practices and reproducibility of your infrastructure deployments. In this article, we’ll explore the contents of the .terraform.lock.hcl file, discuss why […] The article Should .terraform.lock.hcl file be added to .gitignore or committed to Git repo? appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making AI powered .NET apps more consistent and intelligent with Redis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Redis makes intelligent apps smarter and consistent by serving as additional knowledge store, caching chat history, and semantically cache request and responses for an API. Combined with traditional caching scenarios, Redis is the multi-purpose data store for your intelligent apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/redis-makes-intelligent-apps-smarter-and-consistent 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient makes LLM benchmarking cost-effective and effortless with AWS Inferentia</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 16:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with Michael Feil at Gradient. Evaluating the performance of large language models (LLMs) is an important step of the pre-training and fine-tuning process before deployment. The faster and more frequent you’re able to validate performance, the higher the chances you’ll be able to improve the performance of the model. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/gradient-makes-llm-benchmarking-cost-effective-and-effortless-with-aws-inferentia/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable single sign-on access of Amazon SageMaker Canvas using AWS IAM Identity Center: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 16:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Canvas allows you to use machine learning (ML) to generate predictions without having to write any code. It does so by covering the end-to-end ML workflow: whether you’re looking for powerful data preparation and AutoML, managed endpoint deployment, simplified MLOps capabilities, or the ability to configure foundation models for generative AI, SageMaker Canvas […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enable-single-sign-on-access-of-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-using-aws-iam-identity-center-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar models from Upstage are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 15:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is co-written with Hwalsuk Lee at Upstage. Today, we’re excited to announce that the Solar foundation model developed by Upstage is now available for customers using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. Solar is a large language model (LLM) 100% pre-trained with Amazon SageMaker that outperforms and uses its compact size and powerful track records […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/solar-models-from-upstage-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The history of computing, as told by the hallways of Microsoft Building 41</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A walk through history, in the form of wall textures.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240402-00/?p=109604 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empower Your Development: Dive into Docker’s Comprehensive Learning Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 13:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out about Docker&#39;s multifaceted approach to developer education, including partnerships with platforms like Udemy and LinkedIn Learning, official docs and use-cases, and content created by Docker Captains and the developer community.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-learning-ecosystem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 10:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A step-by-step guide to enable the AI-powered coding assistant within Visual Studio Introduction to GitHub Copilot GitHub Copilot is a new tool that helps you write code faster and smarter with the help of artificial intelligence. It can suggest code completions, generate code snippets, and even write entire functions for you. ...
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-to-install-github-copilot-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syncing a git branch between Windows and WSL filesystems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how you can work on a git branch with a repository checked out in Windows, and then sync that to another git folder in WSL
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/working-on-a-git-branch-in-two-different-folders-concurrently/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create conditional access base policies for a Microsoft Entra ID tenant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 06:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article shows some of the base conditional access policies which can be implemented for all Microsoft Entra ID tenants. Phishing resistant authentication should be required for all administration flows and some other user policies like sign-in risk MFA or terms of conditions. I recommend these base policies when implementing an Microsoft Entra ID tenant […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/04/02/create-conditional-access-base-policies-for-a-microsoft-entra-id-tenant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Validate a GUID in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore several approaches to validate a string representation of a GUID in C#. So let’s dive in. What Does a GUID Look Like? The term “GUID” was first introduced by Microsoft as a specific version of the broader term “Universally Unique Identifier” (UUID). As time passed, these terms have become […] The post How to Validate a GUID in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation of the Microsoft Graph meeting registration beta APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 19:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Graph meeting registration beta APIs that support the initial version are currently being deprecated and will stop returning data on September 30, 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-of-the-microsoft-graph-meeting-registration-beta-apis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSH and XZ/liblzma: A nation-state attack was thwarted, what did we learn?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 19:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker CTO Justin Cormack looks at what we can learn from malicious code in upstream tarballs of xz targeted at a subset of OpenSSH servers. &amp;quot;It is hard to overstate how lucky we were here, as there are no tools that will detect this vulnerability.&amp;quot;
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/openssh-and-xz-liblzma/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git: Merge Repositories with History</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 16:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Merging two Git repositories together in not a common task. In my own consulting work, this is a task that does come up every so often when the code I’m working on needs to be moved from an initial Git repository, whether it’s GitHub or Azure DevOps, to another Git repository that will be the […] The article Git: Merge Repositories with History appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced templating in Semantic Kernel for Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 15:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello to all Python enthusiasts working with Semantic Kernel! We are very happy to share some of the latest work we have been doing, namely we introduced not one but two new options for templates: Handlebars and Jinja2. And we also made some updates to the ‘semantic-kernel’
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/enhanced-templating-in-semantic-kernel-for-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ancient world before computers had stacks or heaps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A lot of computing got done even before we had stacks and heaps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240401-00/?p=109599 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Json schema validation in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is often useful to validate JSON documents against a JSON schema. For example, you may want to validate the JSON document that you receive from a REST API or a configuration file written by a user. In this post, I describe how to validate JSON data against a JSON schema in .NET. Using PowerShell, you can use the Test-Json cmdlet to validate JSON data against a JSON schema. .NET doesn&#39;t support JSON…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start using ChatGPT instantly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re making it easier for people to experience the benefits of AI without needing to sign-up
Link to article: https://openai.com/blog/start-using-chatgpt-instantly 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Sortable Unique IDs With the NewId Library in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 06:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore why we might need sortable unique IDs in .NET and how to create them with the NewId NuGet Package. Let’s dive in! Why Might We Need Sortable Unique IDs in .NET We all know there are two main approaches when it comes to generating IDs for entities in our projects: […] The post Generate Sortable Unique IDs With the NewId Library in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Ways to Create a Generic List of Anonymous Types in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2024/31_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 06:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2024/31_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Knowing how to manipulate complex datatypes such as Lists is crucial when storing and manipulating data in C#. Sometimes, we may want to incorporate versatility by not having to define explicit classes and create generic lists of anonymous types in C#. In this article, we are going to learn some of the different ways we […] The post Different Ways to Create a Generic List of Anonymous Types in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fastest Way to Remove the Last Character of a String</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_03_2024/30_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 08:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_03_2024/30_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Creating and manipulating string objects can be useful when building applications. In the C# programming language, string objects contain text values stored as a sequential read-only collection of character objects. This means string objects are immutable and thus can’t be changed once created. Despite this, we often find ourselves needing to manipulate them. In this […] The post The Fastest Way to Remove the Last Character of a String appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Install Latest Version on macOS and Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 18:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Terraform from HashiCorp is provided as a command-line tool that must first be installed locally before excution. It’s easy to install, as the full tool is contained within a single executable. This makes it easy to put terraform in any folder on your machine for use. Although, to make it executable from anywhere on your […] The article Terraform: Install Latest Version on macOS and Linux appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (March 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 17:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.03.19 and 2024.03.25 releases as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout March. This month’s vcpkg release includes an arm64ec platform expression, more flexibility when mixing static and dynamic libraries,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-march-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bing on .NET 8: The Impact of Dynamic PGO</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bing Extensible Application Platform&#39;s upgrade to .NET 8 and how dynamic profile guided optimization continues to deliver performance gains
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/bing-on-dotnet-8-the-impact-of-dynamic-pgo 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide live agent assistance for your chatbot users with Amazon Lex and Talkdesk cloud contact center</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 14:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Lex provides advanced conversational artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities to enable self-service support for your organization’s contact center. With Amazon Lex, you can implement an omnichannel strategy where customers engage via phone, websites, and messaging platforms. The bots can answer FAQs, provide self-service experiences, or triage customer requests before transferring to a human agent. Amazon Lex integrates […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/provide-live-agent-assistance-for-your-chatbot-users-with-amazon-lex-and-talkdesk-cloud-contact-center/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I tell C&#43;&#43; that I want to discard a nodiscard value?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A variety of tricks, with different degrees of readability and legality.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240329-00/?p=109592 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #207</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 09:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #207 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks C# 12: Alias Any Type [www.thomasclaudiushuber.com] Aliasing types and namespaces has been around for the longest time. With C# that feature has been extended and now we can alias almost any type out […] The post Code Maze Weekly #207 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fastest Way to Check if a List is in Order in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 07:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll examine different techniques to check whether or not a list is in order in C#. We’ll begin by examining several techniques, including parallel processing. Finally, we’ll run a series of benchmarks to help us choose which option fits best in our use case. So, let’s begin! Initial Setup Before we start […] The post Fastest Way to Check if a List is in Order in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image manipulation experiments for Mobile Read Hero Images(MRHI) compatibility</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Consumer-packaged goods industry relies on multiple channels for selling the products and aims to provide a seamless buying experience for the consumer. With the advent of omni-channel retailing, CPGs (Consumer packaged goods) and retailers are striving towards providing the best possible experience to the customer alongside working on providing the most available information on the product they are selling on these touch points. On an e-commerce Channel which sells multiple products, the need for a compliant SKU image is key.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Challenges and Opportunities of Synthetic Voices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re sharing lessons from a small scale preview of Voice Engine, a model for creating custom voices.
Link to article: https://openai.com/blog/navigating-the-challenges-and-opportunities-of-synthetic-voices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Paths for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 20:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to highlight new learning content released focused on Semantic Kernel. APL-2005 Develop AI agents using Azure OpenAI and the Semantic Kernel SDK – Training | Microsoft Learn Student Hub Overview – Microsoft Learn Student Hub | Microsoft Learn .NET Conf Student Zone –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/learning-paths-for-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced RAG patterns on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 16:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, customers of all industries—whether it’s financial services, healthcare and life sciences, travel and hospitality, media and entertainment, telecommunications, software as a service (SaaS), and even proprietary model providers—are using large language models (LLMs) to build applications like question and answering (QnA) chatbots, search engines, and knowledge bases. These generative AI applications are not only […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advanced-rag-patterns-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient continual pre-training LLMs for financial domains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 16:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) are generally trained on large publicly available datasets that are domain agnostic. For example, Meta’s Llama models are trained on datasets such as CommonCrawl, C4, Wikipedia, and ArXiv. These datasets encompass a broad range of topics and domains. Although the resulting models yield amazingly good results for general tasks, such as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/efficient-continual-pre-training-llms-for-financial-domains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Video Analysis and Transcription Chatbot with the GenAI Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 14:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dive into a video transcription and chat project that leverages the GenAI Stack, along with seamless integration provided by Docker, to streamline video content processing and understanding.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-a-video-analysis-and-transcription-chatbot-with-the-genai-stack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I called Create­Environment­Block with a process’s token, but I didn’t get that process’s environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That&#39;s not what the Create­Environment­Block function does.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240328-00/?p=109590 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Native Authentication for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 12:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the public preview of Native Authentication for Microsoft Entra External ID, a feature that allows you to design and control the sign-in experience within your mobile apps. We compare browser-delegated authentication to native authentication which enables you to create customized, visually cohesive login screens that enhance user experience and maintain brand consistency.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/native-auth-for-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bot Powered Viva Connections extensibility supported for Teams Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 11:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bot powered Viva Connections extensibility is now supported in Microsoft Teams solutions. Market place support is coming within April 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/bot-powered-viva-connections-extensibility-supported-for-teams-solutions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 4 Weeks: Visual Studio LIVE! Chicago 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio LIVE! Chicago 2024 April 29 – May 3 | Swissôtel, Chicago Join us for Visual Studio LIVE! Chicago for a focused, deep dive into the latest .NET Microsoft Platform developments. You pick the package you want, 3, 4 or all 5 days!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-live-2024-chicago 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get the HTML Content of a Web Page as a String in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 07:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will look into a comprehensive guide on how to get the HTML content of a web page as a string and how to parse the content retrieved. First things first, we’ll learn how to retrieve HTML content as a string from the web using tools like HttpClient, HtmlAgilityPack, and AngleSharp. Then, […] The post How to Get the HTML Content of a Web Page as a String in .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.16 with simulated handling Teams Admin Center notifications for Microsoft Graph connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 07:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to share the launch of Dev Proxy v0.16, with new features for Microsoft Graph connectors and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-16-with-simulated-handling-teams-admin-center-notifications-for-microsoft-graph-connectors 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve DevOps maturity with BMC AMI zAdviser Enterprise and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post discusses how BMC Software added AWS Generative AI capabilities to its product BMC AMI zAdviser Enterprise. The zAdviser uses Amazon Bedrock to provide summarization, analysis, and recommendations for improvement based on the DORA metrics data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-devops-maturity-with-bmc-ami-zadviser-enterprise-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune your Amazon Titan Image Generator G1 model using Amazon Bedrock model customization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Titan lmage Generator G1 is a cutting-edge text-to-image model, available via Amazon Bedrock, that is able to understand prompts describing multiple objects in various contexts and captures these relevant details in the images it generates. It is available in US East (N. Virginia) and US West (Oregon) AWS Regions and can perform advanced image […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-your-amazon-titan-image-generator-g1-model-using-amazon-bedrock-model-customization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>containerd vs. Docker: Understanding Their Relationship and How They Work Together</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 13:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what containerd is, how Docker and containerd work together, and how their combined strengths can improve developer experience.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/containerd-vs-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Your Container Image Really Distroless?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 13:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out what makes an image distroless, tools that make the creation of distroless images practical, and security benefits of this approach.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/is-your-container-image-really-distroless/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Entity Framework Core Migrations in Production</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss the different approaches to migrating a production database when using Entity Framework (EF) Core code-first migrations. Let’s start. Entity Framework Core Project Setup Let’s start by creating a template Web API project and installing the necessary Entity Framework Core NuGet packages: Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore.SqlServer Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore.Design In this article, we use […] The post How to Use Entity Framework Core Migrations in Production appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Reverse a Number as an Integer and Not as a String in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will dive into various ways to reverse a number using integer reversal. We will begin by exploring the iterative approach, which breaks down numbers into individual digits and rebuilds them in reverse order. Next, we will discuss recursion as an alternative solution. We will also use a built-in function Math.Pow() for […] The post How to Reverse a Number as an Integer and Not as a String in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
