<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 19:45:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modernize ASP.NET Web Forms UI to Blazor with AWS Transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 19:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Transform is an agentic service that accelerates modernization, including .NET applications. With it, you can transform .NET Framework Windows applications to cross-platform .NET and reduce operating costs up to 40% by running on Linux. For ASP.NET web applications, AWS Transform can port the UI layer to ASP.NET Core. In this post, I’ll explain how […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-asp-net-web-forms-ui-to-blazor-with-aws-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Coding Agents and Domain-Specific Languages: Challenges and Practical Mitigation Strategies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Introduction AI coding agents/assistants such as GitHub Copilot have become common in modern software engineering workflows. Their strengths—rapid pattern completion, context-aware suggestions, and the ability to learn style from local code—stem from broad training on large corpora of public, general-purpose code. They perf Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/ai-coding-agents-domain-specific-languages 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.3.1 Released: Next Edit Suggestions and Other Important Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since the 2025.3 release, we’ve published several rapid-response updates (2025.3.0.1–2025.3.0.4) for ReSharper and Rider to address the most urgent issues as quickly as possible. The 2025.3.1 update brings all of those fixes together and includes additional improvements that required more time to implement. For Rider, it also delivers the data-sharing functionality we announced earlier this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/18/resharper-and-rider-2025-3-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and deploy scalable AI agents with NVIDIA NeMo, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use the powerful combination of Strands Agents, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and NVIDIA NeMo Agent Toolkit to build, evaluate, optimize, and deploy AI agents on Amazon Web Services (AWS) from initial development through production deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-and-deploy-scalable-ai-agents-with-nvidia-nemo-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-and-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bi-directional streaming for real-time agent interactions now available in Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn about bi-directional streaming on AgentCore Runtime and the prerequisites to create a WebSocket implementation. You will also learn how to use Strands Agents to implement a bi-directional streaming solution for voice agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bi-directional-streaming-for-real-time-agent-interactions-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Edit Suggestions: Now Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next edit suggestions feature is now enabled in all JetBrains IDEs for JetBrains AI Pro, AI Ultimate, and AI Enterprise subscribers. Yes, you read that right! JetBrains-native diff suggestions are available right in your editor. Global support for optimized latency. Out-of-the-box IDE actions for reliability. And the best part? It doesn’t consume your AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/next-edit-suggestions-now-generally-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring Your Own Key (BYOK) Is Now Live in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bring Your Own Key (BYOK) is now available in the AI chat inside JetBrains IDEs as well as for AI agents, including JetBrains’ Junie and Claude Agent. Whether you’re looking to use cutting-edge frontier models, cost-efficient small models, locally hosted private models, or experimental research previews, BYOK makes it easy to bring them all directly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/bring-your-own-key-byok-is-now-live-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3.1 is out with a number of useful fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. The latest update brings the following improvements: For a comprehensive overview of the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-2025-3-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Consoles Are Coming Back</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi DataGrip and Database Tools community, Shortly after the 2025.3 release, your feedback made it clear that the redesigned workflow for query files and query consoles introduced issues in several important scenarios, especially when working with global data sources. After reviewing the impact, we’ve decided that the best course of action is to revert this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/18/query-consoles-are-coming-back/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adopting Kotlin in a Java-centric company is not about flipping a switch or rewriting everything “the right way”. It’s about people, timing, risk, and trust. Over the last four weeks, we’ve published a series of blog posts by Urs Peter, covering all of these aspects of migrating to Kotlin. In this post, we’ll tie the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/the-ultimate-guide-to-successfully-adopting-kotlin-in-a-java-dominated-environment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concluding thoughts on our deep dive into Windows clipboard text conversion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the past few articles (starting with conversion between CF_OEM­TEXT and CF_TEXT), we&#39;ve been looking at how Windows performs text conversion
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251218-00/?p=111882 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating chain-of-thought monitorability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces a new framework and evaluation suite for chain-of-thought monitorability, covering 13 evaluations across 24 environments. Our findings show that monitoring a model’s internal reasoning is far more effective than monitoring outputs alone, offering a promising path toward scalable control as AI systems grow more capable.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/evaluating-chain-of-thought-monitorability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Programming Courses in 2025: New and Favorite Picks on JetBrains Academy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “It’s tiiiiiiiiiiiime!”, and not just for Mariah Carey on the playlist. Here’s our annual roundup of JetBrains Academy courses – the favorites you loved this year and the new courses launched in 2025. If you’re trying to figure out where to start, what to learn next, or how to invest in your future skills, this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/18/best-programming-courses-in-2025-new-and-favorite-picks-on-jetbrains-academy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI literacy resources for teens and parents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI shares new AI literacy resources to help teens and parents use ChatGPT thoughtfully, safely, and with confidence. The guides include expert-vetted tips for responsible use, critical thinking, healthy boundaries, and supporting teens through emotional or sensitive topics.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/ai-literacy-resources-for-teens-and-parents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deepening our collaboration with the U.S. Department of Energy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and the U.S. Department of Energy have signed a memorandum of understanding to deepen collaboration on AI and advanced computing in support of scientific discovery. The agreement builds on ongoing work with national laboratories and helps establish a framework for applying AI to high-impact research across the DOE ecosystem.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/us-department-of-energy-collaboration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating our Model Spec with teen protections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is updating its Model Spec with new Under-18 Principles that define how ChatGPT should support teens with safe, age-appropriate guidance grounded in developmental science. The update strengthens guardrails, clarifies expected model behavior in higher-risk situations, and builds on our broader work to improve teen safety across ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/updating-model-spec-with-teen-protections 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Copilot Studio &#43; Azure AI Search Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction: The Challenge In the early days of Microsoft Copilot Studio, our team noticed a recurring pattern. Across customer engagements, organizations were consistently struggling to integrate copilots with Azure AI Search. Organizations were consistently struggling to integrate copilot with Azure AI Search - not because either
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/mcs-azure-ai-search-intro 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addendum to GPT-5.2 System Card: GPT-5.2-Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This system card outlines the comprehensive safety measures implemented for GPT‑5.2-Codex. It details both model-level mitigations, such as specialized safety training for harmful tasks and prompt injections, and product-level mitigations like agent sandboxing and configurable network access.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-2-codex-system-card 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5.2-Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2-Codex is OpenAI’s most advanced coding model, offering long-horizon reasoning, large-scale code transformations, and enhanced cybersecurity capabilities.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-2-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the power of distributed graph databases with JanusGraph and Azure Apache Cassandra</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Connecting the Dots: How Graph Databases Drive Innova
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/janusgraph-azure-cassandra-graph-databases 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking and managing assets used in AI development with Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll explore the new capabilities and core concepts that help organizations track and manage models development and deployment lifecycles. We will show you how the features are configured to train models with automatic end-to-end lineage, from dataset upload and versioning to model fine-tuning, evaluation, and seamless endpoint deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/tracking-and-managing-assets-used-in-ai-development-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track machine learning experiments with MLflow on Amazon SageMaker using Snowflake integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to integrate Amazon SageMaker managed MLflow as a central repository to log these experiments and provide a unified system for monitoring their progress.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/track-machine-learning-experiments-with-mlflow-on-amazon-sagemaker-using-snowflake-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 10 Years of DirectX 12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DirectX12 shipped in 2015 with a simple goal: give developers more control so games run faster, look better, and scale across Windows PC and console. Over the last decade, DirectX 12 delivered on that promise. We added features and made it easier for developers to focus on gameplay &amp;amp; graphics by providing more flexibility and achievable pe
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/celebrating-10-years-of-directx-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire 13.1 - Our holiday gift to you</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aspire 13.1 - Our holiday gift to you 🎁 Before we head off for the holidays, we wanted to leave you with one more release. Aspire 13.1 is packed with improvements to make your AI coding assistants first-class citizens in your development workflow, along with CLI enhancements, dashboard refinements, and streamlined Azure deploym
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspire-13-1-holiday-gift 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deducing the consequences of Windows clipboard text formats on UTF-8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve been looking at how Windows performs automatic conversion between the three text formats CF_TEXT, CF_OEM­TEXT, and CF_UNICODE­TEXT. The use of UTF-8 as the 8-bit character set is growing in popularity, and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251217-00/?p=111880 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When AI Amplifies Your Bad (and Good) Habits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is more like a megaphone than a magic wand. It amplifies what is already there. Whatever habits you bring to your workflow, good or bad, AI will turn up the volume. Every untested component, undocumented design, and ill-specified feature, to name a few, becomes louder when AI enters the mix. Teams with a clear […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/when-ai-amplifies-your-bad-and-good-habits/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack Roadmap for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I normally write this out in January, but I’m feeling like now is a good time to get this out as some of it is in flight. So with plenty of feedback from the other Critter Stack Core team members and a lot of experience seeing where JasperFx Software clients have hit friction in the … Continue reading Critter Stack Roadmap for 2026 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/12/17/critter-stack-roadmap-for-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Safer Container Ecosystem with Docker: Free Docker Hardened Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Containers are the universal path to production for most developers, and Docker has always been the steward of the ecosystem. Docker Hub has over 20 billion monthly pulls, with nearly 90% of organizations now relying on containers in their software delivery workflows. That gives us a responsibility: to help secure the software supply chain for...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hardened-images-for-every-developer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.3 Has Been Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MPS 2025.3 introduces a major overhaul of the JavaDoc language, significant changes to generator plans, and a major update to the reflective editor. It also enables keyboard actions in the Logical view and allows TextIcon to offer visually distinct variants for light and dark themes. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 What’s new Check out all the available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/12/mps-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Leaders on the KotlinConf’25 Stage: What Global Brands Built With Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin ecosystem continues to grow among the world’s most recognized brands, including Meta, AWS, Duolingo, Uber, and others. At KotlinConf 2025, these companies took the stage to share practical, real-world engineering stories. KotlinConf is where developers can learn directly from the teams building products at global scale. Software engineers showcase how they are tackling […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/industry-leaders-on-the-kotlinconf25-stage/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock your email potential with Schema.org</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Email is a key part of how people get things done, whether it’s booking a reservation, confirming a package delivery, or managing a cab reservation. But as inboxes become increasingly cluttered, important transactional information often gets buried. Users are forced to open multip
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/unlock-your-email-potential-with-schema-org 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing OpenAI Academy for News Organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is launching the OpenAI Academy for News Organizations, a new learning hub built with the American Journalism Project and The Lenfest Institute to help newsrooms use AI effectively. The Academy offers training, practical use cases, and responsible-use guidance to support journalists, editors, and publishers as they adopt AI in their reporting and operations.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-academy-for-news-organizations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers can now submit apps to ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers can now submit apps for review and publication in ChatGPT, with approved apps appearing in a new in-product directory for easy discovery. Updated tools, guidelines, and the Apps SDK help developers build powerful chat-native experiences that bring real-world actions into ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/developers-can-now-submit-apps-to-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize ASP.NET MVC Razor UI with AWS Transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Transform is an agentic service that accelerates modernization, including .NET applications. With it, you can transform .NET Framework Windows applications to cross-platform .NET and reduce operating costs up to 40% by running on Linux. For ASP.NET web applications, AWS Transform can port the UI layer to ASP.NET Core. In this post, I’ll explain how […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-asp-net-mvc-razor-ui-with-aws-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why “Microservices” Debates Miss the Point</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 22:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DHH had a take on microservices in small teams that is getting a lot of attention. And while I agree with what he’s pointing out, all of these types of conversations miss what actually matters. This is not about microservices or a monolith or small teams. Now what’s implied here is microservices is much more… Read More »Why “Microservices” Debates Miss the Point The post Why “Microservices” Debates Miss the Point appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance by design: The essential guide for successful AI scaling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 21:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picture this: Your enterprise has just deployed its first generative AI application. The initial results are promising, but as you plan to scale across departments, critical questions emerge. How will you enforce consistent security, prevent model bias, and maintain control as AI applications multiply?
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/governance-by-design-the-essential-guide-for-successful-ai-scaling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Ergonomics: How the Azure Command Launcher for Java Improves GC Stability and Throughput on Azure VMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog we introduced Azure Command Launcher for Java (jaz) —a safe, resource-aware way to launch the JVM without hand-tuning dozens of flags. This follow-up shares performance results, focusing on
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/beyond-ergonomics-how-the-azure-command-launcher-for-java-improves-gc-stability-and-throughput-on-azure-vms 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tata Power CoE built a scalable AI-powered solar panel inspection solution with Amazon SageMaker AI and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Tata Power CoE and Oneture Technologies use AWS services to automate the inspection process end-to-end.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-tata-power-coe-built-a-scalable-ai-powered-solar-panel-inspection-solution-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking video understanding with TwelveLabs Marengo on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll show how the TwelveLabs Marengo embedding model, available on Amazon Bedrock, enhances video understanding through multimodal AI. We&#39;ll build a video semantic search and analysis solution using embeddings from the Marengo model with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless as the vector database, for semantic search capabilities that go beyond simple metadata matching to deliver intelligent content discovery.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-video-understanding-with-twelvelabs-marengo-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip turns 10. Hidden gems of DataGrip.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking back Hello, friends! 10 years ago to this very day, DataGrip was born. That’s right, on December 16, 2016, the first-ever version of DataGrip was released! But the origins of DataGrip go back even further. We had already been working to create a database IDE for quite some time by then, and its codename […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/16/datagrip-turns-10-hidden-gems-of-datagrip/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; code editing tools for GitHub Copilot: now in Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In November, we introduced C++ code editing tools for GitHub Copilot as a Private Preview, focusing on partnering with customers to tackle one of the common, taxing challenges for C++ development: refactoring at s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-code-editing-tools-for-github-copilot-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft.Testing.Platform Now Fully Supported in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this year, we announced that all major .NET test frameworks now support Microsoft.Testing.Platform. The next logical step? Making sure it works seamlessly with your CI/CD pipelines. Today, we&#39;re announcing comprehensive Azure DevOps integration for Microsof
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/microsoft-testing-platform-azure-retry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.3.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.3.0 release is out! This version includes new language features, stable ones, and other features now enabled by default. This release also brings tooling updates, performance improvements for different platforms, and important fixes. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/kotlin-2-3-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging, but Without the Drama (A Visual Studio 2026 Story)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It starts the way these things always start. A red build.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2026-debugging-with-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is the Windows clipboard taking the scenic route when converting from &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; to &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;OEM­TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our investigation of why the CF_OEM­TEXT clipboard format is not being created from CF_TEXT via Ansi­To­Oem led us to the realization that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251216-00/?p=111873 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and deploy voice AI apps using Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Voice is the next frontier of conversational AI. It is the most natural modality for people to chat and interact with another intelligent being. However, the voice AI software stack is complex, with many moving parts. Docker has emerged as one of the most useful tools for AI agent deployment. In this article, we&#39;ll explore...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/develop-deploy-voice-ai-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards integration with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A few months ago we introduced the Azure Boards integration with GitHub Copilot in private preview. The goal was simple: allow teams to take a work item from Azure Boards and send it directly to GitHub Copilot so the coding agent
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/github-copilot-for-azure-boards 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner now included with the Universal Blue family</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running large language models (LLMs) and other generative AI models can be a complex, frustrating process of managing dependencies, drivers, and environments. At Docker, we believe this should be as simple as docker model run. That&#39;s why we built Docker Model Runner, and today, we’re thrilled to announce a new collaboration with Universal Blue. Thanks...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-universal-blue/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs C&#43;&#43;: competition or evolution in systems programming for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C and C++ are the backbone of modern software. Operating systems, databases, game engines, and compilers all trace their roots to these languages. They give developers low-level control over memory, hardware, and performance. It’s a level of control that has defined decades of software development. However, the landscape has shifted, and the Rust vs. C++ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/12/16/rust-vs-cpp-comparison-for-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents, Protocols, and Why We’re Not Playing Favorites</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past few weeks, after we announced ACP protocol support, I’ve gotten lots of messages asking something along these lines: “Microsoft just launched AgentHQ for GitHub and VS Code. So, does this mean JetBrains will drop ACP? Will you only support your own thing now?” The quick answer: We’re not picking sides. Here’s why – […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/agents-protocols-and-why-we-re-not-playing-favorites/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a .NET CLR profiler using C# and NativeAOT with Silhouette</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at how to create a simple .NET profiler. But instead of using C++, the profiler uses C# and NativeAOT with the Silhouette library
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-dotnet-profiler-using-csharp-with-silhouette/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating AI’s ability to perform scientific research tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces FrontierScience, a benchmark testing AI reasoning in physics, chemistry, and biology to measure progress toward real scientific research.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/frontierscience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring AI’s capability to accelerate biological research</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces a real-world evaluation framework to measure how AI can accelerate biological research in the wet lab. Using GPT-5 to optimize a molecular cloning protocol, the work explores both the promise and risks of AI-assisted experimentation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/accelerating-biological-research-in-the-wet-lab 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in .NET 10 and C# 14: Optimizations in log aggregation jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:55:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 is officially out, along with C# 14. Microsoft has released .NET 10 as Long-Term Support (LTS) as a successor to .NET 8. Like every version, it is not just an update but brings something new to the table. In this series, we will explore which aspects of software
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/new-in-net-10-and-c-14-optimizations-in-log-aggregation-jobs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt Noise Is Killing Your AI Accuracy: How to Optimize Context for Grounded Output</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 01:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The most common reason an AI system “hallucinates” in production isn’t that the model is dumb. It’s that we’re drowning it. In the last year, many teams have quietly adopted a pattern that looks sophisticated on paper: throw everything into the prompt. Policies, API schemas, examples, edge cases, brand voice, product specs, meeting notes, customer […] The article Prompt Noise Is Killing Your AI Accuracy: How to Optimize Context for Grounded Output was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[C# Tip] How to create and access custom C# Attributes by using Reflection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In C#, Attributes are a handy mechanism to attach metadata to your classes, methods, properties, etc. In this article, we will see how to create custom Attributes and access them at runtime using Reflection.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/custom-csharp-attributes-reflection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new ChatGPT Images is here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new ChatGPT Images is powered by our flagship image generation model, delivering more precise edits, consistent details, and image generation up to 4× faster. The upgraded model is rolling out to all ChatGPT users today and is also available in the API as GPT-Image-1.5.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/new-chatgpt-images-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checkpointless training on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod: Production-scale training with faster fault recovery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce checkpointless training on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod, a paradigm shift in model training that reduces the need for traditional checkpointing by enabling peer-to-peer state recovery. Results from production-scale validation show 80–93% reduction in recovery time (from 15–30 minutes or more to under 2 minutes) and enables up to 95% training goodput on cluster sizes with thousands of AI accelerators.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/checkpointless-training-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-production-scale-training-with-faster-fault-recovery/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build declarative agents for Microsoft 365 Copilot with MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is revolutionizing AI by providing a universal integration standard for the external systems, unlocking unprecedented capabilities, transforming how AI models access and utilize real-time data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-declarative-agents-for-microsoft-365-copilot-with-mcp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive infrastructure for foundation model training with elastic training on SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker HyperPod now supports elastic training, enabling your machine learning (ML) workloads to automatically scale based on resource availability. In this post, we demonstrate how elastic training helps you maximize GPU utilization, reduce costs, and accelerate model development through dynamic resource adaptation, while maintain training quality and minimizing manual intervention.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/adaptive-infrastructure-for-foundation-model-training-with-elastic-training-on-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build iOS Widgets with .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog from Toine de Boer. I&#39;m a .NET developer primarily focused on .NET MAUI to ASP.NET backend services. Because I recently have worked a lot with Widgets and encountered many obstacles and very limited documentation in the initial phas
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/how-to-build-ios-widgets-with-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize agent workflows with advanced orchestration techniques using Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore two powerful orchestration patterns implemented with Strands Agents. Using a common set of travel planning tools, we demonstrate how different orchestration strategies can solve the same problem through distinct reasoning approaches,
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/customize-agent-workflows-with-advanced-orchestration-techniques-using-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operationalize generative AI workloads and scale to hundreds of use cases with Amazon Bedrock – Part 1: GenAIOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this first part of our two-part series, you&#39;ll learn how to evolve your existing DevOps architecture for generative AI workloads and implement GenAIOps practices. We&#39;ll showcase practical implementation strategies for different generative AI adoption levels, focusing on consuming foundation models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/operationalize-generative-ai-workloads-and-scale-to-hundreds-of-use-cases-with-amazon-bedrock-part-1-genaiops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying data loading best practices for ML training with Amazon S3 clients</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present practical techniques and recommendations for optimizing throughput in ML training workloads that read data directly from Amazon S3 general purpose buckets.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/applying-data-loading-best-practices-for-ml-training-with-amazon-s3-clients/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.11.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have rolled out 2025.11.1, the first update for the major 2025.11 version. This bug-fix resolves a number of issues, including: Bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements, so we recommend installing them promptly. See TeamCity 2025.11.1 Release Notes for the complete list of resolved issues. Why update? Staying up to date with minor […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/teamcity-2025-11-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes of the Visual Studio feedback system</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Here on the Visual Studio team, our top priority is making your coding experience smoother and more enjoyable. And that begins with truly listening to your feedback. We understand that sometimes sharing your thoughts can feel like tossing bug reports and suggestions into a black hole. It doesn’t feel good, and we get it. But here’s the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/behind-the-scenes-of-the-visual-studio-feedback-system 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misunderstanding what the Cricket Celebration Bowl is</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Apparently, late last week was an event known as the Cricket Celebration Bowl. I thought to myself, &amp;quot;The Cricket Celebration Bowl sounds like the name of the least popular item on the Panera menu.&amp;quot; And no, it&#39;s not a cricket match either.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251215-01/?p=111871 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Windows clipboard automatic text conversion algorithm is path-dependent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We closed last time with this table: To get First try
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251215-00/?p=111869 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Tame Your Flaky Tests in TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Satish Subrahmanya, draft.dev. It’s 4:47 pm on a Friday. Your feature branch just passed all tests locally, and the code review went smoothly, so you hit the merge button. But then it happens: The CI build fails. The same test suite that passed five minutes ago is now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/how-to-tame-flaky-tests/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auth0 Changes The Game for AI Agents - Dev Leader Weekly 119</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss some of the awesome features Auth0 is bringing for building AI agents!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/14/auth0-changes-the-game-for-ai-agents-dev-leader-weekly-119 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-12-12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/14/weekly-recap-20251212 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private MCP Catalogs and the Path to Composable Enterprise AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most discussions about Model Context Protocol infrastructure ask how to govern thousands of AI tools and monitor which MCP servers are running. This question is table stakes but undershoots the possibilities. A better question is how we can unleash MCP to drive developer creativity from a trusted foundation. The first question produces a phone book...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/private-mcp-catalogs-oci-composable-enterprise-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Chronicles: When OpenAI’s Magic Meets a Messy User Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author expresses frustration with Sora&#39;s poor user experience and ongoing instability, emphasizing navigation difficulties, session issues, and prolonged outages. Despite Sora&#39;s impressive capabilities, the author argues that without prioritizing user experience and reliability, OpenAI risks losing the trust of professional creators. They urge the hiring of experienced UX designers and engineers.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/12/14/ux-chronicles-when-openais-magic-meets-a-messy-user-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New .slnx Solution Format (migration guide)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2025/13_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2025/13_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            See what changes in .slnx, how to convert your existing .sln, and what to watch out for in CI.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-new-slnx-solution-format-migration-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from AWS re:Invent: Supercharging Kiro with Docker Sandboxes and MCP Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the recent AWS re:Invent, Docker focused on a very real developer problem: how to run AI agents locally without giving them access to your machine, credentials, or filesystem. With AWS introducing Kiro, Docker demonstrated how Docker Sandboxes and MCP Toolkit allow developers to run agents inside isolated containers, keeping host environments and secrets out...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/aws-reinvent-kiro-docker-sandboxes-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a voice-driven AWS assistant with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a sophisticated voice-powered AWS operations assistant using Amazon Nova Sonic for speech processing and Strands Agents for multi-agent orchestration. This solution demonstrates how natural language voice interactions can transform cloud operations, making AWS services more accessible and operations more efficient.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-voice-driven-aws-assistant-with-amazon-nova-sonic/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving an ambiguity in the Windows clipboard automated text conversion table</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we encountered a mystery where the synthesis of CF_OEM­TEXT from CF_TEXT did not use Ansi­To­Oem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251212-05/?p=111862 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of Global Personal Access Tokens in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the new year, we’ll be retiring the Global Personal Access Token (PAT) type in Azure DevOps. Global PATs allow users to authenticate across all accessible organizations. While this can feel convenient, a single credential with broad reach creates a concentrated security risk — especially as a user’s access
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/retirement-of-global-personal-access-tokens-in-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is AI the New Insider Threat?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Insider threats have always been difficult to manage because they blur the line between trusted access and risky behavior. With generative AI, these risks aren&#39;t tied to malicious insiders misusing credentials or bypassing controls; they come from well-intentioned employees simply trying to get work done faster. Whether it&#39;s developers refactoring code, analysts summarizing long reports,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-insider-threat-shadow-ai-risk-controls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add MCP Servers to ChatGPT with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT is great at answering questions and generating code. But here&#39;s what it can&#39;t do: execute that code, query your actual database, create a GitHub repo with your project, or scrape live data from websites. It&#39;s like having a brilliant advisor who can only talk, never act. Docker MCP Toolkit changes this completely. Here&#39;s what...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/add-mcp-server-to-chatgpt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 3: Under Observation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously in this series: Two articles in, and our coding agent can already do quite a bit. It can explore projects, read and write code, execute shell commands, and run tests. Adding a definition of done (DoD) in our last article gave it the feedback loop it needed – the agent now iterates until all […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-3-under-observation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Qodana on Kubernetes: More Scalability, More Control</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As engineering teams scale, so do the demands on their tooling. Code quality checks that worked well for one repository or service often need a more resilient, automated, and infrastructure-native setup when development ecosystems grow. That’s exactly why we’re excited to introduce first-class Kubernetes support for Qodana, bringing fully automated deployments, lifecycle management, and future-ready […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/12/deploying-qodana-on-kubernetes-more-scalability-more-control/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: 4 Tools That Keep Systems Running</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference — the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and to contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/12/open-source-in-focus-4-tools-that-keep-systems-running/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBVA and OpenAI collaborate to transform global banking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BBVA is expanding its work with OpenAI through a multi-year AI transformation program, rolling out ChatGPT Enterprise to all 120,000 employees. Together, the companies will develop AI solutions that enhance customer interactions, streamline operations, and help build an AI-native banking experience.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bbva-collaboration-expansion 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BNY builds “AI for everyone, everywhere” with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BNY is using OpenAI technology to expand AI adoption enterprise-wide. Through its Eliza platform, 20,000+ employees are building AI agents that enhance efficiency and improve client outcomes.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bny 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Used Codex to Ship Sora for Android in 28 Days</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI shipped Sora for Android in 28 days using Codex. AI-assisted planning, translation, and parallel coding workflows helped a nimble team deliver rapid, reliable development.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/shipping-sora-for-android-with-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Harmonic Security improved their data-leakage detection system with low-latency fine-tuned models using Amazon SageMaker, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Nova Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how Harmonic Security used Amazon SageMaker AI, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Nova Pro to fine-tune a ModernBERT model, achieving low-latency, accurate, and scalable data leakage detection.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-harmonic-security-improved-their-data-leakage-detection-system-with-low-latency-fine-tuned-models-using-amazon-sagemaker-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-nova-pro/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Swisscom builds enterprise agentic AI for customer support and sales using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll show how Swisscom implemented Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to build and scale their enterprise AI agents for customer support and sales operations. As an early adopter of Amazon Bedrock in the AWS Europe Region (Zurich), Swisscom leads in enterprise AI implementation with their Chatbot Builder system and various AI initiatives. Their successful deployments include Conversational AI powered by Rasa and fine-tuned LLMs on Amazon SageMaker, and the Swisscom Swisscom myAI assistant, built to meet Swiss data protection standards.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying the various locale mismatch scenarios in Windows clipboard text format synthesis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So far, we&#39;ve learned that the conversion between Unicode and the 8-bit ANSI and OEM code pages is performed with the assistance of the CF_LOCALE clipboard format, which itself c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251211-37/?p=111858 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling MLflow for enterprise AI: What’s New in SageMaker AI with MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re announcing Amazon SageMaker AI with MLflow, now including a serverless capability that dynamically manages infrastructure provisioning, scaling, and operations for artificial intelligence and machine learning (AI/ML) development tasks. In this post, we explore how these new capabilities help you run large MLflow workloads—from generative AI agents to large language model (LLM) experimentation—with improved performance, automation, and security using SageMaker AI with MLflow.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scaling-mlflow-for-enterprise-ai-whats-new-in-sagemaker-ai-with-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Observability with Langfuse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how to integrate Langfuse observability with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to gain deep visibility into an AI agent&#39;s performance, debug issues faster, and optimize costs. We walk through a complete implementation using Strands agents deployed on AgentCore Runtime followed by step-by-step code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-agentcore-observability-with-langfuse/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Windows Terminal awesome with GitHub Copilot CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As someone who lives and breathes in the command line, I love making my terminal feel like home. Windows Terminal is full of personalization options that really allow for a custom experience. Additionally, I can stay within my terminal for my development with GitHub Copilot with the GitHub Copilot CLI. Let&#39;s walk through how you can trick out
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/making-windows-terminal-awesome-with-github-copilot-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner now supports vLLM on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Great news for Windows developers working with AI models: Docker Model Runner now supports vLLM on Docker Desktop for Windows with WSL2 and NVIDIA GPUs! Until now, vLLM support in Docker Model Runner was limited to Docker Engine on Linux. With this update, Windows developers can take advantage of vLLM&#39;s high-throughput inference capabilities directly through...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-vllm-windows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Way to Explore kotlinx-benchmark Results with Kotlin Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Benchmarking is an important part of writing efficient Kotlin code. The kotlinx-benchmark library helps you measure and compare performance across different implementations or hardware configurations. However, raw text results only take you so far. Sometimes you need to visualize your data, not just read it. That’s where Kotlin notebooks come in. Kotlin notebooks combine the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/a-better-way-to-explore-kotlinx-benchmark-results-with-kotlin-notebooks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire Integrations, Batteries Included</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aspire Integrations: Batteries included Modern applications depend on many external services: databases, caches, message brokers, storage layers, observability tools, and sometimes AI systems. Each of these brings its own rules for configuration, connection strings, environment variables, authentication, and deployment. Setting al
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspire-integrations-batteries-included 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy Plugin 2025.11 is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the holidays just around the corner and the year coming to a cheerful close, we’re ringing in the final JetBrains Academy plugin update of 2025, version 2025.11! This release focuses on the introduction of the standalone Hyperskill plugin, expands achievement-sharing to IDE-based courses, and brings a number of improvements and fixes to make your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/11/jetbrains-academy-plugin-2025-11-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Free From AI Vendor Lock-in: Integrating GitHub Models with Docker cagent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The landscape of AI development is rapidly evolving, and one of the most exciting developments in 2025 from Docker is the release of Docker cagent. cagent is Docker&#39;s open-source multi-agent runtime that orchestrates AI agents through declarative YAML configuration. Rather than managing Python environments, SDK versions, and orchestration logic, developers define agent behavior in a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/configure-cagent-github-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB vNext Emulator: Query and Observability Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure Cosmos DB Linux-based vNext emulator (preview) is a local version of the Azure Cosmos DB service that runs as a Docker container on Linux, macOS, and Windows. It provides a cost-effective way to develop and test applications locally without requiring an Azure
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-vnext-emulator-query-and-observability-enhancements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider and ReSharper 2025.3.0.4: Important Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another set of updates for the 2025.3 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. Rider 2025.3.0.4 Multi-agent experience in the AI Chat window: Junie and Claude Agent Claude Agent has become the first third-party AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/11/rider-and-resharper-2025-3-0-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing science and math with GPT-5.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2 is OpenAI’s strongest model yet for math and science, setting new state-of-the-art results on benchmarks like GPQA Diamond and FrontierMath. This post shows how those gains translate into real research progress, including solving an open theoretical problem and generating reliable mathematical proofs.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-2-for-science-and-math 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB : Becoming a Search-Native Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For years, “Database” and “Search systems&amp;quot; (think Elastic Search) lived in separate worlds. While both Databases and Search Systems operate in the same domain (storing, indexing and querying data), they prioritized different aspects. OLTP Databases prioritized Structured and Semi-structured data
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-becoming-a-search-native-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing revenue 300% by bringing AI to SMBs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Podium used OpenAI’s GPT-5 to build “Jerry,” an AI teammate driving 300% growth and transforming how Main Street businesses serve customers.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/podium 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2 is our most advanced frontier model for everyday professional work, with state-of-the-art reasoning, long-context understanding, coding, and vision. Use it in ChatGPT and the OpenAI API to power faster, more reliable agentic workflows.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten years</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI reflects on ten years of progress, from early research breakthroughs to widely used AI systems that reshaped what’s possible. We share lessons from the past decade and why we remain optimistic about building AGI that benefits all of humanity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/ten-years 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Walt Disney Company and OpenAI reach landmark agreement to bring beloved characters to Sora</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disney and OpenAI have reached an agreement to bring more than 200 Disney, Marvel, Pixar and Star Wars characters to Sora for fan-inspired short videos. The agreement emphasizes responsible AI in entertainment and includes Disney’s company-wide use of ChatGPT Enterprise and the OpenAI API.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/disney-sora-agreement 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update to GPT-5 System Card: GPT-5.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2 is the latest model family in the GPT-5 series. The comprehensive safety mitigation approach for these models is largely the same as that described in the GPT-5 System Card and GPT-5.1 System Card. Like OpenAI’s other models, the GPT-5.2 models were trained on diverse datasets, including information that is publicly available on the internet, information that we partner with third parties to access, and information that our users or human trainers and researchers provide or generate.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
