<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 16:41:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Rerank 3 Nimble now generally available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 16:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Cohere Rerank 3 Nimble foundation model (FM) is now generally available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. This model is the newest FM in Cohere’s Rerank model series, built to enhance enterprise search and Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) systems. In this post, we discuss the benefits and capabilities of this new model with some examples. Overview […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cohere-rerank-3-nimble-now-generally-available-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Code Arena: How Well Can AI Models Understand Your Entire Project?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the last couple of years, AI has found its way into virtually all aspects of software development. We know that AI models are getting smarter, and we can clearly see how they have become better at seemingly everything, but why is this happening? One factor that is changing is context size, which is how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/08/long-code-arena-how-well-can-ai-models-understand-your-entire-project/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New git tooling features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 v17.11 includes fantastic updates to everyone working with Git. They bring the richness of both GitHub and Azure DevOps into Visual Studio and part of your natural workflow. This greatly simplifies your inner loop, making you even more productive than before.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-git-tooling-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the PyCharm Databricks Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 08:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re introducing the Databricks integration with PyCharm Professional to make it easier for you to process, store, and analyze your data! The integration allows you to build your data and AI apps on the Databricks Data Intelligence Platform directly within PyCharm Professional, enhancing the data analytics platform with the powerful Python IDE by JetBrains. It […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/introducing-the-pycharm-databricks-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Debugging in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 06:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll be talking about advanced debugging and inspecting data in C#. We’ll be using Visual Studio 2022 to demonstrate all the debugging techniques. For more information about general debugging, we have another article on the basics of debugging, so feel free to check it out. Let’s start by creating a project that […] The post Advanced Debugging in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vital Role of QA: Why Independent Testing is Essential for Software Integrity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2024/18_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2024/18_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of real estate, rigorous inspections are essential for a safe and functional home. Similarly, in software development, Quality Assurance (QA) plays a crucial role in testing software for quality, security, and performance. While unit tests are important, they cannot replace the comprehensive testing provided by a dedicated QA team. Collaborative integration of QA from the beginning of a project, effective communication, and comprehensive documentation are essential for robust and reliable software.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build A Web API From Scratch – Dev Leader Weekly 57</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2024/17_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2024/17_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Build A Web API From Scratch – Dev Leader Weekly 57 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the basic building blocks for building a Web API in DotNet! The post Build A Web API From Scratch – Dev Leader Weekly 57 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/08/17/build-a-web-api-from-scratch-dev-leader-weekly-57/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete Guide to Amazon SQS and Amazon SNS With MassTransit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2024/17_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2024/17_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we&#39;ll explore how to use Amazon SQS and SNS for asynchronous messaging in .NET applications. We&#39;ll also see how MassTransit simplifies the process, enabling you to build robust message-driven systems.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/complete-guide-to-amazon-sqs-and-amazon-sns-with-masstransit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.0-1 Microsoft build now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 16:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-0-1-microsoft-build-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify development with Dev Container templates for Azure SQL Database – Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 15:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced software development landscape, having a reliable and efficient local development setup is crucial. Dev Containers provide developers with a seamless way to build and test applications locally before deploying them to the cloud. We are announcing the Public Preview of Dev Container templates for Azure SQL Database.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/azure-sql-dev-containers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Malware protection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 15:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read about the different ways that Microsoft 365 Certification validates anti-malware controls.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-malware-protection 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing a new learning module for evaluating and building with Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 15:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing a new learning module that helps you explore Microsoft Entra External ID. This module guides you through building a website for an online grocery store, demonstrating how to use External ID for customer sign-ups and sign-ins. It&#39;s a perfect starting point if you&#39;re new to External ID, offering a hands-on way to create a proof-of-concept project while discovering the platform&#39;s features and capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-id-learning-module 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the missing ordinal 380</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Untangling the error message and developing a theory.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240816-00/?p=110136 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking a JVM Application With IntelliJ IDEA’s Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 09:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in the day, computer games were different. Not only have their graphics and mechanics evolved, but they also had one characteristic that doesn’t seem very common in games today: cheat codes. Cheat codes were sequences of keys that would give you something extraordinary, such as infinite ammo or the ability to walk through walls. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/hacking-a-jvm-application-with-intellij-idea-s-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Router using Azure AI Search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Potential semantic routing solution using Azure AI Search for scalable query handling.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/semantic-routing-using-azure-ai-search 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perform generative AI-powered data prep and no-code ML over any size of data using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 03:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Canvas now empowers enterprises to harness the full potential of their data by enabling support of petabyte-scale datasets. Starting today, you can interactively prepare large datasets, create end-to-end data flows, and invoke automated machine learning (AutoML) experiments on petabytes of data—a substantial leap from the previous 5 GB limit. With over 50 connectors, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/perform-generative-ai-powered-data-prep-and-no-code-ml-over-any-size-of-data-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving OpenJDK Scalar Replacement – Part 3/3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 21:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the final part of our series on scalar replacement in OpenJDK. In the previous posts, we covered the basics of scalar replacement and detailed the improvements we introduced to the implementation. Now, it’s time to see these enhancements in action.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/improving-openjdk-scalar-replacement-part-3-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 Preview 7 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Try out the latest features in .NET 9 Preview 7 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, C#, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-preview-7 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot Content Exclusion Now Available in Visual Studio 2022 17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 17:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Copilot Content Exclusion is now available in Visual Studio 2022 17.11. This feature allows your admins to configure Copilot to ignore certain files in a repository or organization, giving you enterprise control that ensures sensitive information is protected while seamlessly integrating trusted AI for efficient coding.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/copilot-content-exclusion-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delight your customers with great conversational experiences via QnABot, a generative AI chatbot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 15:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            QnABot on AWS (an AWS Solution) now provides access to Amazon Bedrock foundational models (FMs) and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed end-to-end Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) workflow. You can now provide contextual information from your private data sources that can be used to create rich, contextual, conversational experiences. In this post, we discuss how to use QnABot on AWS to deploy a fully functional chatbot integrated with other AWS services, and delight your customers with human agent like conversational experiences.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create scripts with Power Platform CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Power Platform CLI is a great tool to use when you are working with the Power Platform. You can create Power Apps Component Framework (PCF) components with it, you can do tons of administrative actions, and much more! You can run these one by one in the console when you’re developing a Power Platform solution,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/create-scripts-with-power-platform-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code update – August 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 14:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the latest Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code updates including the capability to create declarative copilots.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/teams-toolkit-for-visual-studio-code-update-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instead of putting a hash in the Portable Executable timestamp field, why not create a separate field for the hash?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That would defeat the purpose.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240815-00/?p=110131 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2024.2 Versions of JetBrains IDEs Are Here With Enhanced FLCC and Remote Development, the New UI as the Default, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 09:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains IDEs, .NET tools, and AI Assistant are ready to be updated to the 2024.2 versions, which introduce a plethora of new features and improvements. We’ve seen high adoption rates for the new UI, and in the 2024.2 versions of JetBrains IDEs, the new UI is now the default for all users. The classic UI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/08/15/the-2024-2-versions-of-jetbrains-ides-are-here-with-enhanced-flcc-and-remote-development-the-new-ui-as-the-default-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotCover, dotMemory, dotPeek, and dotTrace 2024.2 Have Been Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dotCover 2024.2, dotMemory 2024.2, dotPeek 2024.2, and dotTrace 2024.2 have been released and are ready for download! Let’s take a look at what’s new with these .NET tools. dotMemory 2024.2 dotTrace 2024.2 dotCover 2024.2 dotPeek 2024.2 General enhancements Handling of external sources Build configuration detection If you’re also interested in learning more about ReSharper 2024.1 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/15/dotnet-tools-242-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2024.2: Deepened C#12 and Initial C#13 Support, New AI Capabilities, Localization, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, ReSharper 2024.2 and the latest versions of other JetBrains .NET tools have just been released. This release brings support for the .NET 9 Preview SDK, new C# and C++ features, localization updates, AI Assistant enhancements, and much more. In this article, we’ll cover the highlights of this major update for ReSharper and touch […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/15/resharper-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2: Full Line Code Completion, Reader Mode, Major Enhancements to Debugging, and More.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, We’re happy to announce the release of Rider 2024.2, which comes packed with a range of exciting features and improvements designed to elevate your .NET and game development experience. From enhanced language support to advanced AI capabilities, this update has something for everyone. Now, let’s dive into the details! Key features and enhancements […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/15/rider-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build better HTTP APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 20:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many of the business systems we build are for managing life cycles and workflows. It provides ways to make the state transition from beginning to end. One of the challenges when building systems is that they evolve, and you can start leaking business logic to the frontend or clients where you end up with duplicate… Read More »Build better HTTP APIs The post Build better HTTP APIs appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing document-level sync reports: Enhanced data sync visibility in Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 19:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a fully managed, generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered assistant that helps enterprises unlock the value of their data and knowledge. With Amazon Q, you can quickly find answers to questions, generate summaries and content, and complete tasks by using the information and expertise stored across your company’s various data sources and enterprise […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-document-level-sync-reports-enhanced-data-sync-visibility-in-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on deprecating legacy Exchange Online tokens for Outlook add-ins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April, we announced that Exchange tokens will be turned off by default for all tenants in October 2024. This has been updated and you should have more time to move your Outlook add-ins from Exchange tokens to NAA.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/updates-on-deprecating-legacy-exchange-online-tokens-for-outlook-add-ins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Conf 2024 – Celebrating the Release of .NET 9! – Save the Date!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing .NET Conf 2024 - a free, three-day virtual developer event that celebrates the release of .NET 9.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-conf-2024-celebrating-the-release-of-dotnet-9-save-the-date 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derive generative AI-powered insights from ServiceNow with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 14:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to configure the Amazon Q ServiceNow connector to index your ServiceNow platform and take advantage of generative AI searches in Amazon Q. We use an example of an illustrative ServiceNow platform to discuss technical topics related to AWS services.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/derive-generative-ai-powered-insights-from-servicenow-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporarily dropping a lock: The anti-lock pattern</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s not to prevent locking, but rather to counteract a lock.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240814-00/?p=110129 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation of Password Logins on CLI with Docker SSO Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 13:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Docker team announces the deprecation of password logins on the Docker CLI when Single Sign-On (SSO) is enforced, effective September 16, 2024.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/deprecation-of-password-logins-on-cli-with-docker-sso-enforcement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Development and Code With Me for Nova, Full Line Code Completion, and Zephyr West Support Are Available in CLion 2024.2!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 12:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion 2024.2 is now available! This version of the powerful JetBrains IDE for C and C++ introduces several new features and improvements: CLion 2024.2 is available in the Toolbox App, as a snap package (on Ubuntu), from our website, or via a patch update from version 2024.1. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 CLion Nova Full line code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/08/2024-2-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First preview of Visual Studio 2022 v17.12 with .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the availability of Visual Studio 2022 v17.12 Preview 1 – the first preview of our next update to Visual Studio. This update focuses on providing fantastic developer experiences for working with .NET 9 projects and new AI productivity features,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/first-preview-of-visual-studio-2022-v17-12-with-net-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More New UI Icons for Your Plugins!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 08:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve made a major update to our IntelliJ Platform Icons website, adding over 1,000 new icons tailored to the new UI! This makes it easier than ever for plugin developers to find the perfect icons for their projects. If you’ve been struggling to find icons that fit the new UI, your search is over! Most […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/08/more-new-ui-icons-for-your-plugins/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Wolverine Library in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 06:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll introduce the Wolverine library and its benefits for .NET developers. We’ll cover installation, setting up our first project, and core concepts around messaging. By the end, we’ll understand how to use Wolverine effectively in common practices and see real-world examples to help integrate it into our .NET applications. Let’s get into […] The post Introduction to the Wolverine Library in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for Azure.AI.OpenAI and OpenAI v2 is here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 19:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing that support for for Azure.AI.OpenAI and OpenAI v2 .NET SDK is available in the Semantic Kernel v1.18.0-rc release candidate. This release supports the official OpenAI library for .NET which Microsoft announced at the Build 2024 conference. This new SDK ensures that .NET developers have parity with other programming language libraries when accessing Azure OpenAI models.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/support-for-azure-ai-openai-and-openai-v2-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Azure AI Inference SDK: Access More AI Models with the Azure AI Model Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the Azure AI Inference SDK for .NET! This SDK provides easy access to a comprehensive suite of AI models in the Azure AI Model Catalog for inference tasks like chat, enabling you to effortlessly incorporate AI into your applications that align with your requirements.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/azure-ai-model-catalog-dotnet-inference-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2022 v17.11 – Your feedback in action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the General Availability (GA) of Visual Studio 2022 version 17.11. This release is a testament to our commitment to listening to you, our developer community. Every enhancement, every fix, and every new feature in this release has been shaped by your feedback.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2022-v17-11-your-feedback-in-action 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework August 2024 updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the updates for .NET and .NET Framework for August 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-august-2024-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – August 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the August release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd) and recaps the July release. Includes enhancements for azd pipeline config, deployment status tracking for Linux web apps, support for managed identity during login, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent healthcare forms analysis with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore using the Anthropic Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock large language model (LLM). Amazon Bedrock provides access to several LLMs, such as Anthropic Claude 3, which can be used to generate semi-structured data relevant to the healthcare industry. This can be particularly useful for creating various healthcare-related forms, such as patient intake forms, insurance claim forms, or medical history questionnaires.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/intelligent-healthcare-forms-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Dev Box Team Customizations and Imaging to streamline your team’s development workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 15:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TLDR: We are excited to introduce team-based customization of Dev Boxes with built in imaging capabilities, using the familiar Dev Box customization format, to help you create and optimize ready-to-code Dev Box configurations for your entire team. Sign up for the private preview here.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/use-dev-box-team-customizations-and-imaging-to-streamline-your-teams-development-workflow 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to migrate MongoDB to Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB using Spark and Databricks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MongoDB is a popular document database that offers high performance, scalability, and flexibility. Many organizations use MongoDB to store and process large volumes of data for various applications. However, managing and maintaining MongoDB clusters can be challenging and costly, especially as the data grows and the demand increases.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/mongo-migrations-spark-databricks 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back at one of the (many) projects code-named Highlander</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The showdown that almost repeated.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240813-00/?p=110127 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New for C&#43;&#43; Developers in Visual Studio 2022 17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that Visual Studio 2022 version 17.11 is now generally available! This post summarizes the new features you can find in this release for C++. You can download Visual Studio 2022 from the Visual Studio downloads page or upgrade your existing installation by following the Update Visual Studio Learn page.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-for-c-developers-in-visual-studio-2022-17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust and Docker Desktop: An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We explore Zero Trust security and walk through several strategies for implementing Zero Trust within a Docker Desktop-based development environment.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/zero-trust-and-docker-desktop-an-introduction/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer: A Better Way to Navigate Your Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a developer, you may have to work on various projects that involve storing and querying data from different regions and devices. Whether you are building a web application, a mobile app, a gaming platform, or an IoT solution, you want a database that can handle the complexity and scale of your data without compromising on performance and availability.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/a-better-way-to-navigate-your-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Mastering IntelliJ IDEA With DevoxxGenie: Harnessing Local and Cloud-Based LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 10:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Stephan Janssen, where we will dive into AI-enhanced development. Date: August 22, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract This live session will explore: The genesis of DevoxxGenie and its integration of local LLMs. The practical applications and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining multiple docker images into a multi-arch image</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show two ways to combine multiple docker images into a single multi-arch image, discuss manifests and manifest lists, and why they matter
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/combining-multiple-docker-images-into-a-multi-arch-image/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip 2024.2: Text-to-SQL, Scripted Loaders, Improved Search Everywhere, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 08:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2024.2 is out! Here’s a glimpse of what awaits you in the latest version. For a full overview of this update, please visit our What’s New page. AI Assistant Working with data Search Everywhere popup Connectivity If you’re interested in upgrading to DataGrip 2024.2, or if you have any questions or suggestions, here are […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/08/13/datagrip-2024-2-text-to-sql-scripted-loaders-improved-search-everywhere-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2024.2: AI Cells, Enhanced Experience With Jupyter Notebooks, Geo Viewer for Tabular Data Files, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 07:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In DataSpell 2024.2, we’ve introduced AI cells, enabling AI-assisted code generation, code editing, and error fixing in Jupyter notebooks. The streamlined cell execution includes a Run Cell button next to each cell and a Go To button for the previously executed cell. The new version also includes new collapsible cells and cell tag features, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2024/08/dataspell-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to implement customized role permissions in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 08:32:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You often need to add authentication and authorization when developing an application for a user base. But what are they? Why are they so important? This blog post will define these terms and discuss how to implement custom role permissions in an ASP.NET Core API.
What is Authentication?
Authentication asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/how-to-implement-customized-role-permissions-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OData .NET 8 Official Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 21:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that OData .NET 8 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.OData.Core 8.0.0 Microsoft.OData.Edm 8.0.0 Microsoft.OData.Client 8.0.0 Microsoft.Spatial 8.0.0 We would like to thank the community for trying out the pre-release versions and sharing feedback with us following our announcements of the previews and release candidates.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-odata-net-8-official-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2408.09 – Bug fixes &#43; everything in 2408.05</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 20:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2408.09, which can be downloaded here. This release includes everything that was in the 2408.05 version of PIX, plus the following bug fixes: Fix PIX bug that caused misc counter collection errors on Intel GPUs Fix performance regression when opening DXR captures with big shader tables Fix DXR invocations view when DispatchRays() event has no global root signature Fix showing root Acceleration Structures in Pipeline View created via CreateCommittedResource3() Make formatted text in text editor update with theme changes Rename shader table column header from “Root Signature”
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harness the power of AI and ML using Splunk and Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For organizations looking beyond the use of out-of-the-box Splunk AI/ML features, this post explores how Amazon SageMaker Canvas, a no-code ML development service, can be used in conjunction with data collected in Splunk to drive actionable insights. We also demonstrate how to use the generative AI capabilities of SageMaker Canvas to speed up your data exploration and help you build better ML models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/harness-the-power-of-ai-and-ml-using-splunk-and-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2: Improved File-System-Based Routing Support, Bun Debugging Support, Directly Run and Debug TypeScript Files, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 17:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our second major release of 2024 is here! In this version, you’ll find improved file-system-based routing support, initial debugging support for Bun, the ability to run TypeScript files directly, and a whole lot more. DOWNLOAD WEBSTORM 2024.2 If you only have a few minutes to explore the highlights of WebStorm 2024.2, check out this video, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/08/webstorm-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unreal Debugging Improvements in Rider 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2024.2 includes massive improvements to the native debugger, significantly improving the experience of evaluating native code while debugging. There are performance improvements, better handling of optimised code, and support for evaluating operators on smart pointers and string types. The changes will make a big difference to your day-to-day debugging of Unreal games with JetBrains […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/12/unreal-debugging-improvements-in-rider-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel Log Files Support in PhpStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today I want to look at a new feature in PhpStorm, one that I think many Laravel developers will find very interesting. Now, to be clear, I’m a Developer Advocate at JetBrains, so you might think it’s obvious I’m excited about PhpStorm. Well, I wouldn’t be writing this post if I weren’t genuinely thrilled about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/08/laravel-log-files-support-in-phpstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2024.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re glad to announce that the new RubyMine version is now available. You can download it from our website, via the free Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. Starting with RubyMine 2024.2, you no longer need to install language support plugins if you use your IDE in Chinese, Korean, or Japanese. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/08/rubymine-2024-2-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.2 Is Here: Improvements for Jupyter Notebooks, Databricks Integration, New AI Assistant Features, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Offering a wide range of new and improved functionality, including Hugging Face integration, new AI Assistant features, a new default UI, and an overall better user experience, PyCharm 2024.2 is a must for anyone looking to increase their productivity. Learn about all the updates on our What’s New page, download the latest version from our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/pycharm-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing the power of the empty set in API design (and applying this principle to selectors and filters)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You got plenty of nothing.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240812-00/?p=110121 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New SDK Options for Fine-Grained Request Routing to Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 13:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest updates to the Azure Cosmos DB .NET SDK bring a powerful new feature with the release of version 3.37.0: the ExcludeRegions request option. This enhancement allows developers to exclude specific regions from their preferred locations when making a request,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/new-sdk-options-for-fine-grained-request-routing-to-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding the ESLint Tool to an AI Assistant: Improving Recommendations for JS/TS Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 13:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We show how to enable our AI assistant to provide advice that is both helpful and actionable for linting JavaScript and TypeScript projects.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/adding-the-eslint-tool-to-an-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI, including GPT-4o, Approved as a Service within the FedRAMP High Authorization for Azure Government</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of our ongoing effort to deliver the latest AI innovations to our government customers, our team is proud to announce two significant updates: Azure OpenAI Service is now approved as a service within the FedRAMP High Authorization for Azure Government.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/azure-openai-fedramp-high-for-government 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View and Delete Multiple Items at once in Azure Cosmos DB with Data Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One common task that developers need to perform when working with Azure Cosmos DB is deleting and viewing items from a container. Whether it’s for cleaning up test data, removing obsolete records, or complying with data retention policies, deleting items is an essential operation that should be easy and efficient.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/delete-items-azure-cosmos-db-data-explorer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2024.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 09:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PhpStorm 2024.2 has been released now! Here are the highlights of the most impactful changes introduced in this update. Download PhpStorm 2024.2 Log files support Laravel, Symfony, and WordPress log files can now be viewed directly in the IDE with proper highlighting of dates, times, events (by severity level), and hyperlinks. The same functionality is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/08/phpstorm-2024-2-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a Swagger UI using a .NET 9 Json OpenAPI file</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 05:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to implement a Swagger UI using a .NET 9 produced OpenAPI file. The Swagger UI is deployed to a secure or development environment and is not deployed to a public production target. Sometimes, it is required to deploy the Swagger UI to a development deployment target and not the test or […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/08/12/add-a-swagger-ui-using-a-net-9-json-openapi-file/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run a Large Language Model(LLM) Like ChatGPT Locally With C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 05:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are quickly entering the era of AI in Tech and software development. AIs are no longer relegated to research labs. More recently, we have gained access to using AI on the web and even on our personal devices. Now, we can run AIs locally on our personal computers. This article will explore how we […] The post Run a Large Language Model(LLM) Like ChatGPT Locally With C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
