<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:49:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock now supports advanced parsing, chunking, and query reformulation giving greater control of accuracy in RAG based applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that helps you implement the entire Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) workflow from ingestion to retrieval and prompt augmentation without having to build custom integrations to data sources and manage data flows, pushing the boundaries for what you can do in your RAG workflows. However, it’s […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-now-supports-advanced-parsing-chunking-and-query-reformulation-giving-greater-control-of-accuracy-in-rag-based-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Sourcing DXIL Validator Hash</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 21:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today the HLSL team is announcing plans to open source the DXIL validator hashing algorithm and include it in the DirectXShaderCompiler sources on GitHub. If you’re wondering what any of that means, strap in! DXIL Validator To understand the DXIL Validator you first need to understand a few basics of what DXIL is.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/open-sourcing-dxil-validator-hash 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline generative AI development in Amazon Bedrock with Prompt Management and Prompt Flows (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to introduce two powerful new features for Amazon Bedrock: Prompt Management and Prompt Flows, in public preview. These features are designed to accelerate the development, testing, and deployment of generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications, enabling developers and business users to create more efficient and effective solutions that are easier to maintain. You […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-generative-ai-development-in-amazon-bedrock-with-prompt-management-and-prompt-flows-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering everyone with GenAI to rapidly build, customize, and deploy apps securely: Highlights from the AWS New York Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine this—all employees relying on generative artificial intelligence (AI) to get their work done faster, every task becoming less mundane and more innovative, and every application providing a more useful, personal, and engaging experience. To realize this future, organizations need more than a single, powerful large language model (LLM) or chat assistant. They need a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/empowering-everyone-with-genai-to-rapidly-build-customize-and-deploy-apps-securely-highlights-from-the-aws-new-york-summit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A progress update on our commitment to safe, responsible generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Responsible AI is a longstanding commitment at Amazon. From the outset, we have prioritized responsible AI innovation by embedding safety, fairness, robustness, security, and privacy into our development processes and educating our employees. We strive to make our customers’ lives better while also establishing and implementing the necessary safeguards to help protect them. Our practical […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-progress-update-on-our-commitment-to-safe-responsible-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku in Amazon Bedrock to boost model accuracy and quality</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 15:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Frontier large language models (LLMs) like Anthropic Claude on Amazon Bedrock are trained on vast amounts of data, allowing Anthropic Claude to understand and generate human-like text. Fine-tuning Anthropic Claude 3 Haiku on proprietary datasets can provide optimal performance on specific domains or tasks. The fine-tuning as a deep level of customization represents a key […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-anthropics-claude-3-haiku-in-amazon-bedrock-to-boost-model-accuracy-and-quality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an already-completed asynchronous activity in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Making our function a coroutine.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240710-00/?p=109963 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try Full Line Code Completion in JetBrains Rider 2024.1.4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released the 2024.1 version of all our IDE products, including the dotUltimate family of products: ReSharper, Rider, dotMemory, dotTrace, dotCover, and dotPeek. Full Line Code Completion (FLCC), a local and fast AI model fine-tuned for product-specific programming languages, is one feature you may have heard of in this release. FLCC was released with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/10/full-line-code-completion-in-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Coverage in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 10:00:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post delves into the current .NET landscape when we aim to collect Code Coverage. We examine the most frequently used tools such as Coverlet, dotCover, and dotnet-coverage, among others. We discuss how to upload a Code Coverage report to a SaaS product like SonarQube. Lastly, we explain how to publish a Code Coverage report into an Azure Pipeline run or a GitHub Action.
Link to article: https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/code-coverage-in-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Microservices to Modular Monoliths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What do you do when you find yourself in microservice hell? How do you keep the gains you (hopefully) made in breaking up your legacy ball…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/from-microservices-to-modular-monoliths/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve up to ~2x higher throughput while reducing costs by up to ~50% for generative AI inference on Amazon SageMaker with the new inference optimization toolkit – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 21:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative artificial intelligence (AI) inference becomes increasingly critical for businesses, customers are seeking ways to scale their generative AI operations or integrate generative AI models into existing workflows. Model optimization has emerged as a crucial step, allowing organizations to balance cost-effectiveness and responsiveness, improving productivity. However, price-performance requirements vary widely across use cases. For […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-up-to-2x-higher-throughput-while-reducing-costs-by-up-to-50-for-generative-ai-inference-on-amazon-sagemaker-with-the-new-inference-optimization-toolkit-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve up to ~2x higher throughput while reducing costs by ~50% for generative AI inference on Amazon SageMaker with the new inference optimization toolkit – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 21:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, Amazon SageMaker announced a new inference optimization toolkit that helps you reduce the time it takes to optimize generative artificial intelligence (AI) models from months to hours, to achieve best-in-class performance for your use case. With this new capability, you can choose from a menu of optimization techniques, apply them to your generative AI […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-up-to-2x-higher-throughput-while-reducing-costs-by-50-for-generative-ai-inference-on-amazon-sagemaker-with-the-new-inference-optimization-toolkit-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet ranks number 1 for business and finance in S&amp;P AI Benchmarks by Kensho</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet currently ranks at the top of S&amp;amp;P AI Benchmarks by Kensho, which assesses large language models (LLMs) for finance and business. Kensho is the AI Innovation Hub for S&amp;amp;P Global. Using Amazon Bedrock, Kensho was able to quickly run Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet through a challenging suite of business and financial […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/anthropic-claude-3-5-sonnet-ranks-number-1-for-business-and-finance-in-sp-ai-benchmarks-by-kensho/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 RTW now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we released Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 RTW. This is our final release of Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 and will be the new supported version for the Azure DevOps Server 2022 server listing. You can directly install Azure DevOps Server 2022 Update 2 or upgrade from any version of Azure DevOps or TFS,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-server-2022-2-rtw-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 13: Explore the latest preview features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# 13 focuses on flexibility and performance, with top features like params collections for added flexibility, lock object for improved performance, and partial properties to support generators.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/csharp-13-explore-preview-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework July 2024 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for July 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-july-2024-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – July 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The July 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include a new tool for more performant environment discovery, improved support for reStructuredText docstrings, and community contributed Pixi support. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-july-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q2 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Flexible trial periods for paid plugins You can now customize trial periods for your paid plugins or simply disable them. Instead of the default 30-day trial, you can now set a shorter trial period or even none at all. Just select the preferred trial period while uploading your plugin to the Marketplace […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q2-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Column Selection DSL in Kotlin DataFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The Kotlin DataFrame library makes extracting values from structured data an easy task. As discussed in our documentation, there are four separate APIs that can be used for this purpose, with the optimal choice depending on your individual situation and requirements. To demonstrate, let’s read in a JSON document containing information about users: The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/07/enhanced-column-selection-dsl-in-kotlin-dataframe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an already-completed asynchonous activity in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The simplest version.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240709-00/?p=109961 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip User Experience Survey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, DataGrip community! At JetBrains, delivering an excellent user experience is always a top priority. Today, we’re launching a survey to gather your feedback and explore how we can make DataGrip even better. Please take a few minutes to complete the DataGrip User Experience Survey. Your input will help us prioritize future improvements. As a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/07/09/datagrip-user-experience-survey/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in July</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This July, we’ve made some improvements to our courses to better serve your learning needs, added certificates for two more courses, and introduced new learning topics. Let’s take a closer look at these updates. Updated courses Our courses have been restructured to align with the latest job requirements. We’ve incorporated real interview questions and regularly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/09/jetbrains-academy-new-in-july/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding support for collection expressions to your own types: Behind the scenes of collection expressions - Part 5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this final post of the series I show how to add support for collection expressions to your own types that don&#39;t support them automatically
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/behind-the-scenes-of-collection-expressions-part-5-adding-support-for-collection-expressions-to-your-own-types/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open AI Whisper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 07:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Monu Bambroo explores Whisper, a speech to text model from OpenAI that you can use to transcribe audio files. The model is trained on a large dataset of English audio and text. The model is optimized for transcribing audio files that contain speech in English.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/open-ai-whisper 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Entity Framework Core Performance with Complex Types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 01:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, let’s explore what Complex Types are in Entity Framework Core and how we can use them to improve the performance of our .NET applications. Without further ado, let’s get started. What Are Complex Types in EF Core? To begin, let’s first understand what complex types are and why they were added to […] The post Improve Entity Framework Core Performance with Complex Types appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeding in-memory Entity Framework with realistic data with Bogus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You don’t need a physical database to experiment with ORMs. You can use an in-memory DB and seed the database with realistic data generated with Bogus.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/seed-inmemory-entityframework-bogus/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weather Company enhances MLOps with Amazon SageMaker, AWS CloudFormation, and Amazon CloudWatch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 19:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share the story of how The Weather Company (TWCo) enhanced its MLOps platform using services such as Amazon SageMaker, AWS CloudFormation, and Amazon CloudWatch. TWCo data scientists and ML engineers took advantage of automation, detailed experiment tracking, integrated training, and deployment pipelines to help scale MLOps effectively. TWCo reduced infrastructure management time by 90% while also reducing model deployment time by 20%.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-weather-company-enhances-mlops-with-amazon-sagemaker-aws-cloudformation-and-amazon-cloudwatch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eviden scales AWS DeepRacer Global League using AWS DeepRacer Event Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 18:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Eviden is a next-gen technology leader in data-driven, trusted, and sustainable digital transformation. With a strong portfolio of patented technologies and worldwide leading positions in advanced computing, security, AI, cloud, and digital platforms, Eviden provides deep expertise for a multitude of industries in more than 47 countries. Eviden is an AWS Premier partner, bringing together […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/eviden-scales-aws-deepracer-global-league-using-aws-deepracer-event-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate unique images by fine-tuning Stable Diffusion XL with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 18:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stable Diffusion XL by Stability AI is a high-quality text-to-image deep learning model that allows you to generate professional-looking images in various styles. Managed versions of Stable Diffusion XL are already available to you on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart (see Use Stable Diffusion XL with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart in Amazon SageMaker Studio) and Amazon Bedrock (see […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-unique-images-by-fine-tuning-stable-diffusion-xl-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Round Trips are Evil</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 18:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Houston gets drenched by Hurricane Beryl as I write this, I’m reminded of a formative set of continuing education courses I took when I was living in Houston in the late 90’s and plotting my formal move into software development. Whatever we learned about VB6 in those MSDN classes is long, long since obsolete, … Continue reading Network Round Trips are Evil →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/07/08/network-round-trips-are-evil/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wayland Support Preview In 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 15:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are delighted to announce that, starting with the 2024.2 Early Access Program (EAP), IntelliJ-based IDEs will offer preliminary support for the Wayland display server protocol on Linux, including Windows Subsystem for Linux a.k.a. WSLg. How To Opt In On Linux, IntelliJ-based IDEs were using exclusively the X11 protocol and an X server to show […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/wayland-support-preview-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New UI Becomes the Default in 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 14:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that we will enable the new UI for all JetBrains IDE users in the upcoming 2024.2 version. We designed the new UI to reduce visual clutter, ensuring easy access to essential features while gradually revealing more advanced functionality as needed. The new UI is clean and modern, providing bigger, easier-to-use […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/07/08/the-new-ui-becomes-the-default-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the point of std::monostate? You can’t do anything with it!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not doing anything with it is exactly the point.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240708-00/?p=109959 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2024: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 13:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An overview of the latest updates in Microsoft Entra for Jul 2024. Discover how these new capabilities can be integrated into your projects for optimal performance and security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-jul-24 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 EAP 5: Zephyr West Support and Full Line Code Completion for C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 13:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.2 EAP 5 build (242.19890.26) is now out! It’s available from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 EAP Zephyr West support In this EAP build, we introduce a new project model supported by CLion – it’s called the West project model. As we previously mentioned […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/07/2024-2-eap-5-zephyr-west-support-full-line-code-completion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy to Elastic Beanstalk with GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 11:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Elastic Beanstalk makes deploying, managing, and scaling .NET web applications on Amazon Web Services easy. This powerful service is available to anyone developing or hosting .NET apps on IIS. In this post, I’ll demonstrate how to set up a continuous deployment pipeline to Elastic Beanstalk directly from GitHub using GitHub Actions. With just a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/deploy-to-elastic-beanstalk-environment-with-github-actions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystify history with GitHub Copilot commit explanations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 07:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever struggled to understand what a commit was doing or why it was made? Do you wish you had more clarity and context when reviewing or collaborating on code changes? If you answered yes, then you’ll love what GitHub Copilot can do for you: generate commit explanations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/demystify-history-with-github-copilot-commit-explanations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find All the Positions of a Substring in Another String in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 05:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to learn how to find all the positions of a substring in another string. So we are trying to find, for example, all the occurrences of the word ‘the’ in a sentence: “Some consider the occurrences to be the unconscious mind’s attempts to communicate to the conscious mind.” Searching Substrings to Find All the Positions […] The post How to Find All the Positions of a Substring in Another String in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Strong Foundations: The Crucial Role of Data in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2024/07_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2024/07_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Creating beloved software demands collective effort from various teams. Data plays a pivotal role, analogous to a building&#39;s foundation. Neglecting the data infrastructure can lead to persistent issues and eventual failure. Companies should prioritize specialized data professionals and seamless collaboration to ensure software longevity. Siloed teams hamper progress, prompting engineers and customers to flee.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/07/07/building-strong-foundations-the-crucial-role-of-data-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding long-running HTTP API requests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 15:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How do you handle long-running HTTP requests that take long to complete? For example, how would you design an HTTP API that needs to generate a transcript for a specific video (by ID)? Deeper into that question, you can assume that won’t be a fast request/response, so how can we better manage this? Using asynchronous… Read More »Avoiding long-running HTTP API requests The post Avoiding long-running HTTP API requests appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build vs Buy: The Age-old Dev Debate – Dev Leader Weekly 51</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Build vs Buy: The Age-old Dev Debate – Dev Leader Weekly 51 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss different scenarios where I built my own vs when companies decide to build vs buy. The post Build vs Buy: The Age-old Dev Debate – Dev Leader Weekly 51 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/07/06/build-vs-buy-the-age-old-dev-debate-dev-leader-weekly-51/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Discovery in Microservices With .NET and Consul</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Service discovery is a pattern that allows developers to use logical names to refer to external services, instead of physical IP addresses and ports. In this week&#39;s issue, we&#39;ll see how to implement service discovery in your .NET microservices with Consul.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/service-discovery-in-microservices-with-net-and-consul 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the June edition of PHP Annotated! We’ll recap the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, featuring handpicked news, articles, tools, and videos. Highlights PHP 8.1.29, PHP 8.2.20, and PHP 8.3.8 released ❗️These security updates fix CVE-2024-4577, CVE-2024-5458, CVE-2024-5585, and vulnerability in openssl_private_decrypt() function known as the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/07/php-annotated-june-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Turbo in your Rails apps with RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 14:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! The RubyMine team is constantly striving to provide support for new technologies for Ruby and Rails. One of the most exciting recent additions to Rails is undoubtedly Hotwire, so we’ve prepared an overview of this suite of frameworks and a tutorial on how to use the most important Turbo and Stimulus features in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/07/how-to-use-turbo-in-your-rails-apps-with-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I produce a Windows Runtime asynchronous activity from C&#43;&#43;/WinRT?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Somebody that deals with them natively.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240705-00/?p=109957 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Data Science Platform Downtime – neXDos Says It’s Real With Datalore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JupyterHub Hosting Hurdles neXDos heavily relies on diverse data sources – from stock market APIs to in-house PostgreSQL data – to inform their bespoke investment strategies. Previously, neXDos prototyped, backtested, and future-proofed their trading algorithms by hosting JupyterLab and JupyterHub. But this approach was problematic due to complexity in many areas, including managing the server […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/05/zero-data-science-platform-downtime-nexdos-says-it-s-real-with-datalore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Per-Minute macOS Sonoma M2 Agents in TeamCity Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 08:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently introduced per-minute macOS agents in TeamCity Cloud. Now, we’re switching the macOS agents to macOS Sonoma M2, offering you more power efficiency and greater performance when running your builds on TeamCity. We’re offering a 50% discount on the new per-minute macOS build agents in TeamCity Cloud until January 1, 2025. Enjoy the power […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/07/macos-sonoma-agents-teamcity-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Fear to Triumph: My 30-Year Journey in Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This content chronicles my 30-year journey in public speaking, from an unexpected start to embracing challenges and speaking at major conferences. Overcoming fears, I found career success and enriched personal connections. I encourage aspiring speakers to refine their craft and seize opportunities for growth and impact in both professional and personal spheres.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/07/05/from-fear-to-triumph-my-30-year-journey-in-public-speaking/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot Studio – Prompt Response Times</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tahir Naveed walks through how to measure prompt response times with Microsoft Copilot Studio and explores considerations that factor into the overall performance of these requests. Building custom copilots (GenAI chatbots) in Microsoft Copilot Studio is amazing. Especially with the new functionalities which were released in Microsoft Build 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/copilot-studio-prompt-response-times 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – July 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the July edition of Java Annotated Monthly! We’re excited to feature insights from the ever-brilliant Trisha Gee, who’s been busy curating some top-class content over the past month. This edition is packed with Java news and tips, including a spotlight on the upcoming Java 23. You’ll also find articles on Kotlin, Spring, AI, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/java-annotated-monthly-july-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure IoT Operations Data Processor Pipelines: Unlocking Efficiency in the Industrial Metaverse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we explore the implementation of Azure IoT Operations Data Processor pipelines in a manufacturing context, focusing on data processing at the edge.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/aio-data-processor-pipelines-unlocking-efficiency-industrial-metaverse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | July 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 06:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The BinaryFormatter class was traditionally used in .NET for serializing and deserializing objects into a binary format. However, it has been deprecated in 2020 due to serious security vulnerabilities that can allow for remote code execution when deserializing untrusted data. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/05/dotinsights-july-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I produce a Windows Runtime asynchronous activity from C#?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AsyncInfo helper class converts Tasks to Windows Runtime asynchronous activities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240704-00/?p=109955 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polars vs. pandas: What’s the Difference?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 13:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve been keeping up with the advances in Python dataframes in the past year, you couldn’t help hearing about Polars, the powerful dataframe library designed for working with large datasets. Unlike other libraries for working with large datasets, such as Spark, Dask, and Ray, Polars is designed to be used on a single machine, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/07/polars-vs-pandas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science with GenAI is Revolutionizing Investment Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 09:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is the formula for success in the investment management industry? Behind every successful firm is a unique combination of domain expertise, cutting-edge technology, relationship management, rapid adaptability, and competition. While data science driven by generative AI (genAI) cannot turn your employees into domain experts overnight, nor can it single-handedly eliminate the competition, it can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/04/data-science-with-genai-is-revolutionizing-investment-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read appsettings.json in a .NET Console Application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 06:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to read appsettings.json in a .NET console application. Explanation Of appsettings.json The appsettings.json file in .NET applications serves as a centralized repository for configuration settings, utilizing the JSON format for its simplicity and readability. It includes various hierarchically organized sections, such as logging levels, connection strings, and custom application […] The post How to Read appsettings.json in a .NET Console Application appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: preezie’s AI Journey with Microsoft Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re thrilled to feature the preezie team on the Semantic Kernel blog. The preezie team will discuss their AI journey, how they’ve integrated the Semantic Kernel SDK to build out their AI solutions and advice they’d give to other customers getting started on their AI journeys.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-prezzies-ai-journey-with-microsoft-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
