<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 13:07:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing SharePoint Framework 1.19 with updates on building enterprise extensibility within Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 13:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce a new public version of the SharePoint Framework, v1.19, with new features, capabilities and fixes for Microsoft Viva, Microsoft Teams and SharePoint.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-sharepoint-framework-1-19-with-updates-on-building-enterprise-extensibility-within-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Lightroom: Issues with Most Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article outlines the author&#39;s frustration with Adobe Lightroom Classic updates, citing issues like lost edits and export failures due to catalog format changes. They urge for better testing, maintenance of user setups, and swift bug resolution. Specific grievances include vanished settings, performance decline, and incompatibility with MacMini systems. The author emphasizes the need for Adobe to prioritize user experience to retain subscribers.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/01/adobe-lightroom-issues-with-most-updates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance Tip: Optimizing Enum Value Name Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article delves into the optimization of Enum value name retrieval in .NET, comparing three approaches. It demonstrates that one of these methods is 16.13 times more efficient, with no memory allocation.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/01/general-performance-tip-optimizing-enum-value-name-retrieval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Type &amp; Structure Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 20:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These articles delve into strategies for optimizing the performance of your reference types and structures, also known as user-defined types. Both exhibit distinct behaviors, given that reference types are instantiated on the memory heap, overseen by the Garbage Collector, while structures are created on the memory stack, offering potentially superior performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/30/reference-type-structure-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance customer service efficiency with AI-powered summarization using Amazon Transcribe Call Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 19:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the fast-paced world of customer service, efficiency and accuracy are paramount. After each call, contact center agents often spend up to a third of the total call time summarizing the customer conversation. Additionally, manual summarization can lead to inconsistencies in the style and level of detail due to varying interpretations of note-taking guidelines. This […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-customer-service-efficiency-with-ai-powered-summarization-using-amazon-transcribe-call-analytics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AIChatUI: Open Source AI Chat Sample with Azure OpenAI Service &amp; GPT-3 / GPT-4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 17:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since I’ve been working with Azure OpenAI Service from a developer perspective as well, I’ve decided to build a sample application to help demonstrate not just the IaC deployment of Azure OpenAI Service and GPT models, but also to demonstrate some basic use cases of integrating AI into your own enterprise applications. Here’s a screenshot […] The article Introducing AIChatUI: Open Source AI Chat Sample with Azure OpenAI Service &amp;amp; GPT-3 / GPT-4 appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure your container build and publish with .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 8 has new security features for containers, including non-root images and SDK tools. Discover how to create non-root container images, configure Kubernetes pods, and inspect images and containers for enhanced security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/secure-your-container-build-and-publish-with-dotnet-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the hype: Part 1, How trustworthy AI empowers US Government agencies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models’ (LLM) ability to transform mission workflows for US Government agencies is revolutionary and adoption is now starting to accelerate. As agencies begin to leverage LLMs, they unlock capabilities that promise to streamline processes and drive innovation forward. It also means that there’s more to be done in the near term to support the deployment of LLM applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/trustworthy-ai-empowers-us-gov-agencies-part1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2024 is Now Live!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++, our free one-day virtual conference for the whole C++ community, is now live! Check it out on YouTube: The sessions are: Automated Testing of Shader Code with Keith Stockdale (Rare) – 15:00 UTC Message Handling with Boolean Implication with Ben Deane (Intel) –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-cpp-2024-is-now-live 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Build – Community Testimonial Videos</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, Microsoft Build is approaching and will occur from May 21st-23rd, 2024. During our Semantic Kernel session – Bridge the chasm between your ML and app devs with Semantic Kernel, we are looking to feature videos from community members like yourself sharing what you like about Semantic Kernel!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/microsoft-build-community-testimonial-videos 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker and JFrog partner to further secure Docker Hub and remove millions of imageless repos with malicious links</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker and JFrog partner further secure Docker Hub by removing millions of imageless repos with malicious links.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-jfrog-partner-to-further-secure-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles with a timeout, part 1: Starting with two</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s see by seeing if we can do it with just two.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240430-00/?p=109710 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate software development and leverage your business data with generative AI assistance from Amazon Q</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 12:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We believe generative artificial intelligence (AI) has the potential to transform virtually every customer experience. To make this possible, we’re rapidly innovating to provide the most comprehensive set of capabilities across the three layers of the generative AI stack. This includes the bottom layer with infrastructure to train Large Language Models (LLMs) and other Foundation […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-software-development-and-leverage-your-business-data-with-generative-ai-assistance-from-amazon-q/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Q Business and Amazon Q in QuickSight empowers employees to be more data-driven and make better, faster decisions using company knowledge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 12:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we announced the General Availability of Amazon Q, the most capable generative AI powered assistant for accelerating software development and leveraging companies’ internal data. “During the preview, early indications signaled Amazon Q could help our customers’ employees become more than 80% more productive at their jobs; and with the new features we’re planning on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-q-business-and-amazon-q-in-quicksight-empowers-employees-to-be-more-data-driven-and-make-better-faster-decisions-using-company-knowledge/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Commit and Push Changes Back to Repository</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 11:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Actions are great at enabling you to automate workflows directly from within a GitHub repository. The workflows are stored in a YAML definition file located within the .github/workflows directory within the repository. GitHub Actions can be used to configure workflows that can perform a variety of actions to perform build and release steps. On […] The article GitHub Actions: Commit and Push Changes Back to Repository appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a .NET AsciiMath parser and using it in a Markdig extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how I ported a Ruby AsciiMath implementation to .NET, created the AsciiMath NuGet package, and used it to create a Markdig extension
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-dotnet-asciimath-parser-and-using-it-in-a-markdig-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Optimizing Span Operations – Clear vs. Fill</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article compares two key search methods in dictionaries: using Contains() on the Keys collection and ContainsKey() method directly on the dictionary. It demonstrates examples for both approaches, highlighting Microsoft&#39;s recommendation of using ContainsKey(). The article suggests further examination of the performance aspect of these methods.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/30/code-it-any-way-you-want-optimizing-span-operations-clear-vs-fill-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSTest SDK：.NET 8的测试配置与灵活性新篇</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 07:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Marco Rossignoli 和Amaury Levé 的Introducing MSTest SDK – Improved Configuration &amp;amp; Flexibility。 我们很高兴地宣布，基于 MSBuild Project SDK 系统构建的全新 MSTest SDK已推出。它旨在通过合理的默认值和灵活的选项使项目配置更加容易，从而为您提供更好的 MSTest 测试体验。 这种新体验是建立在最近推出的 MSTest 运行程序的基础上（请查看公告）https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-ms-test-runner/，以进一步提高您的体验。 这个新的运行程序是一种轻量级、可靠且高性能的运行 MSTest 测试的方式，作为 MSTest.TestAdapter NuGet 包的依赖项发布。该运行器及其扩展由多个 NuGet 包组成，以提供可扩展、灵活且可配置的测试运行体验。然而，可定制性可能会导致许多问题：推荐的扩展是什么？正确的默认值是什么？如何对齐版本？ 这就是 MSTest SDK 的用武之地。 MSTest SDK 入门 开始使用新的 MSTest SDK 非常简单。 只需创建一个 MSTest 项目（或更新现有的 MSTest 项目）并将 .csproj 文件的内容替换为以下内容： Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/mstest-sdk%ef%bc%9a-net-8%e7%9a%84%e6%b5%8b%e8%af%95%e9%85%8d%e7%bd%ae%e4%b8%8e%e7%81%b5%e6%b4%bb%e6%80%a7%e6%96%b0%e7%af%87 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>使用 .NET 为 Microsoft AI 构建可扩展网关</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 02:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Kara Saucerman的Building a scalable gateway with .NET for Microsoft AI – .NET Blog Microsoft AI 团队构建了全面的内容、服务、平台和技术，以便消费者在任何设备上、任何地方获取他们想要的信息，并为企业改善客户和员工的体验。我们的团队支持多种体验，包括 Bing、Copilot、广告、地图和 Edge，并通过 Edge 新标签页、Windows 10 和 11 等入口点呈现，这些入口点每月有超过 10 亿活跃用户。我们意识到需要一个高性能且可靠的网关作为 Microsoft AI 的前端和入口层。这将使多个团队能够利用我们开发的通用功能来帮助运营业务并专注于客户体验和功能。在本文中，我们将介绍在 .NET 8 上借助 YARP 构建网关（代号为 CETO）的过程。 反向代理 在开始编写 CETO 之前，我们必须决定使用反向代理。 我们应该使用外部的还是尝试自己制作？ 这些外部的能涵盖我们所有的用例吗？ 我们还必须考虑定制这些代理的高成本和持续维护。 我们的需求包括支持 HTTP/2、HTTP/3、WebSocket 等流协议、简单的可扩展性等等。 当我们开始了解 Microsoft 其他内部团队正在做的事情时，我们遇到了 YARP 项目。 YARP 代表：“又一个反向代理”。 该项目使用 ASP.NET 和 .NET（.NET 6 及更高版本）提供一个灵活的解决方案，可以通过 .NET 代码进行修改。这有多方便呢？ 事实证明这正是我们所需要的。 Bing 运行着世界上最大、高性能且可靠的 .NET 应用程序之一。 我们依赖于与 .NET 团队的密切合作关系，并且是每个 .NET 版本的早期采用者。 通过尝试并升级到每个新版本，我们可以向 .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filters in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 19:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s important to understand how the application behaves and have the ability to override that behavior in runtime based on some conditions. For example, we don’t want to send malicious prompt to LLM, and we don’t want to expose more information than needed to the end users.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/filters-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and train large models cost-efficiently with Metaflow and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 19:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-authored with Ville Tuulos (Co-founder and CEO) and Eddie Mattia (Data Scientist) of Outerbounds. To build a production-grade AI system today (for example, to do multilingual sentiment analysis of customer support conversations), what are the primary technical challenges? Historically, natural language processing (NLP) would be a primary research and development […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/develop-and-train-large-models-cost-efficiently-with-metaflow-and-aws-trainium/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to Accessible Apps: Keyboard Accessibility and .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are your apps keyboard accessible? Learn more about keyboard traps and find out how you can ensure your .NET MAUI apps are keyboard accessible.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/the-journey-to-accessible-apps-keyboard-accessible 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Managed RunCommand Artifacts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 18:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As most of you may know from the current Managed RunCommand documentation there are multiple ways your script may be specified. Through the Script parameter. You can inline your entire script in this manner, though we don’t recommend the practice if your script contains confidential information.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/introducing-managed-runcommand-artifacts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Command R and R&#43; are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 17:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is co-written with Pradeep Prabhakaran from Cohere. Today, we are excited to announce that Cohere Command R and R+ foundation models are available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. Command R/R+ are the state-of-the-art retrieval augmented generation (RAG)-optimized models designed to tackle enterprise-grade workloads. In this post, we walk through how […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cohere-command-r-and-r-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting secrets locally</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Keeping security folks happy (or less upset which is the best we can hope for)
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell-community/encrypting-secrets-locally 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing large language model training with Arcee and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post by Mark McQuade, Malikeh Ehghaghi, and Shamane Siri from Arcee. In recent years, large language models (LLMs) have gained attention for their effectiveness, leading various industries to adapt general LLMs to their data for improved results, making efficient training and hardware availability crucial. At Arcee, we focus primarily on enhancing […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-large-language-model-training-with-arcee-and-aws-trainium/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the April edition of PHP Annotated! We’ll recap the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, featuring handpicked news, articles, tools, and videos. Highlights PHP statement on glibc/iconv vulnerability The hype around CVE-2024-2961 in relation to PHP was extremely exaggerated. Many people were under the impression that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/04/php-annotated-april-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2024 is Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++ is our free one-day virtual conference for the whole C++ community. This year it will run on April 30th 15:00 UTC. Sign-up for free to get access to our five sessions on the day. The sessions are: Automated Testing of Shader Code with Keith Stockdale (Rare) –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-c-2024-is-tomorrow 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s easier thank you think.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240429-00/?p=109707 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phi-3: Microsoft Redefines Small Language Models (SLMs)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the area of artificial intelligence (AI), the quest for smaller yet powerful language models has been an ongoing pursuit. Microsoft has taken a significant leap forward with the introduction of Phi-3. These new models promise to redefine the landscape of Small Language Models (SLMs), offering unparalleled capabilities and cost-effectiveness. Phi-3 Unveiled Phi-3 emerges as […] The article Phi-3: Microsoft Redefines Small Language Models (SLMs) appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anything Session With the JetBrains Academy Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’d like to invite you to our very first free Ask Me Anything session on Discord with JetBrains Academy! Send us any questions you may have about JetBrains Academy courses, how to start a career in IT, teaching opportunities, our offline programs, or any other topic you’re interested in. We’ll kick off the chatting session […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/04/29/ask-me-anything-session-with-the-jetbrains-academy-team/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break into Big Tech – My Journey from Startup to Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Break into Big Tech – My Journey from Startup to Microsoft appeared first on Dev Leader.This article is a high-level view of my career journey going from startups to Big Tech -- landing a principal software engineering manager role at Microsoft. The post Break into Big Tech – My Journey from Startup to Microsoft appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/29/break-into-big-tech-my-journey-from-startup-to-microsoft/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Detecting Items in a ConcurrentBag&lt;&gt;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The comparison between using the Count property and the IsEmpty() method in a ConcurrentBag reveals that IsEmpty() is 2.95 times more efficient based on benchmark results. This indicates a significant performance advantage for utilizing IsEmpty().
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/29/collection-performance-detecting-items-in-a-concurrentbag/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.17 includes integration with Azure API Center</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 07:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to share the launch of Dev Proxy v0.17 to help you to build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-17-includes-integration-with-azure-api-center 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Cloud Engineer and How to Become one?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It was once a new concept that enterprises were trying to make sense of, but the term “cloud” has really become ubiquitous across the IT landscape. No matter the industry, your organization is likely depending on some cloud services; from Microsoft Azure, AWS, Microsoft 365, Slack, Teams, GitHub, to so many other services. Behind the […] The article What is a Cloud Engineer and How to Become one? appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Kafka in an ASP.NET Core Web API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 05:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At its core, Kafka is a distributed streaming platform designed to handle large volumes of data in real-time. Its exceptional performance, fault tolerance, and scalability make it a pivotal component in event-driven architectures. In this article, we’ll learn how to integrate Kafka with an ASP.NET Core Web API using a custom Docker Compose setup and […] The post Using Kafka in an ASP.NET Core Web API appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenTofu: Open Source Alternative to Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of cloud, hybrid, and on-premises Infrastructure as Code (IaC), where managing and provisioning infrastructure through code has become indispensable, tools like OpenTofu play a pivotal role. The evolutions of IaC tools continues with OpenTofu, as a fork of Terraform that offers a more open-source, community-driven alternative that is managed by the Linux […] The article OpenTofu: Open Source Alternative to Terraform appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Math Do You Need To Program? – Dev Leader Weekly 41</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How Much Math Do You Need To Program? – Dev Leader Weekly 41 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I answer the question of how much math do you need to program -- with help from Twitter. The post How Much Math Do You Need To Program? – Dev Leader Weekly 41 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 05:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about Server-Sent Events in ASP.NET Core. We will see what they are, their features, advantages, and implementation. So, let’s start. What Are Server-Sent Events The Server-Sent Events (SSE) protocol allows servers to send real-time, event-driven updates to clients over an HTTP connection without the client requesting these updates. It […] The post Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Response Messaging Pattern With MassTransit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building distributed systems with .NET, direct calls between services can create tight coupling. The request-response messaging pattern can allow distributed services to communicate in a loosely coupled way.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/request-response-messaging-pattern-with-masstransit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databricks DBRX is now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 19:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the DBRX model, an open, general-purpose large language model (LLM) developed by Databricks, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy with one click for running inference. The DBRX LLM employs a fine-grained mixture-of-experts (MoE) architecture, pre-trained on 12 trillion tokens of carefully curated data and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/databricks-dbrx-is-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases in Amazon Bedrock now simplifies asking questions on a single document</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 19:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At AWS re:Invent 2023, we announced the general availability of Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock. With Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, you can securely connect foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock to your company data for fully managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). In previous posts, we covered new capabilities like hybrid search support, metadata filtering […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/knowledge-bases-in-amazon-bedrock-now-simplifies-asking-questions-on-a-single-document/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OData .NET 8 Preview Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We would like to announce that we are planning a new major release of OData .NET core libraries in June. Ahead of this release, we have released preview versions of the libraries to get some early feedback from the community. Specifically,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/odata-net-8-preview-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability Improvements in the Visual Studio Connection Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Visual Studio 2022 17.10 Preview 2, we’ve introduced some UX updates and usability improvements to the Connection Manager. With these updates we provide a more seamless experience when connecting to remote systems and/or debugging failed connections. Please install the latest Preview to try it out.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/usability-improvements-in-the-visual-studio-connection-manager 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking changes to Microsoft Graph presence and online meeting basic change notifications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The change removes data about the changed resource from the notifications and applies the established pattern for change notifications to presence and online meeting resources.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/breaking-changes-to-microsoft-graph-presence-and-online-meeting-basic-change-notifications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Dev Experience with Serverless Rust in RustRover</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 14:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Serverless computing and the Rust programming language together offer a promising path for developers to build efficient and scalable applications without the traditional barriers of infrastructure management. In our latest livestream session with James Eastham, a senior cloud architect at AWS, we explored the synergies between Rust and serverless architecture, particularly focusing on AWS Lambda. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/04/26/boosting-dev-experience-with-serverless-rust-in-rustrover/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Comparing the two algorithms.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240426-00/?p=109705 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.1.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WebStorm 2024.1.2, the second update for WebStorm 2024.1, is now available! It contains improvements for Angular and adds ESLint 9 support. You can update to v2024.1.2 by using the Toolbox App, installing it right from the IDE, or downloading it from our website. Angular improvements This update introduces new support for Angular 17.2 syntax output() […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/04/webstorm-2024-1-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Modules using Git Branch as Source</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp Terraform empowers DevOps Engineers and SREs to manage cloud resources efficiently. One of its standout features is the Terraform Modules support, allowing users to organize and reuse infrastructure code effectively as reusable modules. While Terraform’s native module registry serves as a central hub for sharing modules, sometimes you may prefer hosting modules in your […] The article Terraform: Modules using Git Branch as Source appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2022.2.3 Is Ready for Download</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For MPS users still on version 2022.2, we’ve prepared another bug-fix release with several fixes and improvements. Check them out and see how they can make your life easier. DOWNLOAD MPS 2022.2.3 Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/04/mps-2022-2-2-has-been-released-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Spotlight on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Marketplace is a thriving ecosystem where developers can discover plugins that enhance their coding experience and implement and share their plugins with others. While many users find plugins through targeted searches, some may not be aware of tools and integrations that extend beyond programming to general productivity. To draw attention to this trove of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/04/plugin-spotlight-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #211</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 09:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #211 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Unit testing BlobServiceClient with Azure blobs and NSubstitute [blog.elmah.io] If you rely on Azure Blob in your projects, here’s an excellent article by Thomas Ardal that can help you understand it better and […] The post Code Maze Weekly #211 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Is LINQ Always the Most Performant Choice?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores the performance implications of using LINQ for collection queries, finding that a conventional foreach() loop outperforms LINQ by 1.75 times in identifying items matching a given query. The conclusion suggests benchmarking to determine the optimal approach based on the nature of the query and elements being sought.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/26/collection-performance-is-linq-always-the-most-performant-choice/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Containers Simplified</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post talks about the concept of development containers and how it can help us to solve the challenges we face when setting up our development environment or onboarding a new team member.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/dev-containers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Zip File in Memory In C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will look at how we create In-Memory Zip files in C#. Previously, we discussed how to create and read Zip files in .NET in our Working With Zip Files in C#/.NET article, so we recommend taking a look at that to familiarize yourself with working with Zip files. Let’s delve in. […] The post How to Create a Zip File in Memory In C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.5 Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the availability of TypeScript 5.5 Beta. To get started using the beta, you can get it through NuGet, or through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@beta Here’s a quick list of what’s new in TypeScript 5.5!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-5-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Semantic Kernel Hits 1,000,000 Downloads</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 20:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A million moments of innovation, a million instances of creative coding, a million downloads. Microsoft Semantic Kernel has proudly reached a significant milestone within the software development community. This achievement is not just a number—it’s a beacon of collective progress and the power of open-source collaboration.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/microsoft-semantic-kernel-hits-1000000-downloads 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio features for C&#43;&#43; Header Files and Modules</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 19:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the field of C++ programming, the management of header files and modules can often seem challenging. However, there are numerous tools and features available that can simplify this process, enhancing efficiency and reducing the likelihood of errors. Here’s a walkthrough for several tools that we provide for C++ headers and modules.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-features-for-c-header-files-and-modules 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.1.1 Bug-Fix Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.1.1 bug-fix update is here! The fixes included in this update are listed below. Download build 241.15989.121 from our website, through the Toolbox App, as a snap package for Ubuntu, or via a patch from inside the IDE. If you haven’t upgraded to v2024.1, now is a good time to do so. You […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/04/clion-2024-1-1-bug-fix-update/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new for .NET in Ubuntu 24.04</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ubuntu 24.04 is now available with .NET from day one in the official Ubuntu feeds! Thanks to the partnership between Canonical and Microsoft, you can start using .NET with Ubuntu 24.04 today!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/whats-new-for-dotnet-in-ubuntu-2404 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a Hugging Face (PyAnnote) speaker diarization model on Amazon SageMaker as an asynchronous endpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 17:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Speaker diarization, an essential process in audio analysis, segments an audio file based on speaker identity. This post delves into integrating Hugging Face’s PyAnnote for speaker diarization with Amazon SageMaker asynchronous endpoints. We provide a comprehensive guide on how to deploy speaker segmentation and clustering solutions using SageMaker on the AWS Cloud.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-a-hugging-face-pyannote-speaker-diarization-model-on-amazon-sagemaker-as-an-asynchronous-endpoint/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing API Manifest Plugins for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, Today we’re featuring a guest author from another team in Microsoft on our Semantic Kernel blog. We will turn it over to Mustafa Zengin to dive into Introducing API Manifest Plugins for Semantic Kernel. Semantic Kernel allows developers to import plugins from OpenAPI documents.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/introducing-api-manifest-plugins-for-semantic-kernel-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate the text summarization capabilities of LLMs for enhanced decision-making on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations across industries are using automatic text summarization to more efficiently handle vast amounts of information and make better decisions. In the financial sector, investment banks condense earnings reports down to key takeaways to rapidly analyze quarterly performance. Media companies use summarization to monitor news and social media so journalists can quickly write stories on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-the-text-summarization-capabilities-of-llms-for-enhanced-decision-making-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing IBM’s Acquisition of HashiCorp: A Game-Changer in Hybrid Cloud Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IBM has announced its acquisition of HashiCorp Inc., a leading multi-cloud infrastructure automation company, for $6.4 billion! This acquisition is poised to revolutionize the hybrid cloud landscape, offering enterprises a comprehensive end-to-end solution to navigate the complexities of today’s AI-driven application growth. Let’s look at the details of this cloud changing acquisition and its implications […] The article Analyzing IBM’s Acquisition of HashiCorp: A Game-Changer in Hybrid Cloud Management appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K2 Compiler Performance Benchmarks and How to Measure Them on Your Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 15:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the Kotlin 2.0.0 release drawing ever closer, the K2 compiler is now available for you to try! In this blog post, we explore the performance of the K2 compiler in various projects and give you the tools to collect your own performance statistics. The road to the Stable version of the K2 compiler has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/04/k2-compiler-performance-benchmarks-and-how-to-measure-them-on-your-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Going free-threaded.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240425-00/?p=109702 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: How are Data Sources used?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In HashiCorp Terraform, data sources serve as a bridge between the Terraform configuration and external systems or information. Essentially, data sources allow Terraform to query external resources, such as cloud platforms, APIs, databases, or other systems, and use the retrieved information within the configuration. Unlike resources, which represent infrastructure components to be managed by Terraform, […] The article Terraform: How are Data Sources used? appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Comparison of Passing Parameters in Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article explores different methods of passing parameters into methods, including conventional, in operator, and ref readonly approaches, comparing their performance. Despite differences in syntax, benchmark results demonstrate similar performance among these methods.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/25/code-it-any-way-you-want-comparison-of-passing-parameters-in-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Show the Generated SQL Query in EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 06:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core has many useful features, and in this article, we will see how to use it to show a generated SQL query. EF Core is an open source Object-relational mapper that supports several databases like SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and also LINQ (Language Integrated Query). One key benefit to developers is the ability to […] The post How to Show the Generated SQL Query in EF Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing .NET MAUI Community Tookit v8: TouchBehavior support is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET MAUI Community Toolkit version 8.0 has been released with the highly anticipated TouchBehavior on board!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-maui-community-toolkit-touchbehavior 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance conversational AI with advanced routing techniques with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Conversational artificial intelligence (AI) assistants are engineered to provide precise, real-time responses through intelligent routing of queries to the most suitable AI functions. With AWS generative AI services like Amazon Bedrock, developers can create systems that expertly manage and respond to user requests. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-conversational-ai-with-advanced-routing-techniques-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve LLM performance with human and AI feedback on Amazon SageMaker for Amazon Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Amazon EU Design and Construction (Amazon D&amp;amp;C) team is the engineering team designing and constructing Amazon warehouses. The team navigates a large volume of documents and locates the right information to make sure the warehouse design meets the highest standards. In the post A generative AI-powered solution on Amazon SageMaker to help Amazon EU […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-llm-performance-with-human-and-ai-feedback-on-amazon-sagemaker-for-amazon-engineering/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Step-by-Step Guide to Performing Data Analysis With Kotlin DataFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This is the first in a series of tutorials on how to easily manipulate and visualize your data using the Kotlin DataFrame and Kandy libraries. The tutorials are aimed at regular Kotlin developers, so no previous experience of data analysis or similar frameworks (like pandas or Apache Spark) is necessary. You should, however, be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/04/a-step-by-step-guide-to-performing-data-analysis-with-kotlin-dataframe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve accuracy of Amazon Rekognition Face Search with user vectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In various industries, such as financial services, telecommunications, and healthcare, customers use a digital identity process, which usually involves several steps to verify end-users during online onboarding or step-up authentication. An example of one step that can be used is face search, which can help determine whether a new end-user’s face matches those associated with […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-accuracy-of-amazon-rekognition-face-search-with-user-vectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Promising Methodology for Testing GenAI Applications in Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Testing applications that incorporate AI can be difficult. In this article, we share a promising new methodology for testing GenAI applications in Java.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/testing-genai-applications-in-java/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Debugging: How the Signal0ne Docker Extension Uses AI to Simplify Container Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started with Signal0ne, a Docker Desktop extension that scans Docker containers&#39; state and logs in search of problems, analyzes the discovered issues, and outputs insights to help developers debug.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/debug-containers-ai-signal0ne-docker-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, Testing is an integral part of the software development process. Unit testing allows to test your functionality in isolation. This usually means that instead of performing real work (e.g. sending HTTP request to LLM), it needs to be replaced with something that only simulates the work and return some predefined result,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/unit-testing-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using a change counter with coalescing.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240424-00/?p=109700 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Split main.tf into seperate files</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When using HashiCorp Terraform as the Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool of choice, it becomes critical to organize the Terraform code as the Terraform project becomes more complex. One of the most common practices is to split the Terraform project from a single file (typically named main.tf) into multiple smaller files. This helps increase maintainability […] The article Terraform: Split main.tf into seperate files appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seamless Production Deployment with Elastic Beanstalk</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Production deployments can be complicated. You want to avoid disruption to your users and minimize downtime, but you also need to consider cost, time, risk, and how to recover from a failed deployment. You can balance the trade-offs between these considerations by choosing a deployment strategy. AWS Elastic Beanstalk is a managed AWS compute […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/seamless-production-deployment-with-elastic-beanstalk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MudBlazor with Blazor SSR – What You Need To Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post MudBlazor with Blazor SSR – What You Need To Know appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how to use MudBlazor with Blazor SSR! Blazor&#39;s Server Side Rendering can be used alongside this awesome control library for building your next Blazor app! The post MudBlazor with Blazor SSR – What You Need To Know appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/24/mudblazor-with-blazor-ssr-what-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers save up to 8 hours per week with JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI seems to be popping up everywhere, so it’s no surprise that it has made its way into software development. Fortunately, it’s not here to take over, but to make our lives a whole lot easier and a bit more fun. JetBrains joined the AI race on December 6 after the official launch of AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/04/developers-save-up-to-8-hours-per-week-with-jetbrains-ai-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing identity: Exploring application types and authentication flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building on the foundations laid out in an earlier blog post on IAM basics, this blog post dives into the world of application types and authentication flows.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/app-types-and-auth-flows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance: Choosing Between GetValueOrDefault() and Coalesce Operator for Nullable Integers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In dealing with nullable integers and the need for default values, two common approaches are the coalesce operator (??) and GetValueOrDefault(). Alternatively, utilizing HasValue with the conditional operator is demonstrated.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/24/general-performance-choosing-between-getvalueordefault-and-coalesce-operator-for-nullable-integers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HSTS Header Implementation in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 04:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to learn how to implement the HSTS header in ASP.NET Core applications. So let’s get going. What Is HSTS HTTP Strict Transport Security (HSTS) is a web security mechanism that forces browsers to access a website using only secure HTTPS connections. When enabled, the browser automatically upgrades any HTTP […] The post HSTS Header Implementation in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to upload a file with Blazor SSR in .NET 8?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Blazor has built-in support for handling file uploads. If you’re using one of the interactive render modes (or .NET 7 or earlier) you can use the dedicated InputFile component and use that to get hold of a file from the user. You can then save that file somewhere (to disk, or the cloud). Here’s a basic example using Blazor Server. @page &amp;quot;/FileUpload/InteractiveServer&amp;quot; @rendermode InteractiveServer
@code { private async Task UploadFile(InputFileChangeEventArgs e) { var saveFolder = Path.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
