<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 18:14:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.03.3 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 18:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The major TeamCity 2025.07 update is just around the corner! But first, we’re rolling out another bug-fix release for the current version: TeamCity On-Premises 2025.03.3. Here’re some of the bugs resolved in this update: Bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements, so we recommend installing them promptly. See TeamCity 2025.03.3 Release Notes for the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/teamcity-2025-03-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: Local Containers, GitHub Copilot Agent Mode and Connection Groups</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 17:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code continues to evolve, bringing powerful new features that make SQL development more local, more organized, and more intelligent. In version v1.33.0, we’re introducing Local SQL Server container
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-containers-agent-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting summarization and action item extraction with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a benchmark of different understanding models from the Amazon Nova family available on Amazon Bedrock, to provide insights on how you can choose the best model for a meeting summarization task.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/meeting-summarization-and-action-item-extraction-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a custom text-to-SQL agent using Amazon Bedrock and Converse API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 16:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developing robust text-to-SQL capabilities is a critical challenge in the field of natural language processing (NLP) and database management. The complexity of NLP and database management increases in this field, particularly while dealing with complex queries and database structures. In this post, we introduce a straightforward but powerful solution with accompanying code to text-to-SQL using a custom agent implementation along with Amazon Bedrock and Converse API.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-custom-text-to-sql-agent-using-amazon-bedrock-and-converse-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate threat modeling with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 16:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how generative AI can revolutionize threat modeling practices by automating vulnerability identification, generating comprehensive attack scenarios, and providing contextual mitigation strategies.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-threat-modeling-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker State of App Dev: Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 15:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Security is a team sport: why everyone owns it now Six security takeaways from Docker’s 2025 State of Application Development Report. In the evolving world of software development, one thing is clear — security is no longer a siloed specialty. It’s a team sport, especially when vulnerabilities strike. That’s one of several key security findings...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-state-of-app-dev-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional reactions and ease of sharing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 15:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re always exploring ways to enhance DevBlogs for our readers. In the past few weeks, we’ve introduced two updates to features: reactions and sharing. Reactions: You now have six expressive reaction options to choose from—moving beyond the simple heart. It’s a small change that we hope makes a big difference in how you engage with p
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devblogs-news/additional-reactions-and-ease-of-sharing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Microsoft Desired State Configuration v3.1.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 14:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re pleased to announce the General Availability of Microsoft&#39;s Desired State Configuration (DSC) version 3.1.0. This release marks a significant milestone in our effort to deliver cloud-native configuration management for cross-platform environments. DSC is a declarative configuration and orchestration
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/announcing-dsc-v3-1-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You have to tell &lt;code&gt;Get-&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Set­Security­Info&lt;/code&gt; the object type, you can&#39;t make it guess</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was trying to read the security information from a process object, but their call to Get­Security­Info wasn&#39;t working. PACL dacl = nullptr; PSECURITY_DESCRIPTOR sd = nullptr; GetSecurityInfo(processHandle, SE_UNKNOWN_OBJECT_TYPE, DACL_SECURITY_INFORMATION, nullptr, // not interested in ow
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250618-00/?p=111281 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Docker Chose OCI Artifacts for AI Model Packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI development accelerates, developers need tools that let them move fast without having to reinvent their workflows. Docker Model Runner introduces a new specification for packaging large language models (LLMs) as OCI artifacts — a format developers already know and trust. It brings model sharing into the same workflows used for containers, with support...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-docker-chose-oci-artifacts-for-ai-model-packaging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes: How we designed Docker Model Runner and what’s next</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The last few years have made it clear that AI models will continue to be a fundamental component of many applications. The catch is that they’re also a fundamentally different type of component, with complex software and hardware requirements that don’t (yet) fit neatly into the constraints of container-oriented development lifecycles and architectures. To help...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/behind-the-scenes-how-we-designed-docker-model-runner-and-whats-next/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI-Ready Applications with Amazon Bedrock and .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s rapidly evolving technology landscape, Amazon Bedrock and .NET Aspire help in integrating AI capabilities into your applications. Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed service offering access to various Foundation Models (FMs), combined with .NET 9, creates a robust foundation for building such applications. .NET Aspire is an opinionated, cloud-ready stack for building observable, production-ready, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/building-ai-ready-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-and-net-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Developers on AI: Insights and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 12:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI tools continue to advance and become bigger parts of our lives, it is important to think critically about AI interactions. At JetBrains, the Developer Experience (DX) and Human-AI eXperience (HAX) study this, with a particular interest in enhancing these interactions in code-related tasks. In this post we will look at how our teams […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/06/software-developers-on-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for future AI risks in biology</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Advanced AI can transform biology and medicine—but also raises biosecurity risks. We’re proactively assessing capabilities and implementing safeguards to prevent misuse.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/preparing-for-future-ai-capabilities-in-biology 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward understanding and preventing misalignment generalization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We study how training on incorrect responses can cause broader misalignment in language models and identify an internal feature driving this behavior—one that can be reversed with minimal fine-tuning.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/emergent-misalignment 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is infrastructure As Code (IaC) Scanning?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 09:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Kumar Harsh, draft.dev. Infrastructure as code (IaC) is a popular practice in modern DevOps security and automation workflows. By treating infrastructure as code, teams can automate resource provisioning and deployments and significantly reduce efforts spent on manual configurations. However, just as with application code, IaC configurations can introduce […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/what-is-iac-scanning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securely Turbo‑Charge Your Software Delivery with the Codex Coding Agent on Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 22:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction OpenAI’s Codex CLI is the same coding agent that powers ChatGPT’s Codex. You can now run this coding agent entire
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/securely-turbo%e2%80%91charge-your-software-delivery-with-the-codex-coding-agent-on-azure-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Vision Intelligence with .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Expanding the many ways in which users can interact with our apps is one of the most exciting parts of working with modern AI models and device capabilities. With .NET MAUI, it&#39;s easy to enhance your app from a text-based experience to one that supports voice, vision, and more. Previously I covered a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/multimodal-vision-intelligence-with-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server 2025 CTP 2.1: DiskANN Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 19:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m happy to announce that SQL Server 2025 CTP 2.1 is now available, and it brings significant improvements to DiskANN support. While DiskANN remains in preview, each release continues to remove limit
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/sql-server-2025-ctp-2-1-diskann-improvements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect Spring AI to Local AI Models with Foundry Local</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 18:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is Azure AI Foundry and Foundry Local? Azure AI Foundry is Microsoft&#39;s comprehensive platform for enterprise AI development and deployment, enabling organizations to build, customize, and operate AI solutions at scale. It provides tools, services, and infrastructure to develop, fine-tune and deploy AI models in production envi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/connect-spring-ai-to-local-ai-models-with-foundry-local 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps MCP Server, Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 18:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A few weeks ago at BUILD, we announced the upcoming Azure DevOps MCP Server: 👉 Azure DevOps with GitHub Repositories – Your path to Agentic AI Today, we’re excited to share that the local Azure DevOps MCP
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-mcp-server-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent mode is now generally available with MCP support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 18:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Copilot agent mode is the next evolution in AI-assisted development—and it&#39;s now generally available in the Visual Studio June update. Agent mode turns GitHub Copilot into an autonomous pair programmer capable of handling multi-step development tasks from end to end. It builds a plan, executes it, adapts along the way, and loops through t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/agent-mode-is-now-generally-available-with-mcp-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2025 – Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 15:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plugin Developer Conf is back this November! We’re looking for speakers to share their insights with the JetBrains plugin development community. Submit your talk by July 10, 2025. What is JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf? Plugin Developer Conf is a free, live, online event hosted by JetBrains, created for and shaped by the plugin development community. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/06/jetbrains-plugin-developer-conf-2025-call-for-speakers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Anomalo solves unstructured data quality issues to deliver trusted assets for AI with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 15:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how you can use Anomalo with Amazon Web Services (AWS) AI and machine learning (AI/ML) to profile, validate, and cleanse unstructured data collections to transform your data lake into a trusted source for production ready AI initiatives.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-anomalo-solves-unstructured-data-quality-issues-to-deliver-trusted-assets-for-ai-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An open-source AutoScaler for Azure SQL Hyperscale Elastic Pools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Guest Post&amp;quot;]Larry Silverman is the Chief Technology Officer at TrackAbout, Inc. (a Datacor company) and a long-time user of Azure SQL Database and SQL Server. In this blog post Larry shares a novel open-source solution which addresses a core need for their business. Thanks, Larry! [/alert]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/auto-scaling-hyperscale-elastic-pools 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An innovative financial services leader finds the right AI solution: Robinhood and Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Robinhood delivers democratized finance and real-time market insights using generative AI and Amazon Nova.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/an-innovative-financial-services-leader-finds-the-right-ai-solution-robinhood-and-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build conversational interfaces for structured data using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides instructions to configure a structured data retrieval solution, with practical code examples and templates. It covers implementation samples and additional considerations, empowering you to quickly build and scale your conversational data interfaces.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-conversational-interfaces-for-structured-data-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding the Egghead store shopping spree took a little extra legwork</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I told the story of the time the development manager for Windows 95 bought one copy of every PC program in the Egghead Software store and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250617-00/?p=111275 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with stacked branches in git (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe why I like to use stacked branches and stacked PRs for larger features, and how I handle making changes to commits in the stack
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/working-with-stacked-branches-in-git-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16 common mistakes C#/.NET developers make (and how to avoid them)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 08:13:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we often fall into common pitfalls that impact the performance, security, and scalability of our applications. From neglecting data validation to overengineering, and from ignoring async/await to mishandling resource disposal, even experienced C# developers can make these mistakes. In this post, I&#39;ve gathered some of
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/16-common-mistakes-c-net-developers-make-and-how-to-avoid-them/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Apollo Tyres is unlocking machine insights using agentic AI-powered Manufacturing Reasoner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Apollo Tyres used generative AI with Amazon Bedrock to harness the insights from their machine data in a natural language interaction mode to gain a comprehensive view of its manufacturing processes, enabling data-driven decision-making and optimizing operational efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-apollo-tyres-is-unlocking-machine-insights-using-agentic-ai-powered-manufacturing-reasoner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extend your Amazon Q Business with PagerDuty Advance data accessor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how organizations can enhance their incident management capabilities by integrating PagerDuty Advance, an innovative set of agentic and generative AI capabilities that automate response workflows and provide real-time insights into operational health, with Amazon Q Business. We show how to configure PagerDuty Advance as a data accessor for Amazon Q indexes, so you can search and access enterprise knowledge across multiple systems during incident response.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovate business logic by implementing return of control in Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the context of distributed systems and microservices architecture, orchestrating communication between diverse components presents significant challenges. However, with the launch of Amazon Bedrock Agents, the landscape is evolving, offering a simplified approach to agent creation and seamless integration of the return of control capability. In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock Agents revolutionizes agent creation and demonstrates the efficacy of the return of control capability in orchestrating complex interactions between multiple systems.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code - June 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the June 2025 release of the Python, Pylance and Jupyter ext
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-june-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 EAP 5: Reimagined Monitoring tool window and New OpenTelemetry Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Rider 2025.2 EAP 5 build has just been released, and this one brings two major productivity enhancements for .NET developers. We’re excited to introduce the reimagined Monitoring tool window, which transforms how you identify and resolve performance issues, plus the new OpenTelemetry plugin, which brings runtime observability directly into your development environment. We can’t […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/16/rider-eap-5-new-monitoring-tool-opentelemetry-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenTelemetry Plugin for JetBrains Rider: Observability Inside Your IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding how your application behaves at runtime has always been a challenge. Traditional debugging and profiling tools can help you understand what’s happening at specific points in time – but getting a complete picture of system behavior, performance patterns, and architectural relationships often means jumping between external tools and dashboards. We’re building the OpenTelemetry plugin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/16/opentelemetry-plugin-for-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a helper class for generating a particular category of C callback wrappers around C&#43;&#43; methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A common pattern for C callbacks is to accept a function pointer and a void*, and then the callback function receives that pointer in addition to the parameters specific to the callback. // Hypothetical callback typedef int (callback_t)( void context, int arg1, char const* arg2, double arg3); void Regi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250616-00/?p=111271 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Rerun Failed GitHub Actions Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Actions doesn&#39;t provide a built-in way to rerun a run automatically. If you have some flakiness in your jobs, this can be a pain as you have to rerun the workflow manually. Hopefully, you can use the workflow_run event to trigger a new workflow when a previous one fails. This allows you to rerun the failed workflow automatically. Note that the following sample workflow will only rerun the failed…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Java Enable Preview: Vector API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 10:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Daniel Hinojosa and explore the Vector API – a powerful tool for writing high-performance code in Java. Date: June 25, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this session, we will discuss the Vector API in a preview in Java. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/new-livestream-new-livestream-new-livestream-java-enable-preview-vector-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Says… Don’t Build Frankenstein’s Monster Applications!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2025/15_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2025/15_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article emphasizes the dangers of creating disjointed software systems, likening them to Frankenstein&#39;s Monster. It warns against overengineering and using mismatched technologies, which can lead to project failures. The author shares personal insights and experiences, urging teams to prioritize coherence and maintainability in their software architecture.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/15/dotnetdave-says-dont-build-frankensteins-monster-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Motivation in Software Engineering - Dev Leader Weekly 98</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to breakdown what keeps you engaged as a software engineer.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/14/uncovering-motivation-in-software-engineering-dev-leader-weekly-98 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-06-13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 07:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/14/weekly-recap-20250613 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run C# Scripts With dotnet run app.cs (No Project Files Needed)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With .NET 10, you can now run C# files directly. No project files, no Main method, just code. In this issue, I&#39;ll show you how to use the new dotnet run app.cs feature in practice: from quick one-liners to a real-world SQL seeding script.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/run-csharp-scripts-with-dotnet-run-app-no-project-files-needed 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Qwen models with Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 17:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now import custom weights for Qwen2, Qwen2_VL, and Qwen2_5_VL architectures, including models like Qwen 2, 2.5 Coder, Qwen 2.5 VL, and QwQ 32B. In this post, we cover how to deploy Qwen 2.5 models with Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import, making them accessible to organizations looking to use state-of-the-art AI capabilities within the AWS infrastructure at an effective cost.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-qwen-models-with-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI solutions with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to build generative AI applications on Amazon Web Services (AWS) using the capabilities of Amazon Bedrock, highlighting how Amazon Bedrock can be used at each step of your generative AI journey. This guide is valuable for both experienced AI engineers and newcomers to the generative AI space, helping you use Amazon Bedrock to its fullest potential.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-solutions-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Netsertive built a scalable AI assistant to extract meaningful insights from real-time data using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Netsertive introduced a generative AI-powered assistant into MLX, using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Nova, to bring their next generation of the platform to life.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-netsertive-built-a-scalable-ai-assistant-to-extract-meaningful-insights-from-real-time-data-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make videos accessible with automated audio descriptions using Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use services like Amazon Nova, Amazon Rekognition, and Amazon Polly to automate the creation of accessible audio descriptions for video content. This approach can significantly reduce the time and cost required to make videos accessible for visually impaired audiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/make-videos-accessible-with-automated-audio-descriptions-using-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Llama 3.3 Swallow: A Japanese sovereign LLM on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 15:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Institute of Science Tokyo has successfully trained Llama 3.3 Swallow, a 70-billion-parameter large language model (LLM) with enhanced Japanese capabilities, using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod. The model demonstrates superior performance in Japanese language tasks, outperforming GPT-4o-mini and other leading models. This technical report details the training infrastructure, optimizations, and best practices developed during the project.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/training-llama-3-3-swallow-a-japanese-sovereign-llm-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – June Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 14:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month, we’ve gathered fun plugins and a course to help you build your own, as well as AI updates, exciting news for C++ learners and professional developers. Dive in!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/06/13/jetbrains-academy-june/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thread pool threads are like preschool: Leave things the way you found them</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to use the Windows thread pool, but they also wanted to use COM from their work item. They saw in the COM documentation that each thread must call Co­Initialize(Ex) before using COM, so they planned on doing something like this: thread_local bool isComInitialized = false; auto DoWork
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250613-00/?p=111268 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains GameDev Days 2025 – Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 09:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains GameDev Day is back! Join us online on October 21, 2025, for a day dedicated to all things game development. We’re looking for speakers who are eager to share their knowledge, experience, tools, or creative approaches across the gamedev community. What is GameDev Day? GameDev Day is a free, live, online event hosted by […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/13/jetbrains-gamedev-days-2025-call-for-speakers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Articul8’s domain-specific model development with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Articul8 is redefining enterprise generative AI with domain-specific models that outperform general-purpose LLMs in real-world applications. In our latest blog post, we dive into how Amazon SageMaker HyperPod accelerated the development of Articul8’s industry-leading semiconductor model—achieving 2X higher accuracy that top open source models while slashing deployment time by 4X.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-articul8s-domain-specific-model-development-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How VideoAmp uses Amazon Bedrock to power their media analytics interface</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate how VideoAmp, a media measurement company, worked with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) team to develop a prototype of the VideoAmp Natural Language (NL) Analytics Chatbot to uncover meaningful insights at scale within media analytics data using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-videoamp-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-power-their-media-analytics-interface/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Your Productivity with New GitHub Copilot Features for .NET!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Visual Studio 17.14 GA release and recent C# Dev Kit releases for VS Code have introduced a whole new batch of GitHub Copilot features des
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/improve-productivity-with-github-copilot-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2025 (version 1.101)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code May 2025 Release (1.101) Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/may-2025-(version-1.101) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft recognized for second consecutive year as a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re proud to share that Microsoft has once again been named a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Data Science and Machine Learning (DSML) Platforms. The post Microsoft recognized for second consecutive year as a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/microsoft-recognized-for-second-consecutive-year-as-a-leader-in-the-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-data-science-and-machine-learning-platforms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You DON’T Need Microservices for Serverless!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I want to talk about something that might sound like a contradiction in terms: the serverless monolith. If you’re scratching your head right now, thinking, “Wait, that makes no sense, serverless is for microservices!” then stick with me. I’m going to clear up one of the biggest misconceptions out there and explain why a serverless… Read More »You DON’T Need Microservices for Serverless! The post You DON’T Need Microservices for Serverless!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build, Run, and Package AI Models Locally with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As a Senior DevOps Engineer and Docker Captain, I’ve helped build AI systems for everything from retail personalization to medical imaging. One truth stands out: AI capabilities are core to modern infrastructure. This guide will show you how to run and package local AI models with Docker Model Runner — a lightweight, developer-friendly tool...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-build-run-and-package-ai-models-locally-with-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Windows even have &lt;code&gt;Interlocked&lt;/code&gt; functions when we have &lt;code&gt;std::atomic&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows provides a family of functions for performing atomic operations. They have the word Interlocked in their name. But why do these functions even exist when we have std::atomic? This is similar to asking
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250612-00/?p=111265 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Building an MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, June 24, at 10 am EDT / 4 pm CEST (check other timezones) for our free livestream, Live Coding: Building an MCP Server. In this livestream, we’ll team up with Max Kless, a senior engineer at Nx, to build a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server from scratch and seamlessly integrate it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/06/livestream-building-an-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs Go: Which one to choose in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The programming landscape continues to evolve, bringing forward languages like Rust and Go that not only challenge traditional paradigms but also cater to the sophisticated needs of modern computing. Both have carved significant niches for themselves, celebrated for their efficient handling of system-level operations and concurrency. Recent findings from the State of Developer Ecosystem Report […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/06/12/rust-vs-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.3: Important Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A third set of updates for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.3 introduces support for SQL &amp;amp; NoSQL query languages You can now edit and format SQL and NoSQL queries […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/12/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-3-important-updates-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor your Quarkus native application on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 12:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Quarkus is a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/monitor-your-quarkus-native-application-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run HTTP Requests in Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 08:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that our HTTP Client plugin is now available in Android Studio! HTTP Client is a powerful tool for making HTTP, gRPC, GraphQL, and WebSocket requests. Its text-based interface offers seamless integration with the editor, along with extensive coding assistance including highlighting, code completion, refactorings, and inline documentation. While it was […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/06/12/run-http-requests-in-android-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from Cursor to IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 07:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re a developer working with Cursor, exploring alternatives for your growing project, and are curious to see what IntelliJ IDEA has to offer, this article is for you. While Cursor emphasizes a minimalistic setup approach, IntelliJ IDEA strikes a balance between out-of-the-box functionality and powerful customization, enabling developers to effortlessly scale from small projects […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/migrate-cursor-to-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dockerizing UV</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Containerizing your Python applications helps standardize environments and streamline deployment—but it also introduces unique challenges. In our team&#39;s exploration of modern dependency management tools, we discovered that while UV (Universal Virtualenv) delivers impressive speed and simplicity in local development, replicating its setup ins
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/dockerizing-uv 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing the Magic of AI to Mattel’s Iconic Brands</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Mattel are partnering to integrate AI into iconic brands such as Barbie and Hot Wheels, aiming to enhance creative development, streamline workflows, and create new ways for fans to engage.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/mattels-iconic-brands 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Complete MCP Experience: Full Specification Support in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VS Code now supports the complete Model Context Protocol specification, including authorization, prompts, resources, and sampling. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/the-complete-mcp-experience:-full-specification-support-in-vs-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security and Trust in Visual Studio Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 22:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s fast-paced digital world, keeping the Visual Studio Marketplace secure and trustworthy is extremely important. We know how crucial it is to protect your extensions, so we&#39;re always working on new ways to keep things safe. We&#39;d like to share an update on the existing safeguards and upcoming investments that ensure VS Marketplace r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//security-and-trust-in-visual-studio-marketplace 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Voice Intelligence with .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most interesting ways to enhance your existing applications with AI is to enable more ways for your users to interact with it. Today you probably handle text input, and perhaps some touch gestures for your power users. Now it&#39;s easier than ever to expand that to voice and vision, especially when your users&#39; primary input is via mobi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/multimodal-voice-intelligence-with-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe enhances developer productivity using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adobe partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and the Vector Engine for Amazon OpenSearch Serverless. This solution dramatically improved their developer support system, resulting in a 20% increase in retrieval accuracy. In this post, we discuss the details of this solution and how Adobe enhances their developer productivity.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/adobe-enhances-developer-productivity-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Nova Lite enables Bito to offer a free tier option for its AI-powered code reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bito is an innovative startup that creates AI agents for a broad range of software developers. In this post, we share how Bito is able to offer a free tier option for its AI-powered code reviews using Amazon Nova.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-nova-lite-enables-bito-to-offer-a-free-tier-option-for-its-ai-powered-code-reviews/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Gardenia Technologies helps customers create ESG disclosure reports 75% faster using agentic generative AI on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Gardenia Technologies, a data analytics company, partnered with the AWS Prototyping and Cloud Engineering (PACE) team to develop Report GenAI, a fully automated ESG reporting solution powered by the latest generative AI models on Amazon Bedrock. This post dives deep into the technology behind an agentic search solution using tooling with Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and text-to-SQL capabilities to help customers reduce ESG reporting time by up to 75%. We demonstrate how AWS serverless technology, combined with agents in Amazon Bedrock, are used to build scalable and highly flexible agent-based document assistant applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing the &lt;code&gt;MAX_PATH&lt;/code&gt; restriction on paths applies only to paths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was playing around with Windows long paths and found that even though they used the \?\ long path prefix, they still couldn&#39;t use a long path. The documentation on the maximum pat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250611-00/?p=111262 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing AI models to Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we first released Docker Model Runner, it came with built-in support for running AI models published and maintained by Docker on Docker Hub. This made it simple to pull a model like llama3.2 or gemma3 and start using it locally with familiar Docker-style commands. Model Runner now supports three new commands: tag, push, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/publish-ai-models-on-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Nemotron Super 49B and Nano 8B reasoning models now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Llama 3.3 Nemotron Super 49B V1 and Llama 3.1 Nemotron Nano 8B V1 are now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, you can now deploy NVIDIA’s newest reasoning models to build, experiment, and responsibly scale your generative AI ideas on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/nvidia-nemotron-super-49b-and-nano-8b-reasoning-models-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy JetBrains Mellum Your Way: Now Available via NVIDIA NIM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deploy Mellum as a production-grade LLM inside your own infrastructure – with NVIDIA. JetBrains Mellum – our open, focused LLM specialized on code completion – is now available to run as a containerized microservice on NVIDIA AI Factories. Using the new NVIDIA universal LLM NIM container, Mellum can be deployed in minutes on any NVIDIA-accelerated […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/06/deploy-jetbrains-mellum-your-way-now-available-via-nvidia-nim/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
