<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 18:22:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code - September 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 18:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the September 2025 release of the Python, Pylance and Jupyter
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-september-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule topology-aware workloads using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod task governance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce topology-aware scheduling with SageMaker HyperPod task governance by submitting jobs that represent hierarchical network information. We provide details about how to use SageMaker HyperPod task governance to optimize your job efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/schedule-topology-aware-workloads-using-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-task-governance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How msg enhanced HR workforce transformation with Amazon Bedrock and msg.ProfileMap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how msg automated data harmonization for msg.ProfileMap, using Amazon Bedrock to power its large language model (LLM)-driven data enrichment workflows, resulting in higher accuracy in HR concept matching, reduced manual workload, and improved alignment with compliance requirements under the EU AI Act and GDPR.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-msg-enhanced-hr-workforce-transformation-with-amazon-bedrock-and-msg-profilemap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Insights Code Optimizations for .NET Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As engineers we know how frustrating it can be to chase and fix performance issues without clear guidance. That’s why we built Application Insights Code Optimizations — to give you actionable insights, reduce the guesswork, and help you focus on what you do best: building great softwar
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/application-insights-code-optimizations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working and Testing Against Scheduled Messages with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine has long had some ability to schedule some messages to be executed at a later time or schedule messages to be delivered at a later time. The Wolverine 4.12 release last night added some probably overdue test automation helpers to better deal with scheduled messaging within integration testing against Wolverine applications — and that … Continue reading Working and Testing Against Scheduled Messages with Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is the name of the Microsoft Wireless Notebook Presenter Mouse 8000 hard-coded into the Bluetooth drivers?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, people noticed that buried in the Windows Bluetooth drivers is the hard-coded name of the Microsoft Wireless Notebook Presenter Mouse 8000. What&#39;s going on there? Does the Microsoft Wireless Notebook Presenter Mouse 8000 receive favorable treatment from the Microsoft Bluetooth drivers? Is this some sort of collusion?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250915-00/?p=111599 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nine Rules of AI PoC Success: How to Build Demos That Actually Ship</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That study claiming &amp;quot;95% of AI POCs fail&amp;quot; has been making the rounds. It&#39;s clickbait nonsense, and frankly, it&#39;s not helping anyone. The real number? Nobody knows, because nobody&#39;s tracking it properly. But here&#39;s what I do know after years of watching teams build AI systems: the study masks a much more important problem. Teams...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-poc-success-rules/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing upgrades to Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Codex just got faster, more reliable, and better at real-time collaboration and tackling tasks independently anywhere you develop—whether via the terminal, IDE, web, or even your phone.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-upgrades-to-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Constexpr Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 07:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “Not a constant expression.” You’ve seen the diagnostics and the note trail, but never the actual state. Until now. Modern C++ pushes more logic into constexpr/consteval: parsers, tables, DSLs, hashing – real code with real branches. When code fails at compile time, you can either try to guess the reason from the compiler’s notes or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/09/introducing-constexpr-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How people are using ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            New research from the largest study of ChatGPT use shows how the tool creates economic value through both personal and professional use. Adoption is broadening beyond early users, closing gaps and making AI a part of everyday life.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/how-people-are-using-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addendum to GPT-5 system card: GPT-5-Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This addendum to the GPT-5 system card shares a new model: GPT-5-Codex, a version of GPT-5 further optimized for agentic coding in Codex. GPT-5-Codex adjusts its thinking effort more dynamically based on task complexity, responding quickly to simple conversational queries or small tasks, while independently working for longer on more complex tasks.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-system-card-addendum-gpt-5-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing auto model selection (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Use auto model selection in VS Code to get faster responses, reduced rate limiting, and a 10% discount on premium requests for paid users. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/introducing-auto-model-selection-(preview) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Ensure Thread-Safe Uniqueness with DistinctConcurrentBag in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_09_2025/14_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_09_2025/14_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DistinctConcurrentBag in Spargine is a thread-safe, unordered collection that ensures uniqueness of elements, preventing duplicates. It offers methods for adding, removing, checking, and enumerating items, making it ideal for concurrent programming in .NET. For blocking behavior with uniqueness, DistinctBlockingCollection is recommended.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/09/14/boost-your-net-projects-ensure-thread-safe-uniqueness-with-distinctconcurrentbag-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Other Side Of Engineering Interviews - Dev Leader Weekly 109</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2025/13_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2025/13_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how I approach software engineering interviews as the interviewer.
Link to article: https://devleader.ca/2025/09/13/the-other-side-of-engineering-interviews-dev-leader-weekly-109 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-09-12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2025/13_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 05:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2025/13_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://devleader.ca/2025/09/13/weekly-recap-20250912 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Slice Architecture Is Easier Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2025/13_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2025/13_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Vertical Slice Architecture organizes .NET code by business features instead of technical layers, keeping related functionality together and making your codebase easier to navigate and maintain.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/vertical-slice-architecture-is-easier-than-you-think 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate advanced agentic RAG pipeline with Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how to streamline your RAG development lifecycle from experimentation to automation, helping you operationalize your RAG solution for production deployments with Amazon SageMaker AI, helping your team experiment efficiently, collaborate effectively, and drive continuous improvement.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-advanced-agentic-rag-pipeline-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock model insights with log probability support for Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how log probabilities work with imported models in Amazon Bedrock. You will learn what log probabilities are, how to enable them in your API calls, and how to interpret the returned data. We also highlight practical applications—from detecting potential hallucinations to optimizing RAG systems and evaluating fine-tuned models—that demonstrate how these insights can improve your AI applications, helping you build more trustworthy solutions with your custom models.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet to Claude 4 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides a systematic approach to migrating from Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet to Claude 4 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock. We examine the key model differences, highlight essential migration considerations, and deliver proven best practices to transform this necessary transition into a strategic advantage that drives measurable value for your organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/migrate-from-anthropics-claude-3-5-sonnet-to-claude-4-sonnet-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Voice Belongs Here: Creating Compelling KotlinConf Proposals [Livestream]</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you given a talk before – maybe at a meetup, online event, or a smaller conference – and wondered if you’re ready for a bigger stage like KotlinConf? This supportive and practical webinar is designed for people from underrepresented groups in tech who already have some speaking experience and are ready to level up. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/creating-kotlinconf-proposals/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I convert a third party in-process server so it runs in the COM surrogate?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer had an app with a plugin model based on vendor-supplied COM objects that are loaded into the process via Co­Create­Instance. Main process
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250912-00/?p=111589 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with US CAISI and UK AISI to build more secure AI systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI shares progress on the partnership with the US CAISI and UK AISI to strengthen AI safety and security. The collaboration is setting new standards for responsible frontier AI deployment through joint red-teaming, biosecurity safeguards, and agentic system testing.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/us-caisi-uk-aisi-ai-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve Effortless GitHub Releases With a New Plugin for TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 10:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub releases are fantastic for distributing your open-source projects, as they let you turn any code revision into ready-to-go assets with a detailed version history. What makes them particularly popular, though, is that they give users a proper Download button (because not everyone dreams of compiling source code). In TeamCity, the traditional approach for publishing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/teamcity-github-releases-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OpenAI Grove</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications are now open for OpenAI Grove, a 5-week founder program designed for individuals at any stage, from pre-idea to product. Participants receive $50K in API credits, early access to AI tools, and hands-on mentorship from the OpenAI team.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-grove 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Team at CppCon 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 22:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             It&#39;s that time of year again! We are excited to see you all at CppCon this year, where we&#39;ll once again b
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/microsoft-at-cppcon-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance video understanding with Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and open-set object detection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In real-world video and image analysis, businesses often face the challenge of detecting objects that weren’t part of a model’s original training set. This becomes especially difficult in dynamic environments where new, unknown, or user-defined objects frequently appear. In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock Data Automation uses OSOD to enhance video understanding.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-video-understanding-with-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-open-set-object-detection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Skello uses Amazon Bedrock to query data in a multi-tenant environment while keeping logical boundaries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Skello is a leading human resources (HR) software as a service (SaaS) solution focusing on employee scheduling and workforce management. Catering to diverse sectors such as hospitality, retail, healthcare, construction, and industry, Skello offers features including schedule creation, time tracking, and payroll preparation. We dive deep into the challenges of implementing large language models (LLMs) for data querying, particularly in the context of a French company operating under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a private workforce on Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth with the AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a complete solution for programmatically creating private workforces on Amazon SageMaker AI using the AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), including the setup of a dedicated, fully configured Amazon Cognito user pool.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-private-workforce-on-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-with-the-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shader Model 6.9 and The Future of Cooperative Vector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Direct
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/shader-model-6-9-and-the-future-of-cooperative-vector 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2025 (version 1.104)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code August 2025 Release (1.104) Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/august-2025-(version-1.104) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratizing Performance: The Copilot Profiler Agent in Action on Real Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 16:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the Copilot Profiler Agent available in Visual Studio 2026 Insiders, it&#39;s an AI-powe
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/copilot-profiler-agent-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains at the ICPC World Finals 2025 Baku</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ICPC World Finals 2025 in Baku was an unforgettable event, and we were honored to be part of it once again. It’s always a joy to see the brightest students from across the globe. The Finals reminds us why supporting the ICPC is such a vital mission – it’s about community, talent, and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/11/jetbrains-at-the-icpc-world-finals-2025-baku/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A joint statement from OpenAI and Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Microsoft sign a new MOU, reinforcing their partnership and shared commitment to AI safety and innovation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/joint-statement-from-openai-and-microsoft 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement on OpenAI’s Nonprofit and PBC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI reaffirms its nonprofit leadership with a new structure granting equity in its PBC, enabling over $100B in resources to advance safe, beneficial AI for humanity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/statement-on-openai-nonprofit-and-pbc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can&#39;t &lt;code&gt;std::apply&lt;/code&gt; figure out which overload I intend to use? Only one of then will work!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Consider the following: void f(int, int); void f(char*, char*); void test(std::tuple&amp;lt;int, int&amp;gt; t) { std::apply(f, t); // error } The compiler complains that it cannot deduce the type of the first parameter. I&#39;m using std::apply here, but the same arguments apply to functions like
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250911-00/?p=111586 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing AI Coding Agents With TeamCity and SWE-bench</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 08:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction AI coding agents are no longer research experiments. They are quickly becoming practical tools that can help developers solve real problems. But how do you know whether an agent is good enough for serious use? How do you measure progress when its answers are not always predictable and when there may be various correct […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/testing-ai-coding-agents-with-teamcity-and-swe-bench/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Storage APIs gain Entra ID and RBAC support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 18:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            API Updates To align with security best practices, Microsoft Entra ID and RBAC (role-based access control) support is now generally available for the following Azure Storage data plane APIs: Get Ac
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-storage-apis-gain-entra-id-and-rbac-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.07.2 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing our second bug-fix release for the 2025.07 major release —TeamCity On-Premises 2025.07.2. This update ships a considerable number of bug fixes, including the following: Apart from resolving regular bugs, all TeamCity bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements. For that reason, we recommend that you never ignore bug-fix releases and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/teamcity-2025-07-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TII Falcon-H1 models now available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of the Technology Innovation Institute (TII)’s Falcon-H1 models on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, developers and data scientists can now use six instruction-tuned Falcon-H1 models (0.5B, 1.5B, 1.5B-Deep, 3B, 7B, and 34B) on AWS, and have access to a comprehensive suite of hybrid architecture models that combine traditional attention mechanisms with State Space Models (SSMs) to deliver exceptional performance with unprecedented efficiency.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oldcastle accelerates document processing with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Oldcastle partnered with AWS to transform their document processing workflow using Amazon Bedrock with Amazon Textract. We discuss how Oldcastle overcame the limitations of their previous OCR solution to automate the processing of hundreds of thousands of POD documents each month, dramatically improving accuracy while reducing manual effort.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/oldcastle-accelerates-document-processing-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How London Stock Exchange Group is detecting market abuse with their AI-powered Surveillance Guide on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how London Stock Exchange Group (LSEG) used Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic&#39;s Claude foundation models to build an automated system that significantly improves the efficiency and accuracy of market surveillance operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-london-stock-exchange-group-is-detecting-market-abuse-with-their-ai-powered-surveillance-guide-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build trustworthy AI agents with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Observability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through implementation options for both agents hosted on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime and agents hosted on other services like Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2), Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), AWS Lambda, or alternative cloud providers. We also share best practices for incorporating observability throughout the development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-trustworthy-ai-agents-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-observability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The documentation says that CompanyName version information is required, but my program seems to work without it, so how required is it?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer observed that the documentation for version resources describes strings like CompanyName and ProductName as &amp;quot;required&amp;quot;. But they found that if they omitted those strings, nothing bad seemed to happen
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250910-00/?p=111582 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Language Updates in MSVC Build Tools v14.50</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C++ Language Updates in MSVC Build Tools v14.50 It has been some time since we have provided an update on MSVC progress, and this one comes with the latest major update to our IDE: Visual Studio 2026 version 18.0. This version of Visual Studio ships with the MSVC Build Tools version 14.50, which incl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-language-updates-in-msvc-build-tools-v14-50 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Hallucinations to Prompt Injection: Securing AI Workflows at Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How developers are embedding runtime security to safely build with AI agents Introduction: When AI Workflows Become Attack Surfaces The AI tools we use today are powerful, but also unpredictable and exploitable. You prompt an LLM and it generates a Dockerfile. It looks correct. A shell script? Reasonable. You run it in dev. Then something...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/secure-ai-agents-runtime-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Improvements in .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            My kids love &amp;quot;Frozen&amp;quot;. They can sing every word, re-enact every scene, and provide detailed notes on the proper sparkle of Elsa&#39;s ice dress. I&#39;ve seen the movie more times than I can recount, to the point where, if you&#39;ve seen me do any live coding, you&#39;ve probably seen my subconscious incorporate an Arendelle reference or two. After
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/performance-improvements-in-net-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Azure Cosmos DB Account Overview Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Simpler Way to Navigate, Learn, and Optimize your Azure Cosmos DB Account within the Azure Portal.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-the-azure-cosmos-db-account-overview-hub 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.2.20 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 09:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.2.20 release is out, delivering important changes for web development. Kotlin/Wasm is now Beta, with improvements to exception handling in JavaScript interop, npm dependency management, built-in browser debugging support, and a new shared source set for js and wasmJs targets. Additionally, here are some main highlights: For the complete list of changes, see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/kotlin-2-2-20-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie Is Now Available in CLion: Supercharge Your C and C&#43;&#43; Development Today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 07:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with version 2025.2.1, CLion now supports Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, thanks to an integration that is currently in Beta. Developers working on embedded systems, projects written in C or C++, or performance-critical software can now experience the full benefit of Junie’s project insights and tooling, directly in CLion. With Junie, you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/09/junie-availability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel announces undo support for 3rd-party Copilot declarative agents &amp; web add-ins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 07:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share a major milestone with our partner community: Excel now supports Undo for 3rd-party Copilot declarative agents and web add-ins! This long-awaited capability unlocks a more seamless, professional experience for both developers and end users and addresses one of the top requests from our ISV ecosystem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/excel-announces-undo-support-for-3rd-party-copilot-declarative-agents-web-add-ins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare your VBA projects for VBScript deprecation in Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 03:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In May 2024, Microsoft announced the phased deprecation of VBScript in Windows, as detailed in the official Windows IT Pro Blog. This change impacts VBA developers who rely on VBScript, particularly for reference libr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/how-to-prepare-vba-projects-for-vbscript-deprecation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get ready –the first Insiders release of Visual Studio 2026 has arrived! In this new evolution of Visual Studio, we’re continuing our commitment to building the best integrated developer environment for C++ developers on Windows. [video src=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; poster=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;] Visual Studio 2026 features a fresh UI, f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-2026-insiders-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing .NET 10 Release Candidate 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 Release Candidate 1 is now available. This is our first of two release candidates which come with a go-live support license so you can confidently use this release for your production applications. This release of .NET 10 is supported in the new
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-rc-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework September 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for September 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of September 05, 2025. This update contains no
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-september-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering innovation at scale: How AWS is tackling AI infrastructure challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative AI continues to transform how enterprises operate—and develop net new innovations—the infrastructure demands for training and deploying AI models have grown exponentially. Traditional infrastructure approaches are struggling to keep pace with today’s computational requirements, network demands, and resilience needs of modern AI workloads. At AWS, we’re also seeing a transformation across the technology […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/powering-innovation-at-scale-how-aws-is-tackling-ai-infrastructure-challenges/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here - and it marks one of the most ambitious steps forward we’ve taken with the IDE. This release brings AI woven directly into the developer workflow, performance improvements that reset expectations for speed at enterprise scale, and a modern design that makes the environment feel lighter
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2026-insiders-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your model training with managed tiered checkpointing on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS announced managed tiered checkpointing in Amazon SageMaker HyperPod, a purpose-built infrastructure to scale and accelerate generative AI model development across thousands of AI accelerators. Managed tiered checkpointing uses CPU memory for high-performance checkpoint storage with automatic data replication across adjacent compute nodes for enhanced reliability. In this post, we dive deep into those concepts and understand how to use the managed tiered checkpointing feature.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-your-model-training-with-managed-tiered-checkpointing-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MPS 2025.2 brings quality and stability improvements across the board, along with several notable upgrades. This release adds the ability to start MPS with OS-native launchers, introduces a modernized Show Node Info dialog, and improves how resolve-info is handled when references are copy-pasted. You can now provide icons using factory methods, and the platform has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/09/mps-2025-1-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A suggestion to people who assign nicknames to meeting rooms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is common for Microsoft buildings to assign nicknames to meeting rooms to make them easier to remember. Instead of &amp;quot;We will be in room 1728&amp;quot; you can say &amp;quot;We will be in the Magellan room.&amp;quot; The new Microsoft Building 3 has a series of meeting rooms labeled 1.3A through 1.3E. (The number 1.3 means &amp;quot;first floor, zone 3.&amp;quot;) These meeti
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250909-00/?p=111578 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating IntelliJ Platform UI Freezes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You have probably seen this picture occasionally and wondered what is happening with your IDE and why it freezes! This is a tricky question, and many types of bugs and performance issues may lead to UI freezes. JetBrains IDEs are built on top of a UI framework (the Java AWT) that uses a single thread, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/investigating-intellij-platform-ui-freezes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging self-contained and native AOT .NET tools for NuGet: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we look at the new support for platform-specific .NET tools, so that you can pack your tools as self-contained or Native AOT packages
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-7-packaging-self-contained-and-native-aot-dotnet-tools-for-nuget/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping smarter agents with every new model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how SafetyKit leverages OpenAI GPT-5 to enhance content moderation, enforce compliance, and outpace legacy safety systems with greater accuracy .
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/safetykit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize HyperPod Cluster utilization with HyperPod task governance fine-grained quota allocation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the general availability of fine-grained compute and memory quota allocation with HyperPod task governance. With this capability, customers can optimize Amazon SageMaker HyperPod cluster utilization on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), distribute fair usage, and support efficient resource allocation across different teams or projects. For more information, see HyperPod task governance best […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maximize-hyperpod-cluster-utilization-with-hyperpod-task-governance-fine-grained-quota-allocation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Runtime JAR inspector in 10 hours</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last Friday I was reviewing our backlog items in the Java Engineering Group, and found an idea we had when Log4Shell happened. To this day, there is still no main stream solution to &amp;quot;find in production where a given JAR is being used&amp;quot;.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/building-a-runtime-jar-inspector-in-10-hours 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and scale adoption of AI agents for education with Strands Agents, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and LibreChat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to quickly build sophisticated AI agents using Strands Agents, scale them reliably with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and make them accessible through LibreChat’s familiar interface to drive immediate user adoption across your institution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-and-scale-adoption-of-ai-agents-for-education-with-strands-agents-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-and-librechat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skai uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to significantly improve customer insights by revolutionized data access and analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Skai (formerly Kenshoo) is an AI-driven omnichannel advertising and analytics platform designed for brands and agencies to plan, launch, optimize, and measure paid media across search, social, retail media marketplaces and other “walled-garden” channels from a single interface. In this post, we share how Skai used Amazon Bedrock Agents to improve data access and analysis and improve customer insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/skai-uses-amazon-bedrock-agents-to-significantly-improve-customer-insights-by-revolutionized-data-access-and-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change to data visibility for Microsoft Graph callRecords APIs in GCC High and DoD</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a continuation of changes previously announced for global customers, we will be making cha
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/change-to-data-visibility-for-microsoft-graph-callrecords-apis-in-gcc-high-and-dod 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“GoLand Can Do That?” Ten Secret Superpowers You Might Not Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Note: This is a guest post from John Arundel, a Go writer and teacher who blogs at bitfieldconsulting.com. His most recent book is The Deeper Love of Go. How do you break it to someone that they’ve wasted most of their life? Well, I worked with a guy who didn’t know how to copy and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/09/08/goland-can-do-that-ten-secret-superpowers-you-might-not-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of AI in driving personalized product discovery at Snoonu</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Snoonu, a leading ecommerce platform in the Middle East, transformed their product discovery experience using AI-powered personalization. In this post, we share how Snoonu, a leading ecommerce platform in the Middle East, transformed their product discovery experience using AI-powered personalization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-power-of-ai-in-driving-personalized-product-discovery-at-snoonu/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A People-First AI Fund: $50M to support nonprofits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications are now open for OpenAI’s People-First AI Fund, a $50M initiative supporting U.S. nonprofits advancing education, community innovation, and economic opportunity. Apply by October 8, 2025, for unrestricted grants that help communities shape AI for the public good.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/people-first-ai-fund 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why didn&#39;t Windows 95 simply special-case the laptops that locked up when it executed the &lt;code&gt;HLT&lt;/code&gt; instruction?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 80386 HLT instruction tells the CPU to stop executing instructions until a hardware interrupt occurs. This was traditionally the instruction performed by the operating system when it had no work to do, allowing the CPU to go into a low-power mode. (In modern times, operating systems use other instructions like MWAIT
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250908-00/?p=111572 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Mellum Now Available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace – For Free</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 12:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Production-grade code completion at your fingertips – deploy Mellum instantly with full control and zero extra model fees JetBrains Mellum – our focused large language model (LLM) for code completion – is now available on the Amazon Bedrock Marketplace. This means Mellum is easier than ever to use in real-world applications, with instant access via […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/jetbrains-mellum-now-available-on-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-for-free/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
