<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 03:27:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot for Xcode: Introducing Copilot Vision, Custom Instructions, Locale-Aware Responses, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 03:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce updates to GitHub Copilot for Xcode, bringing new ways to interact with AI and streamline your development workflow. . With Copilot Vision, you can upload and chat with images—like screenshots and UI designs—directly in Xcode. We’ve also introduced glob
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/github-copilot-for-xcode-introducing-copilot-vision-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (July 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 22:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Full-Stack App with React and Aspire: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we will build we will build a TODO app from start to finish using Aspire and React. We will do this using the CLI and C# Dev Kit. The todo items will be stored in a SQLite database. The React front-end will use a Web API to handle all the interactions with the data. I&#39;m going to be showing this with the dotnet CLI, Aspire CLI a
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Laravel Idea Plugin is Now Free for PhpStorm Users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 16:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting July 30, 2025, we’re making Laravel Idea free for PhpStorm users. If you already have the Laravel Idea plugin installed, you get full access to all plugin features at no extra cost. Laravel Idea is the smartest Laravel development environment based on PhpStorm. Developed by Adel Faizrakhmanov, the plugin has 1.5M+ downloads from JetBrains […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/07/laravel-idea-is-now-free/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate the creation of handout notes using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 16:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can build an automated, serverless solution to transform webinar recordings into comprehensive handouts using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation for video analysis. We walk you through the implementation of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation to transcribe and detect slide changes, as well as the use of Amazon Bedrock foundation models (FMs) for transcription refinement, combined with custom AWS Lambda functions orchestrated by AWS Step Functions.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline GitHub workflows with generative AI using Amazon Bedrock and MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 16:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post explores how to create powerful agentic applications using the Amazon Bedrock FMs, LangGraph, and the Model Context Protocol (MCP), with a practical scenario of handling a GitHub workflow of issue analysis, code fixes, and pull request generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-github-workflows-with-generative-ai-using-amazon-bedrock-and-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing General Availability of UNISTR function and ANSI SQL || Operator in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 15:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the General Availability (GA) of two long-standing capabilities that address critical needs for SQL developers and enterprise customers in Azure SQL Database and Azure SQL Managed Instance, configured with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/announcing-general-availability-of-unistr-function-and-ansi-sql-operator-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, how can I await multiple coroutines and capture the results?, part 0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A while ago, I investigated ways of awaiting multiple C++/WinRT corotuines and capturing the results. I started with winrt::when_all(), but really I co
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250730-00/?p=111421 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Plan Validation in Copilot Studio Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 10:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever wonder why your agent&#39;s answers can be right but for the wrong reasons? Let&#39;s dive into why that matters, with a brief foray into epistemology (bear with me!) Knowledge: More Than Just Right Answers Imagine asking someone the time, and they confidently reply, “2:30 PM.” They&#39;re correct—but what if their watch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/plan-validation-cat-kit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping Students Get Unstuck: AI-Based Hints for Online Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 10:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In online learning environments, tasks can often stump students, which can be challenging to navigate since teachers can’t always be there to help. Our Education Research team develops innovative features for education tools and recently built a smart AI-based hints tool that provides personalized feedback for students who might need help solving tasks. This tool […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/07/ai-hints-for-online-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three lessons for creating a sustainable AI advantage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Intercom built a scalable AI platform with 3 key lessons—from evaluations to architecture—to lead the future of customer support.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/intercom 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate suspicious transaction report drafts for financial compliance using generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A suspicious transaction report (STR) or suspicious activity report (SAR) is a type of report that a financial organization must submit to a financial regulator if they have reasonable grounds to suspect any financial transaction that has occurred or was attempted during their activities. In this post, we explore a solution that uses FMs available in Amazon Bedrock to create a draft STR.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-suspicious-transaction-report-drafts-for-financial-compliance-using-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune and deploy Meta Llama 3.2 Vision for generative AI-powered web automation using AWS DLCs, Amazon EKS, and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a complete solution for fine-tuning and deploying the Llama-3.2-11B-Vision-Instruct model for web automation tasks. We demonstrate how to build a secure, scalable, and efficient infrastructure using AWS Deep Learning Containers (DLCs) on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-and-deploy-meta-llama-3-2-vision-for-generative-ai-powered-web-automation-using-aws-dlcs-amazon-eks-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire 9.4 is here with a CLI and interactive dashboard features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we released .NET Aspire 9.4, our biggest release ever, bringing new integrations, interactive dashboard-based inputs, and a standalone, native AOT command line tool for creating and running Aspirified apps. We also published our first roadmap last week, which outl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-aspire-9-4 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft build of Go 1.25 crypto backend changes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 16:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting in Go 1.25, the Microsoft build of Go will default to using system-provided cryptography: OpenSSL on Linux and CNG on Windows. The systemcrypto GOEXPERIMENT will be enabled by default and picks the supported backend for the target platform.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/microsoft-go-defaults-to-system-crypto 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate modernization and cloud migration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 16:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our recent report, we describe that many enterprises today face a stark reality: despite years of digital transformation efforts, the majority of enterprise workloads—up to 80%—still run on legacy systems. This lag in modernization not only increases operational costs and security risks but also limits the agility needed to compete in a rapidly evolving...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/accelerate-modernization-and-cloud-migration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retiring Docker Content Trust</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 16:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Content Trust (DCT) was introduced 10 years ago as a way to verify the integrity and publisher of container images using The Update Framework (TUF) and the Notary v1 project. However, the upstream Notary codebase is no longer actively maintained and the ecosystem has since moved toward newer tools for image signing and verification....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/retiring-docker-content-trust/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip 2025.2: Database Object Context in the AI Chat, Introspection by Levels for PostgreSQL and MS SQL Server, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 15:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2025.2 introduces a set of new features to elevate your development experience. In this version, introspection by levels is now supported for PostgreSQL and Microsoft SQL Server, giving you greater control over the metadata loaded for these databases. For PostgreSQL, a smart refresh mechanism has been implemented to significantly reduce the time spent refreshing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/07/29/datagrip-2025-2-database-object-context-in-the-ai-chat-introspection-by-levels-for-postgresql-and-ms-sql-server-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Live: Visual Studio Toolbox at VS LIVE! Redmond 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 15:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join Robert Green and Leslie Richardson for a full day of live sessions, demos, and interviews. Live from Microsoft HQ – Stream Tuesday’s Sessions with Visual Studio Toolbox! On Tuesday, August 5, join us for a special edition of Visual Studio Toolbox Live—broadcast f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/watch-live-visual-studio-toolbox-at-vs-live-redmond-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling generative AI in the cloud: Enterprise use cases for driving secure innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our technical guide, “Accelerating Generative AI Innovation with Cloud Migration” we outline how IT and digital transformation leaders can tap into the power and flexibility of Azure to unlock the full potential of generative AI. The post Scaling generative AI in the cloud: Enterprise use cases for driving secure innovation appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/scaling-generative-ai-in-the-cloud-enterprise-use-cases-for-driving-secure-innovation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Nippon India Mutual Fund improved the accuracy of AI assistant responses using advanced RAG methods on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 14:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we examine a solution adopted by Nippon Life India Asset Management Limited that improves the accuracy of the response over a regular (naive) RAG approach by rewriting the user queries and aggregating and reranking the responses. The proposed solution uses enhanced RAG methods such as reranking to improve the overall accuracy
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-nippon-india-mutual-fund-improved-the-accuracy-of-ai-assistant-responses-using-advanced-rag-methods-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a window with no name blocking Windows shutdown?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you try to shut down Windows, and there&#39;s a program that is not allowing the shutdown to proceed, then the Blocked Shutdown Resolver (BSDR) shows a list of windows that includes the one that is processing the shutdown notification, as well as
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250729-00/?p=111417 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog: Building and Scaling AI Agents – Join Our Livestream Series</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 13:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you ready to dive into the world of AI agents and create your own from scratch? We’ve got just the thing for you! Join us this August for a two-part livestream series about Koog, JetBrains’ open-source agentic framework that empowers developers to build AI agents entirely in Kotlin. Whether you’re a Kotlin developer or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/07/koog-building-and-scaling-ai-agents-join-our-livestream-series/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains x ICPC: The 2024–2025 Season at a Glance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 12:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has long supported the International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC), one of the world’s most respected competitive programming contests. Since 2017, we’ve been the ICPC Global Programming Tools Sponsor, providing professional IDEs such as IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, and CLion, along with Kotlin, one of the official ICPC programming languages. We’ve been expanding our reach: Last […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/07/29/jetbrains-icpc-2024-2025-season/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Python: Unlocking the Python Global Interpreter Lock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 10:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is Python’s Global Interpreter Lock (GIL)? “Global Interpreter Lock” (or “GIL”) is a familiar term in the Python community. It is a well-known Python feature. But what exactly is a GIL? If you have experience with other programming languages (Rust, for example), you may already know what a mutex is. It’s an abbreviation for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/07/faster-python-unlocking-the-python-global-interpreter-lock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing study mode in ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing study mode in ChatGPT, a new learning experience that helps you work through problems step by step, guiding students with questions, scaffolding, and feedback for deeper learning.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/chatgpt-study-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running one-off .NET tools with dnx: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show the new dnx command for running .NET tools without installing them and look at exactly how it works.
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-5-running-one-off-dotnet-tools-with-dnx/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Claude Code Effectively: A Step-by-Step Method to Avoid Getting Lost</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use Claude Code effectively without getting lost. Complete guide with proven prompts, TDD methodology, and step-by-step workflow for complex projects. Avoid AI context drift
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/claude-code-effective-method-avoid-getting-lost/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ship, Share, and Win: The Kotlin Multiplatform Award at Shipaton 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 07:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s nothing quite like the thrill of shipping an app and turning an idea into something real that people can use. This summer, you’ve got the perfect chance to capture that feeling at RevenueCat Shipaton 2025 — a two-month global hackathon focused on launching new mobile apps (August 1 to September 30). And for Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/kmp-shipaton/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Source Generators in C#: Real-World Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 08:16:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tired of writing the same class scaffolding over and over? Annoyed by how much time you spend on &amp;quot;glue code&amp;quot; instead of actual features? You&#39;re not alone. Imagine if the C# compiler does this on your behalf every time, perfectly. Let me introduce you to C#
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/exploring-source-generators-in-c-real-world-examples/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build your own Static Code Analysis tool in .NET by knowing how Assembly, Type, MethodInfo, ParameterInfo work.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why buy a whole tool when you can build your own? Learn how the Type system works in .NET, and create your own minimal type analyser.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/assembly-type-methodinfo-parameterinfo/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Chatbot: Event-Driven Agents in Action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker recently completed an internal 24-hour hackathon that had a fairly simple goal: create an agent that helps you be more productive. As I thought about this topic, I recognized I didn&#39;t want to spend more time in a chat interface. Why can&#39;t I create a fully automated agent that doesn’t need a human to...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/beyond-the-chatbot-event-driven-agents-in-action/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 20:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shares the details of the latest changes to the Azure Developer CLI (azd) in release 1.17.1 and 1.18.0. We invite you to join our July release discussion on GitHub with questions and comments. This month&#39;s release focuses on enhancing developer experien
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a drug discovery research assistant using Strands Agents and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 19:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to create a powerful research assistant for drug discovery using Strands Agents and Amazon Bedrock. This AI assistant can search multiple scientific databases simultaneously using the Model Context Protocol (MCP), synthesize its findings, and generate comprehensive reports on drug targets, disease mechanisms, and therapeutic areas.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-drug-discovery-research-assistant-using-strands-agents-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Nova Act SDK (preview): Path to production for browser automation agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 17:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we’ll walk through what makes Nova Act SDK unique, how it works, and how teams across industries are already using it to automate browser-based workflows at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-nova-act-sdk-preview-path-to-production-for-browser-automation-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing enterprise AI assistants: How Crypto.com uses LLM reasoning and feedback for enhanced efficiency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 17:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Crypto.com used user and system feedback to continuously improve and optimize our instruction prompts. This feedback-driven approach has enabled us to create more effective prompts that adapt to various subsystems while maintaining high performance across different use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-enterprise-ai-assistants-how-crypto-com-uses-llm-reasoning-and-feedback-for-enhanced-efficiency/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build modern serverless solutions following best practices using Amazon Q Developer CLI and MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 17:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how the AWS Serverless MCP server accelerates development throughout the serverless lifecycle, from making architectural decisions with tools like get_iac_guidance and get_lambda_guidance, to streamlining development with get_serverless_templates, sam_init, to deployment with SAM integration, webapp_deployment_help, and configure_domain. We show how this conversational AI approach transforms the entire process, from architecture design through operations, dramatically accelerating AWS serverless projects while adhering to architectural principles.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-modern-serverless-solutions-following-best-practices-using-amazon-q-developer-cli-and-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Learn MCP Series Recap: 8 Languages, 4 Code Bases, Full Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) has quickly established itself as the go-to standard for seamlessly connecting AI agents with a variety of external tools and services. In just a few months, it has become a prominent topic at developer events and forums, gaining adoption from companies of all sizes. To meet the rapid pace of advancements, we
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//lets-learn-mcp-series-recap-8-languages-4-code-bases-full-resources 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API design note: Don&#39;t make up multiple names for the same thing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recurring problem I encounter when reviewing API proposals is that teams tend not to be precise in their use of terminology. This casualness is inevitable when you work with a feature for a long time and develop notational shortcuts, but the people who are learning your API don&#39;t have the same level of familiarity that you do, and shiftin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250728-00/?p=111415 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Tool-Calling Becomes an Addiction: Debugging LLM Patterns in Koog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 13:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was testing my agent built on Koog, JetBrains’ open-source framework for building AI agents in Kotlin. I fed it a task from SWE-bench-Verified, a real-world GitHub issue that tests whether AI can actually write code. For the first 100 messages, everything looked promising. The agent methodically explored the codebase, identified bugs, wrote test cases, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/07/when-tool-calling-becomes-an-addiction-debugging-llm-patterns-in-koog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling multi-tenant Go applications: Choosing the right database partitioning approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Multi-tenant applications face a fundamental challenge: how to efficiently store and query data for tenants of vastly different sizes? Consider the typical scenario where your platform serves both enterprise clients with hundreds of thousands of users, as well as small businesses with just a handful. With traditional database partitioning stra
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/scaling-multi-tenant-go-applications-choosing-the-right-database-partitioning-approach 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Exercises to Learn Rust: RustRover Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 12:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mainmatter’s Luca Palmieri’s 100 Exercises to Learn Rust have helped thousands of developers deepen their Rust skills. Now this outstanding course is available right inside RustRover, JetBrains’ powerful Rust IDE! That means no setup headaches and no switching between websites and terminals – just hands-on Rust practice with full IDE support. In this post, I’ll […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/07/28/rust-exercises-rustrover/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interprocedural Analysis: Catch nil Dereferences Before They Crash Your Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 12:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The upcoming GoLand 2025.2 release introduces a powerful set of new features and improvements designed to help you write safer, more reliable Go code. If you’d like a full breakdown of all the updates, be sure to check out the release notes. In this post, we’ll focus on one of the most significant new features: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/07/28/interprocedural-analysis-catch-nil-dereferences-before-they-crash-your-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Remote Closer to Local: 2025.2 Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 10:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our goal is to make remote development with JetBrains IDEs feel just as reliable and consistent as working locally does. Recently, we’ve made progress towards this goal in core areas like the editor, tool windows, plugin behavior, and settings synchronization. Editor All the changes made to the editor in the 2025.2 release are based on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/07/bringing-remote-closer-to-local-2025-2-highlights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Tracking Improvements in Marten</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2025/27_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 21:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2025/27_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We just released a new batch of improvements in the Marten 8.4 release that improved Marten‘s already strong support for tracking metadata on event persistence. Override Event Metadata on Individual Events This work was done at the behest of a JasperFx Software client. They only needed to vary header values between events, but while the … Continue reading Metadata Tracking Improvements in Marten →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/07/27/metadata-tracking-improvements-in-marten/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Enhance Drive Management with DriveHelper in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2025/27_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2025/27_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Microsoft .NET, managing files and directories can lead to errors. The Spargine library, featuring the DriveHelper class, simplifies this task with methods to retrieve drive information and manage drives. Additional utility types, like DirectoryHelper and FileProcessor, enhance file and path management, improving efficiency and reliability in .NET applications.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/27/boost-your-net-projects-enhance-drive-management-with-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Mentors As A Junior Software Engineer - Dev Leader Weekly 103</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how junior software engineers can approach finding mentorship!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/26/finding-mentors-as-a-junior-software-engineer-dev-leader-weekly-103 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-07-25</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 05:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/26/weekly-recap-20250725 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Named Query Filters in EF 10 (multiple query filters per entity)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            EF 10 introduces named query filters, allowing multiple filters on a single entity and letting you selectively disable specific filters without turning off all query filters. This article explains how the feature works, shows practical examples for combining soft deletion and multi-tenancy, highlights best practices like using constants for filter names, and explores where such fine-grained control is particularly useful.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/named-query-filters-in-ef-10-multiple-query-filters-per-entity 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Container Options: Matching Services to Operational Responsibility</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customers are looking to modernize their application on cloud and ask us for guidance on which Azure container services to choose. Should you choose A or B container services or A+B container services? Some choose both (A + B) or use A or B appr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/azure-container-options-matching-services-to-operational-responsibility 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Data Governance &amp; Compliance with UDM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 20:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why Data Governance Matters In today’s data-driven world, governance isn’t just a technical requirement—it’s foundational to successful business operations. Good governance ensures data is not only accurate and compliant but also discoverable and usable at scale. At the heart of this approach lies robust, high-quality meta
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/udm/scalable-data-governance-compliance-with-udm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent eDiscovery solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 17:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build an intelligent eDiscovery solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents for real-time document analysis. We show how to deploy specialized agents for document classification, contract analysis, email review, and legal document processing, all working together through a multi-agent architecture. We walk through the implementation details, deployment steps, and best practices to create an extensible foundation that organizations can adapt to their specific eDiscovery requirements.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PerformLine uses prompt engineering on Amazon Bedrock to detect compliance violations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 17:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PerformLine operates within the marketing compliance industry, a specialized subset of the broader compliance software market, which includes various compliance solutions like anti-money laundering (AML), know your customer (KYC), and others. In this post, PerformLine and AWS explore how PerformLine used Amazon Bedrock to accelerate compliance processes, generate actionable insights, and provide contextual data—delivering the speed and accuracy essential for large-scale oversight.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-performline-uses-prompt-engineering-on-amazon-bedrock-to-detect-compliance-violations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.9 RC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 16:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the Release Candidate (RC) of TypeScript 5.9! To get started using the Release Candidate, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@rc Let&#39;s take a look at what&#39;s new
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-9-rc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Migration Strategies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 14:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Database migrations gone wrong. You deploy a new feature in your app and suddenly half of it breaks. You start digging through your logs and realize it’s a database schema change that’s causing all the issues. Now you’re scrambling, wondering if you can roll back your code changes. Nope, the damage is done. You have… Read More »Database Migration Strategies The post Database Migration Strategies appeared first on CodeOpinion.
Link to article: https://codeopinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I confirm in the Windows debugger that I&#39;m looking at a COMDAT-folded function?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, we learned about identical COMDAT folding (and also
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250725-00/?p=111409 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Changes to JetBrains .NET Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re making some changes to our .NET tools, and we want to give you an overview of what’s happening and the reasons behind the changes. Some features you might be using are being discontinued or transformed, while others are getting significant refinements. We believe that these changes will allow us to build better tools for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/25/upcoming-changes-to-dotnet-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Manual Testing to AI-Generated Automation: Our Azure DevOps MCP &#43; Playwright Success Story</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 06:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced software development cycles, manual testing often becomes a significant bottleneck. Our team was facing a growing backlog of test cases that required repetitive manual execution—running the entire test suite every sprint. This consumed valuable time that could be better spent on exploratory testing and higher-value
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/from-manual-testing-to-ai-generated-automation-our-azure-devops-mcp-playwright-success-story 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Microsoft.PowerShell.PlatyPS 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 21:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re pleased to announce the general availability (GA) release of Microsoft.PowerShell.PlatyPS v1.0.0. PlatyPS is the tool that Microsoft uses to create the PowerShell content you get from Get
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/announcing-platyps-100 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost cold-start recommendations with vLLM on AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 20:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use vLLM for scalable inference and use AWS Deep Learning Containers (DLC) to streamline model packaging and deployment. We’ll generate interest expansions through structured prompts, encode them into embeddings, retrieve candidates with FAISS, apply validation to keep results grounded, and frame the cold-start challenge as a scientific experiment—benchmarking LLM and encoder pairings, iterating rapidly on recommendation metrics, and showing clear ROI for each configuration
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Amazon Nova: A comprehensive analysis through MT-Bench and Arena-Hard-Auto</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The repositories for MT-Bench and Arena-Hard were originally developed using OpenAI’s GPT API, primarily employing GPT-4 as the judge. Our team has expanded its functionality by integrating it with the Amazon Bedrock API to enable using Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet on Amazon as judge. In this post, we use both MT-Bench and Arena-Hard to benchmark Amazon Nova models by comparing them to other leading LLMs available through Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example of Using Alba for HTTP Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Before Marten took off and we pivoted to using the “Critter Stack” naming motif, the original naming theme for the JasperFx OSS tool suite were some of the small towns near where I grew up in Southwest Missouri. Alba, MO is somewhat famous as the hometown of the Boyer brothers. I’m taking a little time … Continue reading Example of Using Alba for HTTP Testing →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/07/24/example-of-using-alba-for-http-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I wait until a named object (say a mutex) is created?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer used a named mutex as a way to detect that another instance of the program is already running. This is pretty standard. They also used the presence of the mutex to indicate that the program is ready to receive work requests: When the program creates the mutex, this prevents new instances from running, and it also announce
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250724-00/?p=111406 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.2 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper and .NET tools 2025.2 Release Candidates are ready for you to try. This release introduces the public preview of ReSharper’s Out-of-Process mode, adds support for the latest C# 14 and C++26 features, and brings a range of improvements for performance, refactorings, and inspections. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/24/resharper-dot-net-tools-2025-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2025.2 Release Candidate Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2025.2 is shaping up to be a big release – especially if you’re a game developer. This update introduces powerful new debugging features for Unity, Unreal Engine, and Godot, including source-level shader debugging, mixed-mode debugging for native and managed code, and stepping time improvements. Beyond game dev, Rider 2025.2 delivers a range of enhancements […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/24/the-rider-2025-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in TeamCity 2025.07: Public Recipes, Pipelines, Dependency Control, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 11:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the launch of TeamCity 2025.07! This release brings a range of improvements across the UI, Perforce integration, recipes, and more. It is also the first version to include pipelines: a reimagined TeamCity experience that focuses on a healthy balance of functionality and an intuitive design-first workflow. Read on to learn what’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/07/teamcity-202507/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Combine MP4 Files on Windows Using FFmpeg</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Merging multiple MP4 files into one can be useful when working with ripped DVDs, split movie parts, or recorded gameplay. On Windows, the…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/combine-mp4-files-ffmpeg-windows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving digital threats 100x faster with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Outtake uses GPT-4.1 and OpenAI o3 to power AI agents that detect and resolve digital threats 100x faster than before.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/outtake 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
