<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 13:00:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid AI Isn’t the Future — It’s Here (and It Runs in Docker)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running large AI models in the cloud gives access to immense capabilities, but it doesn’t come for free. The bigger the models, the bigger the bills, and with them, the risk of unexpected costs. Local models flip the equation. They safeguard privacy and keep costs predictable, but their smaller size often limits what you can...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hybrid-ai-and-how-it-runs-in-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Sense of Your Output Window with Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever found yourself staring at the Output Window, overwhelmed by endless lines of logs and cryptic messages? You&#39;re
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/make-sense-of-your-output-window-with-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Annotation Handling in Kotlin 2.2: Less Boilerplate, Fewer Surprises</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 11:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many developers have run into subtle issues with annotations when working with Kotlin and frameworks like Spring or JPA-based persistence frameworks. For instance, an annotation applied to a constructor parameter might not always end up in the property or backing field where the framework expects it. This often means annotations don’t land where they’re needed. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/improved-annotation-handling-in-kotlin-2-2-less-boilerplate-fewer-surprises/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Test Run Hub in Azure Test Plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 09:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Delivering high-quality software is a necessity and that’s why Azure Test Plans has introduced the all-new Test Run Hub, an enabler for teams who want to take control of their testing process and drive continuous improvement.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-test-run-hub 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v1.1 with improved support for Microsoft Graph batching</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 07:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the release of Dev Proxy v1.1. This update delivers critical fixes for Microsoft Graph batch request simulation, resolves authentication plugin issues, and enhances the MinimalPermissionsGuidancePlugin with new reporting capabilities. In this version: Fixed Microsoft Graph batch response handling
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v1-1-with-improved-support-for-microsoft-graph-batching 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.1-1 and 1.24.7-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 03:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-1-1-and-1-24-7-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Stream Previewing Wolverine 5.0 on Thursday</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 01:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ll be doing a live stream tomorrow (Thursday) August 4th to preview some of the new improvements coming soon with Wolverine 5.0. The highlights are: And of course anything else folks want to discuss on the live stream as well. Check it out here, and the recording will be up later tomorrow anyway:
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/03/live-stream-previewing-wolverine-5-0-on-thursday/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let Copilot Coding Agent handle the busy work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The GitHub Copilot Coding Agent changes how .NET developers get work done. Beyond inline suggestions, it can analyze your repo, plan multi‑step tasks, create issues and pull requests, and carry changes across projects—all in the cloud. In this post, we’ll show two concrete scenarios using the eShopLite sample: automatically creating miss
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/copilot-coding-agent-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are Doing MCP Wrong: 3 Big Misconceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MCP is not an API. Tools are not agents. MCP is more than tools. Here’s what this means in practice. Most developers misread the Model Context Protocol because they map it onto familiar API mental models. That mistake breaks agent designs, observability, and the “last mile” where non-deterministic reasoning must meet deterministic execution. This piece...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-misconceptions-tools-agents-not-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticate Amazon Q Business data accessors using a trusted token issuer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showed how to implement TTI authentication for Amazon Q data accessors. We covered the setup process for both ISVs and enterprises and demonstrated how TTI authentication simplifies the user experience while maintaining security standards.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/authenticate-amazon-q-business-data-accessors-using-a-trusted-token-issuer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the future of professional services: How Proofpoint uses Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Proofpoint has redefined its professional services by integrating Amazon Q Business, a fully managed, generative AI powered assistant that you can configure to answer questions, provide summaries, generate content, and complete tasks based on your enterprise data. In this post, we explore how Amazon Q Business transformed Proofpoint’s professional services, detailing its deployment, functionality, and future roadmap.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-the-future-of-professional-services-how-proofpoint-uses-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing LLM accuracy with Coveo Passage Retrieval on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to deploy Coveo’s Passage Retrieval API as an Amazon Bedrock Agents action group to enhance response accuracy, so Coveo users can use their current index to rapidly deploy new generative experiences across their organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhancing-llm-accuracy-with-coveo-passage-retrieval-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in Azure AI Foundry | August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Models: GPT‑5 family now in Azure AI Foundry (gpt‑5 requires registration; launch regions: East US 2, Sweden Central). Also new: Sora API updates (image→video, inpainting; Global Standard in East US 2 and Sweden Central), Mistral Document AI (OCR), Black Forest Labs FLUX.1 Kontext [pro] and FLUX1.1 [pro],
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/whats-new-in-azure-ai-foundry-august-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I write a C&#43;&#43;/WinRT &lt;CODE&gt;IAsyncOperation&lt;T&gt;&lt;/CODE&gt; where &lt;CODE&gt;T&lt;/CODE&gt; is not a Windows Runtime type?, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I often get asked about how one could use C++/WinRT&#39;s IAsyncOperation where T is not a Windows Runtime type. The T in IAsyncOperation must be a Windows Runtime type because the algorithm for generating an interface ID for IAsyncOperation work
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250903-00/?p=111546 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Vulnerable API Detection in JetBrains IDEs and Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 08:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the start of the year, we announced a partnership with Mend.io to maximize code security in JetBrains tools. The partnership provided us with quality data about vulnerable and malicious packages, allowing our IDEs and Qodana to spot them for you in your projects. Over the last few months, we have been working on integrating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/enhanced-vulnerable-api-detection-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Vector Search with OneLake Indexer and OpenAI Integration in Microsoft Fabric</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our team works with customer solutions that integrate AI into data solutions. Some time ago, this post titled Fabric Change the Game: Unleashing the Power of Microsoft Fabric and OpenAI for Datase
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/msfabric-and-openai-for-dataset 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train and deploy models on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod using the new HyperPod CLI and SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use the new Amazon SageMaker HyperPod CLI and SDK to streamline the process of training and deploying large AI models through practical examples of distributed training using Fully Sharded Data Parallel (FSDP) and model deployment for inference. The tools provide simplified workflows through straightforward commands for common tasks, while offering flexible development options through the SDK for more complex requirements, along with comprehensive observability features and production-ready deployment capabilities.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless Amazon Bedrock batch job orchestration workflow using AWS Step Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce a flexible and scalable solution that simplifies the batch inference workflow. This solution provides a highly scalable approach to managing your FM batch inference needs, such as generating embeddings for millions of documents or running custom evaluation or completion tasks with large datasets.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-amazon-bedrock-batch-job-orchestration-workflow-using-aws-step-functions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural language-based database analytics with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how natural language database analytics can revolutionize the way organizations interact with their structured data through the power of large language model (LLM) agents. Natural language interfaces to databases have long been a goal in data management. Agents enhance database analytics by breaking down complex queries into explicit, verifiable reasoning steps and enabling self-correction through validation loops that can catch errors, analyze failures, and refine queries until they accurately match user intent and schema requirements.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases using Terraform for RAG-based generative AI applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrated how to automate the deployment of Amazon Knowledge Bases for RAG applications using Terraform.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-using-terraform-for-rag-based-generative-ai-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document intelligence evolved: Building and evaluating KIE solutions that scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we demonstrate an end-to-end approach for building and evaluating a KIE solution using Amazon Nova models available through Amazon Bedrock. This end-to-end approach encompasses three critical phases: data readiness (understanding and preparing your documents), solution development (implementing extraction logic with appropriate models), and performance measurement (evaluating accuracy, efficiency, and cost-effectiveness). We illustrate this comprehensive approach using the FATURA dataset—a collection of diverse invoice documents that serves as a representative proxy for real-world enterprise data.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the new cluster creation experience for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the new cluster creation experience, you can create your SageMaker HyperPod clusters, including the required prerequisite AWS resources, in one click, with prescriptive default values automatically applied. In this post, we explore the new cluster creation experience for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/announcing-the-new-cluster-creation-experience-for-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerToys 0.94 is here: Settings search, shortcut conflict detection and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 15:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/powertoys-0-94-is-here-settings-search-shortcut-conflict-detection-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Popular Python Frameworks and Libraries in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 15:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re building APIs, dashboards, or machine learning pipelines, choosing the right framework can make or break your project. Every year, we survey thousands of Python developers to help you understand how the ecosystem is evolving, from tooling and languages to frameworks and libraries. Our insights from the State of Python 2025 offer a snapshot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/09/the-most-popular-python-frameworks-and-libraries-in-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: Remembering passwords for recently-opened ZIP files</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A security vulnerability report arrived that claimed that it could obtain unauthorized access to a password-protected ZIP file by the following means: Start with a password-protected ZIP file, call it &amp;quot;secret.zip&amp;quot;. Create a dummy ZIP file and give it the same password. Call this file &amp;quot;attack&amp;quot;. Open atta
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250902-00/?p=111544 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your Copilot Collaboration with Reusable Prompt Files</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing effective prompts for AI tools can be time-consuming and challenging. Cement those efforts by leveraging reusable prompt files. These custom prompts allow for quick access at the prompt box, and they’re automatically stored and shared with your teammates to make it easy to multiply your Copilot s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/boost-your-copilot-collaboration-with-reusable-prompt-files 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | September 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 11:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The C# language has a GOTO statement? It sure does. This is a case of “just because you could doesn’t mean you should”. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 🌟 Featured Content This month’s featured content is from Chris Woodruff! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/02/dotinsights-september-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vijaye Raji to become CTO of Applications with acquisition of Statsig</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vijaye Raji will step into a new role as CTO of Applications, reporting to CEO of Applications, Fidji Simo, following the acquisition of Statsig.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/vijaye-raji-to-become-cto-of-applications-with-acquisition-of-statsig 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 10:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hold on to your helper methods – RubyMine is now FREE for non-commercial use! Whether you’re learning Ruby and Rails, pushing open-source forward, creating dev content, or building your passion project, we want to make sure you have the tools to enjoy what you do even more… for free. Another chapter in the story We […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/09/rubymine-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using and authoring .NET tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe some of the complexities around authoring .NET tools, specifically around supporting multiple .NET runtimes and testing in CI
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/using-and-authoring-dotnet-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing LINQ Queries with LINQPad: Boost Your EF Core Debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 08:04:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever feel exhausted debugging a complex EF Core query? Do you wonder what went wrong in the EF Core LINQ query spaghetti that hinders the results? At one end, EF Core and LINQ accelerate the development speed and make it easy to communicate with a database. However, its intermediate results
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/visualizing-linq-queries-with-linqpad-boost-your-ef-core-debugging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building more helpful ChatGPT experiences for everyone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re partnering with experts, strengthening protections for teens with parental controls, and routing sensitive conversations to reasoning models in ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/building-more-helpful-chatgpt-experiences-for-everyone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: injecting and testing the current time with TimeProvider and FakeTimeProvider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dates used to be difficult to test. But with TimeProvider and FakeTimeProvider, everything becomes possible!
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/timeprovider-faketimeprovider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Our Newest Innovators: Welcoming AI4SE Interns as JetBrains Employees!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 15:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picture this: You’re working on your MSc thesis as an intern in software engineering, not just as an academic exercise, but side-by-side with an industry team, tackling real projects and real problems, refining code, and witnessing your ideas come alive. By the time you’ve graduated, you’re already a valued team member, ready to hit the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/ai4se-interns-jetbrains-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enriching Microsoft 365 profiles with Microsoft 365 Copilot connectors for people data (public preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 14:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s workplace, employee data lives across multiple systems – HR databases, talent platforms, directories – making it hard to get a complete view of a person. Microsoft 365 Copilot connectors for people data (now in public preview) tackle this challenge by bringing external people data into Microsoft 365. A Mi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/enriching-microsoft-365-profiles-with-microsoft-365-copilot-connectors-for-people-data-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 16: Second attempt to use a list</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Commenter LB pointed out that you can use the splice method to move nodes between lists. So let&#39;s try that. The idea is that each tracking_ptr holds an iterator to a list node that is part of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250901-00/?p=111537 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The LSP API Is Now Available to All IntelliJ IDEA Users and Plugin Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 09:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The way developers create plugins implementing the Language Server Protocol (LSP) in JetBrains IDEs is undergoing a significant shift. With PyCharm and IntelliJ IDEA adopting a unified distribution model, we’re removing a key obstacle that has been limiting LSP adoption within the IntelliJ Platform ecosystem. Starting with IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate 2025.2, users can continue using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/the-lsp-api-is-now-available-to-all-intellij-idea-users-and-plugin-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Wolverine 5.0 Work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2025/31_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 22:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2025/31_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A couple weeks back I posted about some upcoming feature work in Wolverine that might push us to call it “5.0” even though Wolverine 4.0 is only three months old. Despite the obvious issues with quickly cranking out yet another major point release, the core team &amp;amp; I mostly came down on the side of … Continue reading Update on Wolverine 5.0 Work →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/08/31/update-on-wolverine-5-0-work/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Find the Fastest Way to Get an Item’s Index in Arrays</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2025/31_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2025/31_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article examines the performance of three index-finding methods in .NET arrays: Array.BinarySearch (O(log n)), Array.FindIndex (O(n)), and Array.IndexOf (O(n)).
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/08/31/boost-your-net-projects-find-the-fastest-way-to-get-an-items-index-in-arrays/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fearlessly Ask Stupid Questions - Dev Leader Weekly 107</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2025/30_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2025/30_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how asking stupid questions contributes to a stronger engineering culture.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/30/fearlessly-ask-stupid-questions-dev-leader-weekly-107 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-08-29</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2025/30_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 05:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2025/30_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/30/weekly-recap-20250829 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standalone Aspire Dashboard Setup for Distributed .NET Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2025/30_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2025/30_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to run the Aspire Dashboard as a standalone container for instant traces, logs, and metrics in your .NET applications.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/standalone-aspire-dashboard-setup-for-distributed-dotnet-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Graph Toolkit retirement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 20:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are announcing the deprecation of the Microsoft Graph Toolkit (MGT). The retirement period begins September 1st, 2025 with full retirement planned for August 28th, 2026. Why we’re retiri
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-graph-toolkit-retirement 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Graph CLI retirement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 19:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are announcing the retirement of the Microsoft Graph command-line interface (CLI). The Microsoft Graph CLI has served as a powerful tool for developers and IT professionals to interact with Microsoft Graph through simple terminal commands—enabling automation, scripting, and streamli
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-graph-cli-retirement 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPC World Finals Livestream: ecnerwala and SecondThread Speed-Solving Kotlin Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 19:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us live from the ICPC World Finals in Baku, Azerbaijan, for a special event. This year, we are hosting a head-to-head match where two of the world’s top competitive programmers, Andrew ‘ecnerwala’ He and David ‘SecondThread’ Harmeyer, will speed-solve Kotlin problems in real time. Save the date: September 2, 2025, at 9:30 am UTC […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/icpc-world-finals-livestream-ecnerwala-secondthread-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect Amazon Bedrock misconfigurations with Datadog Cloud Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce new security capabilities in Datadog Cloud Security that can help you detect and remediate Amazon Bedrock misconfigurations before they become security incidents. This integration helps organizations embed robust security controls and secure their use of the powerful capabilities of Amazon Bedrock by offering three critical advantages: holistic AI security by integrating AI security into your broader cloud security strategy, real-time risk detection through identifying potential AI-related security issues as they emerge, and simplified compliance to help meet evolving AI regulations with pre-built detections.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up custom domain names for Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to create custom domain names for your Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime agent endpoints using CloudFront as a reverse proxy. This solution provides several key benefits: simplified integration for development teams, custom domains that align with your organization, cleaner infrastructure abstraction, and straightforward maintenance when endpoints need updates.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/set-up-custom-domain-names-for-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing auto scaling on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we announce that Amazon SageMaker HyperPod now supports managed node automatic scaling with Karpenter, enabling efficient scaling of SageMaker HyperPod clusters to meet inference and training demands. We dive into the benefits of Karpenter and provide details on enabling and configuring Karpenter in SageMaker HyperPod EKS clusters.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-auto-scaling-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SQL Server&#39;s new AI features and Python to create a T-SQL assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Guest Post&amp;quot;]Rodrigo Ribeiro Gomes, Head of Innovation at Power Tuning, has been leveraging the new AI features in SQL Server engine to simplify the lives of DBAs and developers. He generously shared his experience with us: thank you, Rodrigo![/alert] I recently created a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/using-sql-servers-new-ai-features-and-python-to-create-a-t-sql-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 15: A custom shared pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we made our trackable object implementation&#39;s constructors and assignment operations non-throwing, although it came at a cost of making
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250829-00/?p=111526 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your Copilot with SonarQube via Docker MCP Toolkit and Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the era of AI copilots and code generation tools productivity is skyrocketing, but so is the risk of insecure, untested, or messy code slipping into production. How do you ensure it doesn’t introduce vulnerabilities, bugs, or bad practices? A widely adopted tool to help address these concerns is SonarQube. It provides a rich set...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/blog-sonarqube-copilot-docker-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 09:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 – v2025.2.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Boti: The AI assistant transforming how the citizens of Buenos Aires access government information with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes the agentic AI assistant built by the Government of the City of Buenos Aires and the GenAIIC to respond to citizens’ questions about government procedures. The solution consists of two primary components: an input guardrail system that helps prevent the system from responding to harmful user queries and a government procedures agent that retrieves relevant information and generates responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/meet-boti-the-ai-assistant-transforming-how-the-citizens-of-buenos-aires-access-government-information-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering air quality research with secure, ML-driven predictive analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a data imputation solution using Amazon SageMaker AI, AWS Lambda, and AWS Step Functions. This solution is designed for environmental analysts, public health officials, and business intelligence professionals who need reliable PM2.5 data for trend analysis, reporting, and decision-making. We sourced our sample training dataset from openAFRICA. Our solution predicts PM2.5 values using time-series forecasting.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/empowering-air-quality-research-with-secure-ml-driven-predictive-analytics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Finance built an AI assistant using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Kendra to support analysts for data discovery and business insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Amazon Finance technical team develops and manages comprehensive technology solutions that power financial decision-making and operational efficiency while standardizing across Amazon’s global operations. In this post, we explain how the team conceptualized and implemented a solution to these business challenges by harnessing the power of generative AI using Amazon Bedrock and intelligent search with Amazon Kendra.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-finance-built-an-ai-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-kendra-to-support-analysts-for-data-discovery-and-business-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with the Aspire CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Aspire CLI is a powerful, cross-platform tool designed to streamline the development, management, and deployment of application systems. Whether you’re building a simple website or an enterprise-scale distributed application with microservices and queues and databases, the Aspire CLI offers an interactive-first experience to help you cre
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/getting-started-with-the-aspire-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Awesome Copilot MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re excited to announce the Awesome Copilot MCP Server - a simple way to search those customizations and save them directly to your repository from the MCP server. In early July, we announced the community-driven Awesome GitHub Co
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/announcing-awesome-copilot-mcp-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 16:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released another update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 – v2025.1.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-1-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 14: Nonthrowing moves with the shared tracking pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So far, we&#39;ve been working on an alternate design for tracking pointers, but we found that it had the unfortunate property of having potentially-throwing constructors and m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250828-00/?p=111524 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bob’s Used Books: Build a .NET Serverless Application on AWS – Part 2: Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 13:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This post covers the architecture and components of a modern .NET serverless application, demonstrating implementation patterns for authentication, data storage, image processing, and API management that showcase the optimization benefits of this architecture. AWS serverless architecture provides improved scalability, cost-efficiency, and reduced operational overhead. Part 1 of this series focused on initial setup and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/bobs-used-books-build-a-net-serverless-application-on-aws-part-2-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure by Design: A Shift-Left Approach with Testcontainers, Docker Scout, and Hardened Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced world of software development, product teams are expected to move quickly: building features, shipping updates, and reacting to user needs in real-time. But moving fast should never mean compromising on quality or security. Thanks to modern tooling, developers can now maintain high standards while accelerating delivery. In a previous article, we explored...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/a-shift-left-approach-with-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing gpt-realtime and Realtime API updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re releasing a more advanced speech-to-speech model and new API capabilities including MCP server support, image input, and SIP phone calling support.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-realtime 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog 0.4.0 Is Out: Observable, Predictable, and Deployable Anywhere You Build</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 09:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Featuring Langfuse and W&amp;amp;B Weave Support, Ktor Integration, Native Structured Output, iOS Target, GPT-5, and More. Koog 0.3.0 was about making agents smarter and persistent. Koog 0.4.0 is about making them observable, seamlessly deployable in your stack, and more predictable in their outputs – all while introducing support for new models and platforms. Read on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/08/koog-0-4-0-is-out-observable-predictable-and-deployable-anywhere-you-build/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper’s New Out-of-Process Engine Cuts UI Freezes in Visual Studio by 80%</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio power users love ReSharper’s deep analysis, but the cost has been the occasional UI hiccup that breaks the flow of work. In ReSharper 2025.2, analysis runs in a separate 64-bit worker out of Visual Studio’s UI process. Previously, ReSharper shared Visual Studio’s UI process, so long analyses could stall the UI thread. Now, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/28/resharper-s-new-out-of-process-engine-cuts-ui-freezes-in-visual-studio-by-80/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting nonprofit and community innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI launches a $50M People-First AI Fund to help U.S. nonprofits scale impact with AI. Applications open Sept 8–Oct 8, 2025 for grants in education, healthcare, research, and more.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/supporting-nonprofit-and-community-innovation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
