<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Optimizing Sequence Comparison</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses different methods for comparing two collections for identity in programming. It introduces the use of the SequenceEqual() method for comparing sequences in the LINQ extension methods, as well as the StructuralSequenceEqual() method, which is beneficial for comparing custom classes based on the values of their elements rather than object references.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/13/collection-performance-optimizing-sequence-comparison/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>无障碍应用程序之旅：键盘可访问性和 .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 07:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Rachel Kang (SHE/HER) 的 The Journey to Accessible Apps: Keyboard Accessibility and .NET MAUI 首先让我们一起来看看您的应用程序是否支持键盘访问： 启动您的其中一个应用。 如果您的设备尚未连接物理键盘，请连接物理键盘。 像平常一样导航您的应用程序，并且仅使用键盘来执行此操作。 这次体验如何？是否轻松？是否与您通常使用应用程序的体验相匹配？ 确保您的应用程序体验在仅通过键盘导航时同样出色，这对于构建一个对所有人都包容且可访问的应用程序体验至关重要。 Web内容可访问性指南 (WCAG) 若要了解键盘可访问性的详细信息，可以从 Web 内容可访问性指南 (WCAG) 开始。 WCAG 是一组针对 Web 可访问性的技术标准，被广泛引用，并扩展到 Web 以外的各种应用程序和平台。 它已成为全球标准和法律基准，并随着技术的发展而不断发展。 在各种指南中，有一个经常被忽视的是指南第2.1条，该指南表明开发人员应“使所有功能可通过键盘访问”。 这包括四个成功标准： 成功标准 2.1.1 键盘 内容的所有功能都可以通过键盘界面操作，而无需对单个按键的时间进行特定的控制，除非底层功能需要依赖用户移动路径而不仅仅是端点的输入。 成功标准 2.1.2 无键盘陷阱 如果您可以使用键盘界面将键盘焦点移动到页面的某个组件，那么您只需使用键盘界面就可以将焦点从该组件移开，并且如果它需要的不仅仅是未修改的箭头或 Tab 键或其他标准退出方法，则用户会被告知移动焦点的方法。 成功标准 2.1.3 键盘（无例外） 内容的所有功能都可以通过键盘界面进行操作，无需为各个按键分配特定的时间。 成功标准 2.1.4 字符快捷键 如果您在仅使用字母(包括大写和小写字母)、标点符号、数字或符号字符的内容中实现键盘快捷键，则至少满足以下条件之一： 关闭 有一种机制可以关闭快捷方式； 重新映射 有一种机制可以重新映射快捷键，使其包含一个或多个不可打印的键盘键（例如 Ctrl、Alt）； 仅在焦点上活动 用户界面组件的键盘快捷键仅在该组件具有焦点时活动。 对这些标准的基本理解将有助于您开始开发键盘可访问的应用程序。 键盘可访问性和 .NET MAUI 除了各种其他考虑因素之外，.NET MAUI的设计目标之一是实现更轻松地开发键盘可访问的体验。 因此，熟悉Xamarin.Forms键盘行为的开发人员注意到了一些改进，以提高他们应用程序中的键盘可访问性。 对于可通过键盘界面操作的所有功能，所有交互式控件都必须是键盘可聚焦的（可以接收键盘焦点）和键盘可导航的（可以使用键盘进行导航）。 这也包括避免让不可见的内容键盘可访问。 正如我们应该期望可见控件可以通过键盘进行聚焦和导航一样，我们应该期望不可见/不存在的控件无法通过键盘访问或呈现。 为了避免键盘陷阱，我们确保可以通过键盘导航进入、内部和外部当前视图内的所有相关控件。 例如，如果您导航具有多个 CollectionView 的屏幕，.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Call an Action From Another Controller in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 06:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to call an action from another controller in .NET MVC. We sometimes need to call an action method from another action method within the same controller or a different controller class. So, let’s see how to do that. Why We Need to Call the Action From Another Controller? […] The post How to Call an Action From Another Controller in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SonarCloud with ASP.NET Core, Angular and github actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 05:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article demonstrates how to implement code analysis and Static Application Security Testing (SAST) using SonarCloud and GitHub Actions. The solution involves building a secure web application with ASP.NET Core for the backend and an Angular UI for the frontend, following a backend-for-frontend security architecture. Both the ASP.NET Core (C#) codebase and the Angular (TypeScript […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/05/13/using-sonarcloud-with-asp-net-core-angular-and-github-actions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2024/12_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2024/12_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore how to integrate the Azure Storage SDK into a .NET application. We’ll cover the steps to read and write blobs from Azure Storage, and we’ll also discuss how to obtain your Storage Account Key. By the end of this guide, you’ll have a simple command-line application that can interact with […] The article Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with C# appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with Javascript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore how to integrate the Azure Storage client library for Javascript into a Node.js application. We’ll cover the steps to read and write blobs from Azure Storage, and we’ll also discuss how to obtain your Storage Account Key. By the end of this guide, you’ll have javascript code that can interact […] The article Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with Javascript appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imposter Syndrome and YOU – Dev Leader Weekly 43</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Imposter Syndrome and YOU – Dev Leader Weekly 43 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss imposter syndrome and how it affects you as a software engineer. The post Imposter Syndrome and YOU – Dev Leader Weekly 43 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/05/11/imposter-syndrome-and-you-dev-leader-weekly-43/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find the Latitude and Longitude of a Location in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 05:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to find the latitude and longitude of a location in C# using the Google Maps Geocoding API. We’ll introduce two different methods for obtaining the coordinates: using the GoogleMaps.LocationServices NuGet package, which simplifies the process but can be less flexible, and using HttpClient directly, which provides us more […] The post How to Find the Latitude and Longitude of a Location in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Resilient Cloud Applications With .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By designing your applications with resilience in mind, you can create robust and reliable systems, even when the going gets tough. In this newsletter, we&#39;ll explore the tools and techniques we have in .NET to build resilient systems.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/building-resilient-cloud-applications-with-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making AI powered .NET apps more consistent and intelligent with Redis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 20:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone! Today we’re featuring a guest author from another team in Microsoft on our Semantic Kernel blog. Today’s topic will cover how to use Azure Cache for Redis, which is an in-memory datastore that allows you to further expand the performance and scalability of your applications that are using AzureOpenAI.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/making-ai-powered-net-apps-more-consistent-and-intelligent-with-redis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS DeepRacer enables builders of all skill levels to upskill and get started with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 18:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s technological landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) are becoming increasingly accessible, enabling builders of all skill levels to harness their power. As more companies adopt AI solutions, there’s a growing need to upskill both technical and non-technical teams in responsibly expanding AI usage. Getting hands-on experience is crucial for understanding and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-deepracer-enables-builders-of-all-skill-levels-to-upskill-and-get-started-with-machine-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform customer engagement with no-code LLM fine-tuning using Amazon SageMaker Canvas and SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 16:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) creates tailored customer experiences that align with a brand’s unique voice. Amazon SageMaker Canvas and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart democratize this process, offering no-code solutions and pre-trained models that enable businesses to fine-tune LLMs without deep technical expertise, helping organizations move faster with fewer technical resources. SageMaker Canvas provides an intuitive […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transform-customer-engagement-with-no-code-llm-fine-tuning-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-and-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to (and how not to) design REST APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 14:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Everyone seems to love best practices or rules for designing REST APIs. But is all this guidance good advice? Let’s find out. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in this post. “REST” API Rules I stumbled upon a post outlining rules around… Read More »How to (and how not to) design REST APIs The post How to (and how not to) design REST APIs appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct streaming of SharePoint Driveitem content in Microsoft Graph now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 14:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now directly download content of a file (of a Driveitem) in a SharePoint Online site through a single call.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/direct-streaming-of-sharepoint-driveitem-content-in-microsoft-graph-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An informal comparison of the three major implementations of std::string</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pros and cons.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240510-00/?p=109742 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform String ‘replace’ Function  for RegEx String Replacement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp Terraform offers a lot of powerful functions that can be used for string manipulation within your Infrastructure as Code (IaC) projects. Among these functions is the versatile replace function, which enables users to perform both simple string replacements as well as regular expressions (RegEx) based string replacement. In this article, we’ll look deeper into […] The article Using Terraform String ‘replace’ Function for RegEx String Replacement appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream – Matt Ellis and Antonio Antunes – An Eye For Success With Odin Inspector and JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Tuesday, June 4, 2024, at 2:00 pm UTC (check other timezones) for a free livestream, An Eye For Success With Odin Inspector and JetBrains Rider, with Antonio Antunes from Sirenix and Matt Ellis from JetBrains. Register now to get a reminder, or join us on YouTube JetBrains and Sirenix have joined forces to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/10/livestream-matt-ellis-and-antonio-antunes-an-eye-for-success-with-odin-inspector-and-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance Tip: Type Conversion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article explores type conversion in programming, comparing the traditional syntax with the newer &amp;quot;as&amp;quot; keyword in .NET. While the &amp;quot;as&amp;quot; keyword improves code readability, benchmark results suggest that the conventional method is slightly more performant, advising developers to stick with traditional type conversion unless significant performance improvements are observed with the &amp;quot;as&amp;quot; keyword.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/10/general-performance-tip-type-conversion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronizing multiple remote Git Repositories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            summary of the post
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/synchronizing-multiple-remote-git-repositories 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate QR Codes With QRCoder in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss how to generate QR codes, specifically with the .NET library QRCoder. We will generate basic QR codes that contain simple strings, discuss reading from and writing QR codes to a database, and try out real-life use cases, such as phoning numbers and opening web pages. Let’s first align on […] The post Generate QR Codes With QRCoder in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Parallelism with Wolverine Background Processing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 22:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A couple weeks back I started a new blog series meant to explore Wolverine’s capabilities for background processing. Working in very small steps and only one new concept at a time, the first time out just showed how to set up Wolverine inside a new ASP.Net Core web api service and immediately use it for offloading some processing … Continue reading Controlling Parallelism with Wolverine Background Processing →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wasm vs. Docker: Performant, Secure, and Versatile Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 18:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what WebAssembly is, why to use it, and how Docker and Wasm work together.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/wasm-vs-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the .NET Team at Microsoft Build 2024!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get ready for a great lineup of .NET sessions at Microsoft Build 2024. Join us either in Seattle or from the comfort of your own home. With a mix of live and online sessions, you won’t miss a beat.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/join-the-dotnet-team-microsoft-build-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluid Framework: Undo/redo and transactions in SharedTree</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 16:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about how undo/redo operations and transactions are handled with SharedTree.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/fluid-framework-undo-redo-and-transactions-in-sharedtree 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building your C&#43;&#43; Code with CMake in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 16:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Build systems can help you manage your C++ project as it grows in scope and complexity, whether you are adding new features, dependencies, or cross-platform support. A popular choice in the C++ community is CMake which supports cross-platform development, streamlines build processes and configurations,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/building-your-cpp-code-with-cmake-in-vs-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How LotteON built dynamic A/B testing for their personalized recommendation system</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 16:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with HyeKyung Yang, Jieun Lim, and SeungBum Shim from LotteON. LotteON is transforming itself into an online shopping platform that provides customers with an unprecedented shopping experience based on its in-store and online shopping expertise. Rather than simply selling the product, they create and let customers experience the product through their […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-lotteon-built-dynamic-a-b-testing-for-their-personalized-recommendation-system/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the power of generative AI: Verisk’s journey to an Instant Insight Engine for enhanced customer support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 16:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Tom Famularo, Abhay Shah and Nicolette Kontor from Verisk. Verisk (Nasdaq: VRSK) is a leading data analytics and technology partner for the global insurance industry. Through advanced analytics, software, research, and industry expertise across over 20 countries, Verisk helps build resilience for individuals, communities, and businesses. The company is committed […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleashing-the-power-of-generative-ai-verisks-journey-to-an-instant-insight-engine-for-enhanced-customer-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing an AI/ML center of excellence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 15:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The rapid advancements in artificial intelligence and machine learning (AI/ML) have made these technologies a transformative force across industries. According to a McKinsey study, across the financial services industry (FSI), generative AI is projected to deliver over $400 billion (5%) of industry revenue in productivity benefits. As maintained by Gartner, more than 80% of enterprises […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/establishing-an-ai-ml-center-of-excellence/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asking for a DispatcherQueue from a GUI thread you created</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Grafting a DispatcherQueue onto an existing thread.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240509-52/?p=109738 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure customer-managed keys for your existing Azure Cosmos DB accounts!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Encryption options for data at rest on Azure Cosmos DB that is available today. Azure Cosmos DB strives to provide the best-in-class security features. Encryption of data at rest is one such important security feature. Encryption of data at rest using Microsoft’s service-managed keys is enabled by default.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/configure-customer-managed-keys-for-your-existing-azure-cosmos-db-accounts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices to Promote from DEV to PROD Environments with HashiCorp Terraform using Workspaces and Folders</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When using HashiCorp Terraform to manage infrastructure as code (IaC), promoting changes from the development (DEV) environment to the production (PROD) environment is critical to the process of managing the development lifecycle of the infrastructure for a system. Most often, organizations will also have test (TEST) or staging (STAGE) environments for additional testing to move […] The article Best Practices to Promote from DEV to PROD Environments with HashiCorp Terraform using Workspaces and Folders appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for an IDE Research Integration Grant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 10:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is devoted to bringing the latest ideas and technologies to developers worldwide. Many innovations are born in academia, and researchers are often looking for practical applications for their projects. We are introducing the IDE Research Integration Grant Program, aimed at computer science researchers who have already completed research projects they would like to deploy […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/05/09/apply-for-an-ide-research-integration-grant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Type &amp; Structure Performance: Constant vs. Read-only Property</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This content discusses the performance of using a constant vs. a read-only property.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/09/reference-type-structure-performance-constant-vs-read-only-property/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count the Number of Vowels in a String in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 03:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will take a closer look at the techniques we can use to count the number of vowels in a string in C#. We will go through the code and learn more about each approach. Let’s get started. Prepare Our Counters Application First, let’s create a VowelCounters console application and update the […] The post Count the Number of Vowels in a String in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Marten with PostgreSQL Read Replicas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 20:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software is open for business and offering consulting services (like helping you craft scalability strategies!) and support contracts for both Marten and Wolverine so you know you can feel secure taking a big technical bet on these tools and reap all the advantages they give for productive and maintainable server side .NET development. First off, big thanks to Jaedyn … Continue reading Scaling Marten with PostgreSQL Read Replicas →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Hugging Face text classification model in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 20:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker JumpStart provides a suite of built-in algorithms, pre-trained models, and pre-built solution templates to help data scientists and machine learning (ML) practitioners get started on training and deploying ML models quickly. You can use these algorithms and models for both supervised and unsupervised learning. They can process various types of input data, including […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-hugging-face-text-classification-model-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Terminal Preview 1.21 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 20:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows Terminal is back with another preview release! Windows Terminal Preview 1.21 introduces long-awaited features like Buffer Restore and fontfall back as well as new experimental features like Scratchpad and the ability to load up an image as a texture. There’s also a LOT MORE stuff so check out the rest of this blog post to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/windows-terminal-preview-1-21-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dialog Axiata used Amazon SageMaker to scale ML models in production with AI Factory and reduced customer churn within 3 months</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 18:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The telecommunications industry is more competitive than ever before. With customers able to easily switch between providers, reducing customer churn is a crucial priority for telecom companies who want to stay ahead. To address this challenge, Dialog Axiata has pioneered a cutting-edge solution called the Home Broadband (HBB) Churn Prediction Model. This post explores the […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-dialog-axiata-used-amazon-sagemaker-to-scale-ml-models-in-production-with-ai-factory-and-reduced-customer-churn-within-3-months/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (April 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 17:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What’s New in vcpkg (April 2024) This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.04.26 release as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout April. This month’s vcpkg release includes improvements for visually generated dependency graphs,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-april-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker now integrates with Amazon DataZone to streamline machine learning governance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 17:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker is a fully managed machine learning (ML) service that provides a range of tools and features for building, training, and deploying ML models. Amazon DataZone is a data management service that makes it faster and easier for customers to catalog, discover, share, and govern data stored across AWS, on-premises, and third-party sources. Today, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-now-integrates-with-amazon-datazone-to-streamline-machine-learning-governance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactor your code with C# collection expressions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore various C# 12 refactoring scenarios for a variety of target types using collection expressions, collection initializers, and the spread syntax.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/refactor-your-code-with-collection-expressions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the JetBrains Team at Microsoft Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 14:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On May 21–23, 2024, the Microsoft Build conference is bringing together a diverse community of coders and engineers, and JetBrains is happy to be a part of it. You can attend the event either online or in person in Seattle, WA, USA. To engage with us online, check out our partner page, and don’t forget […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/08/meet-jetbrains-at-microsoft-build-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles with a timeout, part 7: Just doing it one at a time</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A simpler version with its own quirks.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240508-00/?p=109732 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Modeling in Python With Datalore and AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 13:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Risk is an inherent part of the financial landscape, and as investors, we’re constantly seeking ways to quantify and mitigate it. By modeling risks, we can assess potential losses and make informed decisions. By quantifying risk, we can develop strategies to minimize risk exposure and optimize returns. Python, with its rich ecosystem of libraries and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/05/08/risk-modeling-in-python-with-datalore-and-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stack Overflow Upset Over Users Deleting Answers After OpenAI Partnership</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 13:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this ever changing and evolving world of user generated versus AI generated content, the recent announcement of Stack Overflow partnering with OpenAI recently has been met with some backlash by the community. There are reports today that several users have attempted to delete their content (questions and answers) from Stack Overflow with some difficulty, […] The article Stack Overflow Upset Over Users Deleting Answers After OpenAI Partnership appeared first on Build5Nines | Cloud, DevOps &amp;amp; SRE Guidance.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Your Own Local, Private, ChatGPT-like AI Experience with Ollama and OpenWebUI (Llama3, Phi3, Gemma, Mistral, and more LLMs!)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 11:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the last couple years the emergence of Large Language Models (LLMs) has revolutionized the way we interact with Artificial Intelligence (AI) systems, enabling them to generate human-like text responses with remarkable accuracy. From powering chatbots and virtual assistants to aiding in natural language processing tasks, LLMs have found widespread applications across every industry. However, […] The article Run Your Own Local, Private, ChatGPT-like AI Experience with Ollama and OpenWebUI (Llama3, Phi3, Gemma, Mistral, and more LLMs!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next: The WebStorm 2024.2 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 10:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April this year, we released WebStorm 2024.1, our first major update for 2024. Thank you to everyone who is already using it and providing us with feedback. With April now behind us, we’d like to announce what we’ve got planned for the next release of WebStorm, which is scheduled for the end of July, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/05/2024-2-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Ecosystem Survey Insights: A Comparative Look at Students and Professionals</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 09:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our series exploring how market and user research is done at JetBrains continues. Want to learn more about research insights and take part in future JetBrains studies? Join our JetBrains Tech Insights Lab! The world of IT is a rapidly growing industry, attracting more and more people with a passion for creative and challenging tasks. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2024/05/developer-ecosystem-survey-insights-a-comparative-look-at-students-and-professionals/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String Performance: Checking for a Character</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article compares two methods of checking for the presence of a specific character in a string in C#. Benchmark results reveal that using a character in the search is 3.57 times more efficient than using a string, and Contains() outperforms StringComparison.Ordinal and StringComparison.OrdinalIgnoreCase in terms of speed.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/08/string-performance-checking-for-a-character-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Update an Item in a List in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 05:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look at how to update an item in a List in C#, using a simple library management system as an example. We’ll explore the intricacies of this common operation and learn how to manipulate lists in our C# applications effectively. Let’s start. Understand List in C# In the world of C#, […] The post How to Update an Item in a List in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Data Wrangler: Code-centric viewing and cleaning of tabular data in Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 20:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the general availability of the Data Wrangler extension for Visual Studio Code! Data Wrangler is a free extension that offers data viewing and cleaning that is directly integrated into VS Code and the Jupyter extension.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/announcing-data-wrangler-code-centric-viewing-and-cleaning-of-tabular-data-in-visual-studio-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Management &amp; improved .NET Aspire support come to C# Dev Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the new features and enhancements in the latest version of C# Dev Kit including NuGet package management, .NET Aspire project support, and much more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/may-release-of-csharp-dev-kit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost employee productivity with automated meeting summaries using Amazon Transcribe, Amazon SageMaker, and LLMs from Hugging Face</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 19:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a solution to automatically generate a meeting summary from a recorded virtual meeting (for example, using Amazon Chime) with several participants. The recording is transcribed to text using Amazon Transcribe and then processed using Amazon SageMaker Hugging Face containers to generate the meeting summary. The Hugging Face containers host a large language model (LLM) from the Hugging Face Hub.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-employee-productivity-with-automated-meeting-summaries-using-amazon-transcribe-amazon-sagemaker-and-llms-from-hugging-face/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Veritone uses Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Rekognition, Amazon Transcribe, and information retrieval to update their video search pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 19:40:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Tim Camara, Senior Product Manager at Veritone. Veritone is an artificial intelligence (AI) company based in Irvine, California. Founded in 2014, Veritone empowers people with AI-powered software and solutions for various applications, including media processing, analytics, advertising, and more. It offers solutions for media transcription, facial recognition, content summarization, object […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-veritone-uses-amazon-bedrock-amazon-rekognition-amazon-transcribe-and-information-retrieval-to-update-their-video-search-pipeline/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information extraction with LLMs using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 17:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) have unlocked new possibilities for extracting information from unstructured text data. Although much of the current excitement is around LLMs for generative AI tasks, many of the key use cases that you might want to solve have not fundamentally changed. Tasks such as routing support tickets, recognizing customers intents from a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/information-extraction-with-llms-using-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps Server 2022 Update 2 RC now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 17:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re thrilled to announce the release candidate (RC) of Azure DevOps Server 2022.2! This release includes new features that have been previously released in our hosted version of the product. Here are a few of the highlights: Limits for area and iteration paths Bypass approvals and checks in pipelines Improved YAML validation Azure Artifacts support for Cargo Crates New Dashboard directory experience Quick Copy and import for Test Plan or Suite ID There are more features with this release,
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Rocks The Austin .NET User Group (2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 17:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The dotNetDave No Rest for the Wicked World Tour is coming to the Austin .NET User Group in Texas on May 9th. This session will focus on code and app performance for Microsoft .NET, covering efficient code execution and techniques for minimizing memory footprint. Watch the live session and access related resources to optimize code performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/07/dotnetdave-rocks-the-austin-net-user-group-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles with a timeout, part 6: Capturing the handles efficiently</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 16:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SFINAE&#39;ing the case of a random-access(ish) iterator.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240507-00/?p=109729 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating AI-Enhanced Document Management with the GenAI Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 14:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We show how to integrate Alfresco, a robust document management system, with the GenAI Stack to open up document analysis, description, and classification possibilities.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/creating-ai-enhanced-document-management-with-the-genai-stack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering SREs with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of technology, the role of Site Reliability Engineers (SREs) is becoming increasingly complex and critical. As organizations strive for higher reliability and performance in their systems, the integration of generative AI technologies, such as those offered by Azure OpenAI, is revolutionizing the field of SRE. Let’s explore how these advancements are […] The article Empowering SREs with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI appeared first on Build5Nines | Cloud, DevOps &amp;amp; SRE Guidance.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between .NET and C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 10:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When diving into the programming world, distinguishing between .NET and C# can be puzzling. .NET is a framework, that provides a platform for building applications. In contrast, C# is a programming language used within this framework. Despite their close association, it’s crucial to understand that they serve distinct roles in the development process. In this […] The post Differences Between .NET and C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub Copilot as your Coding GPS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transform Your Coding Workflow with GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio GitHub Copilot is a game-changing AI-powered assistant that can revolutionize your coding workflow in Visual Studio. In our video series, Bruno Capuano explores how this intelligent coding companion can help you write code more efficiently while maintaining quality and accuracy.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/using-github-copilot-as-your-coding-gps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Constants vs. Read-only Fields</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses best practices for checking strings for null in coding. It outlines three common methods: using == null, is null, or string.IsNullOrEmpty().
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/07/code-it-any-way-you-want-constants-vs-read-only-fields/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middleware-Based Exception Handling in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unlock the full potential of your ASP.NET Core applications with our definitive guide to middleware-based exception handling. Learn how to gracefully manage errors, boost your application&#39;s resilience, and protect against downtime with practical, easy-to-follow strategies
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/middleware-exception-handling-aspnet-core-guide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serialization and Deserialization with YamlDotNet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 06:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            YAML (YAML Ain’t Markup Language) is a human-readable data serialization language, while YamlDotNet is a .NET library that helps us serialize and deserialize YAML data. Due to its simple and intuitive syntax, programming languages frequently use YAML for configuration files and data exchange. Its flexibility in handling complex data structures has made YAML popular in […] The post Serialization and Deserialization with YamlDotNet appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;Secret&amp;quot; elmah.io features #4 - Get help from AI and ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 08:01:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this fourth post in the series of &amp;quot;secret&amp;quot; elmah.io features, I want to introduce you to one of several AI features available on elmah.io. We have had machine learning features like automatic bot detection and spike identification for years. But a recent addition to the asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/secret-elmah-io-features-4-get-help-from-ai-and-chatgpt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: Azure Functions Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m very pleased to announce my latest Pluralsight / A Cloud Guru course - Azure Functions Deep Dive. This is a completely new course, using v4 of the Azure Functions runtime and the isolated programming model. It has taken me many months to complete, so apologies that I&#39;ve been fairly quiet on here most of this year. In the course I try to cover all of the most popular triggers and bindings, as well as looking at Durable Functions and some of the options for deployment and monitoring.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Security Architecture: Trust Zones and Security Boundaries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 20:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are many aspects to architecting an Internet of Things (IoT) solution. Security is the most important aspect of any computer system, but it’s especially important with IoT solutions. It seems we are constantly seeing news reports about IoT solutions being hacked or compromised. These compromises are things like Internet connected cameras being hacked to […] The article IoT Security Architecture: Trust Zones and Security Boundaries appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft AI Powering DARPA’s AI Cyber Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most promising applications of advanced AI is its ability to help combat cyberattacks from enhanced threat intelligence to AI-powered remediation. The Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) has launched the AI Cyber Challenge (AIxCC) that will bring together the foremost experts in AI and cybersecurity to develop innovative solutions to safeguard critical infrastructure from cyber threats.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/ai-powering-darpa-ai-cyber-challenge 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting a set of handles with a timeout, part 5: Generalizing the awaiter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fitting into existing patterns.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240506-00/?p=109727 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platform Engineering: What is it? And how it applies to DevOps Engineers and SREs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of software development and operations, the need for streamlined processes, robust infrastructure, and efficient deployment practices has become paramount. DevOps Engineer and Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) roles have emerged as two prominent methodologies to address these challenges. However, bridging the gap between development and operations requires a specialized approach. The latest […] The article Platform Engineering: What is it? And how it applies to DevOps Engineers and SREs appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to check if a DLL  and an exe is a .NET assembly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recently, I needed to check if a file was a .NET assembly without loading the assembly. .NET uses the Portable Executable (PE) format to store assemblies. The PE format is a file format for executables or DLLs on Windows, but .NET also uses it on Linux and MacOS. Hopefully, .NET provides the PEReader class to read the file header. This class can parse the content of a file to extract PE information.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Leveraging LINQ MAXBy() and MINBy() for Efficient and Readable Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores the usage of LINQ&#39;s MinBy() and MaxBy() methods, which efficiently return the objects with the minimum and maximum values in a sequence based on a specified key selector function.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/06/collection-performance-leveraging-linq-maxby-and-minby-for-efficient-and-readable-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fastest Way to Get a Dictionary Key by Value in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 05:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The C# language does not provide a built-in method that we can use to retrieve a key from our dictionary using its value. However, using other features of the language, we can create methods to perform this task. In this article, let’s implement and discuss several methods that we can utilize to get a dictionary […] The post Fastest Way to Get a Dictionary Key by Value in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
