<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 09:23:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Code Readability and Manageability in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 09:23:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Software development, code readability transforms complexity into clarity. Martin Fowler said:
Any fool can write code that a computer can understand. Good programmers write code that humans can understand.
Code should be readable and manageable so other developers can understand and work without additional fatigue. .NET has many ways asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/boosting-code-readability-and-manageability-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.21 with simulating authentication and authorization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 07:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover what&#39;s new in the latest version of Dev Proxy to help you build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-21-with-simulating-authentication-and-authorization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use IHttpClientFactory and WireMock.NET together using Moq</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WireMock.NET is a popular library used to simulate network communication through HTTP. But there is no simple way to integrate the generated in-memory server with an instance of IHttpClientFactory injected via constructor. Right? Wrong!
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/wiremock-ihttpclientfactory-moq/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Event Projections and Subscriptions with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The feature set shown in this post was built earlier this year at the behest of a JasperFx Software client who has some unusually high data throughput and wanted to have some significant ability to scale up Marten and Wolverine‘s ability to handle a huge number of incoming events. We originally put this into what … Continue reading Scaling Event Projections and Subscriptions with the Critter Stack →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import a question answering fine-tuned model into Amazon Bedrock as a custom model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a step-by-step approach of fine-tuning a Mistral model using SageMaker and import it into Amazon Bedrock using the Custom Import Model feature.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/import-a-question-answering-fine-tuned-model-into-amazon-bedrock-as-a-custom-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using task-specific models from AI21 Labs on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will show you how to leverage AI21 Labs’ Task-Specific Models (TSMs) on AWS to enhance your business operations. You will learn the steps to subscribe to AI21 Labs in the AWS Marketplace, set up a domain in Amazon SageMaker, and utilize AI21 TSMs via SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-task-specific-models-from-ai21-labs-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability (GA) of Native Authentication for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the General Availability (GA) of Native Authentication for Microsoft Entra External ID! A feature that allows you to design and control the sign-in experience within your mobile apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/native-auth-for-external-id-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing seamless authentication with Power Pages and Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the public preview of Microsoft Entra External ID as an identity provider for Microsoft Power Pages, streamlining authentication for your external-facing apps. With Power Pages, you can launch a website in minutes, and External ID provides robust tools to secure external identities, with extensive customization options available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-id-and-power-pages 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio at Unreal Fest Seattle 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us in-person at Unreal Fest Seattle 2024 with an in-depth look at how Visual Studio and GitHub Copilot can help modernize your Unreal Engine game development. Session Title: Modernizing Game Development with Visual Studio and AI Session Info: October 3rd, 2024, 2:00 PM-3:00 PM Pacific Time | Room 445 Abstract: Join Microsoft to learn […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-at-unreal-fest-seattle-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Docker for DevOps: What It Is and How It Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We explore the use of Docker for DevOps and explain how the combination can help developers create more efficient and powerful workflows.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-for-devops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – September Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “Wake me up when September ends,” goes the famous song, and here we are! The JetBrains Academy team is back with updates: fresh courses, IT clubs for school students, and ways to boost your portfolio with real-world projects and certificates. Wake up and dive into the tech world with our latest digest!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/09/30/jetbrains-academy-july-digest-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling a single item from a C&#43;&#43; parameter pack by its index, remarks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why such a complicated way to pull the type from the pack?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240930-00/?p=110324 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 IntelliJ IDEA Shortcuts for Efficient Data Querying With the Database Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thanks to the dedicated SQL query console inside IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate’s Database Tools, you can easily modify and extract data from any database connected to your Java application without ever leaving the IDE. The query console comes with an SQL statement-specific code snippets library, code completion, on-the-fly error detection, and useful shortcuts – all to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/top-10-shortcuts-for-efficient-data-querying/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Big Deal About Endpoints for Python Web Development?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Python has almost 30 years of history doing Python web development. Can you believe it? But 3-tier web projects have gotten really complicated and stressful. You’re busy, everything is all over the place – it’s hard! But PyCharm is here to help: bring your work together with the Endpoints tool window. I just made a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/python-web-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling HSTS for localhost using a browser extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Http Strict Transport Security (HSTS) is a security mechanism that instructs the browser to automatically redirect http requests to https before sending a request to the server. When you are developing a web application, you should disable HSTS for localhost. This is because enabling HSTS on localhost has implications for other applications. For instance, some applications start a local web server and…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/avoid-hsts-issues-on-localhost.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless Instrumentation profiling with Persistent Target Selection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 10:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever wished to assess your code’s performance without repeatedly choosing the target process or executable for each instrumentation profiling session? If so, you’re among many developers who find this task cumbersome and prone to errors, especially when profiling the same target repeatedly. We understand your frustration and have a solution: Visual Studio 2022 introduces a […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/effortless-instrumentation-profiling-with-persistent-target-selection 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Recommendations for a Test Automation Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 01:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve been helping a JasperFx Software client with their test automation strategy on a new web application and surrounding suite of services. That makes this a perfectly good time to reevaluate how I think teams can succeed with automated testing as an update to what I thought a decade ago. I think you can justifiably … Continue reading My Recommendations for a Test Automation Strategy →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/29/my-recommendations-for-a-test-automation-strategy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Collection Extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2024/29_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2024/29_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages, offering enhanced functionality for ICollection collections. Features include AddIf, AddRange, AsReadOnlySpan, Upsert, and more. Detailed benchmark results are available on GitHub, and community involvement is encouraged for further improvements. Contact dotnetdave@live.com for contributions or inquiries.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/09/29/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-collection-extensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 中的工作区</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2024/29_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 04:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2024/29_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            亡羊补牢，犹未为晚！ 如果要用一句谚语来形容一下本文要介绍的新功能 – IntelliJ IDEA 中对工作区的支持 – 这句恐怕再贴切不过了。 简介 简单来说，工作区是一个元项目，可让您同时管理多个项目。 无论是协调复杂的开发环境，还是同时处理几个不相关的项目，此功能都非常实用。 急性子须知：下文会涉及一些理论和历史，如果您迫不及待想在 IDE 中使用工作区，请直接跳到如何使用工作区一节立即体验！ 此外，您还可以收看这期在线讲座以获取更多详细信息。 请注意，这项功能目前处于预览阶段，因此您可能会遇到一些 Bug 和限制。 自 2011 年以来，我们的问题跟踪器中就一直有关于工作区支持的工单。 不过，随着 2010 年代中期微服务和单仓库的兴起，工作区似乎失去了开发的必要。 单仓库模型与 IntelliJ IDEA 侧重的“一个项目 – 多个模块”方式完全契合。 然而，用户对工作区的需求依旧在持续增长，这一点可以从 YouTrack 上不断增加的赞和支持性评论中得到证实。 接下来，我们将探究一下为什么时至今日用户仍然需要工作区。 为什么单仓库并没有取代工作区方式 相比其他代码安排（即多仓库）方式，单仓库确实有诸多优势，例如： 改善协作。 所有开发者都能即时查看项目其他部分的进展情况。 只要代码一提交，所有更改都会一目了然。 如果要实现的服务需要与其他团队开发的服务交互，开发者可以查看对方的代码，深入了解其运作方式。 简化依赖项管理。 在大多数情况下，单仓库中的所有项目均使用相同的软件包管理和构建工具，便于跟踪依赖项和版本。 而且，单仓库中的所有应用程序组件通常一起发布，这就规避了项目间依赖项出现问题的风险。 跨项目重构。 由于能够访问整个代码库，IDE 可以为代码引用编制索引，从而能够检测到更改并轻松进行正确的重构。 提升代码的可发现性。 新加入团队的成员可以轻松浏览整个代码库，理解不同项目和组件间的依赖关系。 如果您签出一个单仓码库并用 IntelliJ IDEA 打开，会发现单仓库的结构完美契合“项目-模块”范式。 根文件夹被视为一个“项目”，所有子文件夹则变为“模块”。 因此，从这个角度来看，该模型似乎运行良好，工作区功能的实现可以往后推迟。 不过，单仓库也存在一些不足： […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/workspaces-in-intellij-idea 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You REALLY Need To Write Tests? – Dev Leader Weekly 63</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2024/28_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2024/28_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Do You REALLY Need To Write Tests? – Dev Leader Weekly 63 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss situations where we may or may not want or need to write tests! The post Do You REALLY Need To Write Tests? – Dev Leader Weekly 63 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/09/28/do-you-really-need-to-write-tests-dev-leader-weekly-63/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking It Down: How to Migrate Your Modular Monolith to Microservices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2024/28_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2024/28_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transitioning from a modular monolith to microservices can significantly enhance your system&#39;s scalability and your team&#39;s productivity, but it&#39;s a journey that requires careful planning and execution. In this practical guide, I&#39;ll walk you through the key steps of this migration process, from preparing your monolith and selecting the right module to extract, to implementing effective inter-service communication and data migration strategies, all based on real-world experience with .NET applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture to AWS CloudFormation code using Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 21:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore some ways you can use Anthropic’s Claude 3 Sonnet’s vision capabilities to accelerate the process of moving from architecture to the prototype stage of a solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/architecture-to-aws-cloudformation-code-using-anthropics-claude-3-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Northpower used computer vision with AWS to automate safety inspection risk assessments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 21:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Northpower has worked with their technology partner Sculpt to reduce the effort and carbon required to identify and remediate public safety risks. Specifically, we cover the computer vision and artificial intelligence (AI) techniques used to combine datasets into a list of prioritized tasks for field teams to investigate and mitigate.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-northpower-used-computer-vision-with-aws-to-automate-safety-inspection-risk-assessments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Semantic Kernel for Java 1.3.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 17:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello again Java AI developers! We are announcing the 1.3.0 release of the Semantic Kernel for Java. You can find our updates on the GitHub repository and the artifacts on Maven Central. This release will mark the final experimental version of our Vector Store functionality. Vector search is now available across all our supported vector stores. We’ve implemented approximate search […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-semantic-kernel-for-java-1-3-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (September 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 17:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure SDKs release every month. This post includes the month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-september-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SK Python Kernel Reaches 1,000,000 downloads</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 15:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce that Microsoft Semantic Kernel Python Kernel has reached an incredible milestone of 1,000,000 downloads! This achievement would not have been possible without the unwavering support and enthusiasm of our community. We want to extend our heartfelt thanks to every developer, contributor, and user who has embraced the Python Kernel, providing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/sk-python-kernel-reaches-1000000-downloads 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the crash when destructing a std::map</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Who is corrupting the map?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240927-00/?p=110320 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards, September Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 13:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            September was a productive month for Azure Boards, and we’re excited to share some of the new features coming your way. Area and Iteration Level Fields Area and iteration level fields have been crucial for querying or displaying results based on their specific levels: (Root) Level 1 / Level 2 / Level 3 / etc. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-boards-september-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PromptFlow Serve – Benchmark Result Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we discuss how to test the throughput of PromptFlow pf-serve module and key learnings doing so. We explore the impact on throughput and performance the different WSGI and ASGI hosting methods have and the importance of engineering your Python nodes with the async await pattern for I/O.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/promptflow-performance-testing-analysis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenAI for Aerospace: Empowering the workforce with expert knowledge on Amazon Q and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 18:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we show how you can quickly launch generative AI-enabled expert chatbots, trained on your proprietary document sets, to empower your workforce across specific aerospace roles with Amazon Q and Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/genai-for-aerospace-empowering-the-workforce-with-expert-knowledge-on-amazon-q-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable training platform with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod for innovation: a video generation case study</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 18:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share an ML infrastructure architecture that uses SageMaker HyperPod to support research team innovation in video generation. We will discuss the advantages and pain points addressed by SageMaker HyperPod, provide a step-by-step setup guide, and demonstrate how to run a video generation algorithm on the cluster.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scalable-training-platform-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-for-innovation-a-video-generation-case-study/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.1-3 and 1.22.7-3 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 18:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-1-3-and-1-22-7-3-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using JSON Schema for Structured Output in Python for OpenAI Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In working with AI applications, ensuring that the output generated by a language model is structured and follows a consistent format is critical—especially when handling complex tasks like solving math problems. A powerful way to achieve this is through the use of JSON Schema, which allows the AI model to produce outputs that align with […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/using-json-schema-for-structured-output-in-python-for-openai-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control data access to Amazon S3 from Amazon SageMaker Studio with Amazon S3 Access Grants</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to simplify data access to Amazon S3 from SageMaker Studio using S3 Access Grants, specifically for different user personas using IAM principals.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/control-data-access-to-amazon-s3-from-amazon-sagemaker-studio-with-amazon-s3-access-grants/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 3: Smarter Inline AI Prompts, Improved Terraform and OpenTofu Support, Kubernetes and Docker Compose Updates, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 3 has been released, and it’s packed with new features for you to try out! This build brings inline AI prompts with context awareness, extended support for Terraform, including the new OpenTofu project, notable updates for Kubernetes and Docker Compose, and improvements to remote development environments. You can download this version […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing SharePoint Framework 1.20 with updates on building enterprise extensibility within Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce general availability for the SharePoint Framework 1.20. This time focus is primarily on the Microsoft Viva platform capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-sharepoint-framework-1-20-with-updates-on-building-enterprise-extensibility-within-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Code Completions for C&#43;&#43; Developers: Fine-tuned models are now in limited public beta for GitHub Copilot Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub recently announced that custom models are available for GitHub Copilot Enterprise users in limited public beta. Custom models are fine-tuned on your organization’s proprietary codebases and coding practices to provide more contextually relevant and consistent inline suggestions. How It Works: Security and Privacy in Custom Models The data used to train your organization’s custom […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/tailored-code-completions-for-c-developers-fine-tuned-models-are-now-in-limited-public-beta-for-github-copilot-enterprise 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a chatbot on your own data in 1 hour with Azure SQL, Langchain and Chainlit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Chatbots are the hot topic lately, and now you can create them easily by downloading solutions like OpenWebUI, connect it to Ollama or any OpenAI compatible API, choose your favorite language model, and then run it. It just takes a few minutes and it’s done. But building chatbots is not enough, you most likely want […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-a-chatbot-on-your-own-data-in-1-hour-with-azure-sql-langchain-and-chainlit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you’re going to specify the LVS_SORTASCENDING or LVS_SORTDESCENDING style, you had better be telling the truth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Because the listview control uses it to optimize searching.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240926-00/?p=110316 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Kotlin Heroes: Episode 11 – Your Chance to Win Great Prizes and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 12:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Competitive programming is a fantastic way to sharpen your problem-solving skills in a programming language that you already know, or to explore new programming languages. The Kotlin Heroes contest is the perfect platform for that! Whether you’re a beginner or an experienced coder, Kotlin Heroes gives you the opportunity to challenge yourself, master or learn […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/09/join-kotlin-heroes-episode-11/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a React TODO app in Visual Studio 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this tutorial we will create a React front-end, with JavaScript, of a TODO web app using a Visual Studio 2022. To get started install Visual Studio with the Node.js development workload. This will include the JavaScript/TypeScript (JSTS) projects and the associated support. The code for this app can be found at sayedihashimi/todojswebapp (github.com). Create […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/creating-a-react-todo-app-in-visual-studio-2022 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django Project Ideas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 09:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ready to get started on your Django project? Whether you want to build a personal project, improve your portfolio, or just experiment with a new technology, Django provides the perfect foundation. We’ve compiled a list of Django project ideas that will help you expand your competence, whether you’re new to the framework or looking to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/django-project-ideas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve employee productivity using generative AI with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 20:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you the Employee Productivity GenAI Assistant Example, a solution built on AWS technologies like Amazon Bedrock, to automate writing tasks and enhance employee productivity.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-employee-productivity-using-generative-ai-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a multimodal social media content generator using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 20:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through a step-by-step process to create a social media content generator app using vision, language, and embedding models (Anthropic’s Claude 3, Amazon Titan Image Generator, and Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings) through Amazon Bedrock API and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-multimodal-social-media-content-generator-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate RAG for numerical analysis using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 20:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases provides a powerful solution for numerical analysis on documents. You can deploy this solution in an AWS account and use it to analyze different types of documents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-rag-for-numerical-analysis-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.3 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 19:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor version for IntelliJ IDEA – 2024.2.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, please […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-2-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 19:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I realize the title sounds a little too similar to somebody else’s 2025 platform proposals, but let’s please just overlook that This is a “vision board” document I wrote up and shared with our core team (Anne, JT, Babu, and Jeffry) as well as some friendly users and JasperFx Software customers. I dearly want to … Continue reading Critter Stack 2025 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/25/critter-stack-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common annotated security keys</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 18:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April 2021, GitHub announced changes to their security token format that significantly enhanced security. The improvement leveraged two straightforward techniques: a fixed signature in the generated token and a checksum – both of which are highly effective in eliminating false positives (noise) and false negatives (missed findings). Microsoft also implements these techniques widely in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/common-annotated-security-keys 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Llama 3.2 models from Meta are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 18:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can discover and deploy the Llama 3.2 11B Vision model using SageMaker JumpStart. We also share the supported instance types and context for all the Llama 3.2 models available in SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/llama-3-2-models-from-meta-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision use cases with Llama 3.2 11B and 90B models from Meta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 18:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the first time that the Llama models from Meta have been released with vision capabilities. These new capabilities expand the usability of Llama models from their traditional text-only applications. In this post, we demonstrate how you can use Llama 3.2 11B and 90B models for a variety of vision-based use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/vision-use-cases-with-llama-3-2-11b-and-90b-models-from-meta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with testing and .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to improve your software development process with automated testing in .NET Aspire. This post covers the basics of getting started, writing tests for distributed applications, and ensuring your services run smoothly.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/getting-started-with-testing-and-dotnet-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Stream: How to Migrate Your Kotlin Plugin to K2 Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 15:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently shared the news about Kotlin K2 mode – a new implementation of Kotlin support in IntelliJ IDEA designed to improve IDE stability and support future Kotlin language features. If your plugin uses the K1 API, you need to update it. Without this update, your plugin won’t load when K2 mode is enabled. We […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/09/live-stream-how-to-migrate-your-kotlin-plugin-to-k2-mode/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Secure software development and deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how Microsoft 365 Certification validates secure software development and deployment best practices.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-secure-software-development-and-deployment 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating AI into Business Processes with the Process Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As organizations look to enhance efficiency and decision-making, the integration of AI into business processes has become increasingly important. The new Process Framework for Microsoft Semantic Kernel empowers developers to seamlessly embed AI into their workflows, providing a structured approach to optimizing daily operations. Not sure what a business process is? A Process is a structured sequence […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/integrating-ai-into-business-processes-with-the-process-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the GA of Dynamic Scaling (Per Region and Per Partition Autoscale)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the GA of Azure Cosmos DB dynamic scaling – among multiple new features (Binary Encoding, Reserved Capacity) released recently to make your Azure Cosmos DB workloads even more cost efficient. Dynamic scaling is an enhancement to autoscale which provides cost optimization for nonuniform workloads. In the earlier version of autoscale, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-the-ga-of-dynamic-scaling-per-region-and-per-partition-autoscale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Cost and Performance Improvements with Azure Cosmos DB’s Binary Encoding</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce a significant enhancement to Azure Cosmos DB, bringing substantial cost savings and performance improvements to our users. The new binary encoding feature is now available for new containers and will soon be available for existing ones. What is Binary Encoding? Binary encoding converts JSON or other text-based data formats into […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-cost-and-performance-improvements-with-azure-cosmos-dbs-binary-encoding 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another example of the Windows Runtime interop pattern: Using the UserConsentVerifier from a Win32 program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following the standard pattern.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240925-00/?p=110312 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sep 2024: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 11:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An overview of the latest updates in Microsoft Entra for Sep 2024. Discover how these new capabilities can be integrated into your projects for optimal performance and security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-sep-24 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organize Your Breakpoints like a pro</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you feel overwhelmed by the sheer number of breakpoints in your Visual Studio project? Wish you could categorize and toggle them on and off with ease? The new breakpoint group feature in Visual Studio 2022 is here to transform your debugging experience. Breakpoint groups allow you to create custom collections of breakpoints and apply […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/organize-your-breakpoints-like-a-pro 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Update: Changes to URI Expiry Time in Azure Notification Hubs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 09:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2024/25_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of our ongoing efforts to enhance the security of Azure Notification Hubs, we are making an important change to the expiry time of the generated URIs. Starting from October 2024, the expiry time of PnsErrorDetailsUri will be reduced from 10 days to 5 days. This means that the PnsErrorDetailsUri returned will now be […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-notification-hubs/security-update-changes-to-uri-expiry-time-in-azure-notification-hubs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating the Particular Service Platform with Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 22:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve been playing around with Aspire for a bit mainly to understand &amp;quot;is this a thing I should care about?&amp;quot; and part of what I wanted to do is take a complex &amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot; distributed system and convert it to Aspire. Along the way,
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/integrating-the-particular-service-platform-with-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How generative AI is transforming legal tech with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 21:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Legal professionals often spend a significant portion of their work searching through and analyzing large documents to draw insights, prepare arguments, create drafts, and compare documents. In this post, we share how legal tech professionals can build solutions for different use cases with generative AI on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-generative-ai-is-transforming-legal-tech-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy generative AI agents in your contact center for voice and chat using Amazon Connect, Amazon Lex, and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 20:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how DoorDash built a generative AI agent using Amazon Connect, Amazon Lex, and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases to provide a low-latency, self-service experience for their delivery workers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-generative-ai-agents-in-your-contact-center-for-voice-and-chat-using-amazon-connect-amazon-lex-and-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2409.23 – Support for new devices, bug fixes, and everything in 2408.09</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 20:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2409.23, which can be downloaded here. This release includes everything that was in the 2408.09 version of PIX, plus the following improvements: GPU Captures: Fix capture-time issue on some ARM64 devices Add support for D3D_FEATURE_LEVEL_1_0_GENERIC Significant perf improvement during replay for some ExecuteIndirect users Enable side-by-side installation of pix via command […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2409-23 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Hackathon: Virtual Customer Success Manager (VCSM) using Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 19:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Background on Hackathon Project: Virtual Customer Success Manager (VCSM) Semantic Kernel is a versatile SDK that seamlessly integrates AI models into applications, enhancing their responsiveness and understanding. It offers tools for chat completion, multi-agent coordination, and data retrieval, enabling developers to create advanced AI-driven solutions. The Virtual Customer Success Manager (VCSM), developed during Hackathon ’24, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/microsoft-hackathon-virtual-customer-success-manager-vcsm-using-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Amazon SageMaker: Karini AI Cut Costs by 23%</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 17:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Karini AI’s migration of vector embedding models from Kubernetes to Amazon SageMaker endpoints improved concurrency by 30% and saved over 23% in infrastructure costs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/migrating-to-amazon-sagemaker-karini-ai-cut-costs-by-23/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the power of AI to drive equitable climate solutions: The AI for Equity Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 16:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The International Research Centre on Artificial Intelligence (IRCAI), Zindi, and Amazon Web Services (AWS) are proud to announce the launch of the “AI for Equity Challenge: Climate Action, Gender, and Health”—a global virtual competition aimed at empowering organizations to use advanced AI and cloud technologies to drive real-world impact with a focus on benefitting vulnerable populations around the world.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/harnessing-the-power-of-ai-to-drive-equitable-climate-solutions-the-ai-for-equity-challenge/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot-Reloading C&#43;&#43; with Live&#43;&#43; and JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 16:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve been working with Stefan Reinalter and the team at Molecular Matters to make the industry-leading Live++ binary patching tool work seamlessly with C++ projects in JetBrains Rider! This is a great productivity boost for both Unreal Engine developers and those working on custom C++ engines. Live++ support works with all C and C++ projects […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/24/hot-reloading-cplusplus-with-liveplusplus-and-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UserConsentVerifier confirms that the user is there, but it doesn’t protect any data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Is that really you?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240924-00/?p=110308 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Docker State of Application Development Survey: Share Your Thoughts on Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Take the 2024 Docker State of Application Development Survey now. The survey is open from September 23rd, 2024 (7AM PST) to November 20, 2024 (11:59PM PST).
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/2024-docker-state-of-application-development-survey/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm vs. Jupyter Notebook</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 12:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Jupyter notebooks are an important tool for data scientists, providing an easy option for conducting experiments and presenting results. According to our Developer Ecosystem Survey 2023, at least 35% of data professionals use Jupyter notebooks. Furthermore, over 40% of these users spend more than 20% of their working time using these resources. There are several […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/pycharm-vs-jupyter-notebook/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate Azure VM Across Regions Using Azure CLI and Bash Script</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 12:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Migrating an Azure Virtual Machine (VM) from one Azure Region to another can be necessary for several reasons, including disaster recovery, optimizing performance, or reducing latency. While Azure provides various options for replication and failover, one of the most efficient ways to migrate a VM manually involves creating a Snapshot of the VM Disks, copying […] The article Migrate Azure VM Across Regions Using Azure CLI and Bash Script was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream – Build a 2024 ML Course From Scratch: Insights and Teaching Strategies With JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 11:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, October 1, at 3:00 pm UTC for a livestream in the JetBrains Academy series for educators, Build a 2024 ML Course From Scratch: Insights and Teaching Strategies With JetBrains. Aleksandr Avdiushenko, a JetBrains educator and data scientist, brings over eight years of expertise in IT education. His career bridges both academia […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/09/24/livestream-build-a-2024-ml-course-from-scratch-insights-and-teaching-strategies-with-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 101: Efficient JVM HTTP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 10:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As an experienced Java developer, you’re likely familiar with robust, full-featured web frameworks, like Spring Boot. Today, we’ll explore Ktor, a toolkit for building server applications on JVM with Kotlin. Ktor was designed from the ground up to take advantage of Kotlin’s features, including coroutines, to build efficient and flexible web applications. As a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/ktor-101-efficient-jvm-http-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Gen Code Coverage in Visual Studio: Enhanced C&#43;&#43; Support and Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 10:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share the latest changes in Visual Studio’s code coverage components. If you haven’t already, be sure to check out our previous blog posts: What’s New in Our Code Coverage Tooling? and Code coverage features in Visual Studio Enterprise. C++ Code Coverage Tired of instable native code coverage that doesn’t support ARM64? Now, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/next-gen-code-coverage-in-visual-studio-enhanced-c-support-and-security 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Loop Performance in .NET: The Simple Trick of Caching Array Length</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post discusses optimizing array iteration in programming by caching the array&#39;s length for performance improvements. This method yields a 1.021x performance boost, particularly beneficial for loops executed frequently. The author encourages this technique and recommends their book for more insights on enhancing .NET code performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/09/24/collection-performance-looping-over-a-collection-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Essential Techniques for Managing Transactions in EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 08:15:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transaction are a crucial concept in database operations. It helps in updating related data safely without leaving the database state inconsistent. Entity Framework Core (EF Core) provides a mechanism to wrap database operations as transactions. In this blog post, we will see what a transaction is and how we can asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/3-essential-techniques-for-managing-transactions-in-ef-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Box regional availability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2024/24_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve received some questions recently about where Microsoft Dev Box is available. While you can always check the latest list at https://aka.ms/devbox/regions, for a quick reference, here’s the current regional availability for Dev Box: Dev Box regions West US 2 West Europe Central India West US 3 North Europe Southeast Asia Central US UK South […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/microsoft-dev-box-regional-availability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
