<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Mutex&lt;T&gt; to synchronize access to a shared resource</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you need to access a shared resource, you can use the lock statement or a synchronization primitive such as a Mutex to synchronize access to the resource. However, it&#39;s easy to forget it in complex code. When you need to synchronize access to a single resource, you can use a var obj = new object(); var value = 42; lock (obj) { // You need to ensure you use lock everywhere you access the shared…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level up your collaborations with the pull request experience in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of our main goals is to help you and your team collaborate more effectively and efficiently on your software projects. That’s why we are constantly improving our Version Control features, especially the ones related to the pull request workflow. Starting in Visual Studio version 17.11, you can enjoy a smoother and smarter pull request […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/level-up-your-collaborations-with-the-pull-request-experience-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a Geo-distance search using .NET Aspire, Elasticsearch and ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 08:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article shows how to implement a geo location search in an ASP.NET Core application using a LeafletJs map. The selected location can be used to find the nearest location with an Elasticsearch Geo-distance query. The Elasticsearch container and the ASP.NET Core UI application are setup for development using .NET Aspire. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/WebGeoElasticsearch Setup For […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/09/23/implement-a-geo-distance-search-using-net-aspire-elasticsearch-and-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Code Analysis in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 06:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Static code analysis refers to the practice of scanning code for potential problems without actually running the code. Inspections in IntelliJ IDEA can detect potential problems in your project before you compile it. The IDE can highlight various problems, locate dead code, find probable bugs and spelling problems, and improve the overall code structure. This […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/introduction-to-code-analysis-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use the REPR (Request-Endpoint-Response) Pattern in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 05:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to explore the REPR (Request-Endpoint-Response) design pattern in .NET. We’ll start our discussion by examining what the REPR pattern entails. Then, we’ll go on to see how we can use it in our .NET projects. Finally, we’ll look at the advantages of implementing this pattern and some potential drawbacks […] The post How to Use the REPR (Request-Endpoint-Response) Pattern in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Tenancy in Wolverine Messaging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 02:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2024/23_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building and maintaining a large, hosted system that requires multi-tenancy comes with a fair number of technical challenges. JasperFx Software has helped several of our clients achieve better results with their particular multi-tenancy challenges with Marten and Wolverine, and we’re available to do the same for your shop! Drop us a message on our Discord … Continue reading Multi-Tenancy in Wolverine Messaging →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/22/multi-tenancy-in-wolverine-messaging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Assembly Extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2024/22_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2024/22_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine, an open-source tool for .NET 8, offers enhanced methods like GetAllInterfaces, GetAllTypes, GetInstances, and GetTypes. These methods improve performance and reliability, with benchmark results available on GitHub. Community involvement is crucial for the project&#39;s success, so contributions and feedback are encouraged to make Spargine an essential tool for the .NET community. Contact dotnetdave@live.com for inquiries or contributions.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/09/22/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-assembly-extensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, You Failed Your Interview… – Dev Leader Weekly 62</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_09_2024/21_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_09_2024/21_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post So, You Failed Your Interview… – Dev Leader Weekly 62 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to try and improve from failed interview experiences as software engineers. The post So, You Failed Your Interview… – Dev Leader Weekly 62 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/09/21/so-you-failed-your-interview-dev-leader-weekly-62/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Implemented Full-Text Search On My Website</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_09_2024/21_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_09_2024/21_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article walks you through how I used Lunr.js to add powerful search capabilities to a Next.js static site, dealing with challenges like client-side processing and optimizing for performance along the way.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/how-i-implemented-full-text-search-on-my-website 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate dynamic web content in your generative AI application using a web search API and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 22:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock Agents with a web search API to integrate dynamic web content in your generative AI application.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-dynamic-web-content-in-your-generative-ai-application-using-a-web-search-api-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI assistant to enhance employee experience using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 19:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how you can use Amazon Q Business to build generative AI assistants that enhance employee experience and boost productivity. Amazon Q Business seamlessly integrates with internal data sources, knowledge bases, and productivity tools to equip your workforce with instant access to information, automated tasks, and personalized support.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-generative-ai-assistant-to-enhance-employee-experience-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing document-level sync reports: Enhanced data sync visibility in Amazon Kendra</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 19:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how the new document-level report in Amazon Kendra provides enhanced visibility and observability into the document processing lifecycle during data source sync jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-document-level-sync-reports-enhanced-data-sync-visibility-in-amazon-kendra/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debunking Kafka Top 5 Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 16:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Infographics are easy and quick to look at and they are posted everywhere. But are they actually correct? Not really. Here’s an example of the “Top 5 use cases for Kafka” that aren’t actually valid use-cases at all. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video… Read More »Debunking Kafka Top 5 Use Cases The post Debunking Kafka Top 5 Use Cases appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I check that all the changes in a git branch have been cherry-picked or rebased into its upstream branch?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can pretend to merge it and see if anything happens.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240920-00/?p=110287 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in PyCharm 2024.2.2!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.2.2 is here with many key updates, including Python support improvements, new Django features, and enhancements to the Data View tool window! Visit our What’s New page for more details on all these features and to explore many others. You can download the latest version from our download page or update your current version […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/pycharm-2024-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn Rust in 2024: A Complete Beginner’s Guide to Mastering Rust Programming</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So, you’re thinking about choosing Rust as your next programming language to learn. You already know what it means to write code and have some experience with at least one programming language, probably Python or JavaScript. You’ve heard about Rust here and there. People say it’s a modern systems programming language that brings safety and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/09/20/how-to-learn-rust/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autogen RAG</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 07:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Linkai Yu explores the retrieval-augemented generation pattern with Azure OpenAI Assistants API. The Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) pattern is the standard for integrating ground AI with local data. One powerful way to implement RAG is through the function call or tool call feature in the Function Call API. When examining the samples provided by the Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/autogen-rag 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2024.3 Starts its Early Access Program!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 04:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Say hello to the first build of ReSharper 2024.3 Early Access Program! This build is mostly about improving C++ support, but it still has something new for C# developers as well. Let’s have a look! ReSharper Code Cleanup Now you can substitute a default Code Cleanup profile with another one for particular files via .editorconfig […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/20/resharper-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper C&#43;&#43; 2024.3 Starts its Early Access Program!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 04:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for ReSharper C++ 2024.3 has just begun! Move to Folder The Move to Folder refactoring now also handles C++ files (RSCPP-17126). After moving selected files to the new location, the refactoring will update the #include directives that reference the moved files. Language support ReSharper now supports the following new language features: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rscpp/2024/09/20/resharper-cpp-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.3 Early Access Program Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 04:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s start the last Early Access Program for JetBrains Rider this year! Rider 2024.3 EAP brings the following updates: Support for hot reloading C++ with Live++ We’ve been working with the folks at Live++ to bring seamless C++ hot reloading support to Rider! There’s no new UI, but the user experience will be a lot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/20/rider-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Meta Llama 3.1 models using torchtune on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 22:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, AWS collaborates with Meta’s PyTorch team to showcase how you can use Meta’s torchtune library to fine-tune Meta Llama-like architectures while using a fully-managed environment provided by Amazon SageMaker Training.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-meta-llama-3-1-models-using-torchtune-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the .NET Smart Components ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET Smart Components are now open source to help library authors build and share easy-to-use AI-powered features, including new AI-powered components from Telerik, DevExpress, and Syncfusion.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/join-the-dotnet-smart-components-ecosystem 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DirectX Adopting SPIR-V as the Interchange Format of the Future</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 18:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today the Direct3D and HLSL teams are excited to share some insight into the next big step for GPU programmability. Once Shader Model 7 is released, DirectX 12 will accept shaders compiled to SPIR-V™. The HLSL team is committed to open development processes and collaborating with The Khronos® Group and LLVM Project. We’re sharing this […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directx-adopting-spir-v 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases with Microsoft SharePoint as a data source</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 17:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to configure Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases with SharePoint Online as a data source. By connecting SharePoint Online as a data source, employees can interact with the organization’s knowledge and data stored in SharePoint using natural language, making it straightforward to find relevant information, extract key points, and derive valuable insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-with-microsoft-sharepoint-as-a-data-source/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 2: Enhanced HotSwap in the Debugger, Faster Compilation in Multi-Module Projects, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 15:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 2 build is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 2 Discover the newly introduced features below! Debugger Enhanced HotSwap feature In the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Change controls</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how Microsoft 365 Certification validates change controls are in place for your app.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-change-controls 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My window has the WS_EX_NOACTIVATE extended style, but it got activated anyway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well, at least it wasn&#39;t activated by a click.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240919-00/?p=110283 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Docker Myths Debunked</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 13:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We debunk common Docker myths and explain the capabilities and benefits of this widely used container technology.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-myths-debunked/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in Writerside: The Good Docs Project Templates Right in Your Editor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 13:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “I hate to write, but I love having written,” a famous saying goes. Don’t we all – especially those of us who write functional texts, like technical documentation? We often have too little time to even convey the basic idea, let alone categorize and structure the information – whether it’s a how-to guide, a reference, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/09/new-in-writerside-the-good-docs-project-templates-right-in-your-editor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Approach to Build Runners | TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 11:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In TeamCity Pipelines, build runners tell the system how to build, test, and package your code. For this latest release, we’ve revamped how build runners work. Here’s what’s new: New design for creating a build step With this most recent release of TeamCity Pipelines, we’ve made creating build steps even more straightforward. You can now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/09/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue7-build-runners/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use FastAPI for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 08:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Cheuk Ting Ho, a data scientist who contributes to multiple open-source libraries, such as pandas, Polars, and Jupyter Notebook. FastAPI provides a quick way to build a backend service with Python. With a few decorators, you can turn your Python function into an API application. It is widely used […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/how-to-use-fastapi-for-machine-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.2 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 20:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released a new minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 – 2024.2.2. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. Here are some of the notable updates: To find out more details about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionize logo design creation with Amazon Bedrock: Embracing generative art, dynamic logos, and AI collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how AWS can help accelerate a brand’s creative efforts with access to a powerful image-to-image model from Stable Diffusion available on Amazon Bedrock to interactively create and edit art and logo images.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionize-logo-design-creation-with-amazon-bedrock-embracing-generative-art-dynamic-logos-and-ai-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinvent personalization with generative AI on Amazon Bedrock using task decomposition for agentic workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present an automated solution to provide a consistent and responsible personalization experience for your customers by using smaller LLMs for website personalization tailored to businesses and industries. This decomposes the complex task into subtasks handled by task / domain adopted LLMs, adhering to company guidelines and human expertise.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/reinvent-personalization-with-generative-ai-on-amazon-bedrock-using-task-decomposition-for-agentic-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate pre-training of Mistral’s Mathstral model with highly resilient clusters on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present to you an in-depth guide to starting a continual pre-training job using PyTorch Fully Sharded Data Parallel (FSDP) for Mistral AI’s Mathstral model with SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-pre-training-of-mistrals-mathstral-model-with-highly-resilient-clusters-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an efficient MLOps platform with OSS tools on Amazon ECS with AWS Fargate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Zeta Global, a data-driven marketing technology company, has built an efficient MLOps platform to streamline the end-to-end ML workflow, from data ingestion to model deployment, while optimizing resource utilization and cost efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-an-efficient-mlops-platform-with-oss-tools-on-amazon-ecs-with-aws-fargate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving GitHub Copilot Completions in Visual Studio for C# Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the latest GitHub Copilot improvements for C# developers
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/improving-github-copilot-completions-in-visual-studio-for-csharp-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Project Launch Configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 16:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of the hassle of manually configuring your development environment every time you want to launch multiple projects? We’ve heard your feedback and are thrilled to announce a feature in Visual Studio that simplifies your workflow. The Multi-Project Launch Configuration feature in Visual Studio allows developers to set up and save profiles for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/multi-project-launch-configuration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Quality Booster: Live Qodana Demo and Best Practices for Code Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a live demo of Qodana, the static code analysis platform from JetBrains. Discover how to integrate Qodana with your IDE and your CI pipeline, build quality gates, and catch critical issues early. Date: September 30, 2024 Time: 6 pm CET (4 pm UTC) Register for the webinar Session abstract Whether you’re new to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/09/code-quality-booster-live-qodana-demo-and-best-practices-for-code-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on the mysterious [default_interface] attribute in Windows Runtime classes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Forcing you to make a choice.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240918-00/?p=110279 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Introduces Free Online Clubs for School Students</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 09:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting in October, we invite teenagers interested in math, programming, and AI to join our free online clubs. Whether you want to participate in Olympiads or planning to study at high-intensity and prestigious STEM programs, our clubs will help you prepare and meet like-minded people from different countries. Take a closer look at the clubs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/09/18/jetbrains-introduces-free-online-clubs-for-school-students/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Goodies in Marten 7.28</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 06:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, did you know that JasperFx Software offers both consulting services and support plans for the “Critter Stack” tools? Or for architectural or test automation help with any old server side .NET application. One of the other things we do is to build out custom features that our customers need in the “Critter Stack” — like the … Continue reading New Goodies in Marten 7.28 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/18/new-goodies-in-marten-7-28/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Function Calling Model Available in .NET for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 22:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce release of the new function-calling model that is available in Semantic Kernel v1.20. The new model incorporates the best parts of the existing function-calling model, such as ease of use, and improves on it by making it more extensible and reusable. using Microsoft.SemanticKernel; IKernelBuilder builder = Kernel.CreateBuilder(); // Register OpenAI […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/new-function-calling-model-available-in-net-for-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build RAG-based generative AI applications in AWS using Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 17:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP with Amazon Bedrock to provide a RAG experience for your generative AI applications on AWS by bringing company-specific, unstructured user file data to Amazon Bedrock in a straightforward, fast, and secure way.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-rag-based-generative-ai-applications-in-aws-using-amazon-fsx-for-netapp-ontap-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observability in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many of you have asked similar questions: How do I obtain the rendered prompt that Semantic Kernel sends to the AI service? How do I monitor the token usage of my application? How do I gain insights into Semantic Kernel’s operations during runtime? These are all excellent questions! They fundamentally belong to the same class […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/observability-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2024.3 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for CLion 2024.3 is officially launched. The first EAP build 243.12818.61 is now available, giving you an early glimpse into the enhancements we’ll include in the upcoming major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/09/2024-3-eap-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the new YouTrack 2024.3 release, one of the most hotly anticipated functionalities in the YouTrack roadmap – apps – goes live! Apps help teams customize YouTrack to fit their specific needs, improving project management, reporting, automation, and integration with other tools. You can now use and create apps to extend YouTrack’s functionality and add […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/09/youtrack-introduces-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for AWS DeepComposer ending soon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS DeepComposer was first introduced during AWS re:Invent 2019 as a fun way for developers to compose music by using generative AI. AWS DeepComposer was the world’s first machine learning (ML)-enabled keyboard for developers to get hands-on—literally—with a musical keyboard and the latest ML techniques to compose their own music. After careful consideration, we have […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/support-for-aws-deepcomposer-ending-soon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserve access and explore alternatives for Amazon Lookout for Equipment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we discuss how you can maintain access to Lookout for Equipment after it is closed to new customers and some alternatives to Lookout for Equipment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/preserve-access-and-explore-alternatives-for-amazon-lookout-for-equipment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability (GA) of Microsoft Entra External ID extension for Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 15:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the new Microsoft Entra External ID extension for Visual Studio Code, now Generally Available (GA), created to simplify CIAM integration in your development process. See how this extension provides a smooth experience for setting up External ID applications from within VS Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-id-vs-code-extension-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 23 and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 15:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            New and updated Java language features, core API, and the JVM – Java 23 packs it all – for new Java developers to senior developers. IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 is ready with its support for Java 23 features. Keeping pace with new Java version releases could be difficult – what changed, why, and how to use […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/java-23-and-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a GraphQL Client in .NET with JetBrains Rider and StrawberryShake</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 14:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many teams are using GraphQL for their API needs, thanks to its powerful query language and flexibility. Unlike traditional REST APIs, GraphQL lets you fetch the data you need in a single request, making your applications more efficient and responsive. However, it can be daunting getting started creating schemas, writing queries, and integrating GraphQL into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/17/building-a-graphql-client-in-net-with-jetbrains-rider-and-strawberryshake/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It rather involved being on the other side of this airtight hatchway: Posting completions to somebody else’s I/O completion port</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have gained access to it, then that was the problem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240917-00/?p=110276 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for Web Developers: Getting Started with the Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker empowers web developers by providing efficient, scalable, and collaborative containerization tools that streamline development workflows, ensure consistency across environments, and enhance productivity for building, testing, and deploying web applications.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-for-web-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RubyMine 2024.3 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re starting the RubyMine 2024.3 Early Access Program today. In this blog post, we’ll inform you about the upcoming features and updates in this release cycle. What’s coming in RubyMine 2024.3? AI Assistant For RubyMine 2024.3, we’re working on several Ruby-specific AI features, focusing on context improvements for AI-powered unit test generation, explanation […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/09/the-rubymine-2024-3-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run .NET apps natively on Arm64 devices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you developing .NET applications for Arm-based processors? Do you want to take advantage of the performance and power efficiency of running your apps natively on Arm64 devices? If so, you’ll be happy to hear that Visual Studio 2022 17.11 has a new feature that makes it easier than ever to do just that. Visual […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-to-run-net-apps-natively-on-arm64-devices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing MAX_PATH issues in GitLab</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how you can enable Git&#39;s long-path support in a GitLab job to override Window&#39;s MAX_PATH limitations which can cause git clone failures
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/fixing-max_path-issues-in-gitlab/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Existing Code through TDD: A Password Case Study</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 08:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Week 4 of our Summer Craft Book, which Yann Courtel and I created, we focus on Test-Driven Development with the exercise below.The Initial ChallengeIn this exercise, our task was to create a program that validates a password following Test-Driven Development cycles based on the following criteria:At
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/evolving-existing-code-through-tdd-a-password-validator-case-study/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET User Secrets Demystified: Practical Usage and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 08:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to effectively use .NET User Secrets to secure sensitive data in your development process. This comprehensive guide covers initialization, management, and best practices.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/net-user-secrets-demystified-practical-usage-and-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Remote Development Challenges With CodeCanvas: A CDE Orchestration Tool by JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 07:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the public release of CodeCanvas, JetBrains’ new platform for orchestrating cloud development environments (CDEs). To better understand CodeCanvas and why it is important for JetBrains’ remote development strategy, let’s dive a bit into history and context. Remote development trend Many companies still rely on local development, a method that has several […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/09/17/introducing-codecanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Azure DevOps Security with GHAS Code Scanning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 07:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debjyoti Ganguly shares insights on the security benefits and configuration of GHAS Code Scanning with Azure DevOps. Boosting Azure DevOps Security with GHAS Code Scanning Code scanning, a pipeline-based tool available in GitHub Advanced Security, is designed to detect code vulnerabilities and bugs within the source code of ADO (Azure DevOps) repositories. Utilizing CodeQL as […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/boosting-azure-devops-security-with-ghas-code-scanning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR-Cas9 guide RNA efficiency prediction with efficiently tuned models in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeat (CRISPR) technology holds the promise to revolutionize gene editing technologies, which is transformative to the way we understand and treat diseases. This technique is based in a natural mechanism found in bacteria that allows a protein coupled to a single guide RNA (gRNA) strand to locate and make […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/crispr-cas9-guide-rna-efficiency-prediction-with-efficiently-tuned-models-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve RAG performance using Cohere Rerank</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 19:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use Cohere Rerank to improve search efficiency and accuracy in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-rag-performance-using-cohere-rerank/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure by Design for AI: Building Resilient Systems from the Ground Up</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dive into the “Secure by Design” approach essential for AI systems, focusing on embedding security features from the start to fortify AI against emerging threats.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/secure-by-design-for-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on Win32 carets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Assorted notes and musings.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240916-00/?p=110272 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the behavior of the XAML Designer with abstract base classes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 13:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 introduced a new XAML designer for building WPF apps, with a goal of increasing the performance and reliability of the designer. The new designer can quickly open a XAML file by using WPF’s built-in parser and display. This new design has a nuanced behavior when the root XAML element derives from an […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/understanding-the-behavior-of-the-xaml-designer-with-abstract-base-classes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Developing Spring Boot Applications With Joy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 12:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode, where we will explore how to build modern Spring Boot applications using IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate with Siva Reddy. Date: September 26, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Spring Boot is the most popular application framework in the Java […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for a ManualResetEventSlim to be set asynchronously</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ManualResetEventSlim represents a thread synchronization event that, when signaled, must be reset manually. This is a common synchronization primitive. However, it doesn&#39;t expose a method to wait asynchronously. Hopefully, it&#39;s not too complicated to create an extension method using ThreadPool.RegisterWaitForSingleObject and TaskCompletionSource. static class Extensions { public static Task WaitAsync(this…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/waiting-for-a-manualreseteventslim-to-be-set-asynchronously.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Ways To Use Jupyter Notebooks inside PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 10:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Jupyter notebooks allow you to tell stories by creating and sharing data, equations, and visualizations sequentially, with a supporting narrative as you go through the notebook. Jupyter notebooks in PyCharm Professional provide functionality above and beyond that of browser-based Jupyter notebooks, such as code completion, dynamic plots, and quick statistics, to help you explore and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/7-ways-to-use-jupyter-notebooks-inside-pycharm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Elasticsearch with .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 04:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to use Elasticsearch in .NET Aspire. Elasticsearch is setup to use HTTPS with the dotnet developer certificates and and simple client can be implemented to query the data. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/keycloak-backchannel Setup Two services are setup to run in .NET Aspire. The first service is the official Elasticsearch docker container and deployed […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/09/16/using-elasticsearch-with-net-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediator Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 02:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to talk about a popular design pattern, the Mediator Pattern. We will see how this pattern helps address some design problems and how to implement it in C#. Let’s start. What is The Mediator Design Pattern? Mediator is a behavioral design pattern that promotes loose coupling by eliminating chaotic […] The post Mediator Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
