<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:11:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Innovate business logic by implementing return of control in Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the context of distributed systems and microservices architecture, orchestrating communication between diverse components presents significant challenges. However, with the launch of Amazon Bedrock Agents, the landscape is evolving, offering a simplified approach to agent creation and seamless integration of the return of control capability. In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock Agents revolutionizes agent creation and demonstrates the efficacy of the return of control capability in orchestrating complex interactions between multiple systems.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code - June 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the June 2025 release of the Python, Pylance and Jupyter ext
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-june-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 EAP 5: Reimagined Monitoring tool window and New OpenTelemetry Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Rider 2025.2 EAP 5 build has just been released, and this one brings two major productivity enhancements for .NET developers. We’re excited to introduce the reimagined Monitoring tool window, which transforms how you identify and resolve performance issues, plus the new OpenTelemetry plugin, which brings runtime observability directly into your development environment. We can’t […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/16/rider-eap-5-new-monitoring-tool-opentelemetry-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenTelemetry Plugin for JetBrains Rider: Observability Inside Your IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding how your application behaves at runtime has always been a challenge. Traditional debugging and profiling tools can help you understand what’s happening at specific points in time – but getting a complete picture of system behavior, performance patterns, and architectural relationships often means jumping between external tools and dashboards. We’re building the OpenTelemetry plugin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/16/opentelemetry-plugin-for-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a helper class for generating a particular category of C callback wrappers around C&#43;&#43; methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A common pattern for C callbacks is to accept a function pointer and a void*, and then the callback function receives that pointer in addition to the parameters specific to the callback. // Hypothetical callback typedef int (callback_t)( void context, int arg1, char const* arg2, double arg3); void Regi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250616-00/?p=111271 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Rerun Failed GitHub Actions Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Actions doesn&#39;t provide a built-in way to rerun a run automatically. If you have some flakiness in your jobs, this can be a pain as you have to rerun the workflow manually. Hopefully, you can use the workflow_run event to trigger a new workflow when a previous one fails. This allows you to rerun the failed workflow automatically. Note that the following sample workflow will only rerun the failed…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Java Enable Preview: Vector API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 10:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Daniel Hinojosa and explore the Vector API – a powerful tool for writing high-performance code in Java. Date: June 25, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this session, we will discuss the Vector API in a preview in Java. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/new-livestream-new-livestream-new-livestream-java-enable-preview-vector-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Says… Don’t Build Frankenstein’s Monster Applications!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2025/15_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2025/15_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article emphasizes the dangers of creating disjointed software systems, likening them to Frankenstein&#39;s Monster. It warns against overengineering and using mismatched technologies, which can lead to project failures. The author shares personal insights and experiences, urging teams to prioritize coherence and maintainability in their software architecture.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/15/dotnetdave-says-dont-build-frankensteins-monster-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Motivation in Software Engineering - Dev Leader Weekly 98</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to breakdown what keeps you engaged as a software engineer.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/14/uncovering-motivation-in-software-engineering-dev-leader-weekly-98 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-06-13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 07:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/14/weekly-recap-20250613 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run C# Scripts With dotnet run app.cs (No Project Files Needed)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2025/14_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With .NET 10, you can now run C# files directly. No project files, no Main method, just code. In this issue, I&#39;ll show you how to use the new dotnet run app.cs feature in practice: from quick one-liners to a real-world SQL seeding script.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/run-csharp-scripts-with-dotnet-run-app-no-project-files-needed 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Qwen models with Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 17:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now import custom weights for Qwen2, Qwen2_VL, and Qwen2_5_VL architectures, including models like Qwen 2, 2.5 Coder, Qwen 2.5 VL, and QwQ 32B. In this post, we cover how to deploy Qwen 2.5 models with Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import, making them accessible to organizations looking to use state-of-the-art AI capabilities within the AWS infrastructure at an effective cost.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-qwen-models-with-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI solutions with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to build generative AI applications on Amazon Web Services (AWS) using the capabilities of Amazon Bedrock, highlighting how Amazon Bedrock can be used at each step of your generative AI journey. This guide is valuable for both experienced AI engineers and newcomers to the generative AI space, helping you use Amazon Bedrock to its fullest potential.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-solutions-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Netsertive built a scalable AI assistant to extract meaningful insights from real-time data using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Netsertive introduced a generative AI-powered assistant into MLX, using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Nova, to bring their next generation of the platform to life.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-netsertive-built-a-scalable-ai-assistant-to-extract-meaningful-insights-from-real-time-data-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make videos accessible with automated audio descriptions using Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use services like Amazon Nova, Amazon Rekognition, and Amazon Polly to automate the creation of accessible audio descriptions for video content. This approach can significantly reduce the time and cost required to make videos accessible for visually impaired audiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/make-videos-accessible-with-automated-audio-descriptions-using-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Llama 3.3 Swallow: A Japanese sovereign LLM on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 15:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Institute of Science Tokyo has successfully trained Llama 3.3 Swallow, a 70-billion-parameter large language model (LLM) with enhanced Japanese capabilities, using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod. The model demonstrates superior performance in Japanese language tasks, outperforming GPT-4o-mini and other leading models. This technical report details the training infrastructure, optimizations, and best practices developed during the project.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/training-llama-3-3-swallow-a-japanese-sovereign-llm-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – June Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 14:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month, we’ve gathered fun plugins and a course to help you build your own, as well as AI updates, exciting news for C++ learners and professional developers. Dive in!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/06/13/jetbrains-academy-june/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thread pool threads are like preschool: Leave things the way you found them</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to use the Windows thread pool, but they also wanted to use COM from their work item. They saw in the COM documentation that each thread must call Co­Initialize(Ex) before using COM, so they planned on doing something like this: thread_local bool isComInitialized = false; auto DoWork
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250613-00/?p=111268 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains GameDev Days 2025 – Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 09:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains GameDev Day is back! Join us online on October 21, 2025, for a day dedicated to all things game development. We’re looking for speakers who are eager to share their knowledge, experience, tools, or creative approaches across the gamedev community. What is GameDev Day? GameDev Day is a free, live, online event hosted by […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/13/jetbrains-gamedev-days-2025-call-for-speakers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Articul8’s domain-specific model development with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Articul8 is redefining enterprise generative AI with domain-specific models that outperform general-purpose LLMs in real-world applications. In our latest blog post, we dive into how Amazon SageMaker HyperPod accelerated the development of Articul8’s industry-leading semiconductor model—achieving 2X higher accuracy that top open source models while slashing deployment time by 4X.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-articul8s-domain-specific-model-development-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How VideoAmp uses Amazon Bedrock to power their media analytics interface</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate how VideoAmp, a media measurement company, worked with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) team to develop a prototype of the VideoAmp Natural Language (NL) Analytics Chatbot to uncover meaningful insights at scale within media analytics data using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-videoamp-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-power-their-media-analytics-interface/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Your Productivity with New GitHub Copilot Features for .NET!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Visual Studio 17.14 GA release and recent C# Dev Kit releases for VS Code have introduced a whole new batch of GitHub Copilot features des
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/improve-productivity-with-github-copilot-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2025 (version 1.101)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code May 2025 Release (1.101) Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/may-2025-(version-1.101) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft recognized for second consecutive year as a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re proud to share that Microsoft has once again been named a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Data Science and Machine Learning (DSML) Platforms. The post Microsoft recognized for second consecutive year as a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/microsoft-recognized-for-second-consecutive-year-as-a-leader-in-the-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-data-science-and-machine-learning-platforms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You DON’T Need Microservices for Serverless!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I want to talk about something that might sound like a contradiction in terms: the serverless monolith. If you’re scratching your head right now, thinking, “Wait, that makes no sense, serverless is for microservices!” then stick with me. I’m going to clear up one of the biggest misconceptions out there and explain why a serverless… Read More »You DON’T Need Microservices for Serverless! The post You DON’T Need Microservices for Serverless!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build, Run, and Package AI Models Locally with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As a Senior DevOps Engineer and Docker Captain, I’ve helped build AI systems for everything from retail personalization to medical imaging. One truth stands out: AI capabilities are core to modern infrastructure. This guide will show you how to run and package local AI models with Docker Model Runner — a lightweight, developer-friendly tool...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-build-run-and-package-ai-models-locally-with-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Windows even have &lt;code&gt;Interlocked&lt;/code&gt; functions when we have &lt;code&gt;std::atomic&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows provides a family of functions for performing atomic operations. They have the word Interlocked in their name. But why do these functions even exist when we have std::atomic? This is similar to asking
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250612-00/?p=111265 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Building an MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, June 24, at 10 am EDT / 4 pm CEST (check other timezones) for our free livestream, Live Coding: Building an MCP Server. In this livestream, we’ll team up with Max Kless, a senior engineer at Nx, to build a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server from scratch and seamlessly integrate it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/06/livestream-building-an-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs Go: Which one to choose in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The programming landscape continues to evolve, bringing forward languages like Rust and Go that not only challenge traditional paradigms but also cater to the sophisticated needs of modern computing. Both have carved significant niches for themselves, celebrated for their efficient handling of system-level operations and concurrency. Recent findings from the State of Developer Ecosystem Report […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/06/12/rust-vs-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.3: Important Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A third set of updates for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.3 introduces support for SQL &amp;amp; NoSQL query languages You can now edit and format SQL and NoSQL queries […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/12/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-3-important-updates-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor your Quarkus native application on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 12:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Quarkus is a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/monitor-your-quarkus-native-application-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run HTTP Requests in Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 08:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that our HTTP Client plugin is now available in Android Studio! HTTP Client is a powerful tool for making HTTP, gRPC, GraphQL, and WebSocket requests. Its text-based interface offers seamless integration with the editor, along with extensive coding assistance including highlighting, code completion, refactorings, and inline documentation. While it was […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/06/12/run-http-requests-in-android-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from Cursor to IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 07:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re a developer working with Cursor, exploring alternatives for your growing project, and are curious to see what IntelliJ IDEA has to offer, this article is for you. While Cursor emphasizes a minimalistic setup approach, IntelliJ IDEA strikes a balance between out-of-the-box functionality and powerful customization, enabling developers to effortlessly scale from small projects […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/migrate-cursor-to-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dockerizing UV</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Containerizing your Python applications helps standardize environments and streamline deployment—but it also introduces unique challenges. In our team&#39;s exploration of modern dependency management tools, we discovered that while UV (Universal Virtualenv) delivers impressive speed and simplicity in local development, replicating its setup ins
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/dockerizing-uv 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing the Magic of AI to Mattel’s Iconic Brands</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Mattel are partnering to integrate AI into iconic brands such as Barbie and Hot Wheels, aiming to enhance creative development, streamline workflows, and create new ways for fans to engage.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/mattels-iconic-brands 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Complete MCP Experience: Full Specification Support in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VS Code now supports the complete Model Context Protocol specification, including authorization, prompts, resources, and sampling. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/the-complete-mcp-experience:-full-specification-support-in-vs-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security and Trust in Visual Studio Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 22:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s fast-paced digital world, keeping the Visual Studio Marketplace secure and trustworthy is extremely important. We know how crucial it is to protect your extensions, so we&#39;re always working on new ways to keep things safe. We&#39;d like to share an update on the existing safeguards and upcoming investments that ensure VS Marketplace r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//security-and-trust-in-visual-studio-marketplace 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Voice Intelligence with .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most interesting ways to enhance your existing applications with AI is to enable more ways for your users to interact with it. Today you probably handle text input, and perhaps some touch gestures for your power users. Now it&#39;s easier than ever to expand that to voice and vision, especially when your users&#39; primary input is via mobi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/multimodal-voice-intelligence-with-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe enhances developer productivity using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adobe partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and the Vector Engine for Amazon OpenSearch Serverless. This solution dramatically improved their developer support system, resulting in a 20% increase in retrieval accuracy. In this post, we discuss the details of this solution and how Adobe enhances their developer productivity.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/adobe-enhances-developer-productivity-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Nova Lite enables Bito to offer a free tier option for its AI-powered code reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bito is an innovative startup that creates AI agents for a broad range of software developers. In this post, we share how Bito is able to offer a free tier option for its AI-powered code reviews using Amazon Nova.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-nova-lite-enables-bito-to-offer-a-free-tier-option-for-its-ai-powered-code-reviews/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Gardenia Technologies helps customers create ESG disclosure reports 75% faster using agentic generative AI on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Gardenia Technologies, a data analytics company, partnered with the AWS Prototyping and Cloud Engineering (PACE) team to develop Report GenAI, a fully automated ESG reporting solution powered by the latest generative AI models on Amazon Bedrock. This post dives deep into the technology behind an agentic search solution using tooling with Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and text-to-SQL capabilities to help customers reduce ESG reporting time by up to 75%. We demonstrate how AWS serverless technology, combined with agents in Amazon Bedrock, are used to build scalable and highly flexible agent-based document assistant applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing the &lt;code&gt;MAX_PATH&lt;/code&gt; restriction on paths applies only to paths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was playing around with Windows long paths and found that even though they used the \?\ long path prefix, they still couldn&#39;t use a long path. The documentation on the maximum pat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250611-00/?p=111262 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing AI models to Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we first released Docker Model Runner, it came with built-in support for running AI models published and maintained by Docker on Docker Hub. This made it simple to pull a model like llama3.2 or gemma3 and start using it locally with familiar Docker-style commands. Model Runner now supports three new commands: tag, push, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/publish-ai-models-on-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Nemotron Super 49B and Nano 8B reasoning models now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Llama 3.3 Nemotron Super 49B V1 and Llama 3.1 Nemotron Nano 8B V1 are now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, you can now deploy NVIDIA’s newest reasoning models to build, experiment, and responsibly scale your generative AI ideas on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/nvidia-nemotron-super-49b-and-nano-8b-reasoning-models-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy JetBrains Mellum Your Way: Now Available via NVIDIA NIM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deploy Mellum as a production-grade LLM inside your own infrastructure – with NVIDIA. JetBrains Mellum – our open, focused LLM specialized on code completion – is now available to run as a containerized microservice on NVIDIA AI Factories. Using the new NVIDIA universal LLM NIM container, Mellum can be deployed in minutes on any NVIDIA-accelerated […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/06/deploy-jetbrains-mellum-your-way-now-available-via-nvidia-nim/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework June 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 20:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for June 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Security Update&amp;quot;] All developers using .NET 8.0 and .NET 9.0 should update immediately
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-june-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 19:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing patches that impact the latest version of our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can dow
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/june-patches-for-azure-devops-server-4 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 5 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the fifth preview release of .NET 10 with enhancements across the .NET Runtime, SDK, libraries, C#, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more. Check out the full release notes linked below and get started today. [cta-button align=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Download .NET 10 Preview 5&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;https:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.42: Native IPv6, Built-In MCP, and Better Model Packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.42 introduces powerful new capabilities that enhance network flexibility, improve security, and deepen AI toolchain integration, all while reducing setup friction. With native IPv6 support, a fully integrated MCP Toolkit, and major upgrades to Docker Model Runner and our AI agent Gordon, this release continues our commitment to helping developers move faster, ship...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-42-native-ipv6-built-in-mcp-and-better-model-packaging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate customer support with Amazon Bedrock, LangGraph, and Mistral models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock and LangGraph to build a personalized customer support experience for an ecommerce retailer. By integrating the Mistral Large 2 and Pixtral Large models, we guide you through automating key customer support workflows such as ticket categorization, order details extraction, damage assessment, and generating contextual responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-customer-support-with-amazon-bedrock-langgraph-and-mistral-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build responsible AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Bedrock Guardrails helps block harmful and undesirable multimodal content. Using a healthcare insurance call center scenario, we walk through the process of configuring and testing various guardrails.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-responsible-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective cost optimization strategies for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the increasing adoption of Amazon Bedrock, optimizing costs is a must to help keep the expenses associated with deploying and running generative AI applications manageable and aligned with your organization’s budget. In this post, you’ll learn about strategic cost optimization techniques while using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/effective-cost-optimization-strategies-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How E.ON saves £10 million annually with AI diagnostics for smart meters powered by Amazon Textract</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            E.ON’s story highlights how a creative application of Amazon Textract, combined with custom image analysis and pulse counting, can solve a real-world challenge at scale. By diagnosing smart meter errors through brief smartphone videos, E.ON aims to lower costs, improve customer satisfaction, and enhance overall energy service reliability. In this post, we dive into how this solution works and the impact it’s making.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-e-on-saves-10-million-annually-with-ai-diagnostics-for-smart-meters-powered-by-amazon-textract/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application compatibility for Windows 95 crashed a cash register</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I told the story of the time the development manager for Windows 95 bought one copy of every PC program in the Egghead Software store. I learned that in addition to stunning the store manager,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250610-00/?p=111260 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Python: Concurrency in async/await and threading</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have been coding with Python for a while, especially if you have been using frameworks and libraries such as Fast API and discord.py, then you have probably been using async/await or asyncio. You may have heard statements like “multithreading in Python isn’t real”, and you may also know about the famous (or infamous) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/06/concurrency-in-async-await-and-threading/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Blocks in Java: Perfect for Multiline Strings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve likely used String variables to store values that span multiple lines, such as LLM prompts, JSON, HTML, XML, code snippets, and other such values. Some of these, such as a JSON value, include double quotes as part of the data. Imagine the inconvenience of using backslashes () to escape those quotes, indenting lines using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/text-blocks-in-java-perfect-for-multiline-strings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin for Server-Side Development: Community Content Roundup #2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin community keeps delivering valuable content for server-side development. From gRPC best practices to hands-on Ktor tutorials and Spring integrations, here are the latest highlights. 📖 [Article] Kotlin Tips and Tricks You May Not Know: #6 — Inject Functions in Spring Boot – Elena van Engelen-Maslova shares how to inject functions in Spring Boot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/kotlin-for-server-side-development-community-content-roundup-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PhpStorm Helps Maintain PHP Open-Source Projects: Interviews and Real-World Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The PHP ecosystem is driven by passionate developers building tools that power everything from content management systems right the way through to testing libraries and database layers. Behind each project is a dedicated team working to modernize code, improve performance, and move the ecosystem forward. The fact that many of these teams choose PhpStorm to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/06/10/how-phpstorm-helps-maintain-php-open-source-projects-interviews-and-real-world-examples/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting a Microsoft XNA 3.1 game to MonoGame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how I took a Microsoft XNA 3.1 game from 15 years ago and converted it to use MonoGame on .NET 8 in just a few hours
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/converting-an-xna-game-to-monogame/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL and NoSQL Query langauge support come to ReSharper!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 08:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ReSharper’s query language support for SQL and NoSQL provides C# developers with a more convenient way to work with SQL and NoSQL code directly in Visual Studio with ReSharper, supporting multiple SQL dialects beyond just T-SQL. It includes syntax highlighting, code analysis, auto-completion, and quick fixes to boost efficiency and catch issues early. Based on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/10/sql-and-nosql-query-langauge-support-come-to-resharper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside Ruby Debuggers: TracePoint, Instruction Sequence, and CRuby API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 07:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Debugging is a key part of software development, but most developers use debuggers without knowing how they actually work. The RubyMine team has spent years developing debugging tools for Ruby, and we want to share some of the insights we’ve gained along the way. In this post, we’ll explore the main technologies […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/inside-ruby-debuggers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate JavaScript scanning with Retire.js in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 08:51:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every web developer uses a lot of JavaScript libraries. When installing packages from npm, it almost feels like you are downloading half of the libraries there. Like every other piece of code, JavaScript can include vulnerabilities that make hackers drool and eager to start exploiting your site. In this post,
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/automate-javascript-scanning-with-retire-js-in-azure-devops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental alternative flow for OAuth First-Party Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 04:11:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at an alternative way of implementing a native app authentication and authorization. At present, a web browser is used to implement authentication of native applications when using OAuth and OpenID Connect. The alternative approach implemented in the post is based on the OAuth 2.0 for First-Party Applications draft and adapted to be […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/06/10/experimental-alternative-flow-for-oauth-first-party-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: Handling exceptions with Task.WaitAll and Task.WhenAll</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Task.WhenAll and Task.WaitAll are common methods in C# that allow you to execute multiple Tasks. But… what happens when an exception is thrown?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/task-whenall-vs-task-waitall-error-handling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Rocks SQL Saturday in Louisiana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 16:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The dotNetDave No Rest for the Wicked World Tour will feature a session at SQL Saturday Baton Rouge on July 26, 2025. The speaker, a seasoned software engineer and educator, will share insights from 30 years of experience, focusing on career advancement, work-life balance, and effective learning strategies for tech professionals.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/09/dotnetdave-rocks-the-sql-saturday-in-louisiana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building intelligent AI voice agents with Pipecat and Amazon Bedrock – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this series of posts, you will learn how to build intelligent AI voice agents using Pipecat, an open-source framework for voice and multimodal conversational AI agents, with foundation models on Amazon Bedrock. It includes high-level reference architectures, best practices and code samples to guide your implementation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-intelligent-ai-voice-agents-with-pipecat-and-amazon-bedrock-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stream multi-channel audio to Amazon Transcribe using the Web Audio API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the implementation details of a web application that uses the browser’s Web Audio API and Amazon Transcribe streaming to enable real-time dual-channel transcription. By using the combination of AudioContext, ChannelMergerNode, and AudioWorklet, we were able to seamlessly process and encode the audio data from two microphones before sending it to Amazon Transcribe for transcription.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/stream-multi-channel-audio-to-amazon-transcribe-using-the-web-audio-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Kepler democratized AI access and enhanced client services with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Kepler, a global full-service digital marketing agency serving Fortune 500 brands, we understand the delicate balance between creative marketing strategies and data-driven precision. In this post, we share how implementing Amazon Q Business transformed our operations by democratizing AI access across our organization while maintaining stringent security standards, resulting in an average savings of 2.7 hours per week per employee in manual work and improved client service delivery.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next edit suggestions available in Visual Studio GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot code completions, or gray text, are specialized in autocompleting unfinished code or providing helpful template code. In reality, coding activities are more diverse than writing new code. What if Copilot could better assist your coding not only with code generation, but your code editing activities as well? We are excited to
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/next-edit-suggestions-available-in-visual-studio-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Penetration Testing? Types, Processes, Tools, And Why It’s All Worth It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 14:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Penetration testing (or “pen testing”) is an authorized, simulated cyberattack designed to test the security of a production system. Ethical hackers perform penetration tests, emulating the behavior of cybercriminals to evaluate your software’s security and identify any weaknesses. During a pen test, these cybersecurity specialists use a range of techniques to attack a system. Once […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/what-is-penetration-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: Tricking a program into running non-elevated</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Within the span of a week,¹ we received two security vulnerability reports that claimed that you could use the RunAsInvoker compatibility layer to run any program without requiring administrator privileges. I have pointed out in the past that RunAsInvoker is not a secret, even higher UAC setting, but rather
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250609-00/?p=111258 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Cloud: How to Seamlessly Migrate On-Prem File Shares to Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 11:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For many organizations, legacy file servers have long been the backbone of data sharing and collaboration. But as cloud adoption reaches critical mass, those old file shares start to look like an anchor holding you back. Whether it’s scalability, remote access, disaster recovery, or cost optimization, the writing’s on the wall: it’s time to migrate […] The article Unlocking the Cloud: How to Seamlessly Migrate On-Prem File Shares to Azure Storage was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling security with responsible disclosure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces its Outbound Coordinated Disclosure Policy to guide how it responsibly reports vulnerabilities in third-party software—emphasizing integrity, collaboration, and proactive security at scale.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/scaling-coordinated-vulnerability-disclosure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outbound coordinated vulnerability disclosure policy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Outbound coordinated vulnerability disclosure policy
Link to article: https://openai.com/policies/outbound-coordinated-disclosure-policy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
