<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 17:51:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TLS 1.3 support in Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 17:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article follows announcement on a previous article that mentioned the end of support for Transport Security Layer (TLS) 1.0/1.1. TLS 1.3 is the latest version of the internet’s most deployed security protocol, which encrypts data to provide a secure communication channel between two endpoints. Microsoft has implemented updates to enable TLS 1.3 for Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/tls-1-3-support-in-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent healthcare assistants: Empowering stakeholders with personalized support and data-driven insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 17:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Healthcare decisions often require integrating information from multiple sources, such as medical literature, clinical databases, and patient records. LLMs lack the ability to seamlessly access and synthesize data from these diverse and distributed sources. This limits their potential to provide comprehensive and well-informed insights for healthcare applications. In this blog post, we will explore how Mistral LLM on Amazon Bedrock can address these challenges and enable the development of intelligent healthcare agents with LLM function calling capabilities, while maintaining robust data security and privacy through Amazon Bedrock Guardrails.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing automatic documentation comment generation in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Copilot is now automatically integrated into Visual Studio’s editor to help you generate doc comments for functions. This new feature aims to streamline your documentation process and enhance your coding experience. To access these updates, you will need a GitHub Copilot subscription. If you don’t already have GitHub Copilot, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-automatic-documentation-comment-generation-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a .NET Context-Aware Generative AI Chatbot using Amazon Bedrock and LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 14:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI is taking chatbots to the next level by empowering them to engage in human-like dialogues. These advanced conversational agents understand and respond to complex queries, provide personalized assistance, and even generate creative content. This blog post shows how to build a context-aware chatbot using Amazon Bedrock and LangChain in a .NET environment. The choice […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/building-context-aware-generative-ai-chatbot-using-amazon-bedrock-and-langchain-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: A program does not run correctly if you run it the wrong way</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So what did you expect?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250317-00/?p=110970 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the IntelliJ Infrastructure Team Cuts Build Execution Time by 30% With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction JetBrains is known for developing some of the world’s most popular IDEs, including IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, and WebStorm. Supporting this development is a dedicated infrastructure team that ensures hundreds of developers can efficiently build, test, and release these products. At the core of their workflow is TeamCity, JetBrains’ own CI/CD solution, which powers build […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/how-intellij-uses-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.1 Goes Beta With Enhanced CLion Nova, Debugger, and Embedded Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 08:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of CLion 2025.1 is now available with key improvements and changes announced for the upcoming release. You can download build 251.23774.112 for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.1 BETA Read the full release notes on YouTrack. Below […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/03/clion-2025-1-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify File I/O with Spargine’s FileHelper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_03_2025/16_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_03_2025/16_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a collection of open-source .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages, maintained since .NET 2. It includes the essential FileHelper for efficient file I/O operations on Windows, offering methods for file management, validation, and web downloads.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/16/boost-your-net-projects-simplify-file-i-o-with-spargines-filehelperhelper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keepin&#39; It Together - Dev Leader Weekly 87</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_03_2025/15_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_03_2025/15_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss some thoughts as I&#39;m working through a period of burnout.
Link to article: https://devleader.ca/2025/03/15/keepin-it-together-dev-leader-weekly-87 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-03-14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_03_2025/15_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 05:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_03_2025/15_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://devleader.ca/2025/03/15/weekly-recap-20250314 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining .NET 9 Deployment With GitHub Actions and Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_03_2025/15_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_03_2025/15_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code Faster With Amazon Q. Amazon Q Developer is your AI-powered coding companion that helps developers build, operate, and transform software with intelligent assistance at every step of the development lifecycle. Accelerate your workflow with line-by-line code suggestions and quality improvements in your favorite IDE. Get expert AWS guidance on architecture, troubleshooting, and resource optimization. Transform existing applications and automate upgrades without starting from scratch. Learn more in the AWS Developer Center.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy LiteLLM on Microsoft Azure with AZD, Azure Container Apps and PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 22:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI is evolving rapidly, and developers are increasingly looking for efficient ways to manage multiple LLMs (Large Language Models) using a centralized proxy. LiteLLM is a powerful solution that simplifies multi-LLM management by acting as a proxy server. However, setting it up on Microsoft Azure can be challenging due to lack of clear documentation—until […] The article Deploy LiteLLM on Microsoft Azure with AZD, Azure Container Apps and PostgreSQL was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nobody Codes a Bad System On Purpose</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 19:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I have been writing up a little one pager for a JasperFx Software client for their new CTO on why and how their flagship system could use some technical transformation and modernization. I ran my write up past one of their senior developers that I’ve been collaborating on for tactical performance improvements, and he more … Continue reading Nobody Codes a Bad System On Purpose →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/03/14/nobody-codes-a-bad-system-on-purpose/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with computer use in Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 18:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re announcing computer use support within Amazon Bedrock Agents using Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet V2 and Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet 3.7 models on Amazon Bedrock. This integration brings Anthropic’s visual perception capabilities as a managed tool within Amazon Bedrock Agents, providing you with a secure, traceable, and managed way to implement computer use automation in your workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/getting-started-with-computer-use-in-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: Announcing the Microsoft Semantic Kernel Couchbase Connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the launch of the Semantic Kernel Couchbase Vector Store Connector for .NET developers, created through our strategic partnership with Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel team. This powerful out-of-the-box connector transforms how developers integrate vector search capabilities into their AI applications. What sets this connector apart is how it harnesses Couchbase’s distributed NoSQL platform […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-announcing-the-microsoft-semantic-kernel-couchbase-connector 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio at GDC 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us in-person at Game Developers Conference 2025 with an in-depth look at how Visual Studio and GitHub Copilot can streamline your iteration workflow. Don’t miss the unveiling of our biggest C++ debugger update yet. Session Title: Accelerating Your Inner Loop with Visual Studio and GitHub Copilot Session Info: March 19th, 2025, 12:30 PM-1:30 PM Pacific Time | […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-at-gdc-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for Game Consoles in JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 16:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Big news for console game developers! As part of the 2024.3 release, JetBrains Rider added support for PlayStation®5 and Xbox consoles, allowing you to build, deploy, and debug your Unreal Engine and custom game engines directly on your preferred game consoles. Rider has excellent built-in support for working with C++, with lots of great functionality […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/03/14/support-for-game-consoles-in-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating RAG applications with Amazon Bedrock knowledge base evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 15:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post focuses on RAG evaluation with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, provides a guide to set up the feature, discusses nuances to consider as you evaluate your prompts and responses, and finally discusses best practices. By the end of this post, you will understand how the latest Amazon Bedrock evaluation features can streamline your approach to AI quality assurance, enabling more efficient and confident development of RAG applications.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring SQL Server Integration with .NET Aspire: A Collection of Hands-On Samples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 15:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m happy to share a new GitHub repository with developers: azure-sql-db-aspire. This collection of eight hands-on examples demonstrates how to integrate SQL Server and Azure SQL with .NET Aspire, making it easier to build modern, cloud-native applications. Why .NET Aspire for SQL Server? .NET Aspire is a new opinionated, cloud-ready stack for .NET applications that […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/exploring-sql-server-integration-with-net-aspire-a-collection-of-hands-on-samples 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of COM failing to pump messages in a single-threaded COM apartment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer encountered a hang caused by COM not pumping messages while waiting for a cross-thread operation to complete. They were using the task_sequencer class for serializing asynchronous operations on a UI thread they created to handle accessibility callbacks. The hang stack looked like this: ntdll!ZwWaitForMultipleObjects+0x4 KERNELBASE!WaitForMultipleObjectsEx+0xe0 combase!MTAThreadDispatchCrossApartmentCall+0x3a0 combase!CSyncClientCall::SendReceive2+0x65c combase!DefaultSendReceive+0x88 combase!CSyncClientCall::SendReceive+0x390 combase!CClientChannel::SendReceive+0xc0 combase!NdrExtpProxySendReceive+0x68 rpcrt4!NdrpClientCall3+0x764 combase!ObjectStublessClient+0x180 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250314-00/?p=110965 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2025.1 Beta Is Here With AI Enhancements, Framework Improvements, and a Better User Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 11:18:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The EAP cycle for WebStorm 2025.1 is over, and we’re excited to share what’s included in the Beta builds. The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the Beta builds and keep both them and your stable versions up to date. You can also manually download the Beta builds from our website. DOWNLOAD WEBSTORM […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/03/webstorm-2025-1-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the JetBrains Team at GDC 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From March 17–21, 2025, the Game Developers Conference (GDC) will bring together professionals from across the game industry at the Moscone Center in San Francisco. JetBrains is excited to once again be part of this event, and we invite you to visit our booth to explore how our tools can enhance your game development workflow. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/03/14/jetbrains-meets-gdc-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Xdebug Helper Browser Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 09:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For years, PHP developers have relied on the popular Xdebug Helper Chrome extension to simplify their debugging experience with Xdebug. Unfortunately, this extension may soon no longer be supported, potentially disrupting developers’ workflows. To ensure that PHP developers can continue debugging without interruptions, we’re collaborating with Fraser Chapman on the official Xdebug Helper extension for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/03/jetbrains-xdebug-helper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 2 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 07:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 2 is now available, bringing us one step closer to the major release! This build provides access to all the features we’ve rolled out in the Early Access Program, and there’s still plenty of time for you to explore and test them before the official release. You can download this version […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2025-1-beta-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET AI 模板现已提供预览版</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 06:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Jordan Matthiesen的.NET AI Template Now Available in Preview 想要开始 AI 开发，却不确定从哪里入手？我给您带来了一个好消息——我们全新的 AI 聊天 Web 应用模板现已提供预览版！这个模板是我们不断努力的一部分，旨在通过在Visual Studio，Visual Studio Code 和 .NET CLI 中提供脚手架和指导，让使用 .NET 进行 AI 开发变得更容易上手。 请注意，该模板目前为预览版，未来版本可能会根据您的反馈和 AI 的快速发展进行调整。 立即安装模板 如果想要开始使用该模板的首个预览版，您需要在终端中安装 Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Templates。只需运行： dotnet new install Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Templates 安装完成后，该模板即可在 Visual Studio，Visual Studio Code（需安装 C# Dev Kit）中使用，或者您也可以在工作目录中运行命令 dotnet new aichatweb 来创建它。 入门指南：.NET AI 聊天模板 .NET AI 聊天模板旨在帮助您快速构建一个基于 AI […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/net-ai-%e6%a8%a1%e6%9d%bf%e7%8e%b0%e5%b7%b2%e6%8f%90%e4%be%9b%e9%a2%84%e8%a7%88%e7%89%88 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of AI: Customizing AI Agents with the Semantic Kernel Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 21:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to promote a recent blog from AI Platform focused on customizing AI agents with the Semantic Kernel agent framework. Read the entire blog post: here The Future of AI blog series is an evolving collection of posts from the AI Futures team in collaboration with subject matter experts across Microsoft. In this […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/the-future-of-ai-customizing-ai-agents-with-the-semantic-kernel-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown for large text fields (private preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 20:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adding Markdown capabilities to the work item is a long-standing request. We introduced Markdown for comments in early 2024, but due to the rollout of the New Boards Hub, we put the feature on hold. Today, we’re excited to announce a private preview for Markdown support in large text fields! 🎉 🦄 How it works […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/markdown-for-large-text-fields-private-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift-Left Testing with Testcontainers: Catching Bugs Early with Local Integration Tests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 18:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how integration tests can help you catch defects earlier in the developers inner loop and how Testcontainers can make them feel as easy as unit tests.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/shift-left-testing-with-testcontainers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Data in transit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 18:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ensure your Microsoft Teams app, Microsoft 365 add-in, or agent meets the latest compliance standards with Microsoft 365 Certification.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-data-in-transit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New, Simpler Solution File Format</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 17:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For years, you’ve worked with Visual Studio’s solution file (*.SLN) format, and while it’s a core part of your project organization, we know the experience hasn’t always been smooth. Whether you’ve been modifying, maintaining, or trying to resolve merge conflicts, it’s often felt more like a hassle than it should be. We understand your frustrations, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-simpler-solution-file-format 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing support for SLNX, a new, simpler solution file format in the .NET CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the .NET CLI&#39;s ability to interact with the new XML-based solution file format.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-slnx-support-dotnet-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GoDaddy built a category generation system at scale with batch inference for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 16:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides an overview of a custom solution developed by the for GoDaddy, a domain registrar, registry, web hosting, and ecommerce company that seeks to make entrepreneurship more accessible by using generative AI to provide personalized business insights to over 21 million customers. In this collaboration, the Generative AI Innovation Center team created an accurate and cost-efficient generative AI–based solution using batch inference in Amazon Bedrock, helping GoDaddy improve their existing product categorization system.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Azure AI Agents with Semantic Kernel in .NET and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to dive into Semantic Kernel and Azure AI Agents. There are additional details about using an AzureAIAgent within Semantic Kernel covered in our documentation here. Azure AI Agents are powerful tools for developers seeking to integrate AI capabilities into their applications. In this blog post, we’ll explore how to utilize Azure AI […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/using-azure-ai-agents-with-semantic-kernel-in-net-and-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking customized models on Amazon Bedrock using LLMPerf and LiteLLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post begins a blog series exploring DeepSeek and open FMs on Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import. It covers the process of performance benchmarking of custom models in Amazon Bedrock using popular open source tools: LLMPerf and LiteLLM. It includes a notebook that includes step-by-step instructions to deploy a DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Llama-8B model, but the same steps apply for any other model supported by Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating asynchronous AI agents with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The integration of generative AI agents into business processes is poised to accelerate as organizations recognize the untapped potential of these technologies. Advancements in multimodal artificial intelligence (AI), where agents can understand and generate not just text but also images, audio, and video, will further broaden their applications. This post will discuss agentic AI driven architecture and ways of implementing.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/creating-asynchronous-ai-agents-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run Qwen 2.5 on AWS AI chips using Hugging Face libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we outline how to get started with deploying the Qwen 2.5 family of models on an Inferentia instance using Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) and Amazon SageMaker using the Hugging Face Text Generation Inference (TGI) container and the Hugging Face Optimum Neuron library. Qwen2.5 Coder and Math variants are also supported.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-to-run-qwen-2-5-on-aws-ai-chips-using-hugging-face-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing customer service: MaestroQA’s integration with Amazon Bedrock for actionable insight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive deeper into one of MaestroQA’s key features—conversation analytics, which helps support teams uncover customer concerns, address points of friction, adapt support workflows, and identify areas for coaching through the use of Amazon Bedrock. We discuss the unique challenges MaestroQA overcame and how they use AWS to build new features, drive customer insights, and improve operational inefficiencies.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-customer-service-maestroqas-integration-with-amazon-bedrock-for-actionable-insight/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sure that a DLL loads only from your application directory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can ask for it as an option, but think about what you&#39;re actually protecting against.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250313-00/?p=110963 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize hosting DeepSeek-R1 distilled models with Hugging Face TGI on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 13:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to optimize hosting DeepSeek-R1 distilled models with Hugging Face Text Generation Inference (TGI) on Amazon SageMaker AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimize-hosting-deepseek-r1-distilled-models-with-hugging-face-tgi-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DirectX at GDC 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re counting down the days until the Microsoft DirectX team will be at the Game Developers Conference 2025 with a lineup of exciting sessions and announcements to push the boundaries of game development. Whether you’re a seasoned graphics developer or just diving into the world of DirectX, our sessions will offer valuable insights into the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directx-at-gdc-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Tool Selection for ML Model Production</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            data science and software engineering teams can choose the best tools for their respective roles in delivering machine learning models to production.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/ml-model-prod-tooling 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ardalis Specification v9 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_03_2025/13_03_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new major version of the Ardalis Specification library has been released. This library is used to create and compose specifications for…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/ardalis-specification-v9-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Story: Creating a Semantic Kernel Agent for Automated GitHub Code Reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 22:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today I want to welcome a guest author to our Semantic Kernel blog, Rasmus Wulff Jensen, to cover how he’s created a Semantic Kernel agent for automated GitHub code review. We’ll turn it over to Rasmus to dive in. Introduction If you work in software development, you know that Code reviews are an essential part […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-story-creating-a-semantic-kernel-agent-for-automated-github-code-reviews 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Total Size Allocated to Azure Storage Account (Blobs, Files, Tables and Queues)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 22:18:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Storage Accounts are a fundamental part of cloud storage in Microsoft Azure, providing various types of storage services such as blobs, files, tables, and queues. Understanding the total size allocated to a storage account and the usage breakdown per service type is crucial for optimizing costs, managing capacity, and ensuring efficient data storage management. […] The article Get Total Size Allocated to Azure Storage Account (Blobs, Files, Tables and Queues) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in Microsoft Dev Box</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 19:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post covers the latest features and enhancements in Microsoft Dev Box. These updates introduce advanced customization capabilities, improved security, performance optimizations, and better developer experience to make Dev Box even more efficient. Last update: 03/12/2025 In this post: Config-as-workflow improvements Enhanced user provided customizations Developer onboarding &amp;amp; experience Streamlined and flexible onboarding for enterprises […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/whats-new-in-microsoft-dev-box 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring creative possibilities: A visual guide to Amazon Nova Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 18:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we showcase a curated gallery of visuals generated by Nova Canvas—categorized by real-world use cases—from marketing and product visualization to concept art and design exploration. Each image is paired with the prompt and parameters that generated it, providing a practical starting point for your own AI-driven creativity. Whether you&#39;re crafting specific types of images, optimizing workflows, or simply seeking inspiration, this guide will help you unlock the full potential of Amazon Nova Canvas.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authoring Enhancements in Microsoft Desired State Configuration v3.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 18:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the third post in a multi-part series about the new release of DSC. Microsoft Desired State Configuration (DSC) v3.0.0 provides powerful feature that enhance the authoring experience. Shell completion Schema-based validation Support for modern DSLs like Azure Bicep DSC command completer The completer command returns a shell script that, when executed, registers completions […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/enhanced-authoring-with-dsc-v3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with Microsoft Desired State Configuration v3.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post show you how to install DSC v3.0.0 and get started using the dsc command.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/get-started-with-dsc-v3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Microsoft Desired State Configuration v3.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the release of Microsoft Desired State Configuration v3.0.0. We discuss the features and benefits of DSC and how it differs from PowerShell DSC.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/announcing-dsc-v3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Python Driver for SQL Server and Azure SQL!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the alpha release of our new open-source Python driver for Microsoft SQL Server and the Azure SQL family, now available on GitHub at mssql-python.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/mssql-python-for-sqlserver-alpha-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello HybridCache! Streamlining Cache Management for ASP.NET Core Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HybridCache is now GA, use today
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/hybrid-cache-is-now-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless Scaling: Autoscale goes GA on vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that Autoscale is now generally available (GA) for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB! Say goodbye to manual scaling and overprovisioning—Autoscale dynamically adjusts your database capacity in real time, ensuring peak performance exactly when you need it. Instant scaling? Check. Cost savings? Absolutely. Predictable pricing? You got it. Unlike traditional managed […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/effortless-scaling-autoscale-goes-ga-on-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make more sense of multithreaded debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debugging complex programs often feels like navigating a labyrinth of threads and stack traces. The challenge of understanding thread behaviors and tracing issues can be daunting, leading to longer development times and increased frustration. But now, there’s a solution that simplifies this process—introducing AI-powered thread summaries in Parallel Stacks Window with Visual Studio. To address […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/make-more-sense-of-multithreaded-debugging 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the thread safety requirements of HSTRING and BSTR?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            They do not have thread affinity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250312-00/?p=110960 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: When CountAsync() Outperforms AnyAsync() in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article critiques code analysis rule CA1828 in Microsoft .NET, which suggests using AnyAsync() over CountAsync() for checking item existence in IQueryable collections. Benchmark results indicate CountAsync() outperforms both AnyAsync() and LongCountAsync(), pointing to potential inefficiencies in following CA1828. The author recommends adjusting rule severity to optimize performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/12/microsoft-net-code-analysis-when-countasync-outperforms-anyasync-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework March 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for March 2025.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-march-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing jackson-databind with azure-json and azure-xml</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 20:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post explains how azure-json and azure-xml replaced jackson-databind in the Azure SDK for Java.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/replacing-jackson-databind-with-azure-json-and-azure-xml 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: INCM transforms legal accessibility with an AI Search Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customer Case Study: INCM transforms legal accessibility with an AI Search Assistant The Imprensa Nacional-Casa da Moeda (INCM) is responsible for managing and publishing Portugal’s Diário da República (Official Gazette of the Republic of Portugal), which includes essential information for understanding laws, regulations, and legal processes. The quantity of information and the complex language used […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-incm-transforms-legal-accessibility-with-an-ai-search-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing patches that impact our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can download the latest version of the product, Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 from the Azure DevOps Server download page. The following versions of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/march-patches-for-azure-devops-server-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Boards Hub Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 18:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve reached a major milestone in the rollout of New Boards Hub this week by making it the default experience for all organizations and users. While many users can still temporarily switch back if they encounter a blocking issue, our telemetry shows that 97% of users are staying on New Boards without reverting. This is […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-boards-hub-update-spring-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you really need that abstraction or generic code? (YAGNI)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You Aren’t Gonna Need It. The essence of YAGNI is simple: don’t build something today that you assume you’ll need in the future. However, there’s a nuance here because we also don’t want to handcuff ourselves. Let’s explore how this principle applies both to features and technical implementation. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post… Read More »Do you really need that abstraction or generic code? (YAGNI) The post Do you really need that abstraction or generic code?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Chat History for AI Applications Using Azure Cosmos DB Go SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 15:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post covers how to build a chat history implementation using Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL Go SDK and langchaingo. If you are new to the Go SDK, the sample chatbot application presented in the blog serves as a practical introduction, covering basic operations like read, upsert, etc. It also demonstrates using the Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/implementing-chat-history-for-ai-applications-using-azure-cosmos-db-go-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4o Copilot code completion model available now in Visual Studio public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that the new GPT-4o Copilot code completion model is now available for GitHub Copilot users in Visual Studio starting in 17.14 Preview 2! This new model, based on GPT-4o mini, has undergone additional training on over 275,000 high-quality public repositories across more than 30 popular programming languages. As a result, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/gpt-4o-copilot-code-completion-model-available-now-in-visual-studio-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 10x Faster TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today I’m excited to announce the next steps we’re taking to radically improve TypeScript performance. The core value proposition of TypeScript is an excellent developer experience. As your codebase grows, so does the value of TypeScript itself, but in many cases TypeScript has not been able to scale up to the very largest codebases. Developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/typescript-native-port 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What an insightful observation, you get to wear “the hat”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maybe not so insightful.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250311-00/?p=110958 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunsetting Writerside IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 12:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In October 2023, we launched the Early Access Program for Writerside – a tool for authoring, testing, and publishing documentation. Built on the IntelliJ Platform, Writerside was available in two versions: a standalone tool and a plugin for JetBrains IDEs. Our goal was to serve two key audiences – developers who document their work and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2025/03/sunsetting-writerside-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Dependency Injection: Advanced Techniques Beyond the Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 10:15:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dependency injection (DI) is a powerful feature in .NET applications. It allows you the decoupling of dependencies by injecting required services at runtime, ensuring the modularity and testability of your code. You can create separate services or import them from NuGet packages by registering them into your application. However, injecting
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/net-dependency-injection-advanced-techniques-beyond-the-basics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running an ASP.NET Core app inside IIS in a Windows container</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how to run an ASP.NET Core app inside IIS in a Windows Docker container
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/running-an-aspnetcore-app-behind-iis-in-a-windows-container/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping the Conversation Flowing: Managing Context with Semantic Kernel Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 05:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the dynamic field of conversational AI, managing coherent and contextually meaningful interactions between humans and digital assistants poses increasingly complex challenges. As dialogue lengths extend, maintaining full conversational context becomes problematic due to token constraints and memory limitations inherent to large language models (LLMs). These constraints not only degrade conversational clarity but also compromise […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-python-context-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
