<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:00:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Put your AI to the Test with Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is changing how we build software, but it also introduces new challenges: how do you know if your AI application is giving the right answers and producing the right outcomes? Evaluations (often referred to simply as ‘evals’) provide a structured way to measure quality so you can trust your results. In this blog, we’ll introduce the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/put-your-ai-to-the-test-with-microsoft-extensions-ai-evaluation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New GitHub Copilot capabilities for C&#43;&#43; developers: Upgrade MSVC, improve build performance, and refactor C&#43;&#43; code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot;]GitHub Copilot app modernization for C++, GitHub Copilot build performance for Windows, and C++ code editing tools for GitHub Copilot will be available soon in Private Preview. Join the waitlist for Private Preview today.[/alert] Yesterday at GitHub Universe, Gi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/new-github-copilot-capabilities-for-c-developers-upgrade-msvc-improve-build-performance-and-refactor-c-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation of the previewImageUrl property for Insights items that reference file attachments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re deprecating the previewImageUrl property in the resourceVisualization complex type for
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-of-the-previewimageurl-property-for-insights-items-that-reference-file-attachments 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Dispatch in DDD</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What’s Double Dispatch? Well, before we get to what it is, there is a common belief in domain-driven design that you want to keep your domain pure, meaning no dependencies, no services, no distractions. I get it because you do not want that core logic coupled to infrastructure concerns like database calls. You want it… Read More »Double Dispatch in DDD The post Double Dispatch in DDD appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Distributed Systems: Jason Taylor Shows How .NET Aspire Makes the Complex Feel Effortless</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025, Jason Taylor, Microsoft MVP and Solutions Architect at Particular Software, delivered an engaging presentation that transforms how we think about building distributed systems. Through live coding and interactive polls with the audience, Taylor demonstrated how .NET Aspire can turn what’s traditionally been a complex, friction-filled process into something surprisingly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/29/simplifying-distributed-systems-dotnet-aspire-jason-taylor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do when you have a crash in the runtime control flow guard check</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows Control Flow Guard (CFG) is a defense in depth feature which validates indirect call targets. The idea is that each module that is enabled for CFG provides a bitmap that describes which addresses in the module are intended to be targets of indirect calls. When CFG is enabled in a process, indirect function calls are checked against
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251029-00/?p=111738 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program Has Started</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re starting the MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program (EAP) today. You can download the first 2025.3 EAP release and try it out now! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 EAP Besides numerous bug fixes, this release brings three major improvements: Light and dark TextIcon options TextIcon’s layers can now be configured to apply to the light, dark, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/10/the-mps-2025-3-eap-has-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Order in the Mayhem: A Novel Concurrency Testing Tool that Improved the Kotlin Compiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever tried to track down a bug in concurrent programs, you know how chaotic and frustrating it can be: everything seems to work fine, then suddenly crashes, and you can’t quite pin down why – all while the bugs slip through. To bring order to this chaos, at JetBrains Research we built LitmusKt […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/10/litmuskt-concurrency-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine Does More to Simplify Server Side Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just to set myself up with some pressure to perform, let me hype up a live stream on Wolverine I’m doing later this week! I’m doing a live stream on Thursday afternoon (U.S. friendly this time) entitled Vertical Slices the Critter Stack Way based on a fun, meandering talk I did for Houston DNUG and … Continue reading Wolverine Does More to Simplify Server Side Code →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing gpt-oss-safeguard</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces gpt-oss-safeguard—open-weight reasoning models for safety classification that let developers apply and iterate on custom policies.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-oss-safeguard 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Report: Performance and baseline evaluations of gpt-oss-safeguard-120b and gpt-oss-safeguard-20b</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            gpt-oss-safeguard-120b and gpt-oss-safeguard-20b are two open-weight reasoning models post-trained from the gpt-oss models and trained to reason from a provided policy in order to label content under that policy. In this report, we describe gpt-oss-safeguard’s capabilities and provide our baseline safety evaluations on the gpt-oss-safeguard models, using the underlying gpt-oss models as a baseline. For more information about the development and architecture of the underlying gpt-oss models, see the original gpt-oss model model card⁠.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Custom Agents for .NET Developers: C# Expert &amp; WinForms Expert</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With GitHub’s announcement of Copilot Custom Agents, developers now have powerful new tools to automate and accelerate their workflows. These custom agents enhance Copilot by serving as intelligent accelerators with specialized expertise, able to analyze codebases, plan tasks, and execu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-custom-agents-for-dotnet-developers-csharp-expert-winforms-expert 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Launch of Developer Productivity AI Arena: An Open Platform for Benchmarking AI Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For 25 years, JetBrains has shaped the software development landscape across multiple programming languages, advancing how developers and organizations build software. Our focus has always been on improving productivity and the overall developer experience. With the rise of AI, a key challenge now is understanding how to measure the real-world productivity gains provided by AI-assisted […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/10/28/the-launch-of-developer-productivity-ai-arena-an-open-platform-for-benchmarking-ai-coding-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Developer Productivity AI Arena: An Open Platform for AI Coding Agents Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s software development landscape, AI coding agents are evolving rapidly from prototypes into indispensable tools. Yet the industry still lacks an open, neutral, standards-based way to measure the real-world effectiveness of these agents across languages, frameworks, and environments. With over two decades of experience building developer tools that are trusted by millions worldwide, we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/10/28/introducing-developer-productivity-ai-arena-an-open-platform-for-ai-coding-agents-benchmarks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting NVIDIA speech NIM models on Amazon SageMaker AI: Parakeet ASR</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to deploy NVIDIA&#39;s Parakeet ASR model on Amazon SageMaker AI using asynchronous inference endpoints to create a scalable, cost-effective pipeline for processing large volumes of audio data. The solution combines state-of-the-art speech recognition capabilities with AWS managed services like Lambda, S3, and Bedrock to automatically transcribe audio files and generate intelligent summaries, enabling organizations to unlock valuable insights from customer calls, meeting recordings, and other audio content at scale .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Azure MCP Server 1.0.0 Stable Release – A New Era for Agentic Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re not just shipping software, we’re opening the door to a new era of cloud automation and AI-powered development. Azure MCP server 1.0 is now officially available as a stable release! If you’re a developer, an AI enthusiast, or just someone who loves seeing what’s possible when cloud a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/announcing-azure-mcp-server-stable-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces a Remote MCP Server and New Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The YouTrack 2025.3 release introduces remote MCP (Model Context Protocol) support, which expands the possibilities for those who build integrations with YouTrack. This enables you to securely connect AI-powered tools to YouTrack, allowing your teams to manage their work directly from an LLM, IDE, or agent platform. In addition, many new apps are now available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/10/youtrack-introduces-a-remote-mcp-server-and-new-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java and AI for Beginners: a practical video series for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-and-ai-for-beginners-a-practical-video-series-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Registry and Allowlist Controls for Copilot in JetBrains and Eclipse Now in Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MCP registry and allowlist controls for GitHub Copilot in JetBrains IDEs and Eclipse are now available in public preview in nightly/pre-release builds.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/mcp-registry-and-allowlist-controls-for-copilot-in-jetbrains-and-eclipse-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Registry and Allowlist Controls Now Available in GitHub Copilot for Xcode (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that MCP Registry and Allowlist Controls in GitHub Copilot for Xcode are now available in public preview in pre-release builds. These capabilities help Xcode developers discover, install, and manage Model Context Protocol (MCP)
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/mcp-registry-and-allowlist-controls-now-available-in-github-copilot-for-xcode-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Backup to Discovery: Veeam’s Search Engine Powered by Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was co-authored by Zack Rossman, Staff Software Engineer, Veeam; Ashlie Martinez, Staff Software Engineer, Veeam; and James Nguyen, Senior Principal Cloud Solution Architect, AI/ML, Microsoft. Don&#39;t miss: Hear all about about Veeam&#39;s AI-powered semantic search use case and architecture setup
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/from-backup-to-discovery-veeams-search-engine-powered-by-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Kotlin in Real Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the second post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/evaluating-kotlin-in-real-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did the Windows 95 user interface code get brought to the Windows NT code base?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A long time ago, somebody asked, &amp;quot;How did the new Windows 95 user interface get brought to the Windows NT code base? The development of Windows 95 lined up with the endgame of Windows NT 3.1, so how did the finished Windows 95 code get brought to the Windows NT code base for Windows NT 4.0? Did they reimplement it based on the existing spec
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251028-00/?p=111733 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doppel’s AI defense system stops attacks before they spread</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Doppel uses OpenAI’s GPT-5 and reinforcement fine-tuning (RFT) to stop deepfake and impersonation attacks before they spread, cutting analyst workloads by 80% and reducing threat response from hours to minutes.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/doppel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the worst .NET vulnerability ever: request smuggling and CVE-2025-55315</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss request smuggling, the recent vulnerability in ASP.NET Core with a severity score of 9.9, and how attackers could exploit it
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/understanding-the-worst-dotnet-vulnerability-request-smuggling-and-cve-2025-55315/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.2.4: Another Set of Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A fourth set of updates for the 2025.2 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.2.4 TeamCity extension is back After listening to feedback from teams who rely on it for their CI workflows, we’ve restored […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/28/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-4-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built to benefit everyone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s recapitalization strengthens mission-focused governance, expanding resources to ensure AI benefits everyone while advancing innovation responsibly.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/built-to-benefit-everyone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The next chapter of the Microsoft–OpenAI partnership</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft and OpenAI sign a new agreement that strengthens its long-term partnership, expands innovation, and ensures responsible AI progress.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/next-chapter-of-microsoft-openai-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine 5 and Modular Monoliths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 03:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the announcement for the Wolverine 5.0 release last week, I left out a pretty big set of improvements for modular monolith support, specifically in how Wolverine can now work with multiple databases from one service process. Wolverine works closely with databases for: And all of those features are supported for Marten, EF Core with … Continue reading Wolverine 5 and Modular Monoliths →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/10/27/wolverine-5-and-modular-monoliths/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (October 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Modern Enterprise Toolkit for Secure, High-Quality Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 19, 2025, join JetBrains Qodana for a live session exploring how enterprises can embed quality, security, and compliance directly into their development workflows. Hosted by Product Specialist, Kai Schmithuesen, this session will walk you through the latest Qodana capabilities and real-world applications for modern software development and DevOps teams. Mark your calendars and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/10/the-modern-enterprise-toolkit-for-secure-high-quality-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: Denial of service by loading a very large file</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A denial of service vulnerability report was filed against a program, let&#39;s call it Notepad. The actual text of the report was very hard to understand because the grammar was all messed up. I&#39;ll give the finder the benefit of the doubt on the assumption that they are not a native English speaker. Here&#39;s a cleaned-up version:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251027-00/?p=111731 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Finally Back with News</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a while since you last heard from me – I know, I’ve been a busy bee! Between releases and launches, time just flew by. But I’ve got plenty of updates to share with you. Let’s start with some of the biggest highlights from September and October, and if you’re curious, scroll down for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/kodees-kotlin-roundup-october-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Connect MCP Servers to Claude Desktop with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What if you could turn Claude from a conversational assistant into a development partner that actually does things—safely, securely, and without touching your local machine? If you&#39;ve been exploring Claude Desktop and wondering how to connect it with real developer tools, Docker MCP Toolkit is the missing piece you&#39;ve been looking for. Here&#39;s the reality:...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/connect-mcp-servers-to-claude-desktop-with-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Django 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the highlights and key takeaways from the recently released Django Developers Survey. Now in its fourth year, this annual collaboration between the Django Software Foundation and PyCharm tabulates responses from over 4,600 Django developers worldwide. If you work with Python and the web more broadly, there’s a lot to learn from what’s happening […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/10/the-state-of-django-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seizing the AI opportunity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Meeting the demands of the Intelligence Age will require strategic investment in energy and infrastructure. OpenAI’s submission to the White House details how expanding capacity and workforce readiness can sustain U.S. leadership in AI and economic growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/seizing-the-ai-opportunity 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use a Spec-Driven Approach for Coding with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s see how this works with Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains. What you’ll get from this guide Developing complex software features can be daunting. Such tasks often feel overwhelming due to the sheer size of the codebase, the uncertainty of dependencies, and the difficulty of keeping all requirements in mind. With the advent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/junie/2025/10/how-to-use-a-spec-driven-approach-for-coding-with-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addendum to GPT-5 System Card: Sensitive conversations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This system card details GPT-5’s improvements in handling sensitive conversations, including new benchmarks for emotional reliance, mental health, and jailbreak resistance.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-system-card-sensitive-conversations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening ChatGPT’s responses in sensitive conversations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI collaborated with 170+ mental health experts to improve ChatGPT’s ability to recognize distress, respond empathetically, and guide users toward real-world support—reducing unsafe responses by up to 80%. Learn how we’re making ChatGPT safer and more supportive in sensitive moments.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/strengthening-chatgpt-responses-in-sensitive-conversations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use swiyu, the Swiss E-ID to authenticate users with Duende and .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 06:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to authenticate users using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity which verifies identities (verifiable digital credentials) using the Swiss Digital identity and trust infrastructure (swiyu). The swiyu infrastructure is implemented using the provided generic containers which implement the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations standards as well as many other standards for implementing […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/10/27/use-swiyu-the-swiss-e-id-to-authenticate-users-with-duende-and-net-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SignalR with Wolverine 5.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 01:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Wolverine 5.0 release earlier last last week (finally) added a long requested SignalR transport. The SignalR library from Microsoft isn’t hard to use from Wolverine for simplistic WebSockets or Server Sent Events usage as it was, but what if you want a server side application to exchange any number of different messages between a browser (or … Continue reading Using SignalR with Wolverine 5.0 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/10/26/using-signalr-with-wolverine-5-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A law and tax firm redefines efficiency with ChatGPT Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Steuerrecht.com uses ChatGPT Business to streamline legal workflows, automate tax research, and scale client service—helping law firms boost productivity and stay competitive.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/steuerrecht 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Programming Rule #1: Anticipate Errors and Eliminate Bugs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_10_2025/26_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_10_2025/26_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Defensive programming emphasizes anticipating potential failures in code, treating every line as a possible error point. Developers should use structured exception handling, provide meaningful error messages, and maintain system integrity. Tools like Spargine facilitate effective defensive programming by simplifying error handling and promoting resilience in applications by addressing unexpected scenarios.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/10/26/defensive-programming-rule-1-anticipate-errors-and-eliminate-bugs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College Developer Struggles - Dev Leader Weekly 113</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2025/25_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2025/25_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to focus your time and energy as a developer in college.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/10/25/college-developer-struggles-dev-leader-weekly-113 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-10-24</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2025/25_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2025/25_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/10/25/weekly-recap-20251024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Interview Question That Changed How I Think About System Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2025/25_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2025/25_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how a simple interview question about report generation reveals the difference between optimizing code and designing scalable systems, and why the best solution isn&#39;t making it faster, but making it asynchronous.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-interview-question-that-changed-how-i-think-about-system-design 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Hub Incident Report – October 20, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 23:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker experienced significant disruptions due to a widespread outage in AWS’s US-East-1 region on October 20, 2025. Developers worldwide rely on Docker as part of their daily workflow, and we regret the disruption this caused. In this post, we want to provide transparency about what happened, what we have learned, and how we are strengthening...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hub-incident-report-october-20-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your 6-Step Guide to Deploying a Website with GitHub Codespaces and Copilot agent mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 22:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            👋everyone! Shree here. I&#39;m sure many of you have had a similar chat with someone you know
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/your-6-step-guide-to-deploying-a-website-with-github-codespaces-and-copilot-agent-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Org, Your Tools: Building a Custom MCP Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 19:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m Mike Coleman, a staff solutions architect at Docker. In this role, I spend a lot of time talking to enterprise customers about AI adoption. One thing I hear over and over again is that these companies want to ensure appropriate guardrails are in place when it comes to deploying AI tooling. For instance, many...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-custom-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI design in healthcare and life sciences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the critical design considerations for building responsible AI systems in healthcare and life sciences, focusing on establishing governance mechanisms, transparency artifacts, and security measures that ensure safe and effective generative AI applications. The discussion covers essential policies for mitigating risks like confabulation and bias while promoting trust, accountability, and patient safety throughout the AI development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-design-in-healthcare-and-life-sciences/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond pilots: A proven framework for scaling AI to production</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the Five V&#39;s Framework—a field-tested methodology that has helped 65% of AWS Generative AI Innovation Center customer projects successfully transition from concept to production, with some launching in just 45 days. The framework provides a structured approach through Value, Visualize, Validate, Verify, and Venture phases, shifting focus from &amp;quot;What can AI do?&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;What do we need AI to do?&amp;quot; while ensuring solutions deliver measurable business outcomes and sustainable operational excellence.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The early history of the Windows Runtime PropertyValue and why there is a PropertyType.Inspectable that is never used</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I mentioned that the Property­Value.Create­Inspectable method doesn&#39;t create a Property­Value
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251024-00/?p=111725 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Guide to the Galaxy: MCP Toolkit and Gateway, Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is an abridged version of the interview we had in AI Guide to the Galaxy, where host Oleg Šelajev spoke with Jim Clark, Principal Software Engineer at Docker, to unpack Docker’s MCP Toolkit and MCP Gateway. TL;DR What they are: The MCP Toolkit helps you discover, run, and manage MCP servers; the MCP Gateway...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-toolkit-gateway-explained/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why More People Are Taking Control of Their Digital Lives with Self-Hosted Alternatives</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Remember when owning software meant you bought a CD, installed it, and it was yours until your computer died? Even if you got a new computer, you could install that same software on the new one. Only “serious” software packages had strict licensing restrictions. These days, most of our tools live in the cloud, guarded...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/self-hosted-alternatives-control-your-data/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.4 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.4 has arrived with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. The latest update brings the following improvements: For a comprehensive overview of the fixes, see the release notes. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/10/intellij-idea-2025-2-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Sponsorship on NuGet.org</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 22:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Package maintainers are the backbone of the NuGet.org ecosystem, building and maintaining the packages we all rely on. Today we are excited to announce the new NuGet.org Sponsorship feature which makes it easier than ever for consumers to recognize and support the authors behind their favorite packages. With Sponsorship on NuG
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-sponsorship-on-nugetdotorg-for-maintainer-appreciation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Gremlin queries using Amazon Bedrock models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 20:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore an innovative approach that converts natural language to Gremlin queries using Amazon Bedrock models such as Amazon Nova Pro, helping business analysts and data scientists access graph databases without requiring deep technical expertise. The methodology involves three key steps: extracting graph knowledge, structuring the graph similar to text-to-SQL processing, and generating executable Gremlin queries through an iterative refinement process that achieved 74.17% overall accuracy in testing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating responsible AI into generative AI project prioritization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 20:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how companies can systematically incorporate responsible AI practices into their generative AI project prioritization methodology to better evaluate business value against costs while addressing novel risks like hallucination and regulatory compliance. The post demonstrates through a practical example how conducting upfront responsible AI risk assessments can significantly change project rankings by revealing substantial mitigation work that affects overall project complexity and timeline.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BoldSign Modernized Development at Scale With JetBrains dotUltimate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 19:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When the engineering team at Syncfusion set out to build BoldSign, a modern e-signature platform, they knew speed and stability would be critical. Supporting 40,000+ organizations across industries like finance, legal, and IT, BoldSign had to offer fast, secure document signing at scale without slowing down its own development cycles in the process. But as adoption grew, so […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/23/how-boldsign-modernized-development-at-scale-with-jetbrains-dotultimate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine 5.0 is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 19:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That’s of course supposed to be a 1992 Ford Mustang GT with the 5.0L V8 that high school age me thought was the coolest car I could imagine ever owning (I most certainly never did of course). Queue “Ice, Ice Baby” and sing “rolling, in my 5.0” in your head because here we go… Wolverine … Continue reading Wolverine 5.0 is Here! →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/10/23/wolverine-5-0-is-here/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to Microsoft Agent Framework in Your .NET AI Chat App</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AI App Templates let you spin up a working chat application in minutes, complete with AI integration, custom data ingestion, and all the pieces you need to get started. It&#39;s a cool and solid foundation. But here&#39;s the thing: what if you want to go beyond basic chat? What if you want to build AI agents that can actually reason,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/upgrading-to-microsoft-agent-framework-in-your-dotnet-ai-chat-app 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Runtime design principle: Properties can be set in any order</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the design principles of the Windows Runtime is that if an object has multiple writable properties, then you can set them in any order and the effect will be the same. For example, consider an object with three properties: Minimum, Maximum, and Value. Suppose the rule is that you must, a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251023-00/?p=111716 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker &#43; E2B: Building the Future of Trusted AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trusted Software Starts Here The era of agents is here. Some teams are experimenting, others are just getting started, and a few are already running agents in production. But one challenge stands out: trust. Trust that your agents will act securely. Over 20 million developers already rely on Docker to build and ship software safely...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-e2b-building-the-future-of-trusted-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Performance Matters in Python Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Dido Grigorov, a deep learning engineer and Python programmer with 17 years of experience in the field. Python’s flexibility and ease of use make it a go-to language for developers, but its interpreted nature and global interpreter lock (GIL) can lead to performance bottlenecks, especially in large-scale or resource-intensive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/10/why-performance-matters-in-python-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Kotlin for Java Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This post opens The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how Kotlin adoption grows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/getting-started-with-kotlin-for-java-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI acquires Software Applications Incorporated, maker of Sky</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI has acquired Software Applications Incorporated, maker of Sky—a natural language interface for Mac that brings AI directly into your desktop experience. Together, we’re integrating Sky’s deep macOS capabilities into ChatGPT to make AI more intuitive, contextual, and action-oriented.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-acquires-software-applications-incorporated 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consensus accelerates research with GPT-5 and Responses API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Consensus uses GPT-5 and OpenAI’s Responses API to power a multi-agent research assistant that reads, analyzes, and synthesizes evidence in minutes—helping over 8 million researchers accelerate scientific discovery.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/consensus 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Enterprise AI Complexity: Multi-Agent Orchestration with the Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Architectural Imperative: Why Multi-Agent Orchestration is Essential In modern enterprise AI systems, the scope and complexity of real-world business ch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/unlocking-enterprise-ai-complexity-multi-agent-orchestration-with-the-microsoft-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Testing with Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Ever had to write tests that need a real database, and found yourself juggling local setups or dummy data? Testcontainers might just be your new best friend. In this article, we&#39;ll explore how Testcontainers can simplify integration testing by spinning up real services in Docker containers on-demand. We&#39;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/testing-with-testcontainers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI in South Korea—OpenAI’s Economic Blueprint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI&#39;s Korea Economic Blueprint outlines how South Korea can scale trusted AI through sovereign capabilities and strategic partnerships to drive growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/south-korea-economic-blueprint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work smarter with your company knowledge in ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Company knowledge brings context from your apps into ChatGPT for answers specific to your business, with clear citations, security, privacy, and admin controls. Available now for Business, Enterprise, and Edu users.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-company-knowledge 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build scalable creative solutions for product teams with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how product teams can leverage Amazon Bedrock and AWS services to transform their creative workflows through generative AI, enabling rapid content iteration across multiple formats while maintaining brand consistency and compliance. The solution demonstrates how teams can deploy a scalable generative AI application that accelerates everything from product descriptions and marketing copy to visual concepts and video content, significantly reducing time to market while enhancing creative quality.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a proactive AI cost management system for Amazon Bedrock – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore advanced cost monitoring strategies for Amazon Bedrock deployments, introducing granular custom tagging approaches for precise cost allocation and comprehensive reporting mechanisms that build upon the proactive cost management foundation established in Part 1. The solution demonstrates how to implement invocation-level tagging, application inference profiles, and integration with AWS Cost Explorer to create a complete 360-degree view of generative AI usage and expenses.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a proactive AI cost management system for Amazon Bedrock – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce a comprehensive solution for proactively managing Amazon Bedrock inference costs through a cost sentry mechanism designed to establish and enforce token usage limits, providing organizations with a robust framework for controlling generative AI expenses. The solution uses serverless workflows and native Amazon Bedrock integration to deliver a predictable, cost-effective approach that aligns with organizational financial constraints while preventing runaway costs through leading indicators and real-time budget enforcement.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline code migration using Amazon Nova Premier with an agentic workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Nova Premier with Amazon Bedrock can systematically migrate legacy C code to modern Java/Spring applications using an intelligent agentic workflow that breaks down complex conversions into specialized agent roles. The solution reduces migration time and costs while improving code quality through automated validation, security assessment, and iterative refinement processes that handle even large codebases exceeding token limitations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-code-migration-using-amazon-nova-premier-with-an-agentic-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Context to Copilot: Azure Cosmos DB Best Practices, Right in Your VS Code Workspace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers love GitHub Copilot for its instant, intelligent code suggestions. But what if those suggestions could also reflect your specific database and workload patterns? That’s now possible with a new feature in Azure Cosmos DB for VS Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/bringing-context-to-copilot-azure-cosmos-db-best-practices-right-in-your-vs-code-workspace 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The next chapter for UK sovereign AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI expands its UK partnership with a new Ministry of Justice agreement, bringing ChatGPT to civil servants. It also introduces UK data residency for ChatGPT Enterprise, ChatGPT Edu, and the API Platform to support trusted and secure AI adoption.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/the-next-chapter-for-uk-sovereign-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Planning in Visual Studio (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Quick prompts are great for small fixes, but they fall short on big projects. You end up rewriting instructions, tweaking them constantly, and hoping the model stays on track. It gives Copilot a visible, structured path to follow, one that updates as it works and keeps you in control at every step. In Agent Mode, Copilot can now create plan
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-planning-in-visual-studio-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authorization: Domain or Application Layer?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m diving into a super common question that’s really important: where should your authorization live? Should it live within your domain or your application layer? I am going to show some real world code examples and some simple guidelines so you can keep your software architecture consistent and avoid authorization code scattered everywhere. YouTube Check… Read More »Authorization: Domain or Application Layer? The post Authorization: Domain or Application Layer? appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Matter: The AI Development Companion for Product Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’ve spent 25 years building tools for developers. Over the past two years, we’ve seen that AI isn’t just changing how developers write code – it’s beginning to reshape the entire process of product development. Not only is AI making developers more productive, helping with everything from code completion to testing and deployment, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/matter/2025/10/introducing-matter-the-ai-development-companion-for-product-teams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI Agentic RAG search application with React, SQL Azure and Azure Static Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Leveraging OpenAI for semantic searches on structured databases like Azure SQL enhances search accuracy and context-awareness, providing more relevant and insightful results. This example showcases the use of Azure SQL for storing and searching data with AI. By implementing the RAG pattern with Azure SQL, the sample e
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-an-ai-agentic-rag-search-application-with-react-sql-azure-and-azure-static-web-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes &lt;CODE&gt;cheap_&lt;WBR&gt;steady_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt; faster than &lt;CODE&gt;std::&lt;WBR&gt;chrono::&lt;WBR&gt;high_&lt;WBR&gt;resolution_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I noted that There is a std::chrono::high_resolution_clock, but no low_resolution_clock.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251022-00/?p=111714 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metagenomi generates millions of novel enzymes cost-effectively using AWS Inferentia</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we detail how Metagenomi partnered with AWS to implement the Progen2 protein language model on AWS Inferentia, achieving up to 56% cost reduction for high-throughput enzyme generation workflows. The implementation enabled cost-effective generation of millions of novel enzyme variants using EC2 Inf2 Spot Instances and AWS Batch, demonstrating how cloud-based generative AI can make large-scale protein design more accessible for biotechnology applications .
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/metagenomi-generates-millions-of-novel-enzymes-cost-effectively-using-aws-inferentia/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Offload: Automating Everyday Workflows with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every developer eventually hits a wall with their local machine. Maybe it’s training an AI model that drains your CPU, compiling a massive codebase that makes your fan sound like a jet engine, or simply trying to run GPU workloads on a laptop that doesn’t have one. The result is the same: slow builds, limited...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/getting-started-docker-offload/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Python to Kotlin: A Transition Worth Making</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was written by an external contributor. When it comes to writing short scripts or CRUDs, Python is a great choice. With its rich ecosystem and broad adoption, it can be easily used to scrape some data or to perform data analysis. However, maintaining a large codebase in Python can be very problematic. Python’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/from-python-to-kotlin-a-transition-worth-making/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding metadata to fallback endpoints in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss fallback endpoints and show how adding metadata to MVC or Razor Page fallback endpoints has some quirks to be aware of
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/adding-metadata-to-fallback-endpoints-in-aspnetcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI in Japan—OpenAI’s Japan Economic Blueprint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s Japan Economic Blueprint outlines how Japan can harness AI to boost innovation, strengthen competitiveness, and enable sustainable, inclusive growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/japan-economic-blueprint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Model Choice in VS Code with Bring Your Own Key</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how the new Language Model Chat Provider API in VS Code is enabling more model choice and extensibility for chat experiences via the Bring Your Own Key experience. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/expanding-model-choice-in-vs-code-with-bring-your-own-key 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
