<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Reflect: My Mid-Year Retrospective – Dev Leader Weekly 50</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2024/29_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2024/29_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How To Reflect: My Mid-Year Retrospective – Dev Leader Weekly 50 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss my mid-year retrospective and how retrospectives can help YOU! The post How To Reflect: My Mid-Year Retrospective – Dev Leader Weekly 50 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/06/29/how-to-reflect-my-mid-year-retrospective-dev-leader-weekly-50/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible PDF Reporting in .NET Using Razor Views</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2024/29_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2024/29_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we&#39;ll explore the power of using Razor views for flexible PDF reporting in .NET. We&#39;ll see how to create report templates with Razor views, convert them to HTML, and then transform that HTML into beautifully formatted PDF documents.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/flexible-pdf-reporting-in-net-using-razor-views 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Graph PowerShell and CLI are now verified</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 16:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Graph PowerShell and CLI now have Microsoft set as the verified publisher.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-graph-powershell-and-cli-are-now-verified 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your Writing with Grazie, Now Included in the AI Pro Subscription</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This week, we announced the general availability of Grazie, our AI writing companion for people in tech. We’re also excited to share that Grazie is now part of the AI Pro subscription at no extra cost. Grazie streamlines your non-coding tasks by integrating generative AI into your JetBrains IDEs, browsers, and other tools. Grazie’s main […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/06/enhance-your-writing-with-grazie-now-included-in-the-ai-pro-subscription/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 mid-year link clearance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Emptying out the junk drawer.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240628-01/?p=109945 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a remove_all_pointers type trait, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Factoring out the type resolution to after the dangerous part.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240628-00/?p=109942 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – June Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stay updated with the latest news in the JetBrains Academy Newsletter. Discover the newest version of the JetBrains Academy plugin, celebrate our students’ international achievements, and learn how to become a JetBrains ambassador. All this and more await you in this month’s newsletter
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/06/28/jetbrains-academy-june-digest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReadMeAI: An AI-powered README Generator for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReadMeAI tool allows users to upload a code file and describe their project. The tool generates documentation in Markdown code for immediate preview and editing.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/readmeai-an-ai-powered-readme-generator-for-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code的更新 – 2024年6月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎阅读Visual Studio Code for Java的六月更新！在这篇博客中，我们将分享项目设置项目的重要更新以及一系列Spring的功能改进，让我们开始吧！ 项目设置页面功能增强 编译器配置 在项目设置页面添加了一个新的编译器配置标签页。这使您可以方便地设置项目的Java编译器相关选项。目前的选项包括源代码和目标兼容性、用于交叉编译的–release选项以及类文件生成的自定义。请参见下方截图中的编译器部分。 Maven相关选项 除了编译器部分，我们还添加了Maven标签页，使用户可以轻松指向的Maven配置文件。用户只需点击“Maven”并输入Maven配置文件的名称。 Formatter配置 最后，许多用户需要使用格式化器(Formatter)来格式化代码。我们在项目部分添加了使用格式化器的跳转方式。点击“Formatter”后，Visual Studio Code Java将引导用户进入格式化器视图。如果用户当前没有格式化器的文件，Visual Studio Code Java将引导用户直接创建一个格式化器。请参见下方的演示。 更方便地访问项目设置页面 自从我们引入更新后的项目设置页面以来，我们收到了用户的积极反馈。因此，我们使项目设置页面更加易于访问，现在您可以通过Java状态菜单直接从状态栏进入该页面。请参见下方截图。 要使用上述所有功能，用户可以使用上面提到的状态栏，或直接使用Command Palette并输入&amp;gt;Java: Open Project Settings。 测试覆盖率 测试覆盖率是我们在4月份推出的新功能，该功能可以使Java开发人员可以在Visual Studio Code中轻松查看代码的测试覆盖率。最近，我们推出了一个新的视频，讲述了如何在我们的插件中使用该功能。用户可以直接点击以下链接查看该视频： Build Server for Gradle在Google Summer Projects中的项目 我们很高兴地分享，Google Summer Projects现已宣布，您可以在Gradle Build Tool的简讯中找到详细信息。今年，Visual Studio Code Java团队正在指导两个Gradle Build Server相关的项目。 Gradle构建服务器 –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-visual-studio-code-2024-06 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code Update – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 09:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the June update for Visual Studio Code for Java! In this blog we are going to share several user experience updates, as well as important Spring features improvements, so let’s get started! Project Settings Page Enhancements New Compiler Section A new compiler section was added to the project settings page.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-visual-studio-code-update-june-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Plugins to Enhance Your IntelliJ IDEA Experience in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 07:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Even though IntelliJ IDEA is powerful and self-sufficient, we love to customize it a bit with plugins. Why? Because they’re fun! In this blog post, we’ll share a list of cool plugins that will help you liven things up in your IDE. Let’s go! JetBrains AI Assistant AI has touched every industry over the past […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/10-plugins-to-enhance-your-intellij-idea-experience-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings around developing with Microsoft Graph Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learnings of Microsoft Graph Toolkit from our recent project, including data leaking and privacy concerns that can help developers get a jumpstart with Microsoft Graph Toolkit.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/developing-with-microsoft-graph-toolkit-learnings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditionally Add Middleware in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore different techniques on how to conditionally add middleware in ASP.NET Core applications. Let’s start! Conditional Middleware: Why and When? Conditional middleware in ASP.NET Core is crucial for dynamically adapting our application behavior based on the runtime environment or specific request details. Let’s take a look at the key scenarios where […] The post Conditionally Add Middleware in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of productivity agents with NinjaTech AI and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NinjaTech AI’s mission is to make everyone more productive by taking care of time-consuming complex tasks with fast and affordable artificial intelligence (AI) agents. We recently launched MyNinja.ai, one of the world’s first multi-agent personal AI assistants, to drive towards our mission. MyNinja.ai is built from the ground up using specialized agents that are capable of completing tasks on your behalf, including scheduling meetings, conducting deep research from the web, generating code, and helping with writing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications on Amazon Bedrock — the secure, compliant, and responsible foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has revolutionized industries by creating content, from text and images to audio and code. Although it can unlock numerous possibilities, integrating generative AI into applications demands meticulous planning. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that provides access to large language models (LLMs) and other foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies through a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-on-amazon-bedrock-the-secure-compliant-and-responsible-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Documentation for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 17:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to announce the updated documentation on the Semantic Kernel learn site here: Introduction to Semantic Kernel | Microsoft Learn. We’ve updated the docs to include in depth samples, updated pages focused on concepts and much more for your learning!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/updated-documentation-for-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.03.3 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 17:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2024.03.3 bug fix for TeamCity On-Premises is now available for download! This release includes a few performance and security fixes. Among others, we addressed the following issues: For the full list of the issues fixed in this version, please refer to our release notes. As with other minor updates, TeamCity 2024.03.3 shares the same […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/06/teamcity-2024-03-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational chatbot using different LLMs within single interface – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the advent of generative artificial intelligence (AI), foundation models (FMs) can generate content such as answering questions, summarizing text, and providing highlights from the sourced document. However, for model selection, there is a wide choice from model providers, like Amazon, Anthropic, AI21 Labs, Cohere, and Meta, coupled with discrete real-world data formats in PDF, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-conversational-chatbot-using-different-llms-within-single-interface-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a remove_all_pointers type trait, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Delaying the expansion to avoid infinite recursion.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240627-00/?p=109940 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBRX: Databricks Open Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DBRX is Databricks’ newest Large Language Model (LLM) is open source and designed to bring advanced AI capabilities to businesses across multiple industries. This model stands out for its powerful architecture, efficiency, and user-friendly design, making sophisticated AI accessible and adaptable for diverse applications. By combining cutting-edge technology with practical usability, DBRX aims to transform […] The article DBRX: Databricks Open Large Language Model was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.19 with simulating LLM APIs and new Azure API Center integrations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to share the launch of Dev Proxy v0.19 to help you to build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-19-with-simulating-llm-apis-and-new-azure-api-center-integrations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (June 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.06.15 release, 2024-06-10 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout June. This month’s release includes some error message improvements and bug fixes. Some stats for this period: There are now 2,441 total ports available in the vcpkg public registry.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-june-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tentative Roadmap for Wolverine 3.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By the way, JasperFx Software offers support contracts or tailored consulting engagements to help your shop maximize your success with Wolverine. It’s an unfortunate fact of long running software tooling projects like Wolverine that decisions made years earlier won’t hold up perfectly as the usage requirements, underlying platform, and other tools it’s integrated with change … Continue reading Tentative Roadmap for Wolverine 3.0 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/06/26/tentative-roadmap-for-wolverine-3-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluid Framework 2 is now production ready</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 19:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Fluid Framework 2 is now generally available and ready for production applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/fluid-framework-2-is-now-production-ready 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving OpenJDK Scalar Replacement – Part 2/3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous part of this blog series, we explored the foundational concepts and purpose of scalar replacement (SR) in OpenJDK, laying the groundwork for understanding how this optimization can boost the performance of Java applications. Now, in the second installment of the series,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/improving-openjdk-scalar-replacement-part-2-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate derivative confirms processing using AWS AI services for the capital markets industry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can automate and intelligently process derivative confirms at scale using AWS AI services. The solution combines Amazon Textract, a fully managed ML service to effortlessly extract text, handwriting, and data from scanned documents, and AWS Serverless technologies, a suite of fully managed event-driven services for running code, managing data, and integrating applications, all without managing servers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-derivative-confirms-processing-using-aws-ai-services-for-the-capital-markets-industry/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered assistants for investment research with multi-modal data: An application of Agents for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a follow-up to Generative AI and multi-modal agents in AWS: The key to unlocking new value in financial markets. This blog is part of the series, Generative AI and AI/ML in Capital Markets and Financial Services. Financial analysts and research analysts in capital markets distill business insights from financial and non-financial data, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-powered-assistants-for-investment-research-with-multi-modal-data-an-application-of-agents-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us for .NET Aspire Developers Day – Elevate Your Cloud Native Skills!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on July 23, 2024, for .NET Aspire Developers Day, a livestream event to elevate your .NET skills with keynotes, deep dives, and interactive sessions. Connect with experts and the community.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/join-us-for-dotnet-aspire-developers-day 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a built-in way in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT to get the string name for a Windows Runtime enum?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            No, and maybe you don&#39;t want to.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240626-00/?p=109936 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Where Conditions Work in Entity Framework Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core is a popular data access library in the .NET space that makes it easier to write, execute, and process SQL statements and the resulting data. If you’re new to the .NET space, this blog post will help you understand how to create filtered result sets using the Where operator and how to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/26/how-where-conditions-work-in-entity-framework-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Docker USER Instruction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover best practices and common pitfalls associated with the Docker USER instruction. Also get a hands-on demo to learn the importance of these practices.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/understanding-the-docker-user-instruction/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Grazie – The AI Writing Companion for People in Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Grazie, a new AI writing companion for people working in tech, is now generally available. With Grazie, you can streamline your non-coding tasks by integrating generative AI into your JetBrains IDEs, browsers, and other tools. Grazie helps transform your thoughts into clear, well-articulated text through features like instant proofreading, inline text completion, summarization, translation, rephrasing, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2024/06/introducing-grazie-the-ai-writing-companion-for-people-in-tech/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #3: YAML Configuration Settings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With this TeamCity Pipelines release, we’re introducing the option to store and load pipeline definitions in YAML format from your repositories. The search panel for the YAML editor now looks better than ever. Bugs were squashed, improvements made, and our users are happier than ever. Read on to learn what’s new! Storing and loading configuration […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/06/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is The HashiCorp Infrastructure Cloud?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The cloud is the standard for hosting applications and workloads. However, only a small percentage of organizations realize the full benefits such as cost reduction, enhanced resilience, and new revenue streams. Often, this is due to the complex nature of cloud environments. The HashiCorp Infrastructure Cloud aims to address these challenges, providing a unified platform […] The article What is The HashiCorp Infrastructure Cloud? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Innovation: Explore Exclusive Technology Graphics and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am a technology and software engineering enthusiast with decades of experience creating custom images, videos, and music. My unique designs add a touch of innovation and creativity to projects, crafted with attention to detail for high-quality visuals. Explore and purchase my work at McCarter Photography - Technology to enhance your projects.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/26/unlocking-innovation-explore-exclusive-technology-graphics-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jakarta EE on Azure – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the June 2024 update for Jakarta EE on Azure. The June update covers the following topics: The newly published High Availability and Disaster Recovery tutorials, which demonstrate how to implement HA/DR for different Jakarta EE applications on Azure using a simple and effective method.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/jakarta-ee-on-azure-june-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI21 Labs Jamba-Instruct model is now available in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of the Jamba-Instruct large language model (LLM) in Amazon Bedrock. Jamba-Instruct is built by AI21 Labs, and most notably supports a 256,000-token context window, making it especially useful for processing large documents and complex Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) applications. What is Jamba-Instruct Jamba-Instruct is an instruction-tuned version of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai21-labs-jamba-instruct-model-is-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (June 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure SDKs release every month. This post includes the month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-june-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale and simplify ML workload monitoring on Amazon EKS with AWS Neuron Monitor container</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Web Services is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Neuron Monitor container, an innovative tool designed to enhance the monitoring capabilities of AWS Inferentia and AWS Trainium chips on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS). This solution simplifies the integration of advanced monitoring tools such as Prometheus and Grafana, enabling you to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-and-simplify-ml-workload-monitoring-on-amazon-eks-with-aws-neuron-monitor-container/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.1.4: What’s New!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.1.4 is here! View and navigate to URLs directly from the Editor tab, get context-based model suggestions for Hugging Face, and enjoy smart code assistance for TypedDict (PEP 692). You can download the latest version from our download page, or update your current version through our free Toolbox App. [banner] Key Features Gutter actions […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/06/pycharm-2024-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Assessment with .NET Upgrade Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the latest enhancements to the .NET Upgrade Assistant. .NET Upgrade Assistant helps upgrade solutions to newer versions of .NET. Whether you’re upgrading from .NET Framework to .NET 8 or just between .NET Core versions (from .NET 6 or 7 to .NET 8 or 9),
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/code-assessment-with-net-upgrade-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an automated insight extraction framework for customer feedback analysis with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon QuickSight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to integrate LLMs into enterprise applications to harness their generative capabilities. We delve into the technical aspects of workflow implementation and provide code samples that you can quickly deploy or modify to suit your specific requirements. Whether you’re a developer seeking to incorporate LLMs into your existing systems or a business owner looking to take advantage of the power of NLP, this post can serve as a quick jumpstart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build safe and responsible generative AI applications with guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) enable remarkably human-like conversations, allowing builders to create novel applications. LLMs find use in chatbots for customer service, virtual assistants, content generation, and much more. However, the implementation of LLMs without proper caution can lead to the dissemination of misinformation, manipulation of individuals, and the generation of undesirable outputs such as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-safe-and-responsible-generative-ai-applications-with-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve visibility into Amazon Bedrock usage and performance with Amazon CloudWatch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will share some of capabilities to help you get quick and easy visibility into Amazon Bedrock workloads in context of your broader application. We will use the contextual conversational assistant example in the Amazon Bedrock GitHub repository to provide examples of how you can customize these views to further enhance visibility, tailored to your use case. Specifically, we will describe how you can use the new automatic dashboard in Amazon CloudWatch to get a single pane of glass visibility into the usage and performance of Amazon Bedrock models and gain end-to-end visibility by customizing dashboards with widgets that provide visibility and insights into components and operations such as Retrieval Augmented Generation in your application.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: Fun fork</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A place to party.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240625-00/?p=109931 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 EAP 4: Inline Rendering of Doc Comments and Tasks View</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another week, another Rider 2024.2 Early Access Program build! This EAP build is packed with highly anticipated features such as the Tasks view and inline rendering of documentation comments. Let’s have a look! Inline rendering of documentation comments Instead of a wall of text mixed with tags, inline rendering changes these comments into a more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/25/rider-2024-2-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Measure DevSecOps Success: Key Metrics Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover two key metrics to measure your DevSecOps progression effectively. Learn how tracking security vulnerabilities over time and ensuring compliance with security policies can enhance your organization&#39;s security posture, driving continuous improvement in your DevSecOps practices.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-measure-devsecops-success-key-metrics-explained/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Building AI Agents with Phidata and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 10:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Phidata is a Python framework designed for creating AI assistants that leverage Large Language Models (LLMs), memory, knowledge, and tools. If you’ve ever wanted to create intelligent assistants capable of performing a range of tasks autonomously, you’re in the right place. This article walks through the process of setting up your environment for using Phidata, […] The article Introduction to Building AI Agents with Phidata and Python was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Datalore 2024.3: Quality Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following a feature-rich 2024.2 release, we’ve focused on enhancing the quality and reliability of Datalore in our 2024.3 update. Datalore Community, Professional, and Team customers have already received the new update automatically, and Datalore Enterprise customers can upgrade by following these instructions. Enhanced file handling for scheduled runs We’ve added an option that lets you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/06/25/what-s-new-in-datalore-2024-3-quality-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the generated code: T[], Span&lt;T&gt;, and Immutable collections: Behind the scenes of collection expressions - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at the code generated when you use collection expressions with T[], ReadOnlySpan, Span, and immutable collections
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/behind-the-scenes-of-collection-expressions-part-3-arrays-span-of-t-and-immutable-collections/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform Your .NET Projects: Master Aspect-Oriented Programming with Fody Weaving</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 08:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Imagine you&#39;re crafting the perfect symphony—different instruments contributing to a harmonious whole without drowning each other out. This is what Aspect-Oriented Programming (AOP) brings to your codebase. By isolating secondary concerns like logging, security, and exception handling, AOP ensures your core business logic remains pristine
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/master-aspect-oriented-programming-with-fody-weaving/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multitenancy in .NET With Orchard Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 06:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Orchard Core, a multipurpose open-source platform built upon ASP.NET Core, offers strong support for multi-tenancy. This article explores the installation and configuration of Orchard Core for multitenancy .NET applications, as well as the setup of multitenancy through its admin dashboard and framework. Additionally, we’ll look into the integration of features and modules to extend our […] The post Multitenancy in .NET With Orchard Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Acquires Rockset: A Strategic Move in AI and Data Processing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 01:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s recent acquisition of Rockset is a significant milestone in the AI and data management sectors. This acquisition is poised to bolster OpenAI’s capabilities in real-time analytics and data processing, critical areas for advancing AI technology. The acquisition of Rockset, a company renowned for its real-time analytics platform, aligns with OpenAI’s mission to enhance its […] The article OpenAI Acquires Rockset: A Strategic Move in AI and Data Processing was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: Path.Combine and Path.Join are similar but way different.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When composing the path to a folder or file location, the Path class can come in handy. Path.Join and Path.Combine may look similar, but their behavior differ in an unexpected way.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/path-combine-vs-path-join/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bug Fixes for ReSharper 2024.1.4 and Rider 2024.1.4 Are Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 20:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new bug fixes for the 2024.1 release are available to download. ReSharper ReSharper 2024.1.4 fixes a couple of notable issues: You can find the full list of fixed issues here. Rider In addition to fixed issues from ReSharper, Rider 2024.1.4 delivers several important fixes of its own: For the full list of fixed issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/24/resharper-rider-2024-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement exact match with Amazon Lex QnAIntent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 20:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a continuation of Creating Natural Conversations with Amazon Lex QnAIntent and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Base. In summary, we explored new capabilities available through Amazon Lex QnAIntent, powered by Amazon Bedrock, that enable you to harness natural language understanding and your own knowledge repositories to provide real-time, conversational experiences. In many cases, Amazon […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-exact-match-with-amazon-lex-qnaintent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Krikey AI harnessed the power of Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth to accelerate generative AI development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 17:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Jhanvi Shriram and Ketaki Shriram from Krikey. Krikey AI is revolutionizing the world of 3D animation with their innovative platform that allows anyone to generate high-quality 3D animations using just text or video inputs, without needing any prior animation experience. At the core of Krikey AI’s offering is their powerful […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-krikey-ai-harnessed-the-power-of-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-to-accelerate-generative-ai-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Learn .NET Aspire – Start your cloud-native journey live!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for Let&#39;s Learn .NET Aspire, a global live stream workshop where you can learn all about what .NET Aspire is, why you would use it, and see how to integrate .NET Aspire into your apps with a hands on workshop.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/lets-learn-dotnet-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to integrate Microsoft Entra External ID and Cerbos for authentication and authorization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post, the second in a three-part series, explores how to build a web application with decoupled authentication and authorization using Microsoft Entra External ID and Cerbos. The focus is on practical implementation, demonstrating how to integrate these tools to secure your web application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/integrating-external-id-and-cerbos 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve security posture in Azure service connections with AzurePipelinesCredential</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the new AzurePipelinesCredential, designed to support federated identity credential authentication through Azure Service Connections in Azure Pipelines.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/improve-security-posture-in-azure-service-connections-with-azurepipelinescredential 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding a specific value in a sequence of integers that changes by at most 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s basically a discrete version of the intermediate value theorem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240624-00/?p=109929 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All KotlinConf Recordings Are Now Available. Enjoy!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 11:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now find all of the session recordings from KotlinConf’24 on the conference website! Sessions are also being added to the Kotlin YouTube channel: Photos and slides from some of the sessions are also available – click on a talk and select “Download slides” for the latter. Don’t miss these additional materials from the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/06/kotlinconf24-recordings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code 的 .NET MAUI 扩展现已正式发布</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 06:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Maddy Montaquila的The .NET MAUI Extension for Visual Studio Code is now Generally Available 今天，我们非常高兴地宣布 .NET MAUI VS Code 扩展插件结束了预览阶段，并将包含一些期待已久的新功能 – 包括 XAML IntelliSense 和 Hot Reload！ 什么是 .NET MAUI 扩展插件？ .NET MAUI 扩展插件为您提供了在轻量级 Visual Studio Code 中开发 .NET MAUI 应用所需的工具。它基于C# Dev Kit 和 C# 扩展构建，提供了解决方案资源管理器、C# Hot Reload、强大的 C# IntelliSense 等众多功能。.NET MAUI 扩展增加了针对移动设备和桌面设备的能力，此外，借助最新版本的扩展，增加了 XAML IntelliSense 和 XAML Hot Reload，同时让您的 VS Code 体验更加精简和简单。 全新的和改进的 XAML 编辑体验 .NET MAUI 扩展的预览版附带了基本的 XAML 语法高亮显示和自动补全功能，但它与我们想要交付的完整体验相距甚远。在过去的一年里，我们对 Visual Studio 中现有的 XAML 语言服务进行了现代化改造，将其打包，并带到 VS Code中以供您进行 .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 05:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to talk about a structural design pattern, the Proxy Pattern. We will discuss what problem this pattern solves and how to implement it in C#. If you want to read more about design patterns in C#, you can inspect our C# Design Patterns page. Let’s start. What is The Proxy Design […] The post Proxy Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Building AI Agents with LangChain and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LangChain is a tool for more easily creating AI agents that can autonomously perform tasks. These agents can streamline operations, enhance user experiences, and handle complex processes with minimal human intervention. Building these AI agents can be difficult and this is the reason for why LangChain exists. LangChain is a cutting-edge framework designed to simplify […] The article Introduction to Building AI Agents with LangChain and Python was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String Performance: Improving String Formatting Performance by a Factor of 1.5 or More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article demonstrates how to accelerate string formatting by more than 1.5 times using project resources or static text formats.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/23/string-performance-improving-string-formatting-performance-by-a-factor-of-1-5-or-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
