<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:26:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the May edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This month, we have a special guest – Anton Arhipov. He joins us to share standout articles and other discoveries that recently caught his expert eye. Alongside his picks, you’ll find your regular dose of Java and tech news, AI updates, and industry events that are […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/java-annotated-monthly-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinventing Legacy App Modernization: Crowdbotics’ AI-Native Platform on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Author: Charath Ranganathan, CTO, Crowdbotics Modernizing legacy applications is one of the most daunting tasks facing enterprises today. These systems, often built decades ago using technologies like COBOL on mainframes, power critical business functions but are notoriously difficult, time-consuming, and expensive to update or replace. The process typically involves painstaking manual efforts to understand undocumented […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/reinventing-legacy-app-modernization-crowdbotics-ai-native-platform-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the new AI chat template</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I explore the new .NET AI Chat Web App template (currently in preview) and take a brief look at the implementation it provides
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-the-new-ai-chat-template/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? C# allows you to define custom operators for your own types by overloading built-in operators (like +, -, ==, etc.). This is not something most developers use often, and it can make your code behave like native types, which is a powerful but underutilized feature. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/06/dotinsights-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making WebStorm Faster: How We’re Improving Performance Behind the Scenes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At WebStorm, performance isn’t a side project – it’s a core part of what we do. Every millisecond counts when you’re deep in the flow, writing and navigating code. We’ve heard your feedback loud and clear: performance issues break that flow, and they’re frustrating. That’s why improving speed, responsiveness, and reliability is one of our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/05/improving-webstorm-performance-behind-the-scenes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common HttpClient tasks you&amp;#x27;re googling or asking ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:44:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using HttpClient has become my default choice when making HTTP requests from .NET. While there are many good alternatives out there (like Refit, Flurl, and RestSharp), having a built-in client that does most tasks in a pretty easy and straightforward way, makes this an obvious choice for many. While the
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/common-httpclient-tasks-youre-googling-or-asking-chatgpt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Power of Jitter: Enhancing Retry Patterns with a bit of randomness</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Operations may fail for transient reasons. How can you implement retry patterns? And how can a simple Jitter help you stabilize the system?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/retry-patterns-jitter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the updated Teams AI Library and MCP support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the new and improved Teams AI Library, designed to help developers create even more powerful agents for Microsoft Teams.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-the-updated-teams-ai-library-and-mcp-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Docker MCP Catalog and Toolkit: The Simple and Secure Way to Power AI Agents with MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 15:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Model Context Protocols (MCPs) are quickly becoming the standard for connecting AI agents to external tools, but the developer experience hasn’t caught up. Discovery is fragmented, setup is clunky, and security is too often bolted on last. Fixing this experience isn’t a solo mission—it will take an industry-wide effort. A secure, scalable, and trusted MCP...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-docker-mcp-catalog-and-toolkit-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What were the intended uses of those icons in moricons.dll?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Icons for old MS-DOS apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250505-00/?p=111143 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine Meets AWS SNS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 13:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine 3.13 added a new message transport for Amazon SNS with a big pull request from Luis Villalaz. To get started, add this Nuget to your system: Assuming that you have set up a shared AWS configuration or credential files, you can connect to SNS from Wolverine with this: To set up message publishing with … Continue reading Wolverine Meets AWS SNS →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/05/05/wolverine-meets-aws-sns/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Azure Front Door, Traffic Manager, and Load Balancer: Choosing the Right Tool for Global Application Delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern cloud architectures demand flexible, resilient, and scalable traffic distribution strategies. As workloads increasingly span multiple regions and hybrid environments, choosing the right load balancing service in Microsoft Azure becomes a strategic architectural decision. Among Azure’s suite of traffic distribution tools, Azure Front Door, Azure Traffic Manager, and Azure Load Balancer are commonly evaluated — […] The article Comparing Azure Front Door, Traffic Manager, and Load Balancer: Choosing the Right Tool for Global Application Delivery was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StringComparison.InvariantCulture is not always invariant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CultureInfo.InvariantCulture is not invariant for all operations. It is a special culture that is used for formatting and parsing operations that do not depend on any specific culture. For instance, this is well-suited to format values in order to persist them. However, it is not invariant for string comparisons. Comparing strings using InvariantCulture can lead to different results depending on the…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/stringcomparison-invariantculture-is-not-always-invariant.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving OpenAI’s Structure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An update from the OpenAI board on transitioning its for-profit entity to a Public Benefit Corporation, reinforcing its mission-driven structure under nonprofit oversight while enabling greater impact and long-term alignment with the public good.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/evolving-our-structure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2025.2 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 08:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.2, which we plan to introduce in July. After reviewing your feedback and our strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following areas for development: 🚀 CLion Nova language engine improvements and bug fixes 🎛️ New features for embedded development 🤖 Support for Junie, JetBrains’ smart coding agent Read […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/2025-2-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Unleash the Power of Git with IntelliJ IDEA Version Control Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 08:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Justin Clareburt and discover all of the powerful version control tools available in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: May 15, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Discover all of the powerful UI tooling in IntelliJ IDEA that you never knew was there. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/new-livestream-new-livestream-unleash-the-power-of-git-with-intellij-idea-cersion-control-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowe’s powers home improvement retail with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A conversation with Chandhu Nair, Senior Vice President of Data, AI, and Innovation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/lowes-chandhu-nair 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify Dictionary Handling with AutoDefaultDictionary in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2025/04_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2025/04_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing AutoDefaultDictionary The AutoDefaultDictionary&amp;lt;TKey, TValue&amp;gt; class simplifies handling missing keys in dictionaries by automatically returning a default value or using a custom function to generate values dynamically. This feature is particularly useful in applications where missing data should be handled gracefully instead of throwing exceptions. This type was inspired by an insightful article by Simon … Continue reading Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify Dictionary Handling with AutoDefaultDictionary in Spargine →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Management Is Being Gatekept?! - Dev Leader Weekly 93</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/03/engineering-management-is-being-gatekept-dev-leader-weekly-93 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-05-02</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 06:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/03/weekly-recap-20250502 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event-Driven Architecture in .NET with RabbitMQ</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement flexible and resilient event-driven systems in .NET using RabbitMQ as a message broker with practical code examples for producers and consumers.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/event-driven-architecture-in-dotnet-with-rabbitmq 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port .NET Framework workloads to Linux with Amazon Q Developer, Part 4: MVC projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 21:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This post continues our blog series on modernizing .NET Framework applications to cross-platform .NET using Amazon Q Developer .NET transformation. We’ve already covered porting class libraries in Part 1, test projects in Part 2, and Web API applications in Part 3. In this fourth installment, we’ll focus on migrating ASP.NET MVC applications to ASP.NET […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/port-net-framework-workloads-to-linux-with-amazon-q-developer-part-4-mvc-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (April 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 21:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.04.09 registry release, 2025-03-22, 2025-04-01, and 2025-04-07 tool releases, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout April. This release contains bug fixes, a new documentation article on offline usage of vcpkg, and other minor improvements. Arm64 Linux users of vcpkg […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-april-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Orchestrating AI Agents with Semantic Kernel Plugins: A Technical Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 21:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to welcome Jarre Nejatyab as a guest blog to highlight a technical deep dive on orchestrating AI Agents with Semantic Kernel Plugins. In the rapidly evolving world of Large Language Models (LLMs), orchestrating specialized AI agents has become crucial for building sophisticated cognitive architectures capable of complex reasoning and task execution. While […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-orchestrating-ai-agents-with-semantic-kernel-plugins-a-technical-deep-dive 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a gen AI–powered financial assistant with Amazon Bedrock multi-agent collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 17:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores a financial assistant system that specializes in three key tasks: portfolio creation, company research, and communication. This post aims to illustrate the use of multiple specialized agents within the Amazon Bedrock multi-agent collaboration capability, with particular emphasis on their application in financial analysis.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-gen-ai-powered-financial-assistant-with-amazon-bedrock-multi-agent-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – April Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 16:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month brings new opportunities to support your learning and development – from AI-powered features in your IDE and a new AI course with Nebius to practical Python training. Additionally, don’t miss the upcoming free online IntelliJ IDEA Conf. Read on for more details.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/05/02/jetbrains-academy-april/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordFinder app: Harnessing generative AI on AWS for aphasia communication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 16:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showcase how Dr. Kori Ramajoo, Dr. Sonia Brownsett, Prof. David Copland, from QARC, and Scott Harding, a person living with aphasia, used AWS services to develop WordFinder, a mobile, cloud-based solution that helps individuals with aphasia increase their independence through the use of AWS generative AI technology.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/wordfinder-app-harnessing-generative-ai-on-aws-for-aphasia-communication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get faster and actionable AWS Trusted Advisor insights to make data-driven decisions using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 16:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to create an application using Amazon Q Business with Jira integration that used a dataset containing a Trusted Advisor detailed report. This solution demonstrates how to use new generative AI services like Amazon Q Business to get data insights faster and make them actionable.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-faster-and-actionable-aws-trusted-advisor-insights-to-make-data-driven-decisions-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Stuck to Senior: How Mentorship Accelerates Your Cloud, DevOps &amp; AI Career</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The journey from junior engineer to senior Cloud, DevOps or even AI professional can feel like climbing an ever-growing mountain. New tools. Shifting best practices. Complicated architectures. Add to that the pressure of staying relevant in a sea of LinkedIn updates and GitHub commits, and it’s easy to get stuck—stuck doing the same tasks, stuck […] The article From Stuck to Senior: How Mentorship Accelerates Your Cloud, DevOps &amp;amp; AI Career was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using type aliasing to avoid the ODR problem with conditional compilation, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ensuring that you pick a side.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250502-00/?p=111140 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana 2025.1 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 12:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we continue improving Qodana, we’re excited to introduce a set of powerful updates that enhance performance, improve security analysis, and offer better integration opportunities for you and your team. Let’s take a look at some of the most exciting changes with the Qodana 2025.1 release! Try Qodana OWASP Top 10: covering even more categories […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/qodana-2025-1-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Tim Berners-Lee – Inventor of the World Wide Web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tim Berners-Lee, a name etched into the bedrock of computing history, stands among the most influential figures to ever touch the digital sphere. Credited with inventing the World Wide Web in 1989, his groundbreaking work at CERN sparked a technological revolution that reshaped communication, commerce, and culture. Over three decades later, Berners-Lee’s visionary spirit persists, […] The article Big Thinkers: Tim Berners-Lee – Inventor of the World Wide Web was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure DevOps ID Token Refresh and Terraform Task Version 5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 08:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to share some recent updates that improve the experience of using Workload identity federation (OpenID Connect) with Azure DevOps and Terraform on Microsoft Azure. Many working parts have come together to make this possible and we’ll share those here. We are also very pleased to announce version 5 of the Microsoft DevLabs […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/introducing-azure-devops-id-token-refresh-and-terraform-task-version-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running RAG with ONNX Runtime GenAI for On-Prem Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Exploring how to efficiently run a RAG pipeline with structured language models (SLMs) and guardrails on Windows, achieving inference under 5 seconds with ONNX Runtime GenAI.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/running-rag-onnxruntime-genai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for Meta Llama 3.2 multimodal fine-tuning on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share comprehensive best practices and scientific insights for fine-tuning Meta Llama 3.2 multimodal models on Amazon Bedrock. By following these guidelines, you can fine-tune smaller, more cost-effective models to achieve performance that rivals or even surpasses much larger models—potentially reducing both inference costs and latency, while maintaining high accuracy for your specific use case.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-for-meta-llama-3-2-multimodal-fine-tuning-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing Project Files with AI: A Success Story from the .NET Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 18:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft, we are constantly exploring innovative ways to enhance our workflows, improve productivity, and ensure we have a secure supply chain that uses modern tools. One of our recent initiatives was to rebuild the .NET Framework build system by leveraging AI to automate the process. Here’s the story of how we successfully achieved this […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/modernizing-project-files-with-ai-a-success-story-from-the-dotnet-team 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extend large language models powered by Amazon SageMaker AI using Model Context Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 17:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MCP proposed by Anthropic offers a standardized way of connecting FMs to data sources, and now you can use this capability with SageMaker AI. In this post, we presented an example of combining the power of SageMaker AI and MCP to build an application that offers a new perspective on loan underwriting through specialized roles and automated workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/extend-large-language-models-powered-by-amazon-sagemaker-ai-using-model-context-protocol/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine.Http learns some new tricks!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 17:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the Wolverine 3.13 release yesterday, the Wolverine.HTTP library got some new, long requested, probably overdue capabilities for working with HTTP Form posts and support for ASP.Net Core Minimal API’s [AsParameters] feature. First, let’s look at Wolverine’s new support for working with HTTP Form posts using the ASP.Net Core [FromForm] attribute as a marker. First, … Continue reading Wolverine.Http learns some new tricks! →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/05/01/wolverine-http-learns-some-new-tricks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure AI Foundry extension for Visual Studio Code April 2025 Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 17:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure AI Foundry extension for Visual Studio Code April 2025 Update Azure AI Foundry is a trusted platform for designing, customizing, and managing AI applications, with a portal that enables secure data integration, model customization, and enterprise-grade governance. Earlier this month, we announced the public preview of the Azure AI Foundry extension. And today, the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/azure-ai-foundry-extension-for-visual-studio-code-april-2025-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate document translation and standardization with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Translate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 16:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can automate language localization through translating documents using Amazon Web Services (AWS). The solution combines Amazon Bedrock and AWS Serverless technologies, a suite of fully managed event-driven services for running code, managing data, and integrating applications—all without managing servers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-document-translation-and-standardization-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-translate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous mortgage processing using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 16:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce agentic automatic mortgage approval, a next-generation sample solution that uses autonomous AI agents powered by Amazon Bedrock Agents and Amazon Bedrock Data Automation. These agents orchestrate the entire mortgage approval process—intelligently verifying documents, assessing risk, and making data-driven decisions with minimal human intervention.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/autonomous-mortgage-processing-using-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There’s a Linux File Explorer built into Visual Studio!?!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Remote File Explorer in Visual Studio provides developers with a convenient way to browse, view, and edit files on remote machines—directly from within the IDE. It’s a powerful tool for managing remote environments without leaving your development workflow. Scott Hanselman published a new YouTube video to his channel, taking us on the journey of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/theres-a-linux-file-explorer-built-into-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly prototype with gpt-image-1 from Azure OpenAI Service in the Images Playground in Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 14:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the next-gen images playground in Azure AI Foundry, a high-fidelity UX sandbox for developers to rapidly prototype with state-of-the-art image generation models like gpt-image-1 from Azure OpenAI Service 1. This playground enables real-time experimentation, prompt optimization, and integration with developer tools like VS Code, accelerating the &amp;quot;Build-Measure-Learn&amp;quot; development loop and enhancing productivity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/images-playground-may-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTOs &amp; Mapping : The Good, The Bad, And The Excessive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 14:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Something that’s often overused, misunderstood, or just incorrectly applied in software development: Data Transfer Objects (DTOs). DTOs are a common pattern, but like many things in software, they tend to get used in places where they don’t actually solve the problem at hand. So, what are DTOs really for? When should you use them? And… Read More »DTOs &amp;amp; Mapping : The Good, The Bad, And The Excessive The post DTOs &amp;amp; Mapping : The Good, The Bad, And The Excessive appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Database Management With WebStorm’s Database Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Here’s something that might surprise you: if you’re using WebStorm, you already have access to a professional-grade database IDE. That’s right, the full-featured DataGrip database toolset isn’t just a separate product or an additional paid plugin anymore; it’s bundled into WebStorm. Even if you’re comfortable with other IDEs and their database extensions, you might find […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/05/streamline-database-management-with-webstorm-s-database-tool/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using C&#43;&#43; type aliasing to avoid the ODR problem with conditional compilation, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Still one definition, but two types.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250501-00/?p=111134 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Faster with dotNetTips.com Spargine 8: May 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine 8 (v2025.8.5.1) has been released on May 1, 2025, enhancing .NET 8 &amp;amp; 9 support with new classes, methods, and significant performance improvements. This final major update focuses on performance, usability, and reliability, encouraging community involvement for future enhancements and contributions as the project transitions to .NET 10.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/05/01/coding-faster-with-dotnettips-com-spargine-8-may-2025-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: jQuery – The Tiny Library that Transformed the Web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 11:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “Write less, do more.” That motto wasn’t just a clever tagline—it was a revolution. Before modern JavaScript frameworks became the norm, jQuery quietly changed everything. In the web development landscape now dominated by React, Angular, and Vue, it might be easy to forget a time when making a button click actually do something required verbose, […] The article Software Innovation: jQuery – The Tiny Library that Transformed the Web was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.27 with generating TypeSpec files and configuring using natural language</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 06:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dev Proxy v0.27 is even more developer-friendly, helping you generate API specs faster, improving suggestions while editing, and laying the foundation for more flexible AI integrations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-27-with-generating-typespec-files-and-configuring-using-natural-language 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock Your Code: Object-Oriented Design Principles for Microsoft .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, I am excited to announce the release of my new e-book, Rock Your Code: Object-Oriented Design Principles for Microsoft .NET. This book builds upon a chapter from my previous coding standards work, delving into a crucial topic I often encounter in the code I analyze— the lack of solid object-oriented programming practices when designing … Continue reading Rock Your Code: Object-Oriented Design Principles for Microsoft .NET →
Link to article: https://dotnettips.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Untapped Power of Veteran Engineers: Why Companies Are Overlooking Their Most Valuable Assets – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Veteran Software Engineers, with over 25 years of experience, are invaluable assets to any team, offering deep technical expertise and strategic insight that enhance organizational success. They excel in future-proofing software, managing technical debt, and mentoring less experienced engineers, leading to faster ROI and improved project outcomes while fostering a collaborative work environment.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/05/01/the-untapped-power-of-veteran-engineers-why-companies-are-overlooking-their-most-valuable-assets-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huge Wolverine 3.13 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 01:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine is part of the larger “Critter Stack” suite that provides a robust and productive approach to Event Driven Architecture approaches in the .NET ecosystem. Through its various elements provides an asynchronous messaging framework, an alternative HTTP endpoint framework, and yes, it can be used as just a “mediator” tool (but I’d recommend using Wolverine’s … Continue reading Huge Wolverine 3.13 Release →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/04/30/huge-wolverine-3-13-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Model Distillation: Boost function calling accuracy while reducing cost and latency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 01:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we highlight the advanced data augmentation techniques and performance improvements in Amazon Bedrock Model Distillation with Meta&#39;s Llama model family. This technique transfers knowledge from larger, more capable foundation models (FMs) that act as teachers to smaller, more efficient models (students), creating specialized models that excel at specific tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-model-distillation-boost-function-calling-accuracy-while-reducing-cost-and-latency/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on the Docker DX extension for VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 20:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the latest changes to the Docker DX extension for VS Code, new features for authoring, and what&#39;s coming next to enhance your container workflows.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-dx-extension-for-vs-code-update/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build public-facing generative AI applications using Amazon Q Business for anonymous users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 19:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce that Amazon Q Business now supports anonymous user access. With this new feature, you can now create Amazon Q Business applications with anonymous user mode, where user authentication is not required and content is publicly accessible. In this post, we demonstrate how to build a public-facing generative AI application using Amazon Q Business for anonymous users.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-public-facing-generative-ai-applications-using-amazon-q-business-for-anonymous-users/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FloQast builds an AI-powered accounting transformation solution with Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 18:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how FloQast built an AI-powered accounting transaction solution using Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/floqast-builds-an-ai-powered-accounting-transformation-solution-with-anthropics-claude-3-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights in implementing production-ready solutions with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 18:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative AI revolutionizes industries, organizations are eager to harness its potential. However, the journey from production-ready solutions to full-scale implementation can present distinct operational and technical considerations. This post explores key insights and lessons learned from AWS customers in Europe, Middle East, and Africa (EMEA) who have successfully navigated this transition, providing a roadmap for others looking to follow suit.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/insights-in-implementing-production-ready-solutions-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: Introducing Schema Compare (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview We are excited to introduce Schema Compare in the MSSQL Extension for VS Code! It can be tedious to manually manage and synchronize different database versions. Enter Schema Compare, the powerful new feature for MSSQL in VS Code that transforms this tedious task into a seamless experience. With intuitive visualization that instantly highlights additions, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-schema-compare 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging and Publishing a .NET MAUI Library with GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, learn how to setup a DevOps pipeline to build and publish a .NET MAUI library with GitHub Actions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-maui-libraries-github-actions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Cost Management updates—April 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re always looking for ways to learn more about your challenges and how Microsoft Cost Management can help you better understand where you&#39;re accruing costs in the cloud, identify and prevent bad spending patterns, and optimize costs to empower you to do more with less. The post Microsoft Cost Management updates—April 2025 appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/microsoft-cost-management-updates-april-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Windows have trouble finding my Win32 resource if it contains an accented character?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disagreements over the fine print.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250430-00/?p=111129 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structuring Ktor Projects Using Domain-Driven Design (DDD) Concepts: A Step-by-Step Guide With a Minimalistic CRM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 12:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this guide, we’ll show you how to structure a project using domain-driven design (DDD) concepts, step by step, by building a minimalistic CRM system. Sample code for the article: https://github.com/antonarhipov/ktor-ddd-example Ktor is a highly flexible framework that allows developers to structure their applications however they see fit. Unlike some opinionated frameworks (like Spring Boot), […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/domain-driven-design-guide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock Your Code (and Your Ego): The David McCarter Roast Solo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 11:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            David McCarter is a multifaceted talent, excelling in coding, guitar playing, and photography. Known for his impressive open-source library, Spargine, he combines technical prowess with musical skill. With a knack for teaching through engaging methods, David stands out in both tech and music, transforming coding practices with passion and creativity.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/30/rock-your-code-and-your-ego-the-david-mccarter-roast-solo/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mellum Goes Open Source: A Purpose-Built LLM for Developers, Now on Hugging Face</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 11:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mellum doesn’t try to know everything. It’s designed to do one thing really well: code completion. We call it a focal model – built with purposeful depth and not concerned with chasing breadth. But code completion is just the start. Mellum will grow into a family of focal models, each specialized for different coding tasks […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/04/mellum-goes-open-source-a-purpose-built-llm-for-developers-now-on-hugging-face/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot for Xcode: Explore @workspace and New Models Support (GPT-4.1, GPT-4.5 and More)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 08:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The GitHub Copilot for Xcode extension now allows you to ask questions about your entire codebase using the @workspace context. Additionally, we have integrated support for new models, including OpenAI GPT-4.1, GPT-4.5, o3, o4-mini, Gemini 2.5 Pro and Claude 3.7 Sonnet, to enhance your chat conversations and introduce several UX improvements to boost your productivity. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/github-copilot-for-xcode-explore-workspace-and-new-models-support-gpt-4-1-gpt-4-5-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Efficient Temporary File Management with Spargine’s TempFileManager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8 and 9, developed for efficient temporary file management through the TempFileManager. This utility simplifies file handling, ensuring automatic cleanup via IDisposable. It offers essential methods for creating and deleting files, enhancing resource management in projects. Feedback is encouraged.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/30/boost-your-net-projects-efficient-temporary-file-management-with-spargines-tempfilemanager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.41: Docker Model Runner supports Windows, Compose, and Testcontainers integrations, Docker Desktop on the Microsoft Store</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 20:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.41 brings new tools for AI devs and teams managing environments at scale — build faster and collaborate smarter.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-41/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate Your Virtual Machine Management with Multi-Select, Sorting, Grouping, and Tags in Azure DevTest Labs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 19:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to unveil exciting new enhancements in the My Virtual Machine view within Azure DevTest Labs that will revolutionize your VM management experience. With these updates, managing your virtual machines has never been easier or more efficient. Imagine being able to multi-select VMs to start, stop, restart, or delete them all at once […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/elevate-your-virtual-machine-management-with-multi-select-sorting-grouping-and-tags-in-azure-devtest-labs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jens Oliver Meiert: How WebStorm and AI Assistant Fit Right Into My Workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 17:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For more than two decades, Jens Oliver Meiert has been at the forefront of web development, working with industry giants like Google and Miro, as well as leading engineering teams across various companies. With extensive experience in frontend development, he has witnessed firsthand how tools and workflows have evolved over time. In this interview, Jens […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/04/jens-oliver-meiert-how-webstorm-and-ai-assistant-fit-right-into-my-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI in action: How Data Reply red teaming supports generative AI safety on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 16:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how AWS services can be seamlessly integrated with open source tools to help establish a robust red teaming mechanism within your organization. Specifically, we discuss Data Reply’s red teaming solution, a comprehensive blueprint to enhance AI safety and responsible AI practices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-in-action-how-data-reply-red-teaming-supports-generative-ai-safety-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InterVision accelerates AI development using AWS LLM League and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 16:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how AWS LLM League’s gamified enablement accelerates partners’ practical AI development capabilities, while showcasing how fine-tuning smaller language models can deliver cost-effective, specialized solutions for specific industry needs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/intervision-accelerates-ai-development-using-aws-llm-league-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Amazon Nova migration performance with data-aware prompt optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 16:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present an LLM migration paradigm and architecture, including a continuous process of model evaluation, prompt generation using Amazon Bedrock, and data-aware optimization. The solution evaluates the model performance before migration and iteratively optimizes the Amazon Nova model prompts using user-provided dataset and objective metrics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-amazon-nova-migration-performance-with-data-aware-prompt-optimization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Windows users from Janet Jackson’s Rhythm Nation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 16:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Granting an exception to a system policy.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250429-42/?p=111127 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in Azure AI Foundry | April 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post highlights the latest features and updates in Azure AI Foundry for April 2025, focusing on new models, agents, and tools that enhance AI development capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/whats-new-in-azure-ai-foundry-april-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2025 is Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 09:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++ is our free, one-day, virtual conference for the whole C++ community. It’s running live tomorrow, 30th April, from 14:00 to 16:30 UTC. The talks are: 14:00 UTC: Welcome to v1.0 of the meta::[[verse]]! with Inbal Levi 14:30 UTC: Proxy: Next Generation Polymorphism with Mingxin Wang 15:00 UTC: Making unfamiliar C++ code familiar with […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-cpp-2025-is-tomorrow 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a &#39;pooled&#39; dependency injection lifetime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I investigate how to create a &#39;pooled&#39; dependency injection scope that automatically pools services between multiple requests
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-pooled-dependency-injection-lifetime/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Set of Bug Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.1 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 06:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, The ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.1 bug-fix updates have just been released! If you haven’t upgraded to the 2025.1 versions of our products, we highly recommend that you check out these two blog posts: And now, let’s go over the most important fixes in 2025.1.1. ReSharper 2025.1.1 The first bug-fix update fixes the issue […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/29/2025-1-1-hot-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 real-life examples of using reflection in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 07:41:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As C# developers, we sometimes must interact dynamically with objects, fields, properties, methods, or types. Use cases such as inter-mapping between types, traversing model properties, developing an extensible system, injecting dependencies, etc., demand runtime handling. You may wonder how to tackle such scenarios. In this post, I will show you
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/4-real-life-examples-of-using-reflection-in-c/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
