<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:22:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Monitor Your App&amp;#x27;s Performance with .NET Benchmarking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:22:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Benchmarking is essential in application development, especially if you aim to scale up your app. Benchmarking enables you to evaluate your application&#39;s resource consumption, which helps you identify potential updates to speed up performance. If not scaling, you will need the application performance to be optimal to enhance
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/how-to-monitor-your-apps-performance-with-net-benchmarking/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marten Event Sourcing Gets Some New Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 22:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software has gotten the chance this work to build out several strategic improvements to both Marten and Wolverine through collaborations with our clients who have had some specific needs. This has been highly advantageous because it’s helped push some significant, long planned technical improvements while getting all important feedback as clients integrate the new … Continue reading Marten Event Sourcing Gets Some New Tools →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/09/marten-event-sourcing-gets-some-new-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Local AI models with .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s look at how to build and run local AI models with .NET Aspire.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/local-ai-models-with-dotnet-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating ML experimentation with enhanced security: AWS PrivateLink support for Amazon SageMaker with MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With access to a wide range of generative AI foundation models (FM) and the ability to build and train their own machine learning (ML) models in Amazon SageMaker, users want a seamless and secure way to experiment with and select the models that deliver the most value for their business. In the initial stages of an ML […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-ml-experimentation-with-enhanced-security-aws-privatelink-support-for-amazon-sagemaker-with-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Python in VS Code Wrapped</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year comes to a close, we would like to take the time to reflect and celebrate the incredible progress the Python extension for VS Code has made in the past year. From merging in top requested features to countless lines of code written and deleted, keep reading to get an inside look to all things
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/2024-python-vscode-wrapped 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a Unified Data Model is Critical: Lessons from Building Microsoft’s Semantic Layer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Some years ago, we were wrestling with a persistent issue in our data stack. Every team had their own way of collecting and structuring data. What was a simple query for one team became a debugging nightmare for another. Discovering the right dataset felt like looking for a needle in a haystack, and standardizing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/udm/unified-data-models-101 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Global System Integrators can make the most of their GitHub Copilot licenses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered code assistant tools like GitHub Copilot have revolutionized the development landscape. We’ve observed significant Copilot adoption among Global System Integrators (GSIs), who are leading the charge in harnessing its potential. While many developers are already utilizing GitHub Copilot in their internal projects, GSI’s are eager to integrate Copilot into their own application development lifecycles. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/dont-let-your-github-copilot-licenses-collect-dust-how-gsis-can-make-their-every-license-count 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep working with non-blocking Code Cleanup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of waiting for Code Cleanup to finish every time you save your work? Visual Studio 2022 will no longer lock up and get in the way of your tasks as it’s cleaning up the code under the covers. Every developer knows the importance of maintaining clean code. However, the traditional Code Cleanup […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/keep-working-with-non-blocking-code-cleanup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to read C&#43;&#43; compiler errors: Failing to create a shared_ptr</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding what you asked the compiler to do, and why it couldn&#39;t comply.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241209-00/?p=110619 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New! Security Analysis Plugin for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Application security is a critical requirement in modern software development. The latest release of IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 – along with the optional new Security Analysis by Qodana plugin – elevates your security efforts with advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for code written in Java and Kotlin. Trained on popular OWASP security benchmark projects, this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/security-analysis-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 – 2024.3.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. v2024.3.1 introduces advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for Java and Kotlin. This allows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/intellij-idea-2024-3-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the binary log to find the source of a .NET dependency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding where a dependency comes from can be tedious. This is especially true when you have a large project with many dependencies. Recently, .NET brings a new tool dotnet nuget why to help you understand why a package is installed in your project. However, there is a better way to do it, and it doesn&#39;t requires a recent SDK. dotnet nuget why can explain why a package is included in your project:…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 06:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about the Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern. We are going to see how to implement this pattern in C# and how it can solve certain design problems. Let’s start. What is The Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern? Chain of Responsibility is a behavioral pattern that helps us design a […] The post Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Entra External ID with an Auth0 OpenID Connect identity provider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at implementing an Open ID Connect identity provider in Microsoft Entra External ID. Auth0 is used as the identity provider and an ASP.NET Core application is used to test the authentication. Microsoft Entra External ID federates to Auth0. Client code: https://github.com/damienbod/EntraExternalIdCiam Microsoft Entra External ID supports federation using OpenID Connect and was […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/12/09/using-entra-external-id-with-an-auth0-openid-connect-identity-provider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Resilient Systems with Wolverine’s Transactional Outbox</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 03:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software is completely open for business to help you get the best possible results with the “Critter Stack” tools or really any type of server side .NET development efforts. A lot of what I’m writing about is inspired by work we’ve done with our ongoing clients. I think I’m at the point where I … Continue reading Build Resilient Systems with Wolverine’s Transactional Outbox →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/08/build-resilient-systems-with-wolverines-transactional-outbox/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Type Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2024/08_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2024/08_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source project for .NET 8, featuring assemblies and NuGet packages crucial for .NET applications. It includes the TypeExtensions class, offering performance-optimized methods that simplify type handling.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/12/08/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-type-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Package Management in .NET - Simplify NuGet Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_12_2024/07_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_12_2024/07_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing NuGet packages across multiple .NET projects used to be a nightmare of version mismatches and maintenance headaches, but Central Package Management (CPM) offers a powerful solution by letting you control all package versions from a single source of truth. Learn how CPM can simplify your dependency management, prevent version conflicts, and make your .NET development workflow smoother.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/central-package-management-in-net-simplify-nuget-dependencies 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: How to use Elasticsearch Vector Store Connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel for AI Agent development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to use Elasticsearch Vector Store Connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel for AI Agent development Today we’re excited to feature the Elastic team to share more about their Semantic Kernel Elasticsearch Vector Store connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel. Read the entire announcement here. I’ll turn it over to Srikanth Manvi and Florian Bernd to dive […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-how-to-use-elasticsearch-vector-store-connector-for-microsoft-semantic-kernel-for-ai-agent-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistral-NeMo-Instruct-2407 and Mistral-NeMo-Base-2407 are now available on SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Mistral-NeMo-Base-2407 and Mistral-NeMo-Instruct-2407 large language models from Mistral AI that excel at text generation, are available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. In this post, we walk through how to discover, deploy and use the Mistral-NeMo-Instruct-2407 and Mistral-NeMo-Base-2407 models for a variety of real-world use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mistral-nemo-instruct-2407-and-mistral-nemo-base-2407-are-now-available-on-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deletion of Outdated Azul Zulu for Azure Container Images for Better Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We at Microsoft are committed to providing customers with a secure ecosystem of tools for building and deploying applications. As part of this commitment, we continuously update our Java container image offerings to ensure they meet the highest security standards. Back in January 2022, we announced the End of Updates for the Azul Zulu for Azure build of OpenJDK. As […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/deletion-of-outdated-azul-zulu-for-azure-container-images-for-better-security 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSVC Compiler Language Updates in Visual Studio 2022 version 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 17:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In alignment with the Visual Studio 2022 version 17.12 release, and based upon feedback received from the community, the MSVC compiler team would like to provide greater visibility into the C++ language-level fixes for customer-reported issues that made it into the release. This is similar to how the standard library team publishes regular changelogs […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/msvc-compiler-language-updates-in-visual-studio-2022-version-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your Microsoft 365 app performance: Introducing tree shaking in TeamsJS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Microsoft Teams JavaScript client library (TeamsJS) version 2.31.0, we’re excited to make the TeamsJS library fully tree-shakable.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/boost-your-microsoft-365-app-performance-introducing-tree-shaking-in-teamsjs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to read C&#43;&#43; compiler errors: Nonsensical errors from a function declaration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Look closely at what the error message is complaining about.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241206-00/?p=110614 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream alert: Ace the CSAI Math Entrance Test</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want to study computer science in Europe? Join the Computer Science and AI bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos – with exclusive JetBrains scholarships up for grabs! On December 18, 2024, at 5:00 pm UTC, we’re hosting a special preparation session to help you ace the entrance test for this BSc. You’ll get tips from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/06/livestream-alert-ace-the-csai-math-entrance-test/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Ruby Debugging: From puts to Professional Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Debugging is an essential skill in software development, and in this post, we’ll be looking at how to investigate the behavior of Ruby code. As the RubyMine team, we’ve accumulated considerable expertise in creating tools for Ruby developers, and we’re excited to share our experience and knowledge with you. Recently, at the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/12/mastering_ruby_debugging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Evaluation platform on Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Machine Learning is known for training and deploying models, but can also be used for running experiments. This blog post will show us how we have implemented our Evaluation platform on Azure Machine Learning.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/implement-evaluation-platform-on-aml 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing AI trust with new responsible AI tools, capabilities, and resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 23:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With trust as a cornerstone of AI adoption, we are excited to announce at AWS re:Invent 2024 new responsible AI tools, capabilities, and resources that enhance the safety, security, and transparency of our AI services and models and help support customers’ own responsible AI journeys.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advancing-ai-trust-with-new-responsible-ai-tools-capabilities-and-resources/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy RAG applications on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart using FAISS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 21:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build a RAG application on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart using Facebook AI Similarity Search (FAISS).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-rag-applications-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-using-faiss/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up your cluster procurement time with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training plans, to bring down your training cluster procurement wait time. We guide you through a step-by-step implementation on how you can use the (AWS CLI) or the AWS Management Console to find, review, and create optimal training plans for your specific compute and timeline needs. We further guide you through using the training plan to submit SageMaker training jobs or create SageMaker HyperPod clusters.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code, Learn, Repeat: Get Ready for KotlinConf 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            KotlinConf has always been about more than just code – it’s where ideas spark, skills develop, and the Kotlin community comes together to share knowledge, connect, and celebrate. While we’re still crafting the 2025 program (stay tuned for the big reveal in February), here are the recordings of last year’s top talks to give you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/code-learn-repeat-get-ready-for-kotlinconf-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – November Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year draws to a close, the JetBrains Academy team has some exciting updates for you! In this newsletter, you’ll discover new courses, plugins to enhance your learning, tech career tips, and updates for computer science educators.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/05/jetbrains-academy-november-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3.20 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just published a maintenance update to IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3. This minor release includes several bug fixes and improvements to existing features introduced in the main release. Lambda breakpoints in the debugger We’ve made improvements to how lambda expressions are handled in the debugger. Previously, setting a breakpoint on a line with a lambda […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/12/05/intellij-scala-plugin-2024-3-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Code Referencing for GitHub Copilot Chat in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of the uncertainty that comes with using code suggestions from AI tools? We’ve got exciting news for you! Visual Studio 2022 now includes code referencing in GitHub Copilot, ensuring greater transparency and control for developers. We are thrilled to announce that code referencing is now available in GitHub Copilot Chat within Visual […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-code-referencing-for-github-copilot-chat-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dependabot to Manage .NET SDK Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use Dependabot to keep your .NET SDK version up to date with the latest security patches and improvements.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-dependabot-to-manage-dotnet-sdk-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – December 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As 2024 wraps up, this December edition of Java Annotated Monthly brings you the latest on JEPs targeted for Java 24, helpful tutorials on Java, Kotlin, and AI, and more. This time, we’ve included thought-provoking non-tech articles perfect for year-end reflection. Plus, we’re thrilled to welcome Josh Long as our featured author, who will be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/java-annotated-monthly-december-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding a Legacy Codebase. Keep it Evergreen</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Nobody wants their codebase to turn into a brownfield mess legacy codebase having to use outdated technology. Here are 3 tips for keeping your codebase evergreen. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in this post. Understanding Stability and Advancements How do you… Read More »Avoiding a Legacy Codebase. Keep it Evergreen The post Avoiding a Legacy Codebase.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Azure Cosmos DB Integration with Spring AI and Langchain4J!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re continuing to simplify AI app development by integrating Azure Cosmos DB’s cost-effective and scalable vector search directly with Spring AI and LangChain4J! These frameworks empower Java developers to efficiently manage fast and accurate data retrieval with Azure Cosmos DB’s scalability and efficient vector indexing and search capabilities, allowing for efficient handling of high-dimensional vectors. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-azure-cosmos-db-integration-with-spring-ai-and-langchain4j 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Won’t waiting for multiple threads one at a time introduce a severe performance issue?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It depends on how long you plan on waiting.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241205-00/?p=110609 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12: UI Updates, Experimental Kubernetes Executor Mode, Conditional Dependencies in Build Chains, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity 2024.12 introduces a redesigned UI, conditional build chains, simplified OAuth token management, and enhanced AWS and Perforce integrations. New features also include support for custom Kotlin DSL libraries, centralized refreshable token management, and single-action build chain approvals, among others. Conditional dependencies in build chains In TeamCity, you can break down complex build processes into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/teamcity-202412/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Do Sentiment Analysis With Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sentiment analysis is a powerful tool for understanding emotions in text. While there are many ways to approach sentiment analysis, including more traditional lexicon-based and machine learning approaches, today we’ll be focusing on one of the most cutting-edge ways of working with text – large language models (LLMs). We’ll explain how you can use these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/how-to-do-sentiment-analysis-with-large-language-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest enhancements in Fluid Framework 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 20:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Catch up on all of the Fluid Framework 2 announcements highlighted at Ignite including the AI Collab library, Fluid presence library, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/latest-enhancements-in-fluid-framework-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to develop AI Apps and Agents in Azure – A Visual Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 19:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As organizations explore new AI-powered experiences and automated workflows, there’s a growing need to move beyond experiments and proofs-of-concept to production-ready applications. This guide walks you through the essential steps and decisions for building robust AI applications in Azure, focusing on reliability, security, and enterprise-grade quality. Why Choose Azure’s Managed Services? It’s easy to experiment […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-develop-ai-apps-and-agents-in-azure-a-visual-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Marketplace now includes NVIDIA models: Introducing NVIDIA Nemotron-4 NIM microservices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 19:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At AWS re:Invent 2024, we are excited to introduce Amazon Bedrock Marketplace. This a revolutionary new capability within Amazon Bedrock that serves as a centralized hub for discovering, testing, and implementing foundation models (FMs). In this post, we discuss the advantages and capabilities of Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Nemotron models, and how to get started.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-marketplace-now-includes-nvidia-models-introducing-nvidia-nemotron-4-nim-microservices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Copilot for Code Refactoring</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 19:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I share GitHub Copilot tips every few days, if you are new to the series, below I have linked some of the previous tips. In this article, I am sharing a tip about using GitHub Copilot for code refactoring. GitHub Copilot Tip: Interactive Debugging with GitHub Copilot Chat How to use GitHub Copilot for Efficient […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-use-copilot-for-code-refactoring 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real value, real time: Production AI with Amazon SageMaker and Tecton</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 19:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how Amazon SageMaker and Tecton work together to simplify the development and deployment of production-ready AI applications, particularly for real-time use cases like fraud detection. The integration enables faster time to value by abstracting away complex engineering tasks, allowing teams to focus on building features and use cases while providing a streamlined framework for both offline training and online serving of ML models.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Bedrock tooling with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 18:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to deploy AI models from SageMaker JumpStart and use them with Amazon Bedrock&#39;s powerful features. Users can combine SageMaker JumpStart&#39;s model hosting with Bedrock&#39;s security and monitoring tools. We demonstrate this using the Gemma 2 9B Instruct model as an example, showing how to deploy it and use Bedrock&#39;s advanced capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-bedrock-tooling-with-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to Amazon Bedrock Model Distillation (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 18:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces the workflow of Amazon Bedrock Model Distillation. We first introduce the general concept of model distillation in Amazon Bedrock, and then focus on the important steps in model distillation, including setting up permissions, selecting the models, providing input dataset, commencing the model distillation jobs, and conducting evaluation and deployment of the student models after model distillation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-guide-to-amazon-bedrock-model-distillation-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications quickly with Amazon Bedrock IDE in Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 18:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll show how anyone in your company can use Amazon Bedrock IDE to quickly create a generative AI chat agent application that analyzes sales performance data. Through simple conversations, business teams can use the chat agent to extract valuable insights from both structured and unstructured data sources without writing code or managing complex data pipelines.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-quickly-with-amazon-bedrock-ide-in-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale ML workflows with Amazon SageMaker Studio and Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 18:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The integration of Amazon SageMaker Studio and Amazon SageMaker HyperPod offers a streamlined solution that provides data scientists and ML engineers with a comprehensive environment that supports the entire ML lifecycle, from development to deployment at scale. In this post, we walk you through the process of scaling your ML workloads using SageMaker Studio and SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-ml-workflows-with-amazon-sagemaker-studio-and-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.4-1 and 1.22.10-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 18:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-4-1-and-1-22-10-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Kendra GenAI Index – Enhanced semantic search and retrieval capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 17:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon has introduced the Amazon Kendra GenAI Index, a new offering designed to enhance semantic search and retrieval capabilities for enterprise AI applications. This index is optimized for Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and intelligent search, allowing businesses to build more effective digital assistants and search experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-kendra-genai-index-enhanced-semantic-search-and-retrieval-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Generative AI and ML solutions faster with AI apps from AWS partners using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 17:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce that AI apps from AWS Partners are now available in SageMaker. You can now find, deploy, and use these AI apps privately and securely, all without leaving SageMaker AI, so you can develop performant AI models faster.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-generative-ai-and-ml-solutions-faster-with-ai-apps-from-aws-partners-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Inline Return Values Simplify Debugging in Visual Studio 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 16:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever found yourself creating temporary variables just to inspect return values from functions? It’s a small task that can quickly become tedious, breaking your rhythm and cluttering up your code. Visual Studio 2022 introduces a smarter way to handle this with “Inline Return Values,” allowing you to stay focused on coding without the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-inline-return-values-simplify-debugging-in-visual-studio-2022 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does my DLL reference count go up by one every time I create and exit a thread?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you use a wrapper, you need to follow the wrapper&#39;s rules.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241204-00/?p=110604 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Microsoft Entra ID for enhanced security in three-tier architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how to secure three-tier architecture with Microsoft Entra ID in this first part of a three-part series. Learn how to implement robust authentication and authorization across client app, API, and data layers, ensuring secure and reliable application design in an Azure cloud environment.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/microsoft-entra-id-and-three-tier-arhcitecture 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GreenJinn Took the Strain Off Their Core Tech Team and Achieved a 200% ROI With Datalore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 10:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trapped in the insights loop As GreenJinn scaled, its tech and engineering team became overwhelmed with data extraction requests from non-technical teams, including operations, insights, sales, and marketing. These teams relied on the tech department for all their data needs, creating a bottleneck that slowed down operations and disrupted product development. The insights loop was a repetitive cycle. The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/12/04/greenjinn-achieved-a-200-roi-with-datalore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t use MediatR by default on all .NET projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 09:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET ecosystem has witnessed a significant shift in recent years, with MediatR becoming almost synonymous with Clean Architecture implementations. This library, designed to implement the mediator pattern, has found its way into countless tutorials, templates, and starter kits, making it seem like an essential component of modern .NET Core
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/dont-use-mediatr-by-default-net-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft DevLabs Extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft DevLabs publisher was created as a hub for internal teams at Microsoft to channel their passion for Azure DevOps into experimental extensions. These extensions helped address product gaps and fostered innovation, ultimately benefiting Azure DevOps customers via the public marketplace. The challenge Over time, as the original creators of these extensions moved on […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/microsoft-devlabs-extensions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.3-2 and 1.22.9-2 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-3-2-and-1-22-9-2-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query structured data from Amazon Q Business using Amazon QuickSight integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Amazon Q Business integrates with QuickSight to enable users to query both structured and unstructured data in a unified way. The integration allows users to connect to over 20 structured data sources like Amazon Redshift and PostgreSQL, while getting real-time answers with visualizations. Amazon Q Business combines information from structured sources through QuickSight with unstructured content to provide comprehensive answers to user queries.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate customer experience by using the Amazon Q Business custom plugin for New Relic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The New Relic AI custom plugin for Amazon Q Business creates a unified solution that combines New Relic AI’s observability insights and recommendations and Amazon Q Business’s Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) capabilities, in and a natural language interface for east of use. This post explores the use case, how this custom plugin works, how it can be enabled, and how it can help elevate customers’ digital experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker launches the updated inference optimization toolkit for generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, Amazon SageMaker is excited to announce updates to the inference optimization toolkit, providing new functionality and enhancements to help you optimize generative AI models even faster.In this post, we discuss these new features of the toolkit in more detail.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-launches-the-updated-inference-optimization-toolkit-for-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syngenta develops a generative AI assistant to support sales representatives using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Syngenta collaborated with AWS to develop Cropwise AI, a generative AI assistant powered by Amazon Bedrock Agents that helps sales representatives make better seed product recommendations to farmers across North America. The solution transforms the seed selection process by simplifying complex data into natural conversations, providing quick access to detailed seed product information, and enabling personalized recommendations at scale through a mobile app interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specification Usage with Marten for Repository-Free Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 17:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ll jump into real discussions about architecture later in this post, but let’s say that we’re starting the development of a new software system. And for a variety of reasons I’ll try to discuss later, we want to eschew the usage of repository abstractions and be able to use all the power of our persistence … Continue reading Specification Usage with Marten for Repository-Free Development →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/03/specification-usage-with-marten-for-repository-free-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Fabric API for GraphQL™ for Azure Cosmos DB Mirroring</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Fabric API for GraphQL™ provides a data access layer that enables you to query multiple data sources quickly and efficiently using a widely adopted and familiar API technology. This API abstracts the specifics of backend data sources, allowing you to focus on your application’s logic and deliver all the data a client needs […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/microsoft-fabric-api-for-graphql-for-azure-cosmos-db-mirroring 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing your AI apps with Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 16:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We previously introduced observability within the Semantic Kernel. For further insights, please refer to our previous blog post, and you can also explore our learn site for additional details. To summarize, observability is an essential aspect of your application stack, particularly in today’s landscape where AI plays a significant role in numerous applications. Given that […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/tracing-your-ai-apps-with-azure-ai-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Containers: Unveiling the Full Potential of Docker for Cloud-Native Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about what Docker does as a suite of software development tools to enhance productivity, improve security, and integrate seamlessly with CI/CD pipelines.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/what-does-docker-do/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks from product support: We’re not smart enough to debug the problem, can you help us?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s not you, it&#39;s me.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241203-00/?p=110601 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Copy Git Permalink Feature in Visual Studio 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the release of the Copy Git Permalink feature in Visual Studio 17.12. This new functionality streamlines the process of sharing code references, enhancing collaboration and ensuring that critical context is preserved. Effortless Code Sharing If you’ve found yourself needing to share code snippets with colleagues, you know the challenges of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-the-copy-git-permalink-feature-in-visual-studio-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Origin-Embedder-Policy: securing embedded resources: Understanding cross-origin security headers - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss the Cross-Origin-Embedder-Policy, the requirements it places on your resources, and why it&#39;s required for some JavaScript APIs
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/understanding-security-headers-part-3-cross-origin-embedder-policy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to bulk insert with EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 08:46:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You may have encountered a situation where your application must insert massive amounts of data at once. Scenarios such as analytics applications, IoT monitoring systems, legacy systems, and data migration critically require bulk insertion of records. Sometimes, you must deal with thousands of records simultaneously, so inserting them will significantly
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/how-to-bulk-insert-with-efcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up your AI inference workloads with new NVIDIA-powered capabilities in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At re:Invent 2024, we are excited to announce new capabilities to speed up your AI inference workloads with NVIDIA accelerated computing and software offerings on Amazon SageMaker. In this post, we will explore how you can use these new capabilities to enhance your AI inference on Amazon SageMaker. We&#39;ll walk through the process of deploying NVIDIA NIM microservices from AWS Marketplace for SageMaker Inference. We&#39;ll then dive into NVIDIA’s model offerings on SageMaker JumpStart, showcasing how to access and deploy the Nemotron-4 model directly in the JumpStart interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock cost savings with the new scale down to zero feature in SageMaker Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today at AWS re:Invent 2024, we are excited to announce a new feature for Amazon SageMaker inference endpoints: the ability to scale SageMaker inference endpoints to zero instances. This long-awaited capability is a game changer for our customers using the power of AI and machine learning (ML) inference in the cloud.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-cost-savings-with-the-new-scale-down-to-zero-feature-in-amazon-sagemaker-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your auto scaling for generative AI inference – Introducing Container Caching in SageMaker Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today at AWS re:Invent 2024, we are excited to announce the new Container Caching capability in Amazon SageMaker, which significantly reduces the time required to scale generative AI models for inference. This innovation allows you to scale your models faster, observing up to 56% reduction in latency when scaling a new model copy and up to 30% when adding a model copy on a new instance. In this post, we explore the new Container Caching feature for SageMaker inference, addressing the challenges of deploying and scaling large language models (LLMs).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Fast Model Loader in SageMaker Inference: Accelerate autoscaling for your Large Language Models (LLMs) – part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today at AWS re:Invent 2024, we are excited to announce a new capability in Amazon SageMaker Inference that significantly reduces the time required to deploy and scale LLMs for inference using LMI: Fast Model Loader. In this post, we delve into the technical details of Fast Model Loader, explore its integration with existing SageMaker workflows, discuss how you can get started with this powerful new feature, and share customer success stories.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Fast Model Loader in SageMaker Inference: Accelerate autoscaling for your Large Language Models (LLMs) – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a detailed, hands-on guide to implementing Fast Model Loader in your LLM deployments. We explore two approaches: using the SageMaker Python SDK for programmatic implementation, and using the Amazon SageMaker Studio UI for a more visual, interactive experience. Whether you’re a developer who prefers working with code or someone who favors a graphical interface, you’ll learn how to take advantage of this powerful feature to accelerate your LLM deployments.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: 2 ways to generate realistic data using Bogus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bogus is a library that generates realistic values for your data. When populating fake user names, instead of Foo and Bar, you can have John and Sarah. Let’s see two ways to define and reuse a Faker definition.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/bogus-data-generation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
