<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 04:10:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-03-07</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 04:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/08/weekly-recap-20250307 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Request Tracing with User Context in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adding user context to request tracing in ASP.NET Core helps track issues and understand user behavior. This article shows how to implement middleware that enriches logs with user IDs for better troubleshooting and performance monitoring.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/better-request-tracing-with-user-context-in-asp-net-core 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration of AWS Bedrock Agents in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 21:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview of AWS Bedrock Agents AWS Bedrock Agents provide a managed service that facilitates the experimentation and rapid deployment of AI agents. Users can leverage proprietary AWS models as well as a diverse selection of models from various providers available on AWS Bedrock. Semantic Kernel’s Integration with AWS Bedrock Semantic Kernel now integrates with AWS […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/integration-of-aws-bedrock-agents-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating insurance policy reviews with generative AI: Verisk’s Mozart companion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 20:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-authored with Sundeep Sardana, Malolan Raman, Joseph Lam, Maitri Shah and Vaibhav Singh from Verisk. Verisk (Nasdaq: VRSK) is a leading strategic data analytics and technology partner to the global insurance industry, empowering clients to strengthen operating efficiency, improve underwriting and claims outcomes, combat fraud, and make informed decisions about global risks. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-insurance-policy-reviews-with-generative-ai-verisks-mozart-companion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the March release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-march-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing general availability of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases GraphRAG with Amazon Neptune Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, Amazon Web Services (AWS) announced the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases GraphRAG (GraphRAG), a capability in Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases that enhances Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) with graph data in Amazon Neptune Analytics. In this post, we discuss the benefits of GraphRAG and how to get started with it in Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/announcing-general-availability-of-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-graphrag-with-amazon-neptune-analytics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To some people, time zones are just a fancy way of sounding important, episode 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Words have meaning.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250307-00/?p=110946 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar – OSS Power-Ups: EntityFramework.Exceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 14:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Tuesday, March 18, 2025, 14:00 – 15:30 UTC (check other timezones) for our free live webinar, OSS PowerUps – EntityFramework.Exceptions, with Giorgi Dalakishvili. This is the fourtheenth episode of our series of OSS Power-Ups, where we put a spotlight on open-source .NET projects. Register now and get a reminder, or join on YouTube […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/03/07/webinar-oss-power-ups-entityframework-exceptions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Service Fabric: Is it still relevant? Service Fabric vs Microsoft Fabric?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Azure Service Fabric has been a foundational platform for building and managing microservices-based applications since its release. However, with the rise of Kubernetes and other container orchestration tools, its adoption has seen changes over the years. Additionally, Microsoft introduced Microsoft Fabric, a new data and analytics platform, leading to some confusion between the two […] The article Azure Service Fabric: Is it still relevant? Service Fabric vs Microsoft Fabric? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.3 Bug Fix Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 09:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.3 bug-fix update is out and ready to be installed on your servers! This update resolves over 10 issues and, as always, includes essential security and performance fixes. We highly recommend upgrading to keep your system secure and optimized. The list of resolved issues includes: See TeamCity 2024.12.3 Upgrade Notes for the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/teamcity-2024-12-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are OWASP Top 10 Checks and How Can Your Team Benchmark Security?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 09:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Businesses of different sizes have various motives for prioritizing code security. For an enterprise client, it might have to do with compliance. For a business that handles user data, there could be very imminent risk to customers and staff alike. Any development team could fall prey to the rise of cybercrime and attacks as detailed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/03/owasp-top-10/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.1-1 and 1.23.7-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 09:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-1-1-and-1-23-7-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET MAUI在 .NET 9 中的性能功能</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 06:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自 Jonathan 和 Simon 的 .NET MAUI Performance Features in .NET 9 .NET 多平台应用 UI (.NET MAUI) 随着各个版本的发布而不断发展，与此同时，.NET 9 重点引入了裁剪功能和一个新的受支持运行时：NativeAOT。这些功能可以帮助您减少应用程序大小、提高启动速度，并确保应用程序在各个平台上流畅运行。无论是希望优化 .NET MAUI 应用的开发者，还是 NuGet 包的作者，都可以在 .NET 9 中使用这些功能。 我们还将向开发人员介绍可用于测量 .NET MAUI 应用程序性能的选项。CPU 采样和内存快照可分别通过 dotnet-trace 和 dotnet-gcdump 获得。这些工具可以帮助您深入了解应用程序、NuGet 包的性能问题，甚至是我们需要关注的 .NET MAUI 问题。 背景 默认情况下， iOS 和 Android 上的 .NET MAUI 应用程序使用以下设置： “自包含”: 意味着应用程序中包含 BCL 和运行时的副本。 部分裁剪（TrimMode=partial），意味着默认情况下不修剪应用程序或 NuGet […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/net-maui%e5%9c%a8-net-9-%e4%b8%ad%e7%9a%84%e6%80%a7%e8%83%bd%e5%8a%9f%e8%83%bd 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to your agents! Introducing the Realtime API’s in Semantic Kernel!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 21:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing Realtime Agents in Semantic Kernel for Python! With release 1.23.0 of the Python version of Semantic Kernel we are introducing a new set of clients for interacting with the realtime multi-modal API’s of OpenAI and Azure OpenAI. They provide a abstracted approach to connecting to those services, adding your tools and running apps that […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/talk-to-your-agents-introducing-the-realtime-apis-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop 4.39: Smarter AI Agent, Docker Desktop CLI in GA, and Effortless Multi-Platform Builds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 18:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.39 brings Docker AI Agent for real-time help, plus Bake for faster builds and Multi-Node Kubernetes for better testing. Learn more!
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-39/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Angular Language Server: Understanding IDE Integration Approaches</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 18:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Language Server Protocol (LSP) has been a fundamental part of the code editor landscape for years, providing a consistent development experience across different editors. The Angular Language Server leverages this protocol to provide Angular-specific features to compatible editors. However, not all IDEs take the same approach to delivering these capabilities. Let’s look at the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/03/the-angular-language-server-understanding-ide-integration-approaches/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET AI Template Now Available in Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the first preview of the .NET AI Template, for Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, and the .NET CLI. Get started building amazing AI apps with .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-ai-template-preview1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Multi-Agent System with LangGraph and Mistral on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 17:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use LangGraph and Mistral models on Amazon Bedrock to create a powerful multi-agent system that can handle sophisticated workflows through collaborative problem-solving. This integration enables the creation of AI agents that can work together to solve complex problems, mimicking humanlike reasoning and collaboration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-multi-agent-system-with-langgraph-and-mistral-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Microsoft Copilot scales to millions of users with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is guest authored by Youssef Moussaoui, member of the technical staff, Microsoft Copilot. As part of the team developing Microsoft Copilot, we’re constantly looking for ways to improve the application and keep our millions of users engaged. With this in mind, we recently evaluated the structure of our backend and began looking for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/how-microsoft-copilot-scales-to-millions-of-users-with-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate RAG responses with Amazon Bedrock, LlamaIndex and RAGAS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 16:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we’ll explore how to leverage Amazon Bedrock, LlamaIndex, and RAGAS to enhance your RAG implementations. You’ll learn practical techniques to evaluate and optimize your AI systems, enabling more accurate, context-aware responses that align with your organization’s specific needs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-rag-responses-with-amazon-bedrock-llamaindex-and-ragas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: What’s new and what’s next</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code continues to evolve, bringing powerful new features and enhancements that make SQL development more seamless and efficient. In this update, we’re excited to share the latest improvements in v1.29.0 and give you a sneak peek at what’s coming next in our open roadmap. This extension is designed for developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/mssql-vs-code-whats-new-next 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortlessly Integrate xAI’s Grok with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 15:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For Semantic Kernel users, integrating xAI’s Grok API using the OpenAI connector is a breeze thanks to its compatibility with OpenAI’s API format. This tutorial focuses on setting up Grok in your Semantic Kernel projects with minimal fuss, using C# and Python examples. Why Grok? Grok, built by xAI, is a powerful AI model, offers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/integrate-sk-with-xai-grok-easily 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I choose a different C&#43;&#43; constructor at runtime?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Make somebody else do it, and then use copy elision.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250306-00/?p=110942 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 12:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this month’s Java Annotated Monthly! As always, we bring you the most interesting tutorials on Java, Kotlin, and other technologies, along with the latest news you don’t want to miss. We’re also excited to introduce a brand-new AI section, which we reserve for the most fascinating content on the topic. And this month, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/java-annotated-monthly-march-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try The New Toolbox App 2.6 EAP With Remote Development Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 10:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the latest update, the Toolbox App now supports remote development, allowing you to manage your JetBrains tools and projects both locally and on remote servers. This allows you to connect to cross-platform hosts, including Windows, macOS, and Linux, and use integrated OpenSSH for secure and customizable SSH connections. You can download the latest Toolbox […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/toolbox-app/2025/03/try-the-new-toolbox-app-2-6-eap-with-remote-development-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Guidelines Support Library v4.2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 09:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Version 4.2.0 of Microsoft&#39;s Guidelines Support Library brings performance improvements, safety features, modern compiler support.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/announcing-guidelines-support-library-v4-2-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi Root Workspaces in Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to manage multiple independent python projects, with different dependencies, inside Visual Studio Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/multi_root_workspaces_in_visual_studio_code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovating at speed: BMW’s generative AI solution for cloud incident analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how BMW uses generative AI to speed up the root cause analysis of incidents in complex and distributed systems in the cloud such as BMW’s Connected Vehicle backend serving 23 million vehicles. Read on to learn how the solution, collaboratively pioneered by AWS and BMW, uses Amazon Bedrock Agents and Amazon CloudWatch logs and metrics to find root causes quicker. This post is intended for cloud solution architects and developers interested in speeding up their incident workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series forecasting with LLM-based foundation models and scalable AIOps on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will guide you through the process of integrating Chronos into Amazon SageMaker Pipeline using a synthetic dataset that simulates a sales forecasting scenario, unlocking accurate and efficient predictions with minimal data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/time-series-forecasting-with-llm-based-foundation-models-and-scalable-aiops-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ground truth generation and review best practices for evaluating generative AI question-answering with FMEval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss best practices for applying LLMs to generate ground truth for evaluating question-answering assistants with FMEval on an enterprise scale. FMEval is a comprehensive evaluation suite from Amazon SageMaker Clarify, and provides standardized implementations of metrics to assess quality and responsibility. To learn more about FMEval, see Evaluate large language models for quality and responsibility of LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ground-truth-generation-and-review-best-practices-for-evaluating-generative-ai-question-answering-with-fmeval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Generative AI Uses Text Tokens to Generate a Response</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 19:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI systems using Large Language Models (LLMs) like GPT-4o process natural language input through a series of computational steps: tokenization, numerical representation, neural processing, and text generation. While these models have achieved impressive performance in understanding and generating text, they sometimes struggle with seemingly simple tasks, such as counting letters in a word. This […] The article How Generative AI Uses Text Tokens to Generate a Response was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – March 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 19:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The March 2025 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include improvements to shell integration, a new setting to change auto test discovery file patterns, inline values shown on hover, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-march-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoGen and Semantic Kernel, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 17:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following on from our blog post a couple months ago: Microsoft’s Agentic AI Frameworks: AutoGen and Semantic Kernel, Microsoft’s agentic AI story is evolving at a steady pace. Both Azure AI Foundry’s Semantic Kernel and AI Frontier’s AutoGen are designed to empower developers to build advanced multi-agent systems. The AI Frontier’s team is charging ahead […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-and-autogen-part-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 17:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta is now available! This means we’re in the final stretch before the major release, and you can try out all the new features and improvements right now. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing, Managing and Securing: Building with Microsoft Copilot Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 16:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you would like to start building an agent in Microsoft Copilot Studio, don’t worry we’ve got you covered! In our AI in Action: Building with Copilot Studio series on the Microsoft Power Platform YouTube channel, we have several episodes that guide you through how to get started in building an agent. This blog post […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/publishing-managing-and-securing-building-with-microsoft-copilot-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Debugging and Profiling Features in Visual Studio (v17.13)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 15:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest Visual Studio update (v17.13) brings a strong set of debugging and profiling features designed to speed up troubleshooting, making it more efficient. With AI-driven features in this release, variable analysis and data inspection are smarter and more intuitive, and problems are easier to identify and debug. Profiling tool improvements also deliver better support […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-debugging-and-profiling-features-in-visual-studio-v17-13 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Model Context Protocol Tools with Semantic Kernel: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 15:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes how to use Model Context Protocol tools with Semantic Kernel. Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open protocol that standardizes how applications provide context to LLMs. MCP standardizes the connection between AI models and various data sources and tools. The Model Context Protocol is significant because it enhances the way AI models […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/integrating-model-context-protocol-tools-with-semantic-kernel-a-step-by-step-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I tried to subscribe to a C&#43;&#43;/WinRT event, but my callback was never called</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check how you registered your event handler.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250305-00/?p=110934 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 13:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The [InternalsVisibleTo] attribute in .NET is a powerful feature that allows an assembly to expose its internal members (normally only accessible within the same assembly) to another specified assembly. This is typically used in scenarios like unit testing or multi-assembly projects where tight integration between assemblies is needed. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/03/05/dotinsights-march-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Creating Empty Arrays</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Arrays are a key collection type in .NET. There are three methods to create empty arrays: new string[0], Array.Empty(), and the concise [] expression. Benchmark tests show the [] expression is the fastest and most memory-efficient option. For improved performance, developers should adopt this method in their codebases.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/05/microsoft-net-code-analysis-creating-empty-arrays/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRY principle is why your codebase sucks?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 22:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DRY Principle is seemingly advocated for or against. In reality, it’s not good or bad so as long as you understand why you’re applying it and for what purpose. Misunderstanding DRY is why your system can turn into a hard to change rats nest. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content… Read More »DRY principle is why your codebase sucks? The post DRY principle is why your codebase sucks?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Training on Modern .NET with Vertical Slice Architecture in Frankfurt</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 20:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s training time again! I&#39;ve got another training event coming up focusing on Modern .NET with Vertical Slice Architecture in Frankfurt on June 25th-26th.Also similar to last year&#39;s edition of the course is an option for either a 2-day or 3-day version. The
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/upcoming-training-on-modern-net-with-vertical-slice-architecture-in-frankfurt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate AWS Well-Architected reviews with Generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 16:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a generative AI solution leveraging Amazon Bedrock to streamline the WAFR process. We demonstrate how to harness the power of LLMs to build an intelligent, scalable system that analyzes architecture documents and generates insightful recommendations based on AWS Well-Architected best practices. This solution automates portions of the WAFR report creation, helping solutions architects improve the efficiency and thoroughness of architectural assessments while supporting their decision-making process.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic metadata filtering for Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases with LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 16:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases has a metadata filtering capability that allows you to refine search results based on specific attributes of the documents, improving retrieval accuracy and the relevance of responses. These metadata filters can be used in combination with the typical semantic (or hybrid) similarity search. In this post, we discuss using metadata filters with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dynamic-metadata-filtering-for-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-with-langchain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: Respin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spin it up again, baby.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250304-00/?p=110929 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Horizon: Top Three Updates Coming Soon From Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 14:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we head deeper into Q1 of 2025, some exciting new developments are underway. From expanding Qodana’s integrations with new IDEs to consolidating organizational data, many more promising new projects are in the works to help increase code quality in your team. Let’s take a look at the top three! An organization-wide dashboard Insights into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/03/qodana-roadmap-2025-q1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an analyzer to detect infinite loops caused by ThreadAbortExceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe a Roslyn Analyzer I created to detect code that can result in infinite loops if a ThreadAbortException is raised
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-an-analyzer-to-detect-infinite-loops-caused-by-threadabortexception/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2024.1.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 07:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released an update to MPS 2024.1, which corrects several problems, mainly in the UI, indexing, and migrations. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.1.2 See the full list of fixed issues here. Download this latest version here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/03/mps-2024-1-2-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize DeepSeek-R1 distilled models using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod recipes – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 21:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this two-part series, we discuss how you can reduce the DeepSeek model customization complexity by using the pre-built fine-tuning workflows (also called “recipes”) for both DeepSeek-R1 model and its distilled variations, released as part of Amazon SageMaker HyperPod recipes. In this first post, we will build a solution architecture for fine-tuning DeepSeek-R1 distilled models and demonstrate the approach by providing a step-by-step example on customizing the DeepSeek-R1 Distill Qwen 7b model using recipes, achieving an average of 25% on all the Rouge scores, with a maximum of 49% on Rouge 2 score with both SageMaker HyperPod and SageMaker training jobs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: LLMAgentOps Toolkit for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 20:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today the Semantic Kernel team is excited to welcome a guest author, Prabal Deb to share his work. LLMAgentOps Toolkit is repository that contains basic structure of LLM Agent based application built on top of the Semantic Kernel Python version. The toolkit is designed to be a starting point for data scientists and developers for experimentation […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-llmagentops-toolkit-for-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock new possibilities for AI Evaluations for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Evaluations library is now open source, and a new Azure DevOps plug-in is available to make reporting in your CI pipelines easier than ever.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/start-using-the-microsoft-ai-evaluations-library-today 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI in Action — How to build scalable RAG-enabled AI apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 17:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For developers, the emphasis on building intelligence into apps has never been clearer. Over the next three years, 92% of companies plan on investing in AI to achieve business outcomes like enhancing productivity and delivering better customer service. At Microsoft, developers and engineers are pushing the boundaries of AI at scale, crafting applications that harness […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/ai-in-action-how-to-build-scalable-rag-enabled-ai-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce conversational AI response time through inference at the edge with AWS Local Zones</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 16:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide demonstrates how to deploy an open source foundation model from Hugging Face on Amazon EC2 instances across three locations: a commercial AWS Region and two AWS Local Zones. Through comparative benchmarking tests, we illustrate how deploying foundation models in Local Zones closer to end users can significantly reduce latency—a critical factor for real-time applications such as conversational AI assistants.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/reduce-conversational-ai-response-time-through-inference-at-the-edge-with-aws-local-zones/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixtral-12B-2409 is now available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 16:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how to discover, deploy, and use the Mistral AI Pixtral 12B model for a variety of real-world vision use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pixtral-12b-2409-is-now-available-on-amazon-bedrock-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great new productivity features in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 16:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sometimes it’s the little things in life that matter the most. In the latest version of Visual Studio, we’ve added some features and tweaks that aim to put a smile on your face and make you more productive. Here is a list of some of these, and if you want the full list, make sure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/great-new-productivity-features-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lexically scoped functions accessing parent locals: The display</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using a well-known location instead of copying frame pointers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250303-00/?p=110925 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Azure Resource and Service Limits and Quotas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Azure imposes limits and quotas on how many resources of each type you can provision per Azure Subscription, and even per Azure Region. Some limits are a hard maximum, while others are a soft limit that can be increases upon request. When working with Virtual Machines (VMs), Storage Accounts, Databases, and other resources in […] The article Microsoft Azure Resource and Service Limits and Quotas was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public preview of SharePoint Framework 1.21 – First release of upcoming features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 11:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the first preview of the upcoming SharePoint Framework 1.21. This release will have updates for SharePoint, Viva Connections and Microsoft Teams experiences.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/public-preview-of-sharepoint-framework-1-21-first-release-of-upcoming-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Data Studio Retires February 28, 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced the official retirement of Azure Data Studio on February 28, 2026. This decision marks a significant shift in Microsoft’s approach to database development tools, as users are encouraged to transition to Visual Studio Code (VS Code) with the appropriate extensions for database management and SQL development. What is Azure Data Studio? Azure […] The article Azure Data Studio Retires February 28, 2026 was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Gatherers: The API Your Stream Was Missing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 08:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with José Paumard, where we’ll explore the Stream Gatherer API in JDK 24 and how to use it effectively in your applications. Date: March 13, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract JDK 24 is bringing a new enhancement to the Stream […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/new-livestream-gatherers-the-api-your-stream-was-missing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queue-Based Load Leveling Pattern (Starring Phi4 and Azure Service Bus)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 08:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog, we’re exploring the Queue-Based Load Leveling pattern—a powerful method for smoothing out workload spikes Why Choose Queue-Based Load Leveling? In today’s fast-paced software environment, dynamic workloads are common. The Queue-Based Load Leveling pattern decouples the production and consumption of tasks by introducing a queue between them. This allows producers and consumers to work independently, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/queue-based-load-leveling-pattern-starring-phi4-and-azure-service-bus 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Admission for the Computer Science and AI BSc Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 08:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Admission to the Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos is open! The JetBrains Foundation supports this bachelor’s program and offers 15 fully funded scholarships for the most talented applicants. The scholarships cover tuition, accommodation, medical insurance, visa fees, and spending money (€300 per month). Many students who graduate from bachelor’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/03/03/admission-for-the-computer-science-and-ai-bsc-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New MPS 2024.3.1 Bugfix Release Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released an update for MPS 2024.3 that brings numerous fixes. Check them out and see what you think. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3.1 See the full list of fixed issues here. Download MPS 2024.3.1 here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/03/mps-2024-3-1-has-been-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement Phone verification, 2FA using ASP.NET Core Identity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to implement phone (SMS) verification and two-factor authentication (2FA) using ASP.NET Core Identity. The solution integrates phone-based verification and 2FA mechanisms. The implementation uses ASP.NET Core Identity’s extensibility to incorporate SMS-based verification during user registration and login processes. SMS is no longer a recommended authentication method due to security risks but […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/03/03/implement-phone-verification-2fa-using-asp-net-core-identity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IP Subnet Calculator and Reference (Cloud, Azure, Private, IPv4 CIDR, and more)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 21:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a network engineer, administrator, or Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) you probably have run across CIDR notation for defining IPv4 address spaces for both networks and subnets. CIDR notation is used a lot in the IT infrastructure configuration world. The following is a description of what CIDR notation is, in case you’re not that familiar, […] The article IP Subnet Calculator and Reference (Cloud, Azure, Private, IPv4 CIDR, and more) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Performance Gains in .NET: The Power of Custom Comparers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article highlights the importance of custom comparers in .NET for enhancing application performance when sorting and ordering collections. It discusses the flexibility and control that custom comparers offer over default comparers and provides examples of creating them. Benchmarks also illustrate the performance benefits, while cautioning that custom comparers may introduce overhead in certain scenarios.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/02/unlock-performance-gains-in-net-the-power-of-custom-comparers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senior Developer Means Coding... Less?! - Dev Leader Weekly 85</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss what might be a bit uncomfortable... but do senior engineers actually code less?!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/01/senior-developer-means-coding-less-dev-leader-weekly-85 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-02-28</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 07:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/01/weekly-recap-20250228 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Dapr for .NET Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how Dapr helps .NET developers build better microservices with standardized building blocks, practical code examples, and seamless integration with .NET Aspire to simplify your distributed systems journey.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/introduction-to-dapr-for-dotnet-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
