<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Performance Improvements in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Take an in-depth tour through hundreds of performance improvements in .NET 9.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/performance-improvements-in-net-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the New TeamCity Plugin for IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release of the updated TeamCity plugin for IntelliJ IDEA! 🎉 You can now download it directly from JetBrains Marketplace. Using the plugin, you can trigger TeamCity builds directly from within your IDE and test any changes before committing them to the version control system. Why get the new plugin? This […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/09/new-teamcity-plugin-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VisualStudio.Extensibility 17.11: Settings and more Remote UI support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We continue to invest in the VisualStudio.Extensibility SDK to allow users like you to create extensions that run faster and smoother than ever before! VisualStudio.Extensibility helps you build extensions that run outside the main Visual Studio IDE process for improved performance and reliability. Additional benefits include a sleek and intuitive .NET 8-based API and comprehensive, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visualstudio-extensibility-17-11-settings-and-more-remote-ui-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 08:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 is officially underway! The first EAP build is now available, offering you an early look at the first portion of improvements introduced for the next major release. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Background Tasks With The IHostedLifecycleService Interface</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 06:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll describe the IHostedLifecycleService interface. We’ll see how it extends the IHostedService interface and enables finer control over the hosted service lifecycle. Finally, we’ll show some practical use cases for the IHostedLifecycleService interface. Let’s get started. What Is the IHostedService Interface The IHostedService interface is a powerful feature in .NET that enables […] The post Manage Background Tasks With The IHostedLifecycleService Interface appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Sourcing 101: Terminology &amp; Concepts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 22:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is event sourcing? Many terms are often used that can be pretty confusing. I will explain the core concepts and, specifically, Event Sourcing terminology so you can better understand what it is and what some of the benefits might be. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts,… Read More »Event Sourcing 101: Terminology &amp;amp; Concepts The post Event Sourcing 101: Terminology &amp;amp; Concepts appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 Release Candidate 1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Try out the latest features in .NET 9 Release Candidate 1 across the .NET SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, SignalR, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-release-candidate-1-is-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of purpose-built accelerators for financial services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 19:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we aim to provide business leaders with a non-technical overview of purpose-built accelerators (PBAs) and their role within the financial services industry (FSI).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-review-of-purpose-built-accelerators-for-financial-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly detection in streaming time series data with online learning using Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 19:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a robust real-time anomaly detection solution for streaming time series data using Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink and other AWS managed services.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/anomaly-detection-in-streaming-time-series-data-with-online-learning-using-amazon-managed-service-for-apache-flink/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI-powered technology operations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 19:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we describe how AWS generative AI solutions (including Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Q Developer, and Amazon Q Business) can further enhance TechOps productivity, reduce time to resolve issues, enhance customer experience, standardize operating procedures, and augment knowledge bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generative-ai-powered-technology-operations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing MLOps for Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 18:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we review the guidance for optimizing MLOps for Sustainability on AWS, providing service-specific practices to understand and reduce the environmental impact of these workloads.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-mlops-for-sustainability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Models and .NET: Building Generative AI apps for engineers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you&#39;ll learn how to use AI models on GitHub.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-github-models-and-dotnet-to-build-generative-ai-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure AI Inference Connector for Azure AI Studio Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction With the latest launch of the Azure AI Inference SDK for Azure AI Studio Models Catalog, we are happy to announce that we have also made available our dedicated Azure AI Inference Semantic Kernel Connector. This connector is specially designed on top of the published Azure AI Inference SDK and is targeted to allow […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/introducing-azure-ai-inference-connector-for-azure-ai-studio-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAP for Vector Support Refresh – Introducing Vector type</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not even 6 months ago we started the Early Adopter Preview vector data support in Azure SQL, and we got great feedback and a lot of enthusiasm about the feature. Developers are excited to be able to easily build AI-enabled solution using an enterprise ready, secure, scalable and proven platform like Azure SQL, without the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/eap-for-vector-support-refresh-introducing-vector-type 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize your UWP app with preview UWP support for .NET 9 and Native AOT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re introducing the initial preview UWP (Universal Windows Platform) support for .NET 9, providing a path for existing UWP developers to modernize their apps with the latest .NET and Native AOT. Are you a UWP app developer considering migrating to Windows App SDK and WinUI 3? Or wanting to leverage the latest releases of .NET […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ifdef-windows/preview-uwp-support-for-dotnet-9-native-aot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling complex generative AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we take a closer look at Amazon Bedrock Agents. They empower you to build intelligent and context-aware generative AI applications, streamlining complex workflows and delivering natural, conversational user experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enabling-complex-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing large payloads in Fluid Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about three Fluid Framework features which can be used to work around large payload scenarios: Grouped Batching, Batch Compression, and Compressed Batch Chunking.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/optimizing-large-payloads-in-fluid-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the string being copied from a mysterious pointer to invalid memory, revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reflections on an older topic.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240911-00/?p=110247 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next: The WebStorm 2024.3 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In August of this year, we released WebStorm 2024.2, our second major update for 2024. Thank you to everyone who is already using it and providing feedback. With August now behind us, we’d like to announce what we’ve got planned for the next release of WebStorm, which is scheduled for the middle of November, with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/09/what-s-next-the-webstorm-2024-3-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix C&#43;&#43; warnings and errors with Copilot: Introducing AI-Assisted Code Fixes in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stuck on an unfamiliar build error? Want to resolve your code errors quickly? Copilot is now integrated into Visual Studio error workflows to assist you with understanding and resolving C++ errors and warnings. To access this new feature, you will need an active Copilot subscription and the latest 17.11 GA version of Visual Studio. How […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/fix-c-warnings-and-errors-with-copilot-introducing-ai-assisted-code-fixes-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search scoping helps you find what you’re looking for</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re working on a large and complex solution, you might find yourself overwhelmed by the number of results when you use code search in Visual Studio. You might be looking for a specific class, method, or variable, but end up scrolling through pages of irrelevant matches. Wouldn’t it be nice if you could narrow […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/search-scoping-helps-you-find-what-youre-looking-for 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2024.3 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 07:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The second major release of CLion this year, 2024.2, introduced many improvements and advanced features. These include full line code completion for С++ that runs locally, Zephyr West support, and updates to the new CLion Nova language engine. If you still haven’t tried CLion 2024.2, download and try it today. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 We’ve begun […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/09/2024-3-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomics England uses Amazon SageMaker to predict cancer subtypes and patient survival from multi-modal data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we detail our collaboration in creating two proof of concept (PoC) exercises around multi-modal machine learning for survival analysis and cancer sub-typing, using genomic (gene expression, mutation and copy number variant data) and imaging (histopathology slides) data. We provide insights on interpretability, robustness, and best practices of architecting complex ML workflows on AWS with Amazon SageMaker. These multi-modal pipelines are being used on the Genomics England cancer cohort to enhance our understanding of cancer biomarkers and biology.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine meets RavenDb</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, did you know that JasperFx Software offers both consulting services and support plans for the “Critter Stack” tools? Or for architectural or test automation help with any old server side .NET application. One of the other things we do is to build out custom features that our customers need in the “Critter Stack” — like the … Continue reading Wolverine meets RavenDb →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/10/wolverine-meets-ravendb/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmaps for Microsoft Dev Box and Azure Deployment Environments are now live!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have just published the roadmaps for Microsoft Dev Box and Azure Deployment Environments! These roadmaps showcase our plans and upcoming features for both services, reflecting our commitment to enhancing your experience developing in the cloud. Your feedback is invaluable to us. We’ve built these roadmaps in a direct response to some feedback we’ve heard […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/roadmaps-for-microsoft-dev-box-and-azure-deployment-environments-are-now-live 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Build Your First Blazor Hybrid App!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn all about the Blazor Hybrid workshop that you can follow yourself or teach to others!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-blazor-hybrid-workshop 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Data API Preview in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the preview of the Data API for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB. The Data API provides a flexible and powerful way to interact with your database through HTTP-based API calls. What is the Data API The Data API for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB allows you work with your […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-the-data-api-preview-in-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase your Microsoft Teams app’s visibility and adoption with asynchronous link unfurling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to leverage link unfurling for your Microsoft Teams app, now enhanced with asynchronous capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/how-asynchronous-link-unfurling-increases-your-microsoft-teams-apps-visibility-and-adoption 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add enhanced flexibility to your apps with custom claims on Native Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how the custom claims feature, now available in public preview for Native Authentication on Microsoft Entra External ID, enhances your app&#39;s authentication process. This new capability allows you to tailor app behavior, based on specific user data, by allowing apps to dynamically add custom claims to authentication tokens via a custom claims provider during user sign-up or sign-in.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/custom-claims-on-native-auth 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the Resource Compiler have a separate preprocessor or doesn’t it?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It did, but now it doesn&#39;t.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240910-00/?p=110243 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break for Async User-Unhandled exceptions in the Visual Studio Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Before .NET 9, the debugger was unable to track exceptions thrown from user-code async methods into non-user code framework methods, such as ASP.NET middleware. We are pleased to announce that you will now start seeing the debugger stop for these user-unhandled exceptions in your ASP.NET applications, as well as anywhere else this might happen! Summary […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/break-for-async-user-unhandled-exceptions-in-the-visual-studio-debugger 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing breaking changes in public APIs with PublicApiGenerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how you can use the PublicApiGenerator project to document your public API and build a snapshot unit test to prevent breaking changes
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/preventing-breaking-changes-in-public-apis-with-publicapigenerator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caching Strategies in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 08:28:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Decreasing response time is one of the key measures towards improving the user experience of an application. Caching techniques and other practices can help your .NET application perform well with low effort. With caching, you can keep frequently accessed delay-prone data in a fast, accessible location. This can improve your asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/caching-strategies-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Align Meta Llama 3 to human preferences with DPO, Amazon SageMaker Studio, and Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 22:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to enhance the performance of Meta Llama 3 8B Instruct by fine-tuning it using direct preference optimization (DPO) on data collected with SageMaker Ground Truth.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/align-meta-llama-3-to-human-preferences-with-dpo-amazon-sagemaker-studio-and-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon EC2 P5e instances are generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 22:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss the core capabilities of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) P5e instances and the use cases they’re well-suited for. We walk you through an example of how to get started with these instances and carry out inference deployment of Meta Llama 3.1 70B and 405B models on them.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-ec2-p5e-instances-are-generally-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring data using AI chat at Domo with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 21:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Domo, a cloud-centered data experiences innovator is using Amazon Bedrock to provide a flexible and powerful AI solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/exploring-data-using-ai-chat-at-domo-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Askia, an Ipsos company, achieved faster, reproducible builds with vcpkg</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 19:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            vcpkg is a free and open-source C/C++ package manager maintained by Microsoft and the C++ community that runs on Windows, macOS, and Linux. Over the years we have heard from companies using vcpkg to manage dependencies at enterprise-scale. In this interview, I spoke to Dimitri Rochette, a lead developer at Askia, an Ipsos company, about […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/askia-an-ipsos-company-achieved-faster-reproducible-builds-with-vcpkg 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is F# code so robust and reliable?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            F# is not just for math and big data, it&#39;s a general purpose language that will greatly reduce the amount of bugs in your code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/why-is-fsharp-code-so-robust-and-reliable 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 17:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to announce the release of TypeScript 5.6! If you’re not familiar with TypeScript, it’s a language that builds on top of JavaScript by adding syntax for types. Types describe the shapes we expect of our variables, parameters, and functions, and the TypeScript type-checker can help catch issues like typos, missing properties, and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-6 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with the Labs AI Tools for Devs Docker Desktop Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 16:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the Labs AI Tools for Devs extension in Docker Desktop, designed for prompt authors to easily build, run, and share their AI tools. Get started quickly with our guide to installing the extension and running your first prompts.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/labs-ai-tools-for-devs-docker-desktop-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CQRS Command Handlers with Marten</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 15:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, did you know that JasperFx Software offers both consulting services and support plans for the “Critter Stack” tools? One of the common areas where we’ve helped our clients is in using Marten or Wolverine when the usage involves quite a bit of potential concerns about concurrency. As I write this, I’m currently working with a JasperFx … Continue reading CQRS Command Handlers with Marten →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/09/cqrs-command-handlers-with-marten/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Office Add-ins Development Kit for Visual Studio Code (public preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Office Add-ins Development Kit is a new development tool to help you set up your environment, create Office Add-ins, and debug the code with a streamlined developer experience in Visual Studio Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-the-office-add-ins-development-kit-for-visual-studio-code-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub trick to find the commit that deleted a file</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ask for the history of the file.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240909-00/?p=110234 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Jupyter Notebooks in PyCharm Professional</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 13:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm is one of the most well-known data science tools, offering excellent out-of-the-box support for Python, SQL, and other languages. PyCharm also provides integrations for Databricks, Hugging Face and many other important tools. All these features allow you to write good code and work with your data and projects faster. PyCharm Professional’s support for Jupyter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/how-to-use-jupyter-notebooks-in-pycharm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge C&#43;&#43; Debugging with AI-Generated breakpoint expressions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 13:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever spent hours debugging your C++ code, struggling to set up the right conditional breakpoint or tracepoint? Or wished for a smarter way to obtain detailed runtime information without manually crafting complex expressions? You’re in luck! With Visual Studio 2022, the latest GitHub Copilot feature now offers AI-generated expressions for both conditional breakpoints […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/supercharge-c-debugging-with-ai-generated-breakpoint-expressions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate Tester’s Day With JetBrains Aqua – 50% OFF!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Aqua is proud to join the global tech community in celebrating International Tester’s Day on September 9. This day recognizes the crucial contributions of QA professionals, who ensure that the software we rely on functions flawlessly and delivers a superior user experience. Buy Aqua – 50% OFF Why testers are our everyday heroes In […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qa/2024/09/celebrate-tester-s-day-with-jetbrains-aqua-50-off/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.40 Is Here With Compose Preview for Android, Inlay Hints for Generating Documentation for PHP and Groovy, and Other Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 07:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.40 is now available! In this release, we’ve introduced some new features while also focusing on many important bug fixes. Your feedback is vital to making Fleet even better. Please report any problems you encounter to our issue tracker, or add a vote to an existing issue to express your support. You can update […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/09/fleet-1-40-is-here-with-compose-preview-for-android-inlay-hints-for-generating-documentation-for-php-and-groovy-and-other-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earning Agentic (and LangChain) Complexity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post examines the challenges of adopting complex technologies like LangChain and agentic solutions in production environments, emphasizing the importance of understanding the necessity of such complexity. It provides insights on how to evaluate these technologies carefully, manage dependencies, and adhere to best practices for secure and stable AI applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/earning-agentic-complexity 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement OpenID Connect Back-Channel Logout using ASP.NET Core, Keycloak and .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 06:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to implement an OpenID Connect back-channel logout using Keycloak, ASP.NET Core and .NET Aspire. The Keycloak and the Redis cache are run as containers using .NET Aspire. Two ASP.NET Core UI applications are used to demonstrate the server logout. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/keycloak-backchannel Setup The applications are run and tested using .NET Aspire. […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/09/09/implement-openid-connect-back-channel-logout-using-asp-net-core-keycloak-and-net-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIMD Accelerated Numeric Types in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 05:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, let’s explore the various SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) accelerated numeric types in .NET. We’ll start by examining what SIMD stands for and how it works in .NET. Then, we’ll look at the different SIMD accelerated numeric types available in .NET. To conclude, we’ll implement a benchmark to compare the performance of […] The post SIMD Accelerated Numeric Types in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the September edition of PHP Annotated! After a brief summer break, we’re back with all things PHP. This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise—we’ve done it for you. Highlights […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/09/php-annotated-september-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Hash Code Generation in .NET: A Performance Comparison</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2024/08_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2024/08_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article discusses the importance of hash codes in programming and optimization techniques in Microsoft .NET. It explores different methods for generating hash codes, with RuntimeHelpers.GetHashCode() identified as the fastest option. The article concludes by introducing a new extension method, FastGetHashCode(), for faster hash code generation in projects.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/09/08/optimizing-hash-code-generation-in-net-a-performance-comparison/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Vidmob is using generative AI to transform its creative data landscape</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 21:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate how Vidmob, a creative data company, worked with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) team to uncover meaningful insights at scale within creative data using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-vidmob-is-using-generative-ai-to-transform-its-creative-data-landscape/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Llama 3 for text generation on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to fine-tune the recently released Llama 3 models from Meta, specifically the llama-3-8b and llama-3-70b variants, using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-llama-3-for-text-generation-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.1-1 and 1.22.7-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds including security fixes is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-1-1-and-1-22-7-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ground truth curation and metric interpretation best practices for evaluating generative AI question answering using FMEval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss best practices for working with Foundation Model Evaluations Library (FMEval) in ground truth curation and metric interpretation for evaluating question answering applications for factual knowledge and quality.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ground-truth-curation-and-metric-interpretation-best-practices-for-evaluating-generative-ai-question-answering-using-fmeval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Graph APIs for Teams town hall now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn more about the general availability of new Teams town hall APIs and discover what&#39;s new.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-graph-apis-for-teams-town-hall-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Need More Gender Diversity in the Cybersecurity Space</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Despite progress in many areas, women are still underrepresented in cybersecurity. To commemorate Women’s Equality Day 2024, we look at key statistics.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-we-need-more-gender-diversity-in-the-cybersecurity-space/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the image that came out horribly slanted: Negative stride</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s all topsy-turvy.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240906-00/?p=110228 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – September 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The September 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include Django test support. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-september-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Docker CEO Scott Johnston at SwampUP 2024 in Austin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Docker and JFrog are enhancing secure software development at SwampUP 2024 in Austin, Texas, from September 9-11. Docker CEO Scott Johnston will highlight the critical roles of Docker Desktop, Docker Hub, and Docker Scout in building secure, efficient applications, showcasing their integration within JFrog’s platform.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/swampup-2024-austin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 12 Podcasts for Java Developers in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 08:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 2024, learning new things as a Java developer has never been easier or more fun! How about kicking off your morning with a cup of coffee while some of the biggest names in the industry chat directly into your ear? Or, imagine being stuck in traffic on your way to work, but instead of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/top-12-podcasts-for-java-developers-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (August 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 22:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.08.23 release, 2024-08-01 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout August. This month’s release includes several notable changes as well as bug fixes and documentation improvements. The most notable changes were: The shell function used to run vcpkg […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build powerful RAG pipelines with LlamaIndex and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 21:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use LlamaIndex with Amazon Bedrock to build robust and sophisticated RAG pipelines that unlock the full potential of LLMs for knowledge-intensive tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-powerful-rag-pipelines-with-llamaindex-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating prompts at scale with Prompt Management and Prompt Flows for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 20:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to implement an automated prompt evaluation system using Amazon Bedrock so you can streamline your prompt development process and improve the overall quality of your AI-generated content.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluating-prompts-at-scale-with-prompt-management-and-prompt-flows-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Vision Buddy – Empowering the Visually Impaired with AI and .NET Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 19:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re featuring a guest author, Jonathan David. He’s written an article we’re sharing below, focused on how to create Vision Buddy to empower visually impaired individuals using .NET and Semantic Kernel. We’ll turn it over to Jonathan to share more! Discover how this proof-of-concept leverages AI using .NET Semantic Kernel to provide visually impaired users […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-vision-buddy-empowering-the-visually-impaired-with-ai-and-net-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Vector Search with DiskANN Part 1: Full Space Search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vector Search with Azure Cosmos DB Azure Cosmos DB NoSQL features advanced vector indexing and search capabilities powered by DiskANN, a suite of highly scalable, accurate, and cost-effective approximate nearest neighbor (ANN) algorithms for low-latency vector search at any scale. Azure Cosmos DB features key capabilities important for building Modern AI applications: A mission critical […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-vector-search-with-diskann-part-1-full-space-search 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 16:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the September release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd). Including remote container build support, multiple hooks per event, deployment stack support, promoting resource group scoped deployments to the Beta feature stage, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-september-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing and Licensing Changes in RustRover and the Rust Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RustRover was initially released without support for web frontend technologies and databases. This decision was primarily based on EAP usage statistics and early research. It also allowed us to price RustRover more competitively. However, after the release, we received a large number of requests from our community asking us to support these technologies. Another piece […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/09/05/pricing-and-licensing-changes-in-rustrover-and-the-rust-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the .NET Migration Trenches - Turning Off the Lights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Posts in this series:IntroCatalogingEmpty ProxyShared LibraryOur First ControllerMigrating Initial Business LogicOur First ViewsSession StateHangfireAuthenticationMiddlewareTurning Off the LightsIn the last post, we looked at migrating our middleware, which we tackle in an as-needed basis. When a controller needs
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/tales-from-the-net-migration-trenches-turning-off-the-lights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Vulnerability scanning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Microsoft 365 Certification validates vulnerability scanning for your application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-vulnerability-scanning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel Trends 2024: The Latest Market Insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we move through 2024, Laravel continues to solidify its position as one of the most popular PHP frameworks, powering a multitude of web applications across the globe. In this blog post, we’ll analyze the recently published State of Laravel 2024 survey results, highlighting key takeaways and what they mean for developers, companies, and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/09/laravel-trends-2024-the-latest-market-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the image that came out horribly slanted: Taking the pitch into account</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Getting the pieces to line up.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240905-00/?p=110224 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily dock and float tool windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 10:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’re in the middle of a debugging session, attempting to chase down that one issue that is causing you trouble. In the heat of the moment, you grab a tool window and drag it out of its docked position – purely by accident. You didn’t mean to drag it, but sometimes when you move the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/easily-dock-and-float-tool-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This edition is packed with the latest news on Java, Kotlin, and other influential technologies in the IT world. Don’t miss out on exploring IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2, staying up to date with Java 23, grabbing your tickets for KotlinConf 2025, and learning about the newest developments […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/java-annotated-monthly-september-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Testing ASP.NET Core Web API With JMeter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 05:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to load test an ASP.NET Core Web API with JMeter. So let’s get going. Introduction to JMeter Load testing is crucial for ensuring that web applications perform well under heavy traffic. JMeter is a popular and robust open-source tool for measuring the performance and functionality of web applications. When […] The post Load Testing ASP.NET Core Web API With JMeter appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
