<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 18:17:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projections, Consistency Models, and Zero Downtime Deployments with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 18:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This content will later be published as a tutorial somewhere on one of our documentation websites. This was originally “just” an article on doing blue/green deployments when using projections with Marten, so hence the two martens up above:) Event Sourcing may not seem that complicated to implement, and you might be tempted to forego any … Continue reading Projections, Consistency Models, and Zero Downtime Deployments with the Critter Stack →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Enterprise Computing: How Agentic AI and Multi-Agent Workflows Are Transforming Business Processes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 17:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enterprise computing is undergoing a radical transformation. As businesses strive to remain competitive in an AI-driven world, a new paradigm is emerging: agentic AI and multi-agent systems. These intelligent, autonomous software agents are not just augmenting workflows—they’re redefining them. In the next five years, multi-agent architectures will become a foundational element of enterprise infrastructure, impacting […] The article Future of Enterprise Computing: How Agentic AI and Multi-Agent Workflows Are Transforming Business Processes was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use BrowserStack App Automate with Appium UI Tests for .NET MAUI Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, learn how to run your Appium UI Tests for .NET MAUI Apps on real devices on the cloud using BrowserStack App Automate.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/browserstack-appium-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Overlapping Secrets on Azure DevOps OAuth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 16:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As you may have read, Azure DevOps OAuth apps are due for deprecation in 2026. All developers are encouraged to migrate their applications to use Microsoft Entra ID OAuth, which can access all Azure DevOps APIs and has the added benefit of enhanced security features and long-term investment. Although we are nearing Azure DevOps OAuth’s […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-overlapping-secrets-on-azure-devops-oauth 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker JumpStart adds fine-tuning support for models in a private model hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 16:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are announcing an enhanced private hub feature with several new capabilities that give organizations greater control over their ML assets. These enhancements include the ability to fine-tune SageMaker JumpStart models directly within the private hub, support for adding and managing custom-trained models, deep linking capabilities for associated notebooks, and improved model version management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-adds-fine-tuning-support-for-models-in-a-private-model-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging with the AI-powered IEnumerable visualizer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of wrestling with complex LINQ queries during debugging? Visual Studio 2022 has introduced powerful new improvement, powered by AI, to simplify your workflow with its editable expression feature in the IEnumerable Visualizer. These added functionalities aim to make debugging more intuitive and efficient, helping you write and refine LINQ queries with ease. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/debugging-with-the-ai-powered-ienumerable-visualizer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI-powered game design: Accelerating early development with Stability AI models on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 14:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has emerged as a game changer, offering unprecedented opportunities for game designers to push boundaries and create immersive virtual worlds. At the forefront of this revolution is Stability AI’s cutting-edge text-to-image AI model, Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large (SD3.5 Large), which is transforming the way we approach game environment creation. In this post, we explore how you can use SD3.5 Large to address practical gaming needs such as early concept art and character design.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve performance and security using Standard Load Balancer and Standard SKU public IP addresses in Azure DevTest Labs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 14:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce preview of enhancements in Azure DevTest Labs designed to accommodate two upcoming retirements in Azure: Retirement Date Details Azure Basic Load Balancer September 30, 2025 The Azure Basic Load Balancer will be retired. You can continue using your existing Basic Load Balancers until this date, but you will not be […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/improve-performance-and-security-using-standard-load-balancer-and-standard-sku-public-ip-addresses-in-azure-devtest-labs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does INVALID_HANDLE_VALUE cast through a LONG_PTR first?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To ensure that the proper sign extension happens.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250326-00/?p=111002 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch Laravel Foundation Meetup at the JetBrains Office</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 13:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this month, we had the pleasure of hosting a community meetup in our Amsterdam office in collaboration with our partner DLF (the Dutch Laravel Foundation). The event brought together Laravel and PHP developers for an evening of technical talks, networking, and knowledge sharing. The Dutch Laravel Foundation is a non-profit organization that works to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/03/dutch-laravel-foundation-meetup-at-the-jetbrains-office/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDE Workspaces Development: Challenges and Plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 11:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a while since we announced workspaces for IntelliJ IDEA – a feature that lets you manage multiple projects in a single IDE window – and we’ve received tons of feedback and made a lot of improvements since then. We see this feature as a tool to improve the developer experience by allowing you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/ide-workspaces-development-challenges-and-plans/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Improving Performance with Count() and LongCount() vs Any()</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Microsoft .NET, checking if an IEnumerable contains items can be done using Count(), LongCount(), or Any(). Despite Microsoft’s recommendation to use Any() for efficiency, benchmarks reveal Count() is faster. For optimal performance, it’s advised to benchmark methods contextually. Resources for further learning and performance optimization are provided.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/26/microsoft-net-code-analysis-improving-performance-with-count-and-longcount-vs-any/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Code C&#43;&#43; Extension Updates: 4x Faster Colorization &amp; 3.5x Faster Project Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 22:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the latest releases of the C++ Extension in Visual Studio Code, we have focused on performance improvements and stability. A fast, responsive, and reliable development environment is essential for maintaining productivity, especially in large and complex C++ projects. These updates include many incremental optimizations that collectively speed up the time from opening a C++ […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/vs-code-c-extension-updates-4x-faster-colorization-3-5x-faster-project-startup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock launches Session Management APIs for generative AI applications (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 22:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock announces the preview launch of Session Management APIs, a new capability that enables developers to simplify state and context management for generative AI applications built with popular open source frameworks such as LangGraph and LlamaIndex. Session Management APIs provide an out-of-the-box solution that enables developers to securely manage state and conversation context across […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-launches-session-management-apis-for-generative-ai-applications-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance deployment guardrails with inference component rolling updates for Amazon SageMaker AI inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 21:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss the challenges faced by organizations when updating models in production. Then we deep dive into the new rolling update feature for inference components and provide practical examples using DeepSeek distilled models to demonstrate this feature. Finally, we explore how to set up rolling updates in different scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-deployment-guardrails-with-inference-component-rolling-updates-for-amazon-sagemaker-ai-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commands or Events: Which One for Workflow?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 20:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So, you’re building a system around business processes and workflows. Great! But where does the code go that has to orchestrate all this? This is a common question I’ve received, especially from members of my channel on our private Discord. Let’s dive into the guidelines on process managers, bounded contexts, and clever ways to collocate… Read More »Commands or Events: Which One for Workflow? The post Commands or Events: Which One for Workflow?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your CMake Development with Copilot Custom Instructions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 17:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Creating a new CMake project that uses unfamiliar libraries can be daunting and time-consuming. This blog post takes you along on my journey using Copilot to make this easier, and leveraging Custom Instructions to tailor Copilot responses. For a sneak peek, see the outcome of this journey in this repository. Background As C++ developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/boost-your-cmake-development-with-copilot-custom-instructions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring new .NET releases with Dev Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to set up and use dev containers for experimenting with new .NET releases.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-in-dev-container 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Ways to Empower Engineering Teams to Balance Productivity, Security, and Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how Docker’s suite of products empowers industry leaders and their development teams to innovate faster, stay secure, and deliver impactful results.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/empower-engineering-teams-to-balance-productivity-security-innovation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate and improve performance of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to evaluate the performance of your knowledge base, including the metrics and data to use for evaluation. We also address some of the tactics and configuration changes that can improve specific metrics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-and-improve-performance-of-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance enterprise productivity for your LLM solution by becoming an Amazon Q Business data accessor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to enhance enterprise productivity for your large language model (LLM) solution by using the Amazon Q index for ISVs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-enterprise-productivity-for-your-llm-solution-by-becoming-an-amazon-q-business-data-accessor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the winners of the 2025 Powerful Devs Hack Together</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2025 Powerful Devs Hack Together brought developers together to build secure and scalable AI-powered solutions using Power Platform, Azure, AI Builder, and more. If you missed the event, you can still catch up on all the sessions covering AI, automation, security, extensibility, and more! 🎥 Watch here: aka.ms/powerfuldevs/ondemand Technologies Used in the Hackathon We […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-the-winners-of-the-2025-powerful-devs-hack-together 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We’ll fly you to Atlanta, Texas, and getting to your hotel in Atlanta, Georgia is your problem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reading the fine print.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250325-01/?p=110995 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note on the USB-to-PS/2 mouse adapter that came with Microsoft mouse devices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s a purely mechanical adapter that relies on smarts in the mouse itself.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250325-00/?p=110993 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn JavaScript This Week: Start Your Web Applications Journey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JavaScript is the backbone of modern web development, powering dynamic websites and creating interactive user experiences. It’s an essential programming language, whether you’re just starting out or already an experienced developer. JetBrains Academy’s new free course, Introduction to JavaScript, provides a clear and structured approach to mastering JavaScript quickly and effectively. Why learn JavaScript? Why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/03/25/course-javascript/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core delegated Microsoft OBO access token management (Entra only)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 12:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog shows how to implement a delegated Microsoft On-Behalf-Of flow in ASP.NET Core, and has a focus on access token management. The solution uses Microsoft.Identity.Web to implement the different flows and it really simple to implement, when you know how to use the Nuget package and use the correct Microsoft documentation. The application can […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/03/25/asp-net-core-delegated-microsoft-obo-access-token-management-entra-only/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding EF Core Change Tracking: How It Works Under the Hood</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:16:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core (EF Core) makes data handling easy. We all are leveraging its conciseness, flexibility, and rich features in our projects. However, have you ever wondered what goes under the hood? How has EF Core detached us from SQL queries? Today, I will disclose the curtain behind EF Core
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-ef-core-change-tracking-how-it-works-under-the-hood/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending Claude with External Tools: MCPs in Action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 09:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Model Context Protocol (MCP) breaks through Claude&#39;s knowledge limitations by enabling real-time web search and external tool integration through the desktop application.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/extend-claude-model-context-protocol/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a software bill of materials (SBOM) for an open-source NuGet package</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss several tools you can use to create a software bill of materials (SBOM) for an application or a NuGet package
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-software-bill-of-materials-sbom-for-an-open-source-nuget-package/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: An In-Depth Look at CallerMemberName (and some Compile-Time trivia)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s dive deep into the CallerMemberName attribute and explore its usage from multiple angles. We’ll see various methods of invoking it, shedding light on how it is defined at compile time.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/callermembername-attribute/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2503.24: misc bug fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2503.24, which can be downloaded here. This release includes everything in the previous 2501.30 release, plus the following bug fixes: Fix capture-time crash introduced in 2501.30 in CPU write tracking code Fix capture-time issue with reserved resources, that could cause replay-time corruption for some UE5 captures Fix PIXBeginCapture() deadlocking for Timing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2503-24 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Substantial Wolverine 3.11 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Critter Stack community just made a pretty big Wolverine 3.11 release earlier today with 5 brand new contributors making their first pull requests! The highlights are: Wolverine 4.0 is also under way, but there will be at least some Wolverine.HTTP improvements in the 3.* branch before we get to 4.0. Big thanks to the … Continue reading Pretty Substantial Wolverine 3.11 Release →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/03/24/pretty-substantial-wolverine-3-11-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IngressNightmare: Critical Zero-Day Kubernetes Vulnerabilities Put Thousands of Clusters at Risk (March 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A set of ‘critical’ zero-day vulnerabilities, collectively named IngressNightmare, have been discovered in the widely used Ingress-NGINX Controller for Kubernetes that can result in a ‘full takeover‘ of a Kubernetes cluster! These flaws expose over 6,500 publicly exposed clusters to the risk of unauthenticated remote code execution (RCE) and privilege escalation, putting sensitive data and […] The article IngressNightmare: Critical Zero-Day Kubernetes Vulnerabilities Put Thousands of Clusters at Risk (March 2025) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Conf 2025: Learn, Build, and Connect with the Community</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for the 5th annual Azure Cosmos DB Conf, a free virtual developer event co-hosted by Microsoft and the Azure Cosmos DB community. This is your opportunity to learn from Microsoft product managers, industry experts, and real-world customers who are building applications with Azure Cosmos DB. This year, we received over 100 session proposals […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-conf-2025-learn-build-and-connect-with-the-community 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xbox &#43; .NET Aspire: Transforming Local Development Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how the Xbox services team leveraged .NET Aspire to boost their team&#39;s productivity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/xboxs-usage-of-aspire-transforming-development-practices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: API Interaction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog posts (1,2), we created integration tests that interact with UI components and assert different properties of UI components. However, sometimes we need to check the internal state of our plugin or invoke some method to simplify or speed up the test and avoid too many UI interactions. Let’s explore exactly how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/03/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-api-interaction/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure APIs with Data API Builder, Keycloak, and SQL Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore how to create a secure, on-premises API using Data API Builder (DAB), Keycloak, and SQL Server. You’ll learn to set up JSON Web Token (JWT) authentication with Role-Based Access Control (RBAC), Attribute-Based Access Control (ABAC), and Row-Level Security (RLS), ideal for secure business scenarios. Want to replicate this setup?All the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/secure-apis-with-data-api-builder-keycloak-and-sql-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: New Releases, OpenAI vs. DeepSeek, and Compose Hot Reload</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, Kotlin fans! Kodee’s back with another roundup of the latest updates and stories from the Kotlin world. Grab your favorite drink, sit back, and enjoy! Kotlin YouTube spotlight Check out our latest YouTube videos and Shorts – sit back, relax, and enjoy!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/03/kodee-s-kotlin-roundup-new-releases-openai-vs-deepseek-and-compose-hot-reload/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Visual Studio Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Visual Studio Hub is here! Keeping up with the latest Visual Studio updates, features, and resources can feel like a full-time job. We’ve heard it time and time again—you want a simpler way to stay informed without digging through scattered blog posts, release notes, and social media updates. That’s why we created Visual Studio […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-hub 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code update – March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the latest updates for Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code featuring tenant switching, new capabilities for declarative agents, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/teams-toolkit-for-visual-studio-code-update-march-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On how different Windows ABIs choose how to pass 32-bit values in 64-bit registers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Surveying the options and looking for commonalities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250324-00/?p=110988 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable continuous backup for multi-region write account</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB already delivers 99.999% availability with multi-region write capability and continuous backup for point-in-time restores within a 7 or 30 day retention period. Now, we’re making it even better! Going forward – You can migrate existing single region write region with point in time restore capability to support multi-region write. You can enable […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/enable-continuous-backup-for-multi-region-write-account 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose the Right LLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant is now multimodel! This is an exciting development, but what does it actually mean for you? It means AI Assistant is now more adaptable. It combines the strengths of different AI models, from the deep reasoning of large ones to the speed of compact ones, and even the privacy of local ones. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/how-to-choose-the-right-llm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment l’IA générative impacte-t-elle l’expérience développeur?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 07:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adlene Sifi explore l’impact de l’IA générative sur l’expérience des développeurs. Dans cet article, nous allons tenter de déterminer s’il existe un lien entre l’utilisation de l’IA générative (ex. : GitHub Copilot) et l’expérience développeur (DevEx). Nous souhaitons vérifier plus précisément si l’utilisation de l’IA générative a un impact positif sur l’expérience développeur. Nous tenterons même […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/comment-lia-generative-impacte-t-elle-lexperience-developpeur 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does generative AI impact Developer Experience?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 07:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adlene Sifi explores the impact of generative AI on developer experience. In this article, we will try to determine if there is a link between the use of generative AI (e.g., GitHub Copilot) and developer experience (DevEx). Specifically, we aim to verify whether the use of generative AI has a positive impact on developer experience. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/how-does-generative-ai-impact-developer-experience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify StringBuilder Usage with Spargine’s StringBuilderExtensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_03_2025/23_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_03_2025/23_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a collection of open-source assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, created by the author since .NET 2&#39;s launch. The StringBuilderExtensions enhance StringBuilder&#39;s performance and usability, featuring methods for efficient data appending.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/23/boost-your-net-projects-simplify-stringbuilder-usage-with-spargines-stringbuilderextensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is SAST? A Guide to Static Application Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is brought to you by Thinus Swart, draft.dev. Static application security testing (SAST) is a method for identifying vulnerabilities in application source code, binaries, or bytecode early in the software development lifecycle (SDLC). By analyzing code before it’s compiled or run, SAST allows developers to catch potential security flaws before they can be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/what-is-sast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vibe Coding - Dev Leader Weekly 88</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the hot topic of Vibe Coding and what it means for you!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/22/vibe-coding-dev-leader-weekly-88 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Code Analysis in STEM: Protecting Work That Affects the World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 08:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Qodana, we champion code quality for businesses and enterprise development teams, but it has other crucial applications, and implications. Not only can good (and bad!) code be felt in the digital products we all know and use every day, but its impact also extends to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM). As STEM disciplines […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/03/code-analysis-in-stem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-03-21</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 04:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/22/weekly-recap-20250321 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Pattern Validation in ASP.NET Core With FluentValidation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Elevate your ASP.NET Core configuration with FluentValidation integration that catches configuration errors at startup, preventing silent failures and runtime exceptions with more expressive validation rules than Data Annotations.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/options-pattern-validation-in-aspnetcore-with-fluentvalidation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Model Context Protocol (MCP) in Azure AI Foundry: Create an MCP Server with Azure AI Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 22:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to integrate Azure AI Foundry&#39;s Agent Service with Claude Desktop using the Model Context Protocol (MCP) for powerful integration for MCP clients.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/integrating-azure-ai-agents-mcp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI enabled virtual IT troubleshooting assistant using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how to build a GenAI powered virtual IT troubleshooting assistant using Amazon Q Business. This innovative solution integrates with popular ITSM tools like ServiceNow, Atlassian Jira, and Confluence to streamline information retrieval and enhance collaboration across your organization. By harnessing the power of generative AI, this assistant can significantly boost operational efficiency and provide 24/7 support tailored to individual needs. Learn how to set up, configure, and leverage this solution to transform your enterprise information management.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process formulas and charts with Anthropic’s Claude on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how you can use these multi-modal generative AI models to streamline the management of technical documents. By extracting and structuring the key information from the source materials, the models can create a searchable knowledge base that allows you to quickly locate the data, formulas, and visualizations you need to support your work.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/process-formulas-and-charts-with-anthropics-claude-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate IT operations with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a comprehensive AIOps solution that combines various AWS services such as Amazon Bedrock, AWS Lambda, and Amazon CloudWatch to create an AI assistant for effective incident management. This solution also uses Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon Bedrock Agents. The solution uses the power of Amazon Bedrock to enable the deployment of intelligent agents capable of monitoring IT systems, analyzing logs and metrics, and invoking automated remediation processes.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removal of Deprecated SharePoint &amp; OneDrive Permission Resource Properties</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 15:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are announcing the phased rollout of an update to remove the grantedTo and grantedToIdentities properties from the Permission resource type in Microsoft Graph.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/removal-of-deprecated-sharepoint-onedrive-permission-resource-properties 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the critical section that let multiple threads enter a block of code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It had one job.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250321-00/?p=110984 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.47 Is Here With Folding Support for Multiline Comments, New AI Chat Functionality, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 13:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using our Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.47 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2025/03/fleet-1-47-is-here-with-folding-support-for-multiline-comments-new-ai-chat-functionality-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign Up for the free Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2025 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 11:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every year we run Pure Virtual C++: a free one-day virtual conference for the whole C++ community. Next month we’re doing it again! Sign-up for free to get access to our five live sessions and a host of pre-conference content. The live event will start at April 30th 14:00 UTC. Videos will be available to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/sign-up-for-the-free-pure-virtual-c-2025-conference 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Azure AI Foundry Blog!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the Azure AI Foundry Blog—your essential guide to building, customizing, and scaling AI solutions with Microsoft’s open and modular AI platform.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/welcome-to-azure-ai-foundry-blog 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Java, JS and Python support in Test Plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce new capabilities in Azure Test Plans that will enhance your testing workflows. This feature is currently available in Public Preview. You can find instructions at the end of the article on how to request it for your Azure DevOps project. With this latest release, we are introducing the ability to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/introducing-java-javascript-and-python-support-in-azuredevops-test-plans 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>引入对SLNX的支持，.NET CLI 中更简洁的解决方案文件格式</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Chet Husk的Introducing support for SLNX, a new, simpler solution file format in the .NET CLI 多年来，解决方案文件已成为 .NET 和 Visual Studio 体验中的一部分，并且它们一直拥有相同的自定义格式。最近，Visual Studio 解决方案团队已开始预览一种新的基于 XML 格式的解决方案文件格式，称为 SLNX。从 .NET SDK 9.0.200 开始，dotnet CLI 支持生成这些文件并与之交互，其方式与使用现有解决方案文件的方式相同。在本文的其余部分，我们将展示如何迁移到新格式，探索 dotnet CLI 对该格式的新支持，并讨论该格式走向正式发布的后续计划。 快速开始 在 SDK 9.0.200 之前，创建 SLNX 文件的唯一方式是通过 Visual Studio 设置。勾选 环境 &amp;gt; 预览功能 &amp;gt; 使用解决方案文件持久性模型 设置后，用户可以将现有的 .sln 文件另存为新的 .slnx 格式。 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e5%bc%95%e5%85%a5%e5%af%b9slnx%e7%9a%84%e6%94%af%e6%8c%81%ef%bc%8c-net-cli-%e4%b8%ad%e6%9b%b4%e7%ae%80%e6%b4%81%e7%9a%84%e8%a7%a3%e5%86%b3%e6%96%b9%e6%a1%88%e6%96%87%e4%bb%b6%e6%a0%bc%e5%bc%8f 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Performance Gains in .NET: Evaluating the ‘in’ Modifier for Method Parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The in modifier, introduced in C# 9.0, allows passing read-only references to method parameters, promoting immutability. While it clarifies intent it can also enhance performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/21/unlock-performance-gains-in-net-evaluating-the-in-modifier-for-method-parameters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing DirectX Raytracing 1.2, PIX, Neural Rendering and more at GDC 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 21:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today in the DirectX State of the Union at GDC 2025, we proudly showcased the next evolution in graphics with the announcement of DirectX Raytracing (DXR) 1.2. This update promises groundbreaking performance improvements and breathtaking visual fidelity, marking another milestone in our mission to deliver immersive, realistic experiences to gamers everywhere. We also brought developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/announcing-directx-raytracing-1-2-pix-neural-rendering-and-more-at-gdc-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline AWS resource troubleshooting with Amazon Bedrock Agents and AWS Support Automation Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS provides a powerful tool called AWS Support Automation Workflows, which is a collection of curated AWS Systems Manager self-service automation runbooks. These runbooks are created by AWS Support Engineering with best practices learned from solving customer issues. They enable AWS customers to troubleshoot, diagnose, and remediate common issues with their AWS resources. In this post, we explore how to use the power of Amazon Bedrock Agents and AWS Support Automation Workflows to create an intelligent agent capable of troubleshooting issues with AWS resources.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create generative AI agents that interact with your companies’ systems in a few clicks using Amazon Bedrock in Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock in SageMaker Unified Studio to build a generative AI application to integrate with an existing endpoint and database.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-generative-ai-agents-that-interact-with-your-companies-systems-in-a-few-clicks-using-amazon-bedrock-in-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asure’s approach to enhancing their call center experience using generative AI and Amazon Q in Quicksight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore why Asure used the Amazon Web Services (AWS) post-call analytics (PCA) pipeline that generated insights across call centers at scale with the advanced capabilities of generative AI-powered services such as Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Q in QuickSight. Asure chose this approach because it provided in-depth consumer analytics, categorized call transcripts around common themes, and empowered contact center leaders to use natural language to answer queries. This ultimately allowed Asure to provide its customers with improvements in product and customer experiences.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the multimodal power of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation to transform unstructured data into actionable insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re excited to announce the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation, a powerful, fully managed capability within Amazon Bedrock that seamlessly transforms unstructured multimodal data into structured, application-ready insights with high accuracy, cost efficiency, and scalability.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleashing-the-multimodal-power-of-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-to-transform-unstructured-data-into-actionable-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Box roadmap update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What features and enhancements are planned for Microsoft Dev Box Microsoft Dev Box continues to evolve, providing a secure, scalable, and ready-to-code cloud-based development environment. Over the next few months, significant improvements will focus on three key areas: Ready-to-code environments: Faster setup, enhanced debugging, and GitHub Copilot integration to streamline developer workflows. Developers will benefit […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/microsoft-dev-box-roadmap-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in TeamCity 2025.03: Recipes, Improved Docker and Podman Integration, UI Updates, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity’s first major release of the year, version 2025.03, is now available. It’s packed with new features, including massive UI updates, a new Run in Docker build feature, and JetBrains-crafted recipes available in our Marketplace. UI updates In line with our commitment to make TeamCity easier and more intuitive to use, this release introduces significant […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/teamcity-2025-03-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Data at rest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how Microsoft 365 Certification ensures compliance for data at rest.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-data-at-rest 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforcement of license checks for PSTN Bot calls</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of Microsoft’s feature parity with Teams Phone extensibility, we’re announcing the enforcement of Phone System license checks for Bot-initiated transfers to Teams users. This current gap in our systems will be addressed in June 2025. Microsoft Teams requires that Teams users behind applications such as queue applications require a phone system license and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/enforcement-of-license-checks-for-pstn-bot-calls 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Pull Request Reviews with In-Depth Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 has taken the pull request experience to the next level by making reviews interactive. We previously enabled viewing your pull request comments inline in your working files. Now, the latest update empowers you to add comments directly within the IDE, streamlining the review process. Now, pull request reviewers can conduct deep reviews […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/enhance-pull-request-reviews-with-in-depth-feedback 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What could cause a memory corruption bug to disappear in safe mode?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A simplified execution environment means fewer things that you can stumble over.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250320-00/?p=110981 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.1.20 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 11:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.1.20 release is out! This version includes performance improvements and bug fixes for Kotlin 2.1.0. Here are some highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.1.20 or the release notes on GitHub. How to install Kotlin 2.1.20 Starting from IntelliJ IDEA 2023.3 and Android […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/03/kotlin-2-1-20-released 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Risks of Docker Build Time Arguments and How to Secure Your Secrets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses the security risks of using Docker build-time arguments to pass secrets, and suggests alternative methods for handling secrets securely.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/hidden-risks-of-docker-build-time-arguments-and-how-to-secure-your-secrets 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
