<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 09:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Caching with Aspect-Oriented Programming and Metalama in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Introduction: Simplifying Caching with Aspect-Oriented Programming in .NET Aspect-Oriented Programming (AOP) offers elegant solutions for handling cross-cutting concerns in our .NET applications, such as method caching. In a previous article on GoatReview 🐐, we explored using Fody to implement a caching aspect. Although powerful, this tool presents significant challenges. Link to article: https://goatreview.com/simplifying-caching-with-aop-metalama/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s UlidGenerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages created for efficient ULID generation, combining randomness with alphabetical sorting. ULIDs are compact, sortable identifiers offering uniqueness for distributed systems. The UlidGenerator class provides methods for generating ULIDs.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/05/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-ulidgenerator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in .NET 9: System.Text.Json improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 08:38:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 9 is releasing in mid-November 2024. Like every .NET version, this introduces several important features and enhancements aligning developers with an ever-changing development ecosystem. In this blog series, I will explore critical updates in different areas of .NET. For this post, I will look through advancements in System.Text.
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/whats-new-in-net-9-system-text-json-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davide&#39;s Code and Architecture Notes - the Error Management Trio, and how it affects your software architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When designing a software system, we naturally focus more on the happy flow. But we should carefully plan to handle errors that fall into three categories: Validation, Transient, and Fatal.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/error-management-trio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GitHub Copilot in Data Wrangler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI did not write this blog post, but it will make your exploratory data analysis with Data Wrangler better! Today, we’re excited to introduce our first step of integrating the power of Copilot into Data Wrangler. With this first integration of Copilot with Data Wrangler, you’ll be able to: Use natural language to clean and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/announcing-github-copilot-in-data-wrangler 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSF Scorecard for .NET and the NuGet ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 17:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenSSF Scorecard is a tool developed by the Open Source Security Foundation (OpenSSF) that provides automated security assessments for open-source projects. The primary goal of the Scorecard project is to help developers and users determine the security posture of open-source software by generating a score based on a series of security-related checks. Using Scorecard, developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/nuget/openssf-scorecard-for-net-nuget 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.35: Organization Access Tokens, Docker Home, Volumes Export, and Terminal in Docker Desktop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.35 includes organization access tokens, a new Docker product home page, terminal enhancements, Docker Desktop for Red Hat Enterprise Linux, and improved performance on macOS.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-35/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wow! It’s easy to take the rapid pace of technological advancement for granted, especially given how many of us have been tech-natives for most of our lives. For Mac lovers, Infinite Mac takes a trip across the decades of the 1980s to 2000s through the lens of releases. Experience history all in your browser. Draw […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/04/dotinsights-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Chat History for Large Language Models (LLMs)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large Language Models (LLMs) operate with a defined limit on the number of tokens they can process at once, referred to as the context window. Exceeding this limit can have significant cost and performance implications. Therefore, it is essential to manage the size of the input sent to the LLM, particularly when using chat completion models. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/managing-chat-history-for-large-language-models-llms 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The making of Bring Back Plus/Minus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 15:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A lesson about the software forensics process involved in developing the Bring Back Plus/Minus extension, which brings back the plus/minus symbols to the editor outlining feature in Visual Studio 2022. While I did have the advantage of being able to look at the Visual Studio source code, I could have figured this out just as well without […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/the-making-of-bring-back-plus-minus 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the limits of time travel in the face of undefined behavior in C</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C imposes some constraints, but the principle is mostly still there.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241104-00/?p=110466 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Docker Desktop: How Signing In Unlocks Advanced Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Signing into Docker Desktop unlocks advanced features and integrations, enabling developers and admins to fully leverage Docker’s cloud-native tools for enhanced productivity, security, and scalability.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/maximizing-docker-desktop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AI Tools to Convert a PDF into Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to turn a PDF into a bunch of images with the help of Docker and AI tools.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/using-ai-tools-to-convert-a-pdf-into-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dobar Dan! Algorithm and Code Training School Heads to Serbia This Winter!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the beginning of 2025, the Algorithm and Code Training School (ACTS) camp is moving to an exciting new location – Serbia! While our summer camp in Romania was a great success, we’re taking things to the next level with an even more intensive competition format. This camp is perfect for young coders aiming to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/11/04/dobar-dan-algorithm-and-code-training-school-heads-to-serbia-this-winter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Full-Stack App With Go and React</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a language that emerged over 14 years ago, Go has many use cases. From web development, APIs, and CLIs to Wasm, cloud technologies, and even AI-powered tools, its applications are broad. The same goes for demo projects, which have countless variations and purposes! Now, wouldn’t it be great if there was a full-stack, API-oriented, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/11/04/create-a-full-stack-app-with-go-and-react/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Build GraphQL Services With Spring Boot Like Netflix</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Netflix Staff Engineer, Paul Bakker, to discover how Netflix implements GraphQL services with Spring Boot and the DGS framework. Date: November 14, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Netflix uses GraphQL and the DGS framework (recently fully integrated with Spring […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.22 with improved checking minimal API permissions and logging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 07:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share with you a new version of Dev Proxy that helps you build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-22-with-improved-checking-minimal-api-permissions-and-logging 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core and Angular BFF using a YARP downstream API protected using certificate authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article demonstrates how to implement a downstream API protected by certificate authentication using Microsoft YARP reverse proxy in an ASP.NET Core web application. The application uses Angular for its UI and secures both the UI and the ASP.NET Core backend through a backend-for-frontend security architecture. The downstream API is secured with certificate authentication and […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/11/04/asp-net-core-and-angular-bff-using-a-yarp-downstream-api-protected-using-certificate-authentication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Negotiation in an ASP.NET Core Minimal API Using Carter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll examine how to implement content negotiation in an ASP.NET Core Minimal API. Since there are several ways to implement content negotiation in .NET APIs, we’ll briefly discuss the different approaches and tradeoffs for each. Let’s focus on the ASP.NET Core Minimal API and then use the Carter library to make our […] The post Content Negotiation in an ASP.NET Core Minimal API Using Carter appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 中System.Text.Json 的新增功能</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 01:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Eirik Tsarpalis的 What’s new in System.Text.Json in .NET 9 – .NET Blog System.Text.Json的9.0 版本包含许多功能，主要侧重于 JSON 架构和智能应用程序支持。它还包括一些备受期待的增强功能，例如可空引用类型支持、自定义枚举成员名称、无序元数据反序列化和自定义序列化缩进。 获取最新信息 您可以通过引用 System.Text.Json NuGet 包的最新版本或 .NET 9 的最新 SDK 来尝试新功能。 JSON 架构导出器 新的 JsonSchemaExporter 类可以使用 JsonSerializerOptions 或 JsonTypeInfo 实例从 .NET 类型中提取 JSON 架构文档： using System.Text.Json.Schema; JsonSerializerOptions options = JsonSerializerOptions.Default; JsonNode schema = options.GetJsonSchemaAsNode(typeof(Person)); Console.WriteLine(schema.ToString()); //{ // &amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;object&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;null&amp;quot;], // […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/net-9-%e4%b8%adsystem-text-json-%e7%9a%84%e6%96%b0%e5%a2%9e%e5%8a%9f%e8%83%bd 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Round Trips are Evil, So Batch Your Queries When You Can</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 18:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software frequently helps our customers wring better performance or scalability out of our customer’s systems. A somewhat frequent opportunity for improving the responsiveness and throughput of systems is merely identifying ways to batch up requests from middle tier, server side code to the backing database or databases. There’s a certain amount of overhead in … Continue reading Network Round Trips are Evil, So Batch Your Queries When You Can →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Enum Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source collection of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, created and managed by the author since .NET 2 release. It includes the EnumExtensions class with utility methods for Enum types, such as GetDescription(), GetItems(), and Parse().
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/03/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-enum-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Memory of Stiver</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 13:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On October 20, the original author of the Fernflower Java decompiler, Stiver, passed away after a long fight against glioblastoma. Stiver was a German programmer of Russian origin, primarily developing software for medical equipment. Twenty years ago, he developed a deep professional interest in Java virtual machine internals. You may remember his research blog posts, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/in-memory-of-stiver/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Timezones WRECKED Me! – Dev Leader Weekly 68</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How Timezones WRECKED Me! – Dev Leader Weekly 68 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss fixing an issue in production is WAY harder than just following a tutorial on a happy path. The post How Timezones WRECKED Me! – Dev Leader Weekly 68 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/11/02/how-timezones-wrecked-me-dev-leader-weekly-68/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Architecture: The Missing Chapter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Clean Architecture&#39;s famous diagram is often misinterpreted as a project structure, leading developers to create artificial technical layers that scatter business logic across their codebase. Learn what the diagram really means and how to properly organize your code around business capabilities using components and clear boundaries.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/clean-architecture-the-missing-chapter 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and lessons for fine-tuning Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 21:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the best practices and lessons learned for fine-tuning Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku on Amazon Bedrock. We discuss the important components of fine-tuning, including use case definition, data preparation, model customization, and performance evaluation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-and-lessons-for-fine-tuning-anthropics-claude-3-haiku-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track, allocate, and manage your generative AI cost and usage with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 19:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock has launched a capability that organizations can use to tag on-demand models and monitor associated costs. Organizations can now label all Amazon Bedrock models with AWS cost allocation tags, aligning usage to specific organizational taxonomies such as cost centers, business units, and applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/track-allocate-and-manage-your-generative-ai-cost-and-usage-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance environmental sustainability in clinical trials using AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to use AWS to support a decentralized clinical trial across the four main pillars of a decentralized clinical trial (virtual trials, personalized patient engagement, patient-centric trial design, and centralized data management). By exploring these AWS powered alternatives, we aim to demonstrate how organizations can drive progress towards more environmentally friendly clinical research practices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advance-environmental-sustainability-in-clinical-trials-using-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Team at CppCon 2024: Trip Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft C++ team attended CppCon, the largest C++ conference in the world. This year, the conference was held in Aurora, Colorado from September 16-20. Microsoft Booth Our team managed a booth from Monday to Thursday of the week. This gave us an amazing opportunity to interact with the C++ community and discuss many topics […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/microsoft-c-team-at-cppcon-2024-trip-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – November 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The November 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include docstring template generation with Pylance, Fold/Unfold All Docstrings commands, a variable view with the Native REPL and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-november-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Performance of the “Proxy” Library</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article analyzes the performance of the &amp;quot;Proxy&amp;quot; library in various scenarios, demonstrating its significant advantages in indirect invocations and lifetime management across different platforms.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/analyzing-the-performance-of-the-proxy-library 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Q to find answers on Google Drive in an enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post covers the steps to configure the Amazon Q Business Google Drive connector, including authentication setup and verifying the secure indexing of your Google Drive content.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-q-to-find-answers-on-google-drive-in-an-enterprise/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Druva used Amazon Bedrock to address foundation model complexity when building Dru, Druva’s backup AI copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Druva enables cyber, data, and operational resilience for thousands of enterprises, and is trusted by 60 of the Fortune 500. In this post, we show how Druva approached natural language querying (NLQ)—asking questions in English and getting tabular data as answers—using Amazon Bedrock, the challenges they faced, sample prompts, and key learnings.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-druva-used-amazon-bedrock-to-address-foundation-model-complexity-when-building-dru-druvas-backup-ai-copilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AWS Bedrock with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the principal features of Semantic Kernel is its ability to integrate various AI services seamlessly. We are pleased to announce that this capability now extends to AWS Bedrock. With AWS Bedrock, you can access foundational models such as the Amazon Titan models. The new connector supports Chat Completion, Text Generation, and Text Embeddings, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/introducing-aws-bedrock-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Blogs for Experienced Programmers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following up on our previous article in which we shared some great multi-author blogs to follow, today we have a curated selection of personal blogs from top Java experts. These experts aren’t just the best at what they do – they’re also great at sharing their knowledge in ways that are easy to understand and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/top-java-blogs-for-experienced-programmers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft JDConf 2025: Building the future with Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Technology is advancing faster than ever, and developers are leading the charge, driving digital transformation and reshaping businesses everywhere. With the rise of AI and cloud-native architectures, Java developers are uniquely positioned to shape the future of enterprise applications. Java remains one of the most widely used programming languages globally, with 45% of developers actively […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/microsoft-jdconf-2025-building-the-future-with-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive AI at Microsoft Ignite 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Ignite 2024 is almost here! This year the in-person conference will be held in Chicago Illinois USA November 19th – 22nd and the Semantic Kernel team will be on site answering questions and sharing best practices and if you can’t attend in-person you can also sign up for free and watch it online or […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/productive-ai-at-microsoft-ignite-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Faster with dotNetTips.com Spargine 8: November 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine 8 was released on November 1st, 2024, featuring significant updates including NuGet packages for .NET 8. The update enhances performance with new utilities like TempFileManager, UlidGenerator, and improved JSON deserialization. Users are encouraged to explore these features and contribute feedback or suggestions to further enhance the project.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/01/coding-faster-with-dotnettips-com-spargine-8-november-2024-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On locale-aware substring matching, either case-sensitive or case-insensitive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s surprisingly complicated, but fortunately, somebody has done it for you.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241101-00/?p=110447 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allow your customers to access your copilots by integrating Copilot Studio with Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to securely integrate Microsoft Entra External ID with Copilot-powered applications in this step-by-step tutorial. Using the Generic OAuth 2.0 service provider in Copilot Studio, this guide shows you how to grant customers seamless access to your AI copilots.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/integrate-copilot-studio-with-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a generative AI–powered custom Google Chat application using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS offers powerful generative AI services, including Amazon Bedrock, which allows organizations to create tailored use cases such as AI chat-based assistants that give answers based on knowledge contained in the customers’ documents, and much more. Many businesses want to integrate these cutting-edge AI capabilities with their existing collaboration tools, such as Google Chat, to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-generative-ai-powered-custom-google-chat-application-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights from Gmail using the Gmail connector for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A number of organizations use Gmail for their business email needs. Gmail for business is part of Google Workspace, which provides a set of productivity and collaboration tools like Google Drive, Gmail, and Google Calendar. Google Drive supports storing documents such as Emails contain a wealth of information found in different places, such as within […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-from-gmail-using-the-gmail-connector-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate custom labeling workflows in Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth without using AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth enables the creation of high-quality, large-scale training datasets, essential for fine-tuning across a wide range of applications, including large language models (LLMs) and generative AI. By integrating human annotators with machine learning, SageMaker Ground Truth significantly reduces the cost and time required for data labeling. Whether it’s annotating images, videos, or […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-custom-labeling-workflows-in-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-without-using-aws-lambda/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>세계로 뻗어갑니다: “G3J Learn Semantic Kernel” 쇼 – 한국어로 배우는 Semantic Kernel!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 17:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            세계로 뻗어갑니다: “G3J Learn Semantic Kernel” 쇼 – 한국어로 배우는 Semantic Kernel! https://aka.ms/g3jlearnsk/live/ep01 다국어 컨텐츠 관련 수요가 늘어나고 있습니다 다국어로 Semantic Kernel 관련 내용을 방송한 이후, 개발자들 사이에서 현지화한 콘텐츠에 대한 수요가 크게 증가한 것을 확인했습니다. 각 지역의 개발자들이 Semantic Kernel에 대해 더 깊이 배우고자 하는 열정을 보여주었고, 이를 반영하여 저희는 다양한 언어로 더욱 심층적인 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/%ec%84%b8%ea%b3%84%eb%a1%9c-%eb%bb%97%ec%96%b4%ea%b0%91%eb%8b%88%eb%8b%a4-g3j-learn-semantic-kernel-%ec%87%bc-%ed%95%9c%ea%b5%ad%ec%96%b4%eb%a1%9c-%eb%b0%b0%ec%9a%b0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of GitHub Models in .NET with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how to integrate GitHub&#39;s AI models, like GPT, Llama and Phi, into your .NET apps using Microsoft&#39;s Semantic Kernel for intelligent applications
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/github-ai-models-dotnet-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – October Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve got Halloween updates just for you! The JetBrains Academy team has brewed up a cauldron of October goodies, including new events, webinars, Git videos, courses, and contests for students with spooktacular prizes!🎃
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/10/31/jetbrains-academy-october-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new for Microsoft 365 Copilot developer tooling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 15:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how declarative agents, now generally available, can quickly and easily integrate your enterprise data securely with Microsoft 365 Copilot.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/whats-new-for-microsoft-365-copilot-developer-tooling 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Business continuity and disaster recovery planning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how Microsoft 365 Certification verifies business continuity and disaster recovery plans are in place.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-business-continuity-and-disaster-recovery-planning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – October 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the October edition of PHP Annotated! This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise—we’ve done it for you. Highlights PHP 8.4 RC3 is available for testing Release managers Calvin Buckley, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/10/php-annotated-october-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What has case distinction but is neither uppercase nor lowercase?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It has one foot in each world but belongs to neither.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241031-00/?p=110443 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Your Workflow in IntelliJ IDEA’s Database Tools With AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 13:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In IntelliJ IDEA, you can leverage AI Assistant’s capabilities within Database Tools for more efficient data querying and handling. It can significantly speed up SQL query generation, explain code, suggest fixes, and even create tables and populate them with test data on your command! Let’s get started! Get IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate To enable the AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/streamline-workflow-in-database-tools-with-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Meet at EDUtech Asia 2024 in Singapore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 11:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Meet the JetBrains Academy team at EDUtech Asia 2024 in Singapore on November 6–7. Stop by booth D40 to talk with us about learning and teaching computer science with JetBrains Academy, grab some swag, or just say hi! You’ll also have the opportunity to learn how to use JetBrains IDEs for course creation and teaching, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/10/31/let-s-meet-at-edutech-asia-2024-in-singapore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Multi-tenant GenAI gateway using APIM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog shares insights on developing a GenAI gateway with multi-tenancy and quota management capabilities implemented using Azure APIM where customers can access the GenAI resources across different service tiers like Freemium, Basic, and Premium with each tier having it&#39;s own quota and rate limits. The solution used the concept of &amp;quot;Products&amp;quot; to group APIs related to specific entitlements and using Product Policies, simplifying the overall design and ensuring scalability.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTMX: What’s Old is New Again</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 21:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What’s old is new again, kind of. HTMX fits into that motto for me and it’s getting pretty popular, but at the same time It gets a lot of pushback. I’m going to take a step back and explain how we got to where we are in current web dev, which will explain what HTMX… Read More »HTMX: What’s Old is New Again The post HTMX: What’s Old is New Again appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Microsoft.PowerShell.PlatyPS 1.0.0-Preview1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 19:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce the release of Microsoft.PowerShell.PlatyPS 1.0.0-Preview1, a tool to build PowerShell help files.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/announcing-microsoft-powershell-platyps-1-0-0-preview1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate data from external sources into Microsoft Entra tokens using the Authentication Events library</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Streamline the integration of custom claims into authentication tokens with the new Authentication Events NuGet library. This blog post introduces a NuGet library that simplifies the implementation of custom claims providers, reducing the need for extensive code and minimizing validation errors. Learn how to efficiently fetch and add custom data, like entitlements or profile attributes, from external systems, such as CRMs or legacy databases, while ensuring secure, scalable solutions for your applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock organizational wisdom using voice-driven knowledge capture with Amazon Transcribe and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces an innovative voice-based application workflow that harnesses the power of Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Transcribe, and React to systematically capture and document institutional knowledge through voice recordings from experienced staff members. Our solution uses Amazon Transcribe for real-time speech-to-text conversion, enabling accurate and immediate documentation of spoken knowledge. We then use generative AI, powered by Amazon Bedrock, to analyze and summarize the transcribed content, extracting key insights and generating comprehensive documentation.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve multi-Region resiliency for your conversational AI chatbots with Amazon Lex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Global Resiliency is a new Amazon Lex capability that enables near real-time replication of your Amazon Lex V2 bots in a second AWS Region. When you activate this feature, all resources, versions, and aliases associated after activation will be synchronized across the chosen Regions. With Global Resiliency, the replicated bot resources and aliases in the […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-multi-region-resiliency-for-your-conversational-ai-chatbots-with-amazon-lex/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create and fine-tune sentence transformers for enhanced classification accuracy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showcase how to fine-tune a sentence transformer specifically for classifying an Amazon product into its product category (such as toys or sporting goods). We showcase two different sentence transformers, paraphrase-MiniLM-L6-v2 and a proprietary Amazon large language model (LLM) called M5_ASIN_SMALL_V2.0, and compare their results.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-and-fine-tune-sentence-transformers-for-enhanced-classification-accuracy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Beta Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 is now available with all the key improvements and new features coming in the major release. You can download the latest build from our website, from the free Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Beta To see the most notable updates from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smooth Parameter Replacement | TeamCity Pipelines Pulse #8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 15:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to bring you an update on our smooth parameter replacement feature. It’s already made parameter replacement easier, and now we’re taking it even further with some key improvements. In this iteration, we’re rolling out the smooth parameter replacement feature to more areas. You’ll now find it in almost all runner fields except for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/smooth-parameter-replacement-feature-teamcity-pipelines-pulse-8/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never mind, Lamar is going to continue</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 14:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A couple months ago I wrote Retiring Lamar and the Ghost of IoC Containers Past as we were closing in on decoupling Wolverine 3.0 from Lamar (since completed) and I was already getting sick of edge case bugs introduced by Microsoft from their inexplicably wacky approach for keyed services. Since releasing Wolverine 3.0 without its previous … Continue reading Never mind, Lamar is going to continue →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have enabled “take ownership” permission, but I still cannot obtain write access</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Taking ownership is only one part of gaining write access.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241030-00/?p=110440 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of the SharePoint SendEmail API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 12:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Retirement of the SharePoint SendEmail API from SharePoint Online - impacting both REST and CSOM API surfaces.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/retirement-of-the-sharepoint-sendemail-api 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unreal Engine Toolbar in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Visual Studio 2022 version 17.11, we’ve added a new Unreal Engine toolbar to Visual Studio. The Unreal Engine toolbar is a new feature that provides quick access to common Unreal Engine tasks. You can find the toolbar at the top of your code window when you have an Unreal Engine project loaded. The toolbar […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/unreal-engine-toolbar-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verifying code against architecture with Metalama</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 09:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In my previous article, I demonstrated how Metalama can generate boilerplate code during compilation, automating the repetitive yet necessary tasks. But Metalama doesn’t stop there. If Metalama were a goat, its second horn would be its ability to validate source code against architectural rules — ensuring that your
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/verifying-code-against-architecture-with-metalama/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Azure Tooling的更新 – 2024年10月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 08:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎阅读 Java on Azure 开发人员工具的十月份更新。在本次更新中，我们将介绍针对 IntelliJ IDEA 的 Azure 工具包中 Azure Functions 的托管身份支持（Managed Identity）。此外，我们还将推出一个名为Java on Azure 工具指南的新系列，在第一篇文章中，我们将讨论如何利用 Azure 工具包使用 App Service。我们希望您喜欢这些更新，并享受使用 Azure 工具包的流畅体验。请下载并安装 IntelliJ 的 Azure 工具包。让我们开始吧！ Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ 提升 在Azure Functions上支持Managed Identity 在 8 月份的更新中，我们推出了对 Azure 应用服务的支持，这将帮助开发人员简化应用程序的凭证管理，降低凭证暴露的风险。 在最新版本中，我们还为工具包中的 Azure 函数添加了托管身份支持。该功能为开发人员提供了使用托管身份进行身份验证和访问 Azure 存储等 Azure 资源的灵活性，而无需直接管理凭据。将 Java 应用程序部署到工具包中的 Azure Functions 应用程序时，系统会提示您分配角色以访问 Azure 资源。下面是一个简短的演示。 Azure上的Java […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-azure-tooling-update-october-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Azure Tooling Update – October 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 07:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the October update of Java on Azure developer tools. In this update, we will introduce our Managed Identity Support for Azure Functions in Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ IDEA. Additionally, we are launching a new series called Java on Azure Tooling Guide, and in our first post, we will discuss using App […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-azure-tooling-update-october-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot upgrade assistant for Java技术预览发布</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 03:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            随着人工智能和大型语言模型（LLMs）的不断发展，Agent(“智能代理”)和智能代理化工作流程正在迅速成为AI领域的下一个前沿。这些自主系统带来了巨大的好处，它们可以创建计划、执行单个任务、使用外部工具、与用户互动，甚至自行修复错误。 凭借这些功能，代理化工作流程可以解决一些企业客户在开发周期中经常遇到的复杂、关键任务，甚至是一些极其繁琐的任务。对于使用Java的企业客户来说，升级JDK、框架、依赖项等一直是一个挑战。这些挑战覆盖的范围相当地广，开发者可能会需要经常面对重复且繁琐的场景，例如API签名发生变化等等。我们见过一些企业在将代码库从Java 8升级到Java 17时，花费了几天甚至几周的时间，这是一项巨大的资源和人力投入。 今天，我们很高兴宣布GitHub Copilot upgrade assistant Java的技术预览版。这是一个基于AI的解决方案，它使用智能代理化工作流程和多代理框架帮助您更新Java应用程序。通过安装Visual Studio Code插件，您可以从本地Java项目开始，GitHub Copilot将自动处理大部分升级过程。以下是该产品的一些关键功能。 创建一个智能的计划 GitHub Copilot upgrade assistant for Java会分析您当前的项目，并提示用户输入JDK和Maven路径、分支名称等参数。点击“Start(开始)”后，工具将进一步评估该项目的依赖项，例如Spring Boot和JUnit等框架。您还可以选择生成一个GitHub Issue，记录升级过程中的任务。 您可以在执行计划前，审核即将执行的任务。以下是一个演示。 可视化每一步操作 当升级开始后，工具的信息面板(Dashboard)将成为主要信息中心，您可以在此查看每个任务的实时详情，包括运行OpenRewrite工具的命令、查看选择的配方、审查修改的文件和错误详情、每个步骤日志等。您还可以深入探索每个任务及其子任务的详细信息。 在升级过程中，您可以随时选择暂停、停止、继续，甚至重新启动新的升级计划。该工具在整个升级过程中为用户提供了高度的控制权和透明度。以下是一个演示。 自动修复错误与人机协作 如果在升级过程中出现错误，无论是由OpenRewrite代码转换引入的错误，还是其他原因，GitHub Copilot upgrade assistant for Java将通过动态构建/修复/重试AI循环自动处理这些问题。AI将自动尝试自动解决这些，并通过重新构建项目进行验证。如果问题仍然存在，系统将继续尝试不同的方法，只有在达到指定的尝试次数后才会需要“人类”的协助。工具将提供明确的信号，提示何时需要人工干预，并在工具中提供了人机协作体验的交互。以下是一个演示。 从开发者学习 当用户在升级过程中手动修复错误时，GitHub Copilot upgrade assistant for Java会学习这些修复并将这些模式应用于未来的问题。这些修复会被标记为“使用开发者的指导修复”。企业开发人员会发现随着工具对其代码库问题的适应，升级变得更加简单。以下是一个演示。 分支，Commit与PR流程整合 在操作过程中，GitHub Copilot upgrade assistant for Java将针对新的分支执行本地代码提交。这些提交与特定任务相关联，例如由OpenRewrite转换引起的所有代码更改，或者在错误修复循环期间的更改。 无论是OpenRewrite工具引起的更改，还是AI在动态构建/修复/重试循环中的更改，或是人工干预引起的更改，都会被适当标记，方便您专注于特定的更改。 升级过程总览 升级结束时的总结页面将提供所有重要细节的概览，包括文件更改、更新的依赖项、新的分支中的Commit。错误摘要部分还显示错误是如何解决的，无论是通过AI、开发人员还是通过开发者指导。此外，您还可以直接合并Commit并创建Pull Request！以下是一个演示。 申请技术预览的等候名单 准备好节省Java升级的时间了吗？您可以在此申请技术预览的等候名单。早期访问将仅限于选定的用户，但我们鼓励您注册！ AI时代充满了令人兴奋的可能性，我们相信这只是个开始。我们将为复杂的工作流程带来更多支持，帮助客户应对这些任务。人工智能与人类的合作将帮助我们实现创造性解决方案并提高效率，为我们的工作节省数千小时的时间。
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/technical-preview-github-copilot-upgrade-assistant-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empower your generative AI application with a comprehensive custom observability solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 22:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we set up the custom solution for observability and evaluation of Amazon Bedrock applications. Through code examples and step-by-step guidance, we demonstrate how you can seamlessly integrate this solution into your Amazon Bedrock application, unlocking a new level of visibility, control, and continual improvement for your generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/empower-your-generative-ai-application-with-a-comprehensive-custom-observability-solution/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Amazon Bedrock batch inference: Building a scalable and efficient pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 19:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although batch inference offers numerous benefits, it’s limited to 10 batch inference jobs submitted per model per Region. To address this consideration and enhance your use of batch inference, we’ve developed a scalable solution using AWS Lambda and Amazon DynamoDB. This post guides you through implementing a queue management system that automatically monitors available job slots and submits new jobs as slots become available.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-amazon-bedrock-batch-inference-building-a-scalable-and-efficient-pipeline/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData.Abstractions: Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 18:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the launch of Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData for .NET! Our collaboration with the .NET team since the debut of Semantic Kernel has resulted in a powerful new feature that aligns with the best practices of both current and upcoming .NET releases. This is the second new package as part of this collaboration. You can […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/microsoft-extensions-vectordata-abstractions-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to introduce the Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData.Abstractions package available in preview today. This new package provides a unified abstraction layer that enables you to integrate vector stores into your .NET applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-microsoft-extensions-vector-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot in Windows Terminal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 18:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot users can now use the power of GitHub Copilot to get command suggestions and explanations without leaving the terminal with Terminal Chat in Windows Terminal Canary 🚀 This is available for all GitHub Copilot Individual, Business, and Enterprise customers. To get started, sign up for a GitHub Copilot free trial and check out […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/github-copilot-in-windows-terminal 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB: Understanding Partition Keys</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 17:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB is Microsoft’s globally distributed, multi-model database service designed to meet the demands of large-scale, low-latency applications. One of the most critical design choices when using Azure Cosmos DB is understanding and effectively using Partition Keys. These keys impact how your data is stored, accessed, and managed across physical servers, directly affecting performance, […] The article Azure Cosmos DB: Understanding Partition Keys was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Technical Preview of the GitHub Copilot upgrade assistant for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 16:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI and LLMs continue to evolve, agentic workflows are rapidly emerging as the next wave of AI-assistance. Agentic workflows allow AI systems to coordinate tasks and make decisions with minimal human input. These systems use autonomous agents in their workflow and can bring enormous benefits as they can create plans, perform individual tasks, employ […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/technical-preview-github-copilot-upgrade-assistant-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a video insights and summarization engine using generative AI with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 16:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a solution where you can upload a recording of your meeting (a feature available in most modern digital communication services such as Amazon Chime) to a centralized video insights and summarization engine. This engine uses artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) services and generative AI on AWS to extract transcripts, produce a summary, and provide a sentiment for the call. The solution notes the logged actions per individual and provides suggested actions for the uploader.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Unreal Engine modules faster</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 16:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unreal Engine modules help keep your code organized and modular. However, creating modules can be a tedious and error-prone process that involves manually editing configuration files and adding boilerplate code. Visual Studio 2022 version 17.11 comes with a new dialog to help with this process. With the new Add Module dialog, you can quickly add […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/create-unreal-engine-modules-faster 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI applications with the new AI App Template Gallery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the launch of the AI App Template Gallery of templates using azd.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/build-ai-applications-with-the-new-ai-app-template-gallery 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate document processing with Amazon Bedrock Prompt Flows (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to build an IDP pipeline for automatically extracting and processing data from documents using Amazon Bedrock Prompt Flows, a fully managed service that enables you to build generative AI workflow using Amazon Bedrock and other services in an intuitive visual builder. Amazon Bedrock Prompt Flows allows you to quickly update your pipelines as your business changes, scaling your document processing workflows to help meet evolving demands.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governing the ML lifecycle at scale: Centralized observability with Amazon SageMaker and Amazon CloudWatch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is part of an ongoing series on governing the machine learning (ML) lifecycle at scale. To start from the beginning, refer to Governing the ML lifecycle at scale, Part 1: A framework for architecting ML workloads using Amazon SageMaker. A multi-account strategy is essential not only for improving governance but also for enhancing […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/governing-the-ml-lifecycle-at-scale-centralized-observability-with-amazon-sagemaker-and-amazon-cloudwatch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Exploration With pandas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maybe you’ve heard complicated-sounding phrases such as ‘“Students t-test”, “regression models”, “support vector machines”, and so on. You might think there’s so much you need to learn before you can explore and understand your data, but I am going to show you two tools to help you go faster. These are summary statistics and graphs. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/data-exploration-with-pandas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse-engineering what a “short” section is</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The long and short of it all.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241029-00/?p=110436 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a CRUD REST API Using Spring Boot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 09:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Boot is an application framework for the Java platform designed to make it easy to build Spring-powered applications. Its opinionated convention-over-configuration approach to building Spring applications improves developer productivity. IntelliJ IDEA provides extensive coding assistance for Spring, including a dedicated project wizard, code highlighting, intelligent context actions, embedded documentation, navigation, and highly customizable run […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/how-to-build-a-crud-rest-api-using-spring-boot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the result pattern worth it?: Working with the result pattern - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to extend your LINQ-based result pattern code to handle more scenarios, such as Task&amp;gt; and collections of Result
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/working-with-the-result-pattern-part-4-is-the-result-pattern-worth-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unlocking the Power of Spargine’s App Class</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a collection of open-source assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, crucial for application development. Its App class optimizes various functions, including culture adjustments, environment variable retrieval, and process management.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/29/boost-your-net-projects-unlocking-the-power-of-spargines-app-class/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#x27;s new in .NET 9: Two new LINQ methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 06:41:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 9 is releasing in mid-November 2024. Like every .NET version, this introduces several important features and enhancements aligning developers with an ever-changing development ecosystem. In this blog series, I will explore critical updates in different areas of .NET. In this post, I&#39;ll look at two new LINQ
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/whats-new-in-net-9-two-new-linq-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
