<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debug Docker Builds with Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building Docker images is an important component of the software delivery pipeline for modern applications. It’s how we package our apps and services so that they can be distributed to others and deployed to production. While the Dockerfile has long been the standard for defining container images, it is known to be challenging to make...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/debug-docker-builds-with-visual-studio-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “10x” Commandments of Highly Effective Go</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from John Arundel of Bitfield Consulting, a Go trainer and writer who runs a free newsletter for Go learners. His most recent book is The Deeper Love of Go. Ever wondered if there’s a software engineer, somewhere, who actually knows what they’re doing? Well, I finally found the one serene, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/10/16/the-10x-commandments-of-highly-effective-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Is Sunsetting CodeCanvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We started the development of CodeCanvas back in 2022, with the strong belief that cloud development environments (CDEs) would make development faster, smoother, and more efficient. With this goal in mind, we launched CodeCanvas publicly in 2024 and started accumulating users. We dove into the issues they faced in their development workflows and how we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/10/jetbrains-is-sunsetting-codecanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a secure MCP OAuth desktop client using OAuth and Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article demonstrates how to implement a secure MCP OAuth desktop client using Microsoft Entra ID. The MCP server is built with ASP.NET Core and secured using Microsoft Entra ID. The MCP client is a .NET console application that must acquire an OAuth access token to interact with the MCP server. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/McpSecurity Setup A […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/10/16/implement-a-secure-mcp-oauth-desktop-client-using-oauth-and-entra-id/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming enterprise operations: Four high-impact use cases with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share four high-impact, widely adopted use cases built with Nova in Amazon Bedrock, supported by real-world customers deployments, offerings available from AWS partners, and experiences. These examples are ideal for organizations researching their own AI adoption strategies and use cases across industries.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transforming-enterprise-operations-four-high-impact-use-cases-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building smarter AI agents: AgentCore long-term memory deep dive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory transforms raw conversational data into persistent, actionable knowledge through sophisticated extraction, consolidation, and retrieval mechanisms that mirror human cognitive processes. The system tackles the complex challenge of building AI agents that don&#39;t just store conversations but extract meaningful insights, merge related information across time, and maintain coherent memory stores that enable truly context-aware interactions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-smarter-ai-agents-agentcore-long-term-memory-deep-dive/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily connect AI workloads to Azure Blob Storage with adlfs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 17:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Easily connect AI workloads to Azure Blob Storage with adlfs We&#39;re excited to announce the newest release of adlfs—a unified Pythonic file system interface to Azure Blob Storage and Azure Data Lake Storage. Microsoft works closely with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/easily-connect-ai-workloads-to-azure-blob-storage-with-adlfs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure and verify a distributed training cluster with AWS Deep Learning Containers on Amazon EKS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Misconfiguration issues in distributed training with Amazon EKS can be prevented following a systematic approach to launch required components and verify their proper configuration. This post walks through the steps to set up and verify an EKS cluster for training large models using DLCs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/configure-and-verify-a-distributed-training-cluster-with-aws-deep-learning-containers-on-amazon-eks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala development in Amazon SageMaker Studio with Almond kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides a comprehensive guide on integrating the Almond kernel into SageMaker Studio, offering a solution for Scala development within the platform.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scala-development-in-amazon-sagemaker-studio-with-almond-kernel/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Hardened Images: crafted by humans, protected by AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Docker, we are building our hardened images to exacting standards. That means carefully crafting by hand, because humans are still the best security architects. That said, we understand the value of AI and deploy it as an extra set of eyes at critical junctures in our Docker Hardened Image (DHI) build process. With this...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hardened-images-crafted-by-humans-protected-by-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of PHP 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The State of PHP 2025 examines how developers use, prefer, and rely on PHP, showing how this long-standing web language continues to modernize through new frameworks, improved tooling, and AI-assisted workflows. In this report, we present findings from the Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025. Alongside the numbers, you’ll also hear commentary from Brent Roose, JetBrains Developer […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/10/state-of-php-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can you increment a reference count with relaxed semantics, but you have to decrement with release semantics?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When managing reference counts, there is an asymmetry between incrementing and decrementing: Incrementing the reference count can use relaxed semantics, but decrementing requires release semantics (and destroying requires acquire semantics). The asymmetry may strike you as odd, but maybe it shouldn&#39;t. After all, it&#39;s not surprising
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251015-00/?p=111686 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Developer Ecosystem 2025: Coding in the Age of AI, New Productivity Metrics, and Changing Realities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every year, the JetBrains Developer Ecosystem Survey takes a deep dive into the world of software development, looking at how developers work, what tools they use, and how the industry is changing. The survey has been running since 2017 and has since grown into one of the most comprehensive studies of its kind. The 2025 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/10/state-of-developer-ecosystem-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add MCP Servers to Gemini CLI with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the rapidly evolving landscape of AI-assisted development, most developers continue to struggle with clunky web interfaces, resource-intensive IDEs, and fragmented toolchains. But what if we told you there&#39;s a combination that pairs Google&#39;s 76.3K-star Gemini CLI (in just 5 months) with Docker&#39;s innovative MCP Toolkit, quietly revolutionizing how modern AI developers work? Enter the...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-set-up-gemini-cli-with-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Livestream] Maximizing TeamCity: New Features in Action and a Look Ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on October 22, 2025, for an essential TeamCity update livestream. In a live session, TeamCity Solutions Engineers, Ricardo Leite and Daniel Gallo, will walk you through the powerful features introduced in the most recent release and give you an exclusive look at what’s next on our roadmap. Whether you’re looking to optimize your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/10/livestream-maximizing-teamcity-oct22-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Prediction: The Data Kings Will Rule the World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author reflects on their successful mid-1990s prediction that data ownership would dictate power. They discuss the present reality, where tech giants utilize data for profit and manipulation. Emphasizing personal data protection, they share practical habits for minimizing exposure and invite others to contribute their own safety tips.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/10/15/tech-prediction-the-data-kings-will-rule-the-world/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plex Coffee delivers fast service and personal connections with ChatGPT Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Plex Coffee uses ChatGPT Business to centralize knowledge, train staff faster, and preserve personal connections while expanding.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/plex-coffee 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework October 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 22:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for October 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of October 14, 2025. This update contains securi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-october-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing .NET 10 Release Candidate 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 Release Candidate 2 is now available. This is our second and final release candidate and it comes with a go-live support license so you can confidently use this release for your production applications ahead of general availability. This release of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-rc-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) - October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 21:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the October 2025 edition of the Azure Developer CLI (azd) release blog! This post covers releases 1.19.0 and 1.20.0. To share your feedback and questions, join the October release discussion on GitHub. This month brings game-changing features including
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Developer’s Guide to Smarter Fine-tuning: Unlock custom AI for every business challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/the-developers-guide-to-smarter-fine-tuning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the .NET Security Group</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET project is run by Microsoft and follows our security reporting and disclosure practices. We publish vulnerability fixes and disclosures most months on Patch Tuesday. Nothing about that is changing. We are announcin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-security-group 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a device management agent with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a conversational device management system using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore. With this solution, users can manage their IoT devices through natural language, using a UI for tasks like checking device status, configuring WiFi networks, and monitoring user activity.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-device-management-agent-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import streamlined LLM deployment for Salesforce</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how Salesforce integrated Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import into their machine learning operations (MLOps) workflow, reused existing endpoints without application changes, and benchmarked scalability. We share key metrics on operational efficiency and cost optimization gains, and offer practical insights for simplifying your deployment strategy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import-streamlined-llm-deployment-for-salesforce/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.3-1 and 1.24.9-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-3-1-and-1-24-9-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing Authentication for Legacy Visual Studio Clients</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of our ongoing commitment to security and modernization, we’re updating outdated authentication mechanisms used by older versions of clients reliant on our older Visual Studio client libraries. For full details on all known impacted clients, refer to the official announcement we made in April 2024:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/modernizing-authentication-for-legacy-visual-studio-clients 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bug-Fix Releases Are Available for MPS – 2025.2.1, 2025.1.1, 2024.3.4, and 2024.1.5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released updates for multiple major MPS versions that fix several additional issues. The two most notable improvements that these releases bring are: MPS-38681 – Invisible references can now be excluded from usage highlighting. MPS-36481 – The task in Ant now recognizes two additional project properties to configure the location of the log files: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/10/new_bugfix_releases_mps-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper Is Now on the Open VSX Registry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ReSharper for Visual Studio Code has been available on the Microsoft Visual Studio Marketplace for some time now. However, ReSharper didn’t appear in many VS Code-compatible editors because these editors aren’t able to connect directly to the Visual Studio Code Marketplace. For this reason, users of such editors who wanted to install ReSharper had to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/14/resharper-open-vsx/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I remember taking a screen shot of a video, and when I opened it in Paint, the video was playing in it! What witchcraft is this?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            @ChenCravat In an old version of Windows (Windows 98 iirc) if you took screenshot of a video from media player and paste it into paint, and resume media player, video would play inside paint. Do you why it happened? It is still bugging me to this day.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251014-00/?p=111681 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Multi-Agent System in 5 Minutes with cagent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Models are advancing quickly. GPT-5, Claude Sonnet, Gemini. Each release gives us more capabilities. But most real work isn’t solved by a single model. Developers are realizing they need a system of agents: different types of agents working together to accomplish more complex tasks. For example, a researcher to find information, a writer to summarize,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-build-a-multi-agent-system/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us in Rebooting the Docker Model Runner Community!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to announce that we&#39;re breathing new life into the Docker Model Runner community, and we want you to be a part of it! Our goal is to make it easier than ever for you to contribute, collaborate, and help shape the future of running AI models with Docker. From a Limited Beta to...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/rebooting-model-runner-community/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expert Council on Well-Being and AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s new Expert Council on Well-Being and AI brings together leading psychologists, clinicians, and researchers to guide how ChatGPT supports emotional health, especially for teens. Learn how their insights are shaping safer, more caring AI experiences.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/expert-council-on-well-being-and-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How .NET Garbage Collector works (and when you should care)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:42:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of .NET, memory management is an important aspect of any application. Fortunately, you don&#39;t have to shoulder this immense task yourself. .NET handles it with the superpower of the Garbage Collector (GC). A GC is an engine that keeps your app fast, responsive, and resource-efficient.
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/how-net-garbage-collector-works-and-when-you-should-care/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argentina’s AI opportunity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Sur Energy are exploring Argentina’s first Stargate project—an AI and clean energy collaboration that could make Argentina a Latin American leader in artificial intelligence, sustainable infrastructure, and digital innovation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/argentinas-ai-opportunity 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing AWS development costs for .NET applications with LocalStack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Development and testing of AWS integrated applications incur AWS costs and need reliable internet connectivity. LocalStack helps reduce AWS costs by running emulated AWS services locally, while also eliminating connectivity issues. In this blog post, we will demonstrate how to reduce AWS costs for a sample .NET application in Development and Test cycles by setting […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/optimizing-aws-development-costs-for-net-applications-with-localstack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner on the new NVIDIA DGX Spark: a new paradigm for developing AI locally</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to bring NVIDIA DGX™ Spark support to Docker Model Runner. The new NVIDIA DGX Spark delivers incredible performance, and Docker Model Runner makes it accessible. With Model Runner, you can easily run and iterate on larger models right on your local machine, using the same intuitive Docker experience you already trust. In this...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/new-nvidia-dgx-spark-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming the physical world with AI: the next frontier in intelligent automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 22:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Physical AI represents the next frontier in intelligent automation, where artificial intelligence transcends digital boundaries to perceive, understand, and manipulate the tangible world around us.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transforming-the-physical-world-with-ai-the-next-frontier-in-intelligent-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100% Transparency and Five Pillars</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 21:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to Do Hardened Images (and Container Security) Right Container security is understandably a hot topic these days, with more and more workloads running atop this mainstay of the cloud native landscape. While I might be biased because I work at Docker, it is safe to say that containers are the dominant form factor for...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/100-transparency-and-five-pillars/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical reports analysis dashboard using Amazon Bedrock, LangChain, and Streamlit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 20:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the development of a conceptual Medical Reports Analysis Dashboard that combines Amazon Bedrock AI capabilities, LangChain&#39;s document processing, and Streamlit&#39;s interactive visualization features. The solution transforms complex medical data into accessible insights through a context-aware chat system powered by large language models available through Amazon Bedrock and dynamic visualizations of health parameters.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/medical-reports-analysis-dashboard-using-amazon-bedrock-langchain-and-streamlit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kitsa transforms clinical trial site selection with Amazon Quick Automate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll show how Kitsa, a health-tech company specializing in AI-driven clinical trial recruitment and site selection, used Amazon Quick Automate to transform their clinical trial site selection solution. Amazon Quick Automate, a capability of Amazon Quick Suite, enables enterprises to build, deploy and maintain resilient workflow automations at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/kitsa-transforms-clinical-trial-site-selection-with-amazon-quick-automate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect Amazon Quick Suite to enterprise apps and agents with MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Quick Suite&#39;s Model Context Protocol (MCP) client enables secure, standardized connections to enterprise applications and AI agents, eliminating the need for complex custom integrations. You&#39;ll discover how to set up MCP Actions integrations with popular enterprise tools like Atlassian Jira and Confluence, AWS Knowledge MCP Server, and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway to create a collaborative environment where people and AI agents can seamlessly work together across your organization&#39;s data and applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make agents a reality with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore: Now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 14:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn why customers choose AgentCore to build secure, reliable AI solutions using their choice of frameworks and models for production workloads.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-agentcore-is-now-generally-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API design principle: Don&#39;t tempt people to divide by zero</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A team was bringing forward an API for review, and one of the parts involved expressing a set of supported values in the form of three numbers: A minimum allowed value. An increment. A maximum allowed value. The supported values are the minimum, integer multiples of the increment added t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251013-00/?p=111677 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps local MCP Server is generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to take our local MCP Server for Azure DevOps out of preview 🥳. Since the initial preview announcement, we&#39;ve worked closely with early adopters and the community to incorporate feature suggestions and feedback. We’ve improved login and authorization, adde
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-local-mcp-server-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and Broadcom announce strategic collaboration to deploy 10 gigawatts of OpenAI-designed AI accelerators</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Broadcom announce a multi-year partnership to deploy 10 gigawatts of OpenAI-designed AI accelerators, co-developing next-generation systems and Ethernet solutions to power scalable, energy-efficient AI infrastructure by 2029.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-and-broadcom-announce-strategic-collaboration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify Windows Service and Process Management with Spargine’s Services Helper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_10_2025/12_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_10_2025/12_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Spargine Services type simplifies Windows service management in .NET applications, allowing developers to efficiently load, start, stop, and check service statuses without complex API interactions. With functionalities for bulk operations and process management, it streamlines service-dependent application development, saving significant time and effort for users.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/10/12/boost-your-net-projects-simplify-windows-service-and-process-management-with-spargines-services-helper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Testing Vial: a (better?) alternative to Testing Diamond and Testing Pyramid</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_10_2025/12_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_10_2025/12_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Testing Pyramid focuses on Unit Tests; the Testing Diamond focuses on Integration Tests; and what about the Testing Vial?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/testing-vial/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promotions Without Burnout - Dev Leader Weekly 112</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2025/11_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2025/11_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the trade-off with doing extra work to get promoted as a developer.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/10/11/promotions-without-burnout-dev-leader-weekly-112 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-10-10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2025/11_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2025/11_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/10/11/weekly-recap-20251010 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Fast Serverless APIs With Minimal APIs on AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2025/11_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2025/11_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to deploy ASP.NET Core Minimal APIs to AWS Lambda with just one library and a single line of code. We&#39;ll explore the setup process, measure real-world performance including cold start times, and discuss when serverless makes sense for your APIs.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/building-fast-serverless-apis-with-minimal-apis-on-aws-lambda 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code - October 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce that the October 2025 release of the Python extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available! This release includes the following announcements: Python Environments extension improvements Enhanced testing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-october-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The self-assignment principle for Windows Runtime properties: Don&#39;t change behavior based on whether a property has been written to</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the past few days, I&#39;ve been investigating the self-assignment principle for Windows Runtime properties: Setting a property to its current value is legal and has no effect. One corollary to this was that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251010-00/?p=111673 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add MCP Servers to Claude Code with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI coding assistants have evolved from simple autocomplete tools into full development partners. Yet even the best of them, like Claude Code, can’t act directly on your environment. Claude Code can suggest a database query, but can&#39;t run it. It can draft a GitHub issue, but can&#39;t create it. It can write a Slack message,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/add-mcp-servers-to-claude-code-with-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.2-1 and 1.24.8-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 01:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-2-1-and-1-24-8-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HYGH powers next-gen digital ads with ChatGPT Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HYGH speeds up software development and campaign delivery with ChatGPT Business, cutting turnaround times, scaling output, and driving revenue growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/hygh 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon SageMaker HyperPod and Anyscale for next-generation distributed computing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to integrate Amazon SageMaker HyperPod with Anyscale platform to address critical infrastructure challenges in building and deploying large-scale AI models. The combined solution provides robust infrastructure for distributed AI workloads with high-performance hardware, continuous monitoring, and seamless integration with Ray, the leading AI compute engine, enabling organizations to reduce time-to-market and lower total cost of ownership.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-and-anyscale-for-next-generation-distributed-computing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing text content moderation with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce Amazon Nova customization for text content moderation through Amazon SageMaker AI, enabling organizations to fine-tune models for their specific moderation needs. The evaluation across three benchmarks shows that customized Nova models achieve an average improvement of 7.3% in F1 scores compared to the baseline Nova Lite, with individual improvements ranging from 4.2% to 9.2% across different content moderation tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/customizing-text-content-moderation-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete Beginner&#39;s Guide to Vibe Coding an App in 5 Minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picture this: I&#39;m staring at a CSV file containing metrics from 492 episodes of my podcast, Merge Conflict. Years of data—listen counts, retention rates, performance metrics—all sitting there, waiting to tell a story. But I&#39;m not in the mood to spend days building dashboards and wrangling data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/complete-beginners-guide-to-vibe-coding-an-app-in-5-minutes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2025 (version 1.105)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code September 2025 Release (1.105). Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/september-2025-(version-1.105) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The self-assignment principle for Windows Runtime properties applies to default values</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, I introduced the self-assignment principle for Windows Runtime properties: Setting a property to its current value is legal and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251009-00/?p=111664 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Kotlin Multiplatform Project and Win a Trip to KotlinConf 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year’s Kotlin Multiplatform Contest for students and recent graduates is open. Build a project using KMP, and it could take you to KotlinConf 2026 in Munich, Germany! Whether you are already exploring Kotlin Multiplatform or just curious about how far you can take shared Kotlin code, seize the chance to challenge yourself, stand out, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/kotlin-multiplatform-contest-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining and evaluating political bias in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI evaluates political bias in ChatGPT through new real-world testing methods that improve objectivity and reduce bias.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/defining-and-evaluating-political-bias-in-llms 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LoRA Explained: Faster, More Efficient Fine-Tuning with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fine-tuning a language model doesn’t have to be daunting. In our previous post on fine-tuning models with Docker Offload and Unsloth, we walked through how to train small, local models efficiently using Docker’s familiar workflows. This time, we’re narrowing the focus. Instead of asking a model to be good at everything, we can specialize it:...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/lora-explained/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana’s Public API Is Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Qodana Public API is now live, complete with full documentation, examples, and OpenAPI specifications. This release gives all Qodana Cloud users the ability to integrate Qodana directly into their own systems, automate key workflows, and access core functionality programmatically. View Documentation What’s new? Until now, a few API endpoints were available only to selected […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/10/qodana-public-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.07.3 Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re releasing one of the final bug-fix updates before the next major version —TeamCity On-Premises 2025.07.3. This minor update addresses several issues, including: In addition to regular bug fixes, all TeamCity bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements. For that reason, we recommend that you never ignore bug-fix releases and update your On-Premises […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/10/teamcity-2025-07-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Git Submodules: Managing Dependencies Across Repositories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In complex software projects, it’s common to split functionality across multiple repositories. One common scenario arises when your main project depends on outputs or components developed in another repository that&#39;s also evolving in parallel. Managing this dependency effectively—especially when only a specific part of the secondary reposi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/git-submodules-and-dependencies 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
