<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 17:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>C# Dev Kit update brings enhanced Razor IntelliSense, Project Status, and New Config Options</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Boost your dev workflow with the C# Dev Kit August 2024 release, which brings enhanced Razor IntelliSense, updated Project Status Bar, and new Project Configuration Options!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/whats-new-in-csharp-dev-kit-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliable Web App – Reliability Patterns</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 16:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            (Only got 5 minutes? The completed example is available here) As applications migrate to the cloud, they must be designed to handle inevitable failures gracefully. Network issues, service outages, and other transient faults are common in distributed systems. Without proper handling mechanisms,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/reliable-web-app-reliability-patterns 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #6: Introducing Self- Hosted Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 14:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want total control over your CI/CD pipeline? We’re introducing self-hosted agents in TeamCity Pipelines! Define your own build environments, manage your resources, and scale effortlessly. No more waiting in line for shared agents. You can now choose whether to run jobs on JetBrains-hosted agents or your own. You can also add various requirements for the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue6-self-hosted-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Microsoft/IBM joint development was built on mutual respect, wait, is respect the right word?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maybe it&#39;s some other word.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240827-00/?p=110186 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Local Development with Dev Containers and Testcontainers Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 13:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to run Testcontainers-based tests or services from within dev containers and how to leverage Testcontainers Cloud securely and efficiently to make interacting with Docker even easier.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/streamlining-local-development-with-dev-containers-and-testcontainers-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build customized Power BI dashboards with user insights data in External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 12:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The user insights feature in Microsoft Entra External ID, now generally available, provides valuable metrics on user behavior through Microsoft Graph APIs and dashboards in the Microsoft Entra admin center. This blog post will guide you through building a customized Power BI dashboard using user insights to analyze metrics like total user count, active users, and MFA usage.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-id-user-insights-and-power-bi 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Azure Storage Queue messages with Azure Functions and [QueueTrigger]</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss using Azure Storage Queue as a message queue and how you can process Storage Queue messages using an Azure Functions app
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/using-azure-storage-queues-with-azure-functions-and-queuetrigger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Introduction to Workspaces in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 06:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode, where we will explore how to take advantage of the new workspace functionality in your IntelliJ IDEA projects with Andrey Belyaev. Date: September 12, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract This session will provide a comprehensive overview of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding .NET stack traces - A guide for developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 08:44:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stack traces are important for debugging and understanding exceptions in .NET applications. They provide detailed information about the error and the call stack when an exception occurs, allowing us as developers to investigate why an error happened. In this post, I&#39;ll walk you through the basics of reading asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-net-stack-traces-a-guide-for-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: 2 ways to use custom equality rules in a HashSet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With HashSet, you can get a list of different items in a performant way. What if you need a custom way to define when two objects are equal?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/hashset-custom-equality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure RAG applications using prompt engineering on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 20:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss existing prompt-level threats and outline several security guardrails for mitigating prompt-level threats. For our example, we work with Anthropic Claude on Amazon Bedrock, implementing prompt templates that allow us to enforce guardrails against common security threats such as prompt injection. These templates are compatible with and can be modified for other LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/secure-rag-applications-using-prompt-engineering-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get the most from Amazon Titan Text Premier</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 20:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the new Amazon Titan Text Premier model, specifically optimized for enterprise use cases, such as building Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and agent-based applications. Such integrations enable advanced applications like building interactive AI assistants that use enterprise APIs and interact with your propriety documents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-the-most-from-amazon-titan-text-premier/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenASL: Generative AI-powered American Sign Language avatars</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 19:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into the architecture and implementation details of GenASL, which uses AWS generative AI capabilities to create human-like ASL avatar videos. GenASL is a solution that translates speech or text into expressive ASL avatar animations, bridging the gap between spoken and written language and sign language.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/genasl-generative-ai-powered-american-sign-language-avatars/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing AI Application Development with Docker Desktop and NVIDIA AI Workbench</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about Docker&#39;s collaboration with NVIDIA, which enhances your ability to leverage Docker containers and improves your overall experience of building and developing AI/ML applications.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/optimizing-ai-application-development-docker-desktop-nvidia-ai-workbench/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IDE features in Visual Studio v17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 15:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Visual Studio 2022 v17.11, you’ll discover several new features that address specific issues developers have reported. These updates don’t belong to a distinct category, but we’re dedicated to sharing them with you in this blog post. You can download the update and view the comprehensive release notes for full details.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-ide-features-in-visual-studio-v17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains JavaScript Day 2024 Registration Is Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 15:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey everyone! JetBrains JavaScript Day is back for year four, and this edition promises to be our best one yet! Let’s face it, keeping up with the rapid changes in the JavaScript ecosystem is no easy task – it can be hard for us, too. That’s exactly why we created JetBrains JavaScript Day! This year, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/08/jetbrains-javascript-day-2024-registration-is-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Augmented Generation with Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 15:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Retrieval Augmented Generation, or RAG, is one of the hottest topics at the moment as it opens up the possibility of interacting with data using natural language, which is a long-time dream finally coming true. It is very likely that a lot of your data is already stored or will be stored in Azure SQL,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/rag-with-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track and Analyze GitHub Star Growth With  Kandy and Kotlin DataFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin DataFrame and Kandy are two powerful tools for data analysis in Kotlin. Kotlin DataFrame simplifies data manipulation and processing, while Kandy allows you to create visualizations directly within your Kotlin projects. In this post, we’ll show you how these tools can be used together within Kotlin Notebook to analyze the star history of GitHub […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/08/track-and-analyze-github-star-growth-with-kandy-and-kotlin-dataframe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Guide to Credit Risk Analysis With Python and Datalore AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog post by Ryan O’Connell, CFA, FRM. Understanding the relationships between various economic indicators is crucial for navigating the financial landscape. These relationships significantly impact the overall state of the economy, affecting businesses, investors, and individuals alike. We’ll analyze data spanning over two decades of financial history, leveraging the power of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/26/a-complete-guide-to-credit-risk-analysis-with-python-and-datalore-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS empowers sales teams using generative AI solution built on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Through this series of posts, we share our generative AI journey and use cases, detailing the architecture, AWS services used, lessons learned, and the impact of these solutions on our teams and customers. In this first post, we explore Account Summaries, one of our initial production use cases built on Amazon Bedrock. Account Summaries equips our teams to be better prepared for customer engagements. It combines information from various sources into comprehensive, on-demand summaries available in our CRM or proactively delivered based on upcoming meetings.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on finding the essential elements of a set</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another binary search, but searching a different way.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240826-00/?p=110181 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aug 2024: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 13:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An overview of the latest updates in Microsoft Entra for Aug 2024. Discover how these new capabilities can be integrated into your projects for optimal performance and security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-aug-24 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix ESLint Violations with AI Assistance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 13:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use GenAI to fix ESLint violations, without installing Node.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-fix-eslint-violations-with-ai-assistance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspaces in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 09:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Better late than never! This idiom is probably the best way to describe the functionality we’ll introduce in this article, specifically, support for workspaces in IntelliJ IDEA. Intro In a nutshell, a workspace is a meta-project that allows you to manage multiple projects simultaneously. This feature is useful for various reasons, from coordinating complex development […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/workspaces-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Change the ServiceLifetime of a Registered Service in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 05:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing dependencies is essential in modern application development. .NET provides a powerful Dependency Injection (DI) system, with ServiceCollection at its core. Typically, we register a service and use it as is. However, there are instances when we need to change the ServiceLifetime of services after registration. This article explores methods for changing ServiceLifeTime, providing practical […] The post Dynamically Change the ServiceLifetime of a Registered Service in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a software developer, you might spend most of your time immersed in code, solving problems, and building innovative solutions. But have…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/you-should-blog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Observability with OpenTelemetry – Part 3: Distributed Tracing using AWS X-Ray</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2024/25_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 12:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2024/25_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Traces capture requests through services and components, and are essential for understanding application workflows. They are key for pinpointing bottlenecks and identifying hotspots. Particularly vital in microservices, traces reveal the interplay in modern applications, aiding developers and operators in visualizing request paths for effective issue diagnosis. In the first post of this series, we instrumented […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/net-observability-with-opentelemetry-part-3-distributed-tracing-using-aws-x-ray/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Efficiency and Savings: Stop Reinventing the Wheel in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2024/25_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2024/25_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When developing software, prioritize speed and cost, but consider the impact on meeting consumer needs. Leverage existing solutions like Microsoft .NET and third-party tools to avoid costly custom development. For enhanced productivity, explore UI frameworks and essential tools like CodeRush and GhostDoc in Visual Studio development. Embrace third-party products for better quality code, faster feature development, and cost savings.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/08/25/maximize-efficiency-and-savings-stop-reinventing-the-wheel-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Years In Big Tech After Startups – Dev Leader Weekly 58</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_08_2024/24_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_08_2024/24_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post 4 Years In Big Tech After Startups – Dev Leader Weekly 58 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I celebrate 4 years at Microsoft and what I learned from being in Big Tech so far! The post 4 Years In Big Tech After Startups – Dev Leader Weekly 58 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/08/24/4-years-in-big-tech-after-startups-dev-leader-weekly-58/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screaming Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_08_2024/24_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_08_2024/24_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you were to glance at the folder structure of your system, could you tell what the system is about? Your architecture should communicate what problems it solves. This approach is called sreaming architecture.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/screaming-architecture 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step-by-Step Guide to Building a Powerful AI Monitoring Dashboard with Semantic Kernel and Azure Monitor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 18:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re featuring a guest author, Akshay Kokane, who’s a Software Engineer at Microsoft within the Azure CxP team. He’s written an article we’re sharing below, focused on a Step-by-Step Guide to Building a Powerful AI Monitoring Dashboard with Semantic Kernel and Azure Monitor: Master TokenUsage Metrics and Custom Metrics using SK Filters.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/step-by-step-guide-to-building-a-powerful-ai-monitoring-dashboard-with-semantic-kernel-and-azure-monitor 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.6 RC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 16:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the availability of the release candidate of TypeScript 5.6. To get started using the RC, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@rc Here’s a quick list of what’s new in TypeScript 5.6!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-6-rc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if I need to wait for more than MAXIMUM_WAIT_OBJECTS threads?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Studying your options, and the consequences of breaking things up.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240823-00/?p=110169 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fail-Fast Strategy: What Is It and How Does TeamCity Support It?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 09:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Cameron Pavey, draft.dev. Software development teams are always looking for ways to move faster and deliver more value in less time. However, one common pitfall for many teams is spending far too much time and effort building something, only to encounter major issues late in the project’s lifecycle. The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/fail-fast-strategy-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell Spring Cloud Azure 4.x, Hello 5.x: The Future is Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 03:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces that Spring Cloud Azure is deprecating version 4.x in favor of version 5.x.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/farewell-spring-cloud-azure-4-x-hello-5-x-the-future-is-now 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build private and secure enterprise generative AI applications with Amazon Q Business using IAM Federation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 01:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a conversational assistant powered by generative artificial intelligence (AI) that enhances workforce productivity by answering questions and completing tasks based on information in your enterprise systems, which each user is authorized to access. In an earlier post, we discussed how you can build private and secure enterprise generative AI applications with Amazon Q Business and AWS IAM Identity Center. If you want to use Amazon Q Business to build enterprise generative AI applications, and have yet to adopt organization-wide use of AWS IAM Identity Center, you can use Amazon Q Business IAM Federation to directly manage user access to Amazon Q Business applications from your enterprise identity provider (IdP), such as Okta or Ping Identity.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the power of generative AI: Verisk’s Discovery Navigator revolutionizes medical record review</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 22:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we describe the development of the automated summary feature in Verisk&#39;s Discovery Navigator incorporating generative AI, the data, the architecture, and the evaluation of the pipeline. This new functionality offers an immediate overview of the initial injury and current medical status, empowering record reviewers of all skill levels to quickly assess injury severity with the click of a button.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleashing-the-power-of-generative-ai-verisks-discovery-navigator-revolutionizes-medical-record-review/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index your Atlassian Confluence Cloud contents using the Amazon Q Confluence Cloud connector for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 20:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide an overview of Amazon Q Business Confluence Cloud connector and how you can use it for seamless integration of generative AI assistance to your Confluence Cloud.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index-your-atlassian-confluence-cloud-contents-using-the-amazon-q-confluence-cloud-connector-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowflake Arctic models are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 19:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the Snowflake Arctic Instruct model is available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. In this post, we walk through how to discover and deploy the Snowflake Arctic Instruct model using SageMaker JumpStart, and provide example use cases with specific prompts.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/snowflake-arctic-models-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine tune a generative AI application for Amazon Bedrock using Amazon SageMaker Pipeline decorators</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 18:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to convert Python code that fine-tunes a generative AI model in Amazon Bedrock from local files to a reusable workflow using Amazon SageMaker Pipelines decorators.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-a-generative-ai-application-for-amazon-bedrock-using-amazon-sagemaker-pipeline-decorators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevent Critical Bugs with MSVC Code Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 18:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine this: You’re deep into a complex C++ project, and everything seems to be running smoothly. But then, out of nowhere, a critical bug surfaces— one that requires a bit more foresight. We’ve all been there, right? This is where code analysis steps in as your silent guardian.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/prevent-critical-bugs-with-msvc-code-analysis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Application control</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 17:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how Microsoft 365 Certification validates application controls for enterprise-ready apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-application-control 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of the VS Code extension for Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 17:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Machine learning and artificial intelligence are transforming the world as we know it. With the power of data, you will have countless opportunities to create something new, unique, and exciting. Whether you are a seasoned data scientist or a curious beginner,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/announcing-the-general-availability-of-the-vs-code-extension-for-azure-machine-learning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Windows Community Toolkit v8.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 16:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing Windows Community Toolkit v8.1 We’re happy to announce that version 8.1 is available today! It’s a minor update which contains a variety of new features and improvements, made possible again with the support and contributions of our developer community. 🎉 If you’re not familiar with the Windows Community Toolkit,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ifdef-windows/announcing-windows-community-toolkit-v8-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.0.20 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.0.20 release is out! This version includes performance improvements and bug fixes for Kotlin 2.0.0, where we announced the Kotlin K2 compiler as Stable. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.0.20 or the release notes on GitHub. How to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/08/kotlin-2-0-20-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving into Function Calling and its JSON Schema in Semantic Kernel Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most exciting features available in certain Large Language Models (LLMs) is function-calling. In Semantic Kernel, we handle the heavy lifting so that you can bring your own code or utilize built-in plugins that cater to your use case.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/diving-into-function-calling-and-its-json-schema-in-semantic-kernel-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of the activation factory in the Windows Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The activation factory represents the class itself.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240822-00/?p=110165 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Datalore 2024.4: Limit 500 Toggle, Easier Folder Import, Polars DataFrames Support, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2024.4 introduces quality-of-life improvements for SQL cells, a revamped folder import workflow, support for Polars DataFrames, and more. Datalore Cloud customers have already received the new update automatically, and Datalore On-Premises customers can upgrade by following these instructions. Limit 500 toggle for SQL cells To help you prototype SQL queries faster, we’ve introduced a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/22/what-s-new-in-datalore-2024-4-limit-500-toggle-easier-folder-import-polars-dataframes-support-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Code Comprehension: GitHub Copilot’s Features in Visual Studio 2022 17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio 2022 17.11 now offers an improved experience you to refer to their methods, classes, functions, and entire solution directly within the chat. By using the # symbol followed by the name of a method, class, or function,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/enhancing-code-comprehension-github-copilots-features-in-visual-studio-2022-17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Object Limit Tracker in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 03:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce the Object Limit Tracker in Azure DevOps! This new feature provides real-time visibility into resource usage for each organization and project directly within Azure DevOps. By offering insights into commonly asked limits, we enable users to manage resources more proactively and prevent potential issues.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/introducing-object-limit-tracker-in-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance call center efficiency using batch inference for transcript summarization with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce general availability of batch inference for Amazon Bedrock. This new feature enables organizations to process large volumes of data when interacting with foundation models (FMs), addressing a critical need in various industries, including call center operations. In this post, we demonstrate the capabilities of batch inference using call center transcript summarization as an example.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-call-center-efficiency-using-batch-inference-for-transcript-summarization-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Meta Llama 3.1 models for generative AI inference using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fine-tuning Meta Llama 3.1 models with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart enables developers to customize these publicly available foundation models (FMs). The Meta Llama 3.1 collection represents a significant advancement in the field of generative artificial intelligence (AI), offering a range of capabilities to create innovative applications. The Meta Llama 3.1 models come in various sizes, with 8 billion, 70 billion, and 405 billion parameters, catering to diverse project needs. In this post, we demonstrate how to fine-tune Meta Llama 3-1 pre-trained text generation models using SageMaker JumpStart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Sucks?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Serverless sucks… or does it? There is a neverending supply of people saying that serverless is trash and has no value. The issue often with these statements is they need to provide more context. As always, context is king, and understanding the use case to make decisions on when serverless might be appropriate. YouTube Check… Read More »Serverless Sucks? The post Serverless Sucks? appeared first on CodeOpinion.
Link to article: https://codeopinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your testing experience with MSTest.Analyzers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSTest ships with extensive suite of code analyzers to help you write well-formed, performant and error free tests.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/supercharge-your-testing-experience-with-ms-test-analyzers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyze customer reviews using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 17:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores an innovative application of large language models (LLMs) to automate the process of customer review analysis. LLMs are a type of foundation model (FM) that have been pre-trained on vast amounts of text data. This post discusses how LLMs can be accessed through Amazon Bedrock to build a generative AI solution that automatically summarizes key information, recognizes the customer sentiment, and generates actionable insights from customer reviews. This method shows significant promise in saving human analysts time while producing high-quality results.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accuracy evaluation framework for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 16:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative artificial intelligence (AI), particularly Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) solutions, are rapidly demonstrating their vast potential to revolutionize enterprise operations. RAG models combine the strengths of information retrieval systems with advanced natural language generation, enabling more contextually accurate and informative outputs. From automating customer interactions to optimizing backend operation processes, these technologies are not just […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accuracy-evaluation-framework-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate healthcare interaction and documentation with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Transcribe using Live Meeting Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 16:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, physicians spend about 49% of their workday documenting clinical visits, which impacts physician productivity and patient care. Did you know that for every eight hours that office-based physicians have scheduled with patients, they spend more than five hours in the EHR? As a consequence, healthcare practitioners exhibit a pronounced inclination towards conversational intelligence solutions, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-healthcare-interaction-and-documentation-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-transcribe-using-live-meeting-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the power of data governance and no-code machine learning with Amazon SageMaker Canvas and Amazon DataZone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 16:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon DataZone is a data management service that makes it quick and convenient to catalog, discover, share, and govern data stored in AWS, on-premises, and third-party sources. Amazon DataZone allows you to create and manage data zones, which are virtual data lakes that store and process your data, without the need for extensive coding or […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-the-power-of-data-governance-and-no-code-machine-learning-with-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-and-amazon-datazone/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate performance using a custom chunking mechanism with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 16:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Accenture used the customization capabilities of Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock to incorporate their data processing workflow and custom logic to create a custom chunking mechanism that enhances the performance of Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and unlock the potential of your PDF data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-performance-using-a-custom-chunking-mechanism-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does ERROR_KEY_DELETED mean?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You now have a handle to a key that doesn&#39;t exist, and there&#39;s nothing you can do with it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240821-46/?p=110160 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is AI Trained? Is My Data Safe with Generative AI, Copilot and OpenAI Solutions?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 14:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The adoption of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Large Language Models (LLMs) is rapidly increasing, and these technologies are being harnessed across various sectors to drive innovation, streamline operations, and enhance productivity. Generative AI, in particular, has emerged as a transformative technology, capable of creating new content, making predictions, and providing insights that were once the […] The article How is AI Trained? Is My Data Safe with Generative AI, Copilot and OpenAI Solutions?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper Tips &amp; Tricks with Matt Ellis – Livestream</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 13:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on September 12, 2024, at 2:00 PM UTC for another JetBrains livestream event. You can register for the event using the link below or subscribe to our YouTube channel, JetBrainsTV, to get a notification closer to the event. With over 20 years of ReSharper setting the standard for the .NET development experience, it’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/21/resharper-tips-tricks-with-matt-ellis-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing your Azure deployments with PSRule</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 13:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PSRule for Azure is a powerful tool designed to validate your Azure Infrastructure as Code (IaC). PSRule runs checks based on the Well-Architected Framework, helping you ensure your Azure solutions follow security best practices. See how to integrate PSRule into your workflow, and catch security issues in your IaC templates early.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/secure-azure-deployments-with-psrule 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Chatbots With LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 10:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Dido Grigorov, a deep learning engineer and Python programmer with 17 years of experience in the field. Chatbots have evolved far beyond simple question-and-answer tools. With the power of large language models (LLMs), they can understand the context of conversations and generate human-like responses, making them invaluable for customer […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/how-to-build-chatbots-with-langchain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New C&#43;&#43; features in Visual Studio v17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 version 17.11 is here and comes with a host of new features for C++ developers. We’ve made improvements across our toolchain, Unreal Engine support, Build Insights, CMake debugger, and more. This post gives a quick overview of what’s available;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-c-features-in-visual-studio-v17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between Record Struct and Record Class in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 05:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll discuss the differences between record struct and record class in C#. First, we will shortly explain each of the types. Afterward, we’ll show and describe each difference between them. Let’s start. Record Struct and Record Class in C# C# is built upon two categories of types: value types and reference types. […] The post Differences Between Record Struct and Record Class in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Ceremony Sagas with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 21:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine puts a very high emphasis on reducing code ceremony and tries really hard to keep itself out of your application code. Wolverine is also built with testability in mind. If you’d be interested in learning more about how Wolverine could simplify your existing application code or set you up with a solid foundation for sustainable … Continue reading Low Ceremony Sagas with Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/08/20/low-ceremony-sagas-with-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate Amazon SageMaker Data Wrangler flows to Amazon SageMaker Canvas for faster data preparation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 17:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how you can bring your existing SageMaker Data Wrangler flows—the instructions created when building data transformations—from SageMaker Studio Classic to SageMaker Canvas. We provide an example of moving files from SageMaker Studio Classic to Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) as an intermediate step before importing them into SageMaker Canvas.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/migrate-amazon-sagemaker-data-wrangler-flows-to-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-for-faster-data-preparation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Boards Hub Rollout Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 17:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in March, we shared an update on our initiative to make the New Boards Hub the default experience for all organizations. However, that rollout was delayed as we shifted priorities for several months. Today, we’re excited to announce that the rollout of the New Boards Hub is back on track.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-boards-hub-rollout-update-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: KPMG Clara AI and Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 16:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re featuring KPMG on our Semantic Kernel blog for their work on Clara AI in KPMG. You can learn more about the solution here: KPMG Partnership with Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel Here’s a quote from KPMG on the partnership, “Microsoft and KPMG entered a strategic alliance to modernize the work of KPMG professionals.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-kpmg-clara-ai-and-microsofts-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use IP-restricted presigned URLs to enhance security in Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While presigned URLs offer a convenient way to grant temporary access to S3 objects, sharing these URLs with people outside of the workteam can lead to unintended access of those objects. To mitigate this risk and enhance the security of SageMaker Ground Truth labeling tasks, we have introduced a new feature that adds an additional layer of security by restricting access to the presigned URLs to the worker’s IP address or virtual private cloud (VPC) endpoint from which they access the labeling task.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the power of structured data for enterprises using natural language with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss an architecture to query structured data using Amazon Q Business, and build out an application to query cost and usage data in Amazon Athena with Amazon Q Business. Amazon Q Business can create SQL queries to your data sources when provided with the database schema, additional metadata describing the columns and tables, and prompting instructions. You can extend this architecture to use additional data sources, query validation, and prompting techniques to cover a wider range of use cases.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.39 Is Out With Smart Mode for Single Files, the Ability to Compare Files, the Structure Tool Window, Automatic Language Detection for Untitled Files, and Other Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 14:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.39 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.39 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/08/fleet-1-39-is-out-with-smart-mode-for-single-files-the-ability-to-compare-files-the-structure-tool-window-automatic-language-detection-for-untitled-files-and-other-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another tribute to Microsoft history hiding in Building 41</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Logo touches.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240820-00/?p=110152 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Datalore Cloud Plans – What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 13:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Datalore has evolved over the years, we’ve added more and more pricing tiers to cater to different users in the cloud. The variety of tiers sometimes made choosing a plan complicated. Now, we’ve decided to revamp our subscription plans to simplify the process of finding the option that best fits your needs. You no […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/20/new-datalore-cloud-plans-what-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public preview of SharePoint Framework 1.20 – First release of upcoming features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 13:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the first preview of the upcoming SharePoint Framework 1.20. This time focus is primarily on the Microsoft Viva platform capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/public-preview-of-sharepoint-framework-1-20-first-release-of-upcoming-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Learned From the Perforce 2024 State of Game Technology Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 11:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The gaming industry has long been a hotbed of innovation, with developers consistently pushing the boundaries of what’s possible. But as we progress into 2024, it’s clear that game technology’s sphere of influence is expanding far beyond the realm of gaming. Technological advancements coming out of the game industry are quickly adopted by various other […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/perforce-2024-game-tech-report/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New debugging and diagnostic features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debugging and diagnostics are vital skills for any developer, but they can also be difficult and time-consuming to get proficient . That’s why we’ve added some fantastic new features and enhancements to Visual Studio 2022 v17.11 that will help you find and resolve bugs faster and easier than ever before.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-debugging-and-diagnostic-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding CDN supply-chain attacks with Subresource Integrity (SRI)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discus the recent pollyfill.io supply-chain attack and describe how to protect against similar attacks using Subresource Integrity (SRI)
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/avoiding-cdn-supply-chain-attacks-with-subresource-integrity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postman&#39;s pre-request scripts: how to perform HTTP POST requests (with JSON body) and how to set Cookie authentication.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Postman, you can define scripts to be executed before the beginning of a request. Can we use them to work with endpoints using Cookie Authentication?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/postman-prerequest-script-cookie-auth/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
