<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Factory Pattern Real-World Example in C#: Complete Implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            See Abstract Factory pattern in action with a complete real-world C# example. Step-by-step implementation of a furniture shop system demonstrating families of related objects.
Link to article: https://devleader.ca/2026/02/12/abstract-factory-pattern-realworld-example-in-c-complete-implementation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Having the Wrong AI Dreams?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            (This opinion piece by JetBrains’ Team Lead in AI Development Experience reflects on key takeaways from NeurIPS 2025, a major AI research conference. It explains why these insights matter and considers related signals emerging from other recent research.) Mass layoffs, robots taking control of the planet, a post-truth world. Which of these comes to mind […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/02/are-we-having-the-wrong-ai-dreams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Nemotron 3 Nano 30B MoE model is now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to announce that the NVIDIA Nemotron 3 Nano 30B model with 3B active parameters is now generally available in the Amazon SageMaker JumpStart model catalog. You can accelerate innovation and deliver tangible business value with Nemotron 3 Nano on Amazon Web Services (AWS) without having to manage model deployment complexities. You can power your generative AI applications with Nemotron capabilities using the managed deployment capabilities offered by SageMaker JumpStart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 6.0 Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the beta release of TypeScript 6.0! To get started using the beta, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@beta TypeScript 6.0 is a unique release in that we intend f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-6-0-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot Testing for .NET Brings AI-powered Unit Tests to Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot testing for .NET makes it dramatically faster and more convenient to generate high-quality unit tests without leaving your code. Today, we’re excited to announce that this capability is now generally available in Visual Studio 2026 v18.3. This release brings
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/github-copilot-testing-for-dotnet-available-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Prompt - Why and How to Fine-tune Your Own Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large Language Models (LLMs) have reached a point where general intelligence is no longer the bottleneck. The real challenge in enterprise AI systems behavioral alignment ensuring models that produce consistent, reliable, policy-compliant outputs on a scale. Prompt engineering and Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) are powerful but they do n
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/beyond-the-prompt-why-and-how-to-fine-tune-your-own-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Unplugged on PyTV – A Free Online Python Conference for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The PyCharm team loves being part of the global Python community. From PyCon US to EuroPython to every PyCon in between, we enjoy the atmosphere at conferences, as well as meeting people who are as passionate about Python as we are. This includes everyone: professional Python developers, data scientists, Python hobbyists and students. However, we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2026/02/python-unplugged-on-pytv/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Amazon Bedrock throttling and service availability: A comprehensive guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to implement robust error handling strategies that can help improve application reliability and user experience when using Amazon Bedrock. We&#39;ll dive deep into strategies for optimizing performances for the application with these errors. Whether this is for a fairly new application or matured AI application, in this post you will be able to find the practical guidelines to operate with on these errors.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swann provides Generative AI to millions of IoT Devices using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to implement intelligent notification filtering using Amazon Bedrock and its gen-AI capabilities. You&#39;ll learn model selection strategies, cost optimization techniques, and architectural patterns for deploying gen-AI at IoT scale, based on Swann Communications deployment across millions of devices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/swann-provides-generative-ai-to-millions-of-iot-devices-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How LinqAlpha assesses investment theses using Devil’s Advocate on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LinqAlpha is a Boston-based multi-agent AI system built specifically for institutional investors. The system supports and streamlines agentic workflows across company screening, primer generation, stock price catalyst mapping, and now, pressure-testing investment ideas through a new AI agent called Devil’s Advocate. In this post, we share how LinqAlpha uses Amazon Bedrock to build and scale Devil’s Advocate.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-linqalpha-assesses-investment-theses-using-devils-advocate-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock language-specific rich symbol context using new find_symbol tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Refactoring at scale is a time-consuming and error-prone process for developers. In large codebases, developers have relied on manual searches and incremental edits across multiple files to accomplish these tasks. Modern development workflows depend on fast and accurate code navigation to avoid these pitfalls. When developers refactor exist
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/unlock-language-specific-rich-symbol-context-using-new-find_symbol-tool 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I suppress the hover effects when I put a Win32 common controls ListView in single-click mode?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer had a Win32 common controls ListView in single-click mode. This has a side effect of enabling hover effects: When the mouse hovers over an item, the cursor changes to a hand, and the item gets highlighted in the hot-track color. How can they suppress these hover effects while still having single-click activation? When the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260211-00/?p=112057 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy to Azure App Service deployment slots with azd</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deploy to Azure App Service slots with azd deploy Missed deploying to an App Service slot? Now you can—without workarounds or manual scripts. What&#39;s new? Before, azd deploy could only deploy to the default production slot. Now, azd understands the slots you define in Bicep a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azd-app-service-slot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Azure Cosmos DB Performance with Azure Advisor Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the first post of this series, we introduced how Azure Advisor helps Azure Cosmos DB users uncover opportunities to optimize efficiency and make smarter decisions. This follow-up dives deeper into one
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/maximize-azure-cosmos-db-performance-with-azure-advisor-recommendations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Syringe Class: Needlr&#39;s Fluent API Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deep dive into Needlr&#39;s Syringe class and its fluent API for configuring dependency injection, discovery strategies, and type registration in C#.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/11/the-syringe-class-needlrs-fluent-api-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Rust 2025: Popularity, Trends, and Future</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Based on findings from the JetBrains Developer Ecosystem Survey Report 2025, The State of Rust 2025 offers a detailed look at how the Rust ecosystem is evolving – how developers use Rust today, which tools they use, how much they rely on AI tools in their workflows, and where the language is gaining momentum. With […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2026/02/11/state-of-rust-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best AI Models for Coding: Accuracy, Integration, and Developer Fit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI models and coding assistants have become essential tools for developers. Today, developers rely on large language models (LLMs) to accelerate coding, improve code quality, and reduce repetitive work across the entire development lifecycle. From intelligent code completion to refactoring, debugging, and documentation, AI-powered tools are now embedded directly into daily workflows. Drawing on insights […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/02/the-best-ai-models-for-coding-accuracy-integration-and-developer-fit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harness engineering: leveraging Codex in an agent-first world</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By Ryan Lopopolo, Member of the Technical Staff
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/harness-engineering 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Efficient String Prefix Checks — StartsWith() vs. IndexOf()</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using IndexOf() for checking if a string starts with a specific value in .NET is inefficient and unclear. This approach performs unnecessary work and obscures intent.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/02/11/microsoft-net-code-analysis-efficient-string-prefix-checks-startswith-vs-indexof/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects with Spargine: Modern Password Hashing Using PasswordHasher</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure password hashing is vital for application security. The PasswordHasher class in Spargine for .NET 10 consolidates previous hashing implementations into a single solution that supports various modern algorithms. This enhances flexibility and ensures robust security while simplifying usage, making it essential for developers aiming to protect user credentials effectively.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/02/11/boost-your-net-projects-with-spargine-modern-password-hashing-using-passwordhasher/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 11 Preview 1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 22:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the first preview release of .NET 11! We just shipped our first preview release, adding to some major enhancements across the .NET Runtime, SDK, libraries, C#, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more. Check out the full release notes linked below and get started today. [cta-button align=&amp;quot;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-11-preview-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 20:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are releasing patches for our self‑hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly recommend that all customers stay on the latest, most secure version of Azure DevOps Server. The latest release, Azure DevOps Server, is available from the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/february-patches-for-azure-devops-server-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework February 2026 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for February 2026. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of February 10, 2026. This update contains secu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-february-2026-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon uses Amazon Nova models to automate operational readiness testing for new fulfillment centers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock can be used to implement an AI-powered image recognition solution that automates the detection and validation of module components, significantly reducing manual verification efforts and improving accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-uses-amazon-nova-models-to-automate-operational-readiness-testing-for-new-fulfillment-centers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iberdrola enhances IT operations using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Iberdrola, one of the world’s largest utility companies, has embraced cutting-edge AI technology to revolutionize its IT operations in ServiceNow. Through its partnership with AWS, Iberdrola implemented different agentic architectures using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, targeting three key areas: optimizing change request validation in the draft phase, enriching incident management with contextual intelligence, and simplifying change model selection using conversational AI. These innovations reduce bottlenecks, help teams accelerate ticket resolution, and deliver consistent and high-quality data handling throughout the organization.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building real-time voice assistants with Amazon Nova Sonic compared to cascading architectures</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Nova Sonic delivers real-time, human-like voice conversations through the bidirectional streaming interface. In this post, you learn how Amazon Nova Sonic can solve some of the challenges faced by cascaded approaches, simplify building voice AI agents, and provide natural conversational capabilities. We also provide guidance on when to choose each approach to help you make informed decisions for your voice AI projects.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-real-time-voice-assistants-with-amazon-nova-sonic-compared-to-cascading-architectures/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI-Powered Apps with Azure Cosmos DB and the Vercel AI SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Vercel AI SDK is an open-source TypeScript toolkit that provides the core building blocks for integrating AI into any JavaScript application. It works with 20+ AI providers out of the box—including OpenAI, Azure OpenAI, Anthropic, Google, Mistral, and more—so you can write your code once and switch pro
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/building-ai-powered-apps-azure-cosmos-db-vercel-ai-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standardizing HLSL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The HLSL team is excited to announce the formation of Ecma Technical Committee 57; a committee to standardize the High Level Shading Language. The formation of this committee marks an important milestone in HLSL&#39;s development and strengthens Microsoft&#39;s commitment to HLSL
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/standardizing-hlsl 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can high-temperature superconductors transform the power infrastructure of datacenters?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the demand for AI and data-intensive computing is on the rise, the need for efficient and reliable power delivery is critical. The post Can high-temperature superconductors transform the power infrastructure of datacenters? appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/can-high-temperature-superconductors-transform-the-power-infrastructure-of-datacenters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did Windows 95 get permission to put the Weezer video &lt;i&gt;Buddy Holly&lt;/i&gt; on the CD?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I noted that the Windows 95 CD contained a variety of multimedia extras, partly because they were fun, and partly to show off Windows 95&#39;s multimedia capabilities. One of those multime
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260210-00/?p=112052 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | February 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? C# allows digit separators (_) in numeric literals to make large numbers more readable, e.g., int num = 1_000_000; is valid and equals one million. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 🔗 Links Here’s the latest from the developer community. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/02/10/dotinsights-february-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardened Images Are Free. Now What?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Hardened Images are now free, covering Alpine, Debian, and over 1,000 images including databases, runtimes, and message buses. For security teams, this changes the economics of container vulnerability management. DHI includes security fixes from Docker’s security team, which simplifies security response. Platform teams can pull the patched base image and redeploy quickly. But free...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hardened-images-free-now-what/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Databao: The JetBrains Tool That Lets You Talk to Your Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we build tools that help teams work with complex systems in a more productive and enjoyable way. As AI becomes part of everyday workflows, a new challenge is emerging for data teams: How can you enable AI-assisted analytics without sacrificing accuracy, transparency, or control over data? Today, we’re introducing Databao, a new data […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/databao/2026/02/introducing-databao/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[New Livestream] Go 1.26 Release Party</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for the Go 1.26 Release Party, where we’ll celebrate the latest Go release together with the community. In this livestream, Go experts will walk through what’s new in Go 1.26, why the changes matter, and how they impact real-world Go development. Date: February 19, 2026 Time: 4:00 – 5:30 pm UTC The celebration […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2026/02/10/new-livestream-go-1-26-release-party/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to Use Abstract Factory Pattern in C#: Decision Guide with Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn when to use Abstract Factory pattern in C# with clear decision criteria, code examples, and scenarios. Understand the signs that indicate Abstract Factory is the right choice.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/10/when-to-use-abstract-factory-pattern-in-c-decision-guide-with-examples 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Local Models to Agent Workflows: Building a Deep Research Solution with Microsoft Agent Framework on Microsoft Foundry Local</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction: A New Paradigm for AI Application Development In enterprise AI application development, we often face this dilemma: while cloud-based large language models are powerful
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/from-local-models-to-agent-workflows-building-a-deep-research-solution-with-microsoft-agent-framework-on-microsoft-foundry-local 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Scholarships from the JetBrains Foundation – Applications Are Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The JetBrains Foundation is offering up to 40 full scholarships for the Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence BSc program at Neapolis University Pafos starting this year. Find the complete program details here. What’s New for 2026 These scholarships are comprehensive, covering tuition, accommodation, medical insurance, visa fees, and a monthly stipend (€300). Graduates of programs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2026/02/10/full-scholarships-from-the-jetbrains-foundation-applications-are-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing strongly-typed IDs in .NET for safer domain models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:44:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we know that user requests can be unpredictable. When they request data, it is either successfully returned or not found. However, a &amp;quot;not found&amp;quot; result usually happens in two ways. First, the user might request a record, such as a basketball player, by passing an ID
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/pimplementing-strongly-typed-ids-in-net-for-safer-domain-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: .NET Projects and the Tools Behind Them</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 07:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference – the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the people […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2026/02/10/open-source-in-focus-dotnet-projects-and-the-tools-behind-them/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot reference implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post dives deeper into the implementation architecture for the Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automated-reasoning-checks-rewriting-chatbot-reference-implementation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Travel in Azure SQL with Temporal Tables</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications often need to know what data looked like before. Who changed it, when it changed, and what the previous values were. Rebuilding that history in application code is tedious and error prone. This is especially valuable when exposing a database to an AI agent through MCP servers like SQL MCP Server, where information discovery mat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/time-travel-in-azure-sql-with-temporal-tables 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale LLM fine-tuning with Hugging Face and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how this integrated approach transforms enterprise LLM fine-tuning from a complex, resource-intensive challenge into a streamlined, scalable solution for achieving better model performance in domain-specific applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-llm-fine-tuning-with-hugging-face-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Relic transforms productivity with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Working with the Generative AI Innovation Center, New Relic NOVA (New Relic Omnipresence Virtual Assistant) evolved from a knowledge assistant into a comprehensive productivity engine. We explore the technical architecture, development journey, and key lessons learned in building an enterprise-grade AI solution that delivers measurable productivity gains at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-relic-transforms-productivity-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate agentic application development with a full-stack starter template for Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to deploy Fullstack AgentCore Solution Template (FAST) to your Amazon Web Services (AWS) account, understand its architecture, and see how to extend it for your requirements. You will learn how to build your own agent while FAST handles authentication, infrastructure as code (IaC), deployment pipelines, and service integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-agentic-application-development-with-a-full-stack-starter-template-for-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent-to-agent collaboration: Using Amazon Nova 2 Lite and Amazon Nova Act for multi-agent systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how agent-to-agent collaboration on Amazon Bedrock works in practice, using Amazon Nova 2 Lite for planning and Amazon Nova Act for browser interaction, to turn a fragile single-agent setup into a predictable multi-agent system.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/agent-to-agent-collaboration-using-amazon-nova-2-lite-and-amazon-nova-act-for-multi-agent-systems/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should I do if a wait call reports &lt;CODE&gt;WAIT_&lt;WBR&gt;ABANDONED&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you call a wait function like Wait­For­Single­Object and receive the code WAIT_ABANDONED, what does it mean and what should you do? The documentation says that WAIT_ABANDONED means that you successfully claimed a mutex, but the thread that previously owned the mutex failed t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260209-00/?p=112049 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:34:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Better late than never, as I’m writing this in early February 2026… First, here are a few links to past years in review:
My 2017 Year in Review My 2018 Year in Review My 2019 Year in Review My 2020 Year in Review My 2021 Year in Review My 2022 Year in Review My 2023 Year in Review My 2024 Year in Review My Year in Review Post Checklist
Now on to the various categories…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Service Discovery in C# with Needlr: How It Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Needlr&#39;s automatic service discovery works in C# with convention-based registration, type scanning, and the DoNotAutoRegister attribute for .NET applications.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/09/automatic-service-discovery-in-c-with-needlr-how-it-works 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting more information in MSBuild binlogs with property tracking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSBuild binary logs (binlogs) are a powerful tool for diagnosing build issues. If you&#39;re not familiar with binlogs, check out my post Exploring a MSBuild binary log using the binary log viewer to get started, or Stop using diagnostic verbosity in MSBuild to understand why binlogs are better than diagnostic verbosity. By default, binlogs capture a lot of information, but you can get even more details about…
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing ChatGPT to GenAI.mil</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI for Government announces the deployment of a custom ChatGPT on GenAI.mil, bringing secure, safety-forward AI to U.S. defense teams.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bringing-chatgpt-to-genaimil 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing ads in ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI begins testing ads in ChatGPT to support free access, with clear labeling, answer independence, strong privacy protections, and user control.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/testing-ads-in-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolate the swiyu Public Beta management APIs using YARP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at hardening the security for the swiyu public beta infrastructure. The generic containers provide both management APIs and wallet APIs which support the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations 1.0 specification. The management APIs require both network protection and application security. This post looks at implementing the network isolation. Code: https://github.com/swiss-ssi-group/swiyu-passkeys-idp-loi-loa Blogs in this […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2026/02/09/isolate-the-swiyu-public-beta-management-apis-using-yarp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over Optimism of Rewrites in Software Engineering - Dev Leader Weekly 126</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 17:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss rewrites, refactors, and the constant inaccurate optimism as developers.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/08/over-optimism-of-rewrites-in-software-engineering-dev-leader-weekly-126 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2026-02-08</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 17:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/08/weekly-recap-20260208 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Factory vs Factory Method Pattern in C#: Key Differences Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understand the differences between Abstract Factory and Factory Method patterns in C# with code examples, use cases, and guidance on when to use each pattern.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/08/abstract-factory-vs-factory-method-pattern-in-c-key-differences-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects with Spargine: Global Phone Number and Postal Code Validation Made Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CountryPhonePostalInfoRepository provides an efficient solution for validating phone numbers and postal codes globally, addressing the complexities of varying formats and rules. It offers a centralized API for reliable country-specific validation, enhancing data integrity in applications while simplifying maintenance and development. This tool ensures accurate, consistent validation logic.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/02/08/boost-your-net-projects-with-spargine-global-phone-number-and-postal-code-validation-made-easy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source Generation vs Reflection in Needlr: Choosing the Right Approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2026/07_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2026/07_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compare Needlr&#39;s source generation and reflection strategies for dependency injection in C# to choose the right approach for AOT, performance, and flexibility.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/07/source-generation-vs-reflection-in-needlr-choosing-the-right-approach 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering User Settings in SharePoint Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2026/07_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 01:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2026/07_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            User preferences and settings are fundamental components of modern web applications. When developing SharePoint Framework (SPFx) solutions, the ability to store and manage user-specific configurations across devices and sessions becomes crucial for delivering personalized experiences. This article explores a robust, enterprise-ready pattern fo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/mastering-user-settings-in-sharepoint-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (Nov 2025 - Jan 2026)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 21:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.12.12 and 2026.01.16 registry releases and the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-nov-2025-jan-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured outputs on Amazon Bedrock: Schema-compliant AI responses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re announcing structured outputs on Amazon Bedrock—a capability that fundamentally transforms how you can obtain validated JSON responses from foundation models through constrained decoding for schema compliance. In this post, we explore the challenges of traditional JSON generation and how structured outputs solves them. We cover the two core mechanisms—JSON Schema output format and strict tool use—along with implementation details, best practices, and practical code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Amazon SageMaker HyperPod clusters using the HyperPod CLI and SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use the CLI and the SDK to create and manage SageMaker HyperPod clusters in your AWS account. We walk through a practical example and dive deeper into the user workflow and parameter choices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-clusters-using-the-hyperpod-cli-and-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI Skills Executor in .NET: Bringing Anthropic&#39;s Agent Pattern to the Microsoft Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When Anthropic released their Agent Skills framework, they published a blueprint for how enterprise organizations should structure AI agent capabilities. The pattern is straightforward: package procedural knowledge into composable skills that AI agents can discover and apply contextually. Microsoft, OpenAI, Cursor, and others have already adop
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/dotnet-ai-skills-executor-azure-openai-mcp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate generative AI models with an Amazon Nova rubric-based LLM judge on Amazon SageMaker AI (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the Amazon Nova rubric-based judge feature: what a rubric-based judge is, how the judge is trained, what metrics to consider, and how to calibrate the judge. We chare notebook code of the Amazon Nova rubric-based LLM-as-a-judge methodology to evaluate and compare the outputs of two different LLMs using SageMaker training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-generative-ai-models-with-an-amazon-nova-rubric-based-llm-judge-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masking Sensitive Data in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications often need access to data without needing access to everything. Social Security numbers, email addresses, and phone numbers are common examples. Storing them is required. Exposing them broadly is not. This is especially valuable when exposing a database to an AI agent through MCP servers like SQL MCP Server, where safety and re
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/mask-data-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I prevent the user from changing the widths of ListView columns in version 5 of the common controls?, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we had figured out how to prevent the version 5 ListView Win32 common control from resizing columns, but we noticed that the cursor st
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260206-00/?p=112045 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Factory Design Pattern in C#: Complete Guide with Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Master the Abstract Factory design pattern in C# with complete code examples, real-world scenarios, and practical implementation guidance for creating families of related objects.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/06/abstract-factory-design-pattern-in-c-complete-guide-with-examples 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Korea privacy policy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Korea privacy policy
Link to article: https://openai.com/policies/kr-privacy-policy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making AI work for everyone, everywhere: our approach to localization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI shares its approach to AI localization, showing how globally shared frontier models can be adapted to local languages, laws, and cultures without compromising safety.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/our-approach-to-localization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Soft Delete in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sometimes applications need to remove data without actually losing it. Soft delete keeps rows in the database while making them invisible to normal application access. This is especially valuable when exposing a database to an AI agent through MCP servers like SQL MCP Server, where safety and reversibility matter. Lea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/soft-delete-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Keycloak with ASP.NET Core Using OAuth 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to integrate Keycloak with your .NET 10 API using Docker, Swagger UI with OAuth 2.0 Authorization Code flow, and JWT validation.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/integrate-keycloak-with-aspnetcore-using-oauth-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Associa transforms document classification with the GenAI IDP Accelerator and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Associa collaborated with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to build a generative AI-powered document classification system aligning with Associa’s long-term vision of using generative AI to achieve operational efficiencies in document management. The solution automatically categorizes incoming documents with high accuracy, processes documents efficiently, and provides substantial cost savings while maintaining operational excellence. The document classification system, developed using the Generative AI Intelligent Document Processing (GenAI IDP) Accelerator, is designed to integrate seamlessly into existing workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practical guide to Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to configure and use Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings for media asset search systems, product discovery experiences, and document retrieval applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-practical-guide-to-amazon-nova-multimodal-embeddings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Aspire Apps with Microsoft Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;About the Author&amp;quot;]This is a guest post from Jean-Marc Prieur from Microsoft&#39;s 1ES (One Engineering System) team. We help reduce developer toil across Microsoft by making it easy to build services that are secure and compliant from the start, for instance with Aspire and Entra ID.[/alert] TL;D
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/securing-dotnet-aspire-apps-with-microsoft-entra-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Framework 3.5 Moves to Standalone Deployment in new versions of Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The deployment model of .NET Framework 3.5 for future versions of Windows is changing. Starting with Windows 11 Insider Preview Build 27965, .NET Framework 3.5 must be obtained as a standalone installer and is no longer included as an optional Windows component. .NET Framework 3.5 is now available as a standalone installer for legacy
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-framework-3-5-moves-to-standalone-deployment-in-new-versions-of-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.7-1 and 1.24.13-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-7-1-and-1-24-13-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Enable Microsoft Entra ID for Azure Cosmos DB (NoSQL)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Strengthen Identity Security and Eliminate Account Keys Identity is becoming the new security perimeter. As organizations modernize their cloud applications, long‑lived secrets and shared keys introduce unnecessary risk. Azure Cosmos DB now fully supports Microsoft Entra ID for both control plane and data plane access, giving custo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/how-to-enable-microsoft-entra-id-for-azure-cosmos-db-nosql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I prevent the user from changing the widths of ListView columns in version 5 of the common controls?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we saw how to prevent the user from changing the widths of ListView columns, but the technique required version 6 of the common controls. What if you&#39;re stuck in the dark
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260205-00/?p=112042 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a .NET Log Analysis System using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Log analysis helps you maintain reliable applications by identifying issues, troubleshooting problems, and gaining operational insights. Traditional log analysis struggles with unstructured data and requires hours of manual work to extract meaningful patterns. Generative AI transforms this process by automatically identifying anomalies, understanding context, and surfacing specific recommendations without complex configuration. In this post, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/building-a-net-log-analysis-system-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending Qodana: Adding Custom Code Inspections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Qodana is a static code analysis tool that brings code inspections and quick-fixes from JetBrains IDEs to the realm of continuous integration. It can be run in the cloud, executed from a Docker container, integrated into CI/CD pipelines, or invoked through a JetBrains IDE. Qodana already offers an impressive suite of inspections, but it is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/02/extending-qodana-adding-custom-code-inspections/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Needlr: Fluent DI for .NET Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to install and configure Needlr for dependency injection in .NET with step-by-step setup, NuGet packages, and your first fluent DI application.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/05/getting-started-with-needlr-fluent-di-for-net-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 lowers the cost of cell-free protein synthesis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An autonomous lab combining OpenAI’s GPT-5 with Ginkgo Bioworks’ cloud automation cut cell-free protein synthesis costs by 40% through closed-loop experimentation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-lowers-protein-synthesis-cost 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Trusted Access for Cyber</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces Trusted Access for Cyber, a trust-based framework that expands access to frontier cyber capabilities while strengthening safeguards against misuse.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/trusted-access-for-cyber 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – February 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            February is a strange little month. Short, quiet, and typically uneventful. There are fewer distractions and fewer launches, which makes it the ideal time to slow down and take a look at what is actually driving the tech world at the moment. This issue leans into that calm, with Trisha Gee joining us as our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/02/java-annotated-monthly-february-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal GitOps for Edge Applications with Azure IoT Operations and Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Building and operating edge applications is a team sport, especially when you&#39;re working with Azure IoT Operations (AIO), custom Rust services, and a mix of cloud and on-prem environments. Over the past year, our team set out to create a minimal GitOps workflow that&#39;s simple enough for small pilots, but
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/minimal-gitops-for-edge-applications-with-azdo 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing OpenAI Frontier</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI Frontier is an enterprise platform for building, deploying, and managing AI agents with shared context, onboarding, permissions, and governance.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-openai-frontier 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5.3-Codex System Card</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT‑5.3-Codex is the most capable agentic coding model to date, combining the frontier coding performance of GPT‑5.2-Codex with the reasoning and professional knowledge capabilities of GPT‑5.2.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-3-codex-system-card 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5.3-Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.3-Codex is a Codex-native agent that pairs frontier coding performance with general reasoning to support long-horizon, real-world technical work.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-3-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating health questions with ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A family shares how ChatGPT helped them prepare for critical cancer treatment decisions for their son alongside expert guidance from his doctors.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/navigating-health-questions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Home for Multi-Agent Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VS Code has become the unified interface for all your coding agents. Manage local, background, and cloud agents in one place, use Claude and Codex agents alongside Copilot, and benefit from open standards like MCP and Agent Skills. Read the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/your-home-for-multi-agent-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
