<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 20:01:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Commands or Events: Which One for Workflow?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 20:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So, you’re building a system around business processes and workflows. Great! But where does the code go that has to orchestrate all this? This is a common question I’ve received, especially from members of my channel on our private Discord. Let’s dive into the guidelines on process managers, bounded contexts, and clever ways to collocate… Read More »Commands or Events: Which One for Workflow? The post Commands or Events: Which One for Workflow?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your CMake Development with Copilot Custom Instructions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 17:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Creating a new CMake project that uses unfamiliar libraries can be daunting and time-consuming. This blog post takes you along on my journey using Copilot to make this easier, and leveraging Custom Instructions to tailor Copilot responses. For a sneak peek, see the outcome of this journey in this repository. Background As C++ developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/boost-your-cmake-development-with-copilot-custom-instructions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring new .NET releases with Dev Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to set up and use dev containers for experimenting with new .NET releases.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-in-dev-container 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Ways to Empower Engineering Teams to Balance Productivity, Security, and Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how Docker’s suite of products empowers industry leaders and their development teams to innovate faster, stay secure, and deliver impactful results.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/empower-engineering-teams-to-balance-productivity-security-innovation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate and improve performance of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to evaluate the performance of your knowledge base, including the metrics and data to use for evaluation. We also address some of the tactics and configuration changes that can improve specific metrics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-and-improve-performance-of-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance enterprise productivity for your LLM solution by becoming an Amazon Q Business data accessor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to enhance enterprise productivity for your large language model (LLM) solution by using the Amazon Q index for ISVs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-enterprise-productivity-for-your-llm-solution-by-becoming-an-amazon-q-business-data-accessor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the winners of the 2025 Powerful Devs Hack Together</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2025 Powerful Devs Hack Together brought developers together to build secure and scalable AI-powered solutions using Power Platform, Azure, AI Builder, and more. If you missed the event, you can still catch up on all the sessions covering AI, automation, security, extensibility, and more! 🎥 Watch here: aka.ms/powerfuldevs/ondemand Technologies Used in the Hackathon We […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-the-winners-of-the-2025-powerful-devs-hack-together 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We’ll fly you to Atlanta, Texas, and getting to your hotel in Atlanta, Georgia is your problem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reading the fine print.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250325-01/?p=110995 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note on the USB-to-PS/2 mouse adapter that came with Microsoft mouse devices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s a purely mechanical adapter that relies on smarts in the mouse itself.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250325-00/?p=110993 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn JavaScript This Week: Start Your Web Applications Journey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JavaScript is the backbone of modern web development, powering dynamic websites and creating interactive user experiences. It’s an essential programming language, whether you’re just starting out or already an experienced developer. JetBrains Academy’s new free course, Introduction to JavaScript, provides a clear and structured approach to mastering JavaScript quickly and effectively. Why learn JavaScript? Why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/03/25/course-javascript/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core delegated Microsoft OBO access token management (Entra only)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 12:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog shows how to implement a delegated Microsoft On-Behalf-Of flow in ASP.NET Core, and has a focus on access token management. The solution uses Microsoft.Identity.Web to implement the different flows and it really simple to implement, when you know how to use the Nuget package and use the correct Microsoft documentation. The application can […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/03/25/asp-net-core-delegated-microsoft-obo-access-token-management-entra-only/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding EF Core Change Tracking: How It Works Under the Hood</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:16:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core (EF Core) makes data handling easy. We all are leveraging its conciseness, flexibility, and rich features in our projects. However, have you ever wondered what goes under the hood? How has EF Core detached us from SQL queries? Today, I will disclose the curtain behind EF Core
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-ef-core-change-tracking-how-it-works-under-the-hood/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending Claude with External Tools: MCPs in Action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 09:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Model Context Protocol (MCP) breaks through Claude&#39;s knowledge limitations by enabling real-time web search and external tool integration through the desktop application.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/extend-claude-model-context-protocol/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a software bill of materials (SBOM) for an open-source NuGet package</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss several tools you can use to create a software bill of materials (SBOM) for an application or a NuGet package
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-software-bill-of-materials-sbom-for-an-open-source-nuget-package/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: An In-Depth Look at CallerMemberName (and some Compile-Time trivia)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s dive deep into the CallerMemberName attribute and explore its usage from multiple angles. We’ll see various methods of invoking it, shedding light on how it is defined at compile time.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/callermembername-attribute/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2503.24: misc bug fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2503.24, which can be downloaded here. This release includes everything in the previous 2501.30 release, plus the following bug fixes: Fix capture-time crash introduced in 2501.30 in CPU write tracking code Fix capture-time issue with reserved resources, that could cause replay-time corruption for some UE5 captures Fix PIXBeginCapture() deadlocking for Timing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2503-24 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Substantial Wolverine 3.11 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Critter Stack community just made a pretty big Wolverine 3.11 release earlier today with 5 brand new contributors making their first pull requests! The highlights are: Wolverine 4.0 is also under way, but there will be at least some Wolverine.HTTP improvements in the 3.* branch before we get to 4.0. Big thanks to the … Continue reading Pretty Substantial Wolverine 3.11 Release →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/03/24/pretty-substantial-wolverine-3-11-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IngressNightmare: Critical Zero-Day Kubernetes Vulnerabilities Put Thousands of Clusters at Risk (March 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A set of ‘critical’ zero-day vulnerabilities, collectively named IngressNightmare, have been discovered in the widely used Ingress-NGINX Controller for Kubernetes that can result in a ‘full takeover‘ of a Kubernetes cluster! These flaws expose over 6,500 publicly exposed clusters to the risk of unauthenticated remote code execution (RCE) and privilege escalation, putting sensitive data and […] The article IngressNightmare: Critical Zero-Day Kubernetes Vulnerabilities Put Thousands of Clusters at Risk (March 2025) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Conf 2025: Learn, Build, and Connect with the Community</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for the 5th annual Azure Cosmos DB Conf, a free virtual developer event co-hosted by Microsoft and the Azure Cosmos DB community. This is your opportunity to learn from Microsoft product managers, industry experts, and real-world customers who are building applications with Azure Cosmos DB. This year, we received over 100 session proposals […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-conf-2025-learn-build-and-connect-with-the-community 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xbox &#43; .NET Aspire: Transforming Local Development Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how the Xbox services team leveraged .NET Aspire to boost their team&#39;s productivity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/xboxs-usage-of-aspire-transforming-development-practices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: API Interaction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog posts (1,2), we created integration tests that interact with UI components and assert different properties of UI components. However, sometimes we need to check the internal state of our plugin or invoke some method to simplify or speed up the test and avoid too many UI interactions. Let’s explore exactly how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/03/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-api-interaction/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure APIs with Data API Builder, Keycloak, and SQL Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore how to create a secure, on-premises API using Data API Builder (DAB), Keycloak, and SQL Server. You’ll learn to set up JSON Web Token (JWT) authentication with Role-Based Access Control (RBAC), Attribute-Based Access Control (ABAC), and Row-Level Security (RLS), ideal for secure business scenarios. Want to replicate this setup?All the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/secure-apis-with-data-api-builder-keycloak-and-sql-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: New Releases, OpenAI vs. DeepSeek, and Compose Hot Reload</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, Kotlin fans! Kodee’s back with another roundup of the latest updates and stories from the Kotlin world. Grab your favorite drink, sit back, and enjoy! Kotlin YouTube spotlight Check out our latest YouTube videos and Shorts – sit back, relax, and enjoy!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/03/kodee-s-kotlin-roundup-new-releases-openai-vs-deepseek-and-compose-hot-reload/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Visual Studio Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Visual Studio Hub is here! Keeping up with the latest Visual Studio updates, features, and resources can feel like a full-time job. We’ve heard it time and time again—you want a simpler way to stay informed without digging through scattered blog posts, release notes, and social media updates. That’s why we created Visual Studio […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-hub 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code update – March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the latest updates for Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code featuring tenant switching, new capabilities for declarative agents, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/teams-toolkit-for-visual-studio-code-update-march-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On how different Windows ABIs choose how to pass 32-bit values in 64-bit registers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Surveying the options and looking for commonalities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250324-00/?p=110988 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable continuous backup for multi-region write account</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB already delivers 99.999% availability with multi-region write capability and continuous backup for point-in-time restores within a 7 or 30 day retention period. Now, we’re making it even better! Going forward – You can migrate existing single region write region with point in time restore capability to support multi-region write. You can enable […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/enable-continuous-backup-for-multi-region-write-account 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose the Right LLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant is now multimodel! This is an exciting development, but what does it actually mean for you? It means AI Assistant is now more adaptable. It combines the strengths of different AI models, from the deep reasoning of large ones to the speed of compact ones, and even the privacy of local ones. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/how-to-choose-the-right-llm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment l’IA générative impacte-t-elle l’expérience développeur?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 07:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adlene Sifi explore l’impact de l’IA générative sur l’expérience des développeurs. Dans cet article, nous allons tenter de déterminer s’il existe un lien entre l’utilisation de l’IA générative (ex. : GitHub Copilot) et l’expérience développeur (DevEx). Nous souhaitons vérifier plus précisément si l’utilisation de l’IA générative a un impact positif sur l’expérience développeur. Nous tenterons même […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/comment-lia-generative-impacte-t-elle-lexperience-developpeur 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does generative AI impact Developer Experience?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 07:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adlene Sifi explores the impact of generative AI on developer experience. In this article, we will try to determine if there is a link between the use of generative AI (e.g., GitHub Copilot) and developer experience (DevEx). Specifically, we aim to verify whether the use of generative AI has a positive impact on developer experience. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/how-does-generative-ai-impact-developer-experience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify StringBuilder Usage with Spargine’s StringBuilderExtensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_03_2025/23_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_03_2025/23_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a collection of open-source assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, created by the author since .NET 2&#39;s launch. The StringBuilderExtensions enhance StringBuilder&#39;s performance and usability, featuring methods for efficient data appending.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/23/boost-your-net-projects-simplify-stringbuilder-usage-with-spargines-stringbuilderextensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is SAST? A Guide to Static Application Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is brought to you by Thinus Swart, draft.dev. Static application security testing (SAST) is a method for identifying vulnerabilities in application source code, binaries, or bytecode early in the software development lifecycle (SDLC). By analyzing code before it’s compiled or run, SAST allows developers to catch potential security flaws before they can be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/what-is-sast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vibe Coding - Dev Leader Weekly 88</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the hot topic of Vibe Coding and what it means for you!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/22/vibe-coding-dev-leader-weekly-88 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Code Analysis in STEM: Protecting Work That Affects the World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 08:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Qodana, we champion code quality for businesses and enterprise development teams, but it has other crucial applications, and implications. Not only can good (and bad!) code be felt in the digital products we all know and use every day, but its impact also extends to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM). As STEM disciplines […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/03/code-analysis-in-stem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-03-21</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 04:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/22/weekly-recap-20250321 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Pattern Validation in ASP.NET Core With FluentValidation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Elevate your ASP.NET Core configuration with FluentValidation integration that catches configuration errors at startup, preventing silent failures and runtime exceptions with more expressive validation rules than Data Annotations.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/options-pattern-validation-in-aspnetcore-with-fluentvalidation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Model Context Protocol (MCP) in Azure AI Foundry: Create an MCP Server with Azure AI Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 22:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to integrate Azure AI Foundry&#39;s Agent Service with Claude Desktop using the Model Context Protocol (MCP) for powerful integration for MCP clients.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/integrating-azure-ai-agents-mcp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI enabled virtual IT troubleshooting assistant using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how to build a GenAI powered virtual IT troubleshooting assistant using Amazon Q Business. This innovative solution integrates with popular ITSM tools like ServiceNow, Atlassian Jira, and Confluence to streamline information retrieval and enhance collaboration across your organization. By harnessing the power of generative AI, this assistant can significantly boost operational efficiency and provide 24/7 support tailored to individual needs. Learn how to set up, configure, and leverage this solution to transform your enterprise information management.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process formulas and charts with Anthropic’s Claude on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how you can use these multi-modal generative AI models to streamline the management of technical documents. By extracting and structuring the key information from the source materials, the models can create a searchable knowledge base that allows you to quickly locate the data, formulas, and visualizations you need to support your work.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/process-formulas-and-charts-with-anthropics-claude-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate IT operations with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a comprehensive AIOps solution that combines various AWS services such as Amazon Bedrock, AWS Lambda, and Amazon CloudWatch to create an AI assistant for effective incident management. This solution also uses Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon Bedrock Agents. The solution uses the power of Amazon Bedrock to enable the deployment of intelligent agents capable of monitoring IT systems, analyzing logs and metrics, and invoking automated remediation processes.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removal of Deprecated SharePoint &amp; OneDrive Permission Resource Properties</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 15:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are announcing the phased rollout of an update to remove the grantedTo and grantedToIdentities properties from the Permission resource type in Microsoft Graph.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/removal-of-deprecated-sharepoint-onedrive-permission-resource-properties 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the critical section that let multiple threads enter a block of code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It had one job.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250321-00/?p=110984 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.47 Is Here With Folding Support for Multiline Comments, New AI Chat Functionality, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 13:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using our Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.47 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2025/03/fleet-1-47-is-here-with-folding-support-for-multiline-comments-new-ai-chat-functionality-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign Up for the free Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2025 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 11:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every year we run Pure Virtual C++: a free one-day virtual conference for the whole C++ community. Next month we’re doing it again! Sign-up for free to get access to our five live sessions and a host of pre-conference content. The live event will start at April 30th 14:00 UTC. Videos will be available to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/sign-up-for-the-free-pure-virtual-c-2025-conference 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Azure AI Foundry Blog!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the Azure AI Foundry Blog—your essential guide to building, customizing, and scaling AI solutions with Microsoft’s open and modular AI platform.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/welcome-to-azure-ai-foundry-blog 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Java, JS and Python support in Test Plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce new capabilities in Azure Test Plans that will enhance your testing workflows. This feature is currently available in Public Preview. You can find instructions at the end of the article on how to request it for your Azure DevOps project. With this latest release, we are introducing the ability to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/introducing-java-javascript-and-python-support-in-azuredevops-test-plans 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>引入对SLNX的支持，.NET CLI 中更简洁的解决方案文件格式</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Chet Husk的Introducing support for SLNX, a new, simpler solution file format in the .NET CLI 多年来，解决方案文件已成为 .NET 和 Visual Studio 体验中的一部分，并且它们一直拥有相同的自定义格式。最近，Visual Studio 解决方案团队已开始预览一种新的基于 XML 格式的解决方案文件格式，称为 SLNX。从 .NET SDK 9.0.200 开始，dotnet CLI 支持生成这些文件并与之交互，其方式与使用现有解决方案文件的方式相同。在本文的其余部分，我们将展示如何迁移到新格式，探索 dotnet CLI 对该格式的新支持，并讨论该格式走向正式发布的后续计划。 快速开始 在 SDK 9.0.200 之前，创建 SLNX 文件的唯一方式是通过 Visual Studio 设置。勾选 环境 &amp;gt; 预览功能 &amp;gt; 使用解决方案文件持久性模型 设置后，用户可以将现有的 .sln 文件另存为新的 .slnx 格式。 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e5%bc%95%e5%85%a5%e5%af%b9slnx%e7%9a%84%e6%94%af%e6%8c%81%ef%bc%8c-net-cli-%e4%b8%ad%e6%9b%b4%e7%ae%80%e6%b4%81%e7%9a%84%e8%a7%a3%e5%86%b3%e6%96%b9%e6%a1%88%e6%96%87%e4%bb%b6%e6%a0%bc%e5%bc%8f 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Performance Gains in .NET: Evaluating the ‘in’ Modifier for Method Parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The in modifier, introduced in C# 9.0, allows passing read-only references to method parameters, promoting immutability. While it clarifies intent it can also enhance performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/21/unlock-performance-gains-in-net-evaluating-the-in-modifier-for-method-parameters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing DirectX Raytracing 1.2, PIX, Neural Rendering and more at GDC 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 21:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today in the DirectX State of the Union at GDC 2025, we proudly showcased the next evolution in graphics with the announcement of DirectX Raytracing (DXR) 1.2. This update promises groundbreaking performance improvements and breathtaking visual fidelity, marking another milestone in our mission to deliver immersive, realistic experiences to gamers everywhere. We also brought developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/announcing-directx-raytracing-1-2-pix-neural-rendering-and-more-at-gdc-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline AWS resource troubleshooting with Amazon Bedrock Agents and AWS Support Automation Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS provides a powerful tool called AWS Support Automation Workflows, which is a collection of curated AWS Systems Manager self-service automation runbooks. These runbooks are created by AWS Support Engineering with best practices learned from solving customer issues. They enable AWS customers to troubleshoot, diagnose, and remediate common issues with their AWS resources. In this post, we explore how to use the power of Amazon Bedrock Agents and AWS Support Automation Workflows to create an intelligent agent capable of troubleshooting issues with AWS resources.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create generative AI agents that interact with your companies’ systems in a few clicks using Amazon Bedrock in Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock in SageMaker Unified Studio to build a generative AI application to integrate with an existing endpoint and database.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-generative-ai-agents-that-interact-with-your-companies-systems-in-a-few-clicks-using-amazon-bedrock-in-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asure’s approach to enhancing their call center experience using generative AI and Amazon Q in Quicksight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore why Asure used the Amazon Web Services (AWS) post-call analytics (PCA) pipeline that generated insights across call centers at scale with the advanced capabilities of generative AI-powered services such as Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Q in QuickSight. Asure chose this approach because it provided in-depth consumer analytics, categorized call transcripts around common themes, and empowered contact center leaders to use natural language to answer queries. This ultimately allowed Asure to provide its customers with improvements in product and customer experiences.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the multimodal power of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation to transform unstructured data into actionable insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re excited to announce the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation, a powerful, fully managed capability within Amazon Bedrock that seamlessly transforms unstructured multimodal data into structured, application-ready insights with high accuracy, cost efficiency, and scalability.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleashing-the-multimodal-power-of-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-to-transform-unstructured-data-into-actionable-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Box roadmap update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What features and enhancements are planned for Microsoft Dev Box Microsoft Dev Box continues to evolve, providing a secure, scalable, and ready-to-code cloud-based development environment. Over the next few months, significant improvements will focus on three key areas: Ready-to-code environments: Faster setup, enhanced debugging, and GitHub Copilot integration to streamline developer workflows. Developers will benefit […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/microsoft-dev-box-roadmap-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in TeamCity 2025.03: Recipes, Improved Docker and Podman Integration, UI Updates, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity’s first major release of the year, version 2025.03, is now available. It’s packed with new features, including massive UI updates, a new Run in Docker build feature, and JetBrains-crafted recipes available in our Marketplace. UI updates In line with our commitment to make TeamCity easier and more intuitive to use, this release introduces significant […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/teamcity-2025-03-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Data at rest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how Microsoft 365 Certification ensures compliance for data at rest.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-data-at-rest 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforcement of license checks for PSTN Bot calls</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of Microsoft’s feature parity with Teams Phone extensibility, we’re announcing the enforcement of Phone System license checks for Bot-initiated transfers to Teams users. This current gap in our systems will be addressed in June 2025. Microsoft Teams requires that Teams users behind applications such as queue applications require a phone system license and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/enforcement-of-license-checks-for-pstn-bot-calls 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Pull Request Reviews with In-Depth Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 has taken the pull request experience to the next level by making reviews interactive. We previously enabled viewing your pull request comments inline in your working files. Now, the latest update empowers you to add comments directly within the IDE, streamlining the review process. Now, pull request reviewers can conduct deep reviews […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/enhance-pull-request-reviews-with-in-depth-feedback 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What could cause a memory corruption bug to disappear in safe mode?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A simplified execution environment means fewer things that you can stumble over.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250320-00/?p=110981 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.1.20 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 11:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.1.20 release is out! This version includes performance improvements and bug fixes for Kotlin 2.1.0. Here are some highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.1.20 or the release notes on GitHub. How to install Kotlin 2.1.20 Starting from IntelliJ IDEA 2023.3 and Android […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/03/kotlin-2-1-20-released 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Risks of Docker Build Time Arguments and How to Secure Your Secrets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses the security risks of using Docker build-time arguments to pass secrets, and suggests alternative methods for handling secrets securely.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/hidden-risks-of-docker-build-time-arguments-and-how-to-secure-your-secrets 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: Get YouTube Video Transcript from URL for use in Generative AI and RAG Summarization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are times when it’s necessary to download the text transcript of a YouTube video using Python. This can be done with the help of the youtube_transcript_api library. Getting access to the text content of YouTube videos can be extremely helpful when using Generative AI and Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to create summarization, analysis, or […] The article Python: Get YouTube Video Transcript from URL for use in Generative AI and RAG Summarization was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Dynamic Debugging: Full Debuggability for Optimized Builds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past 5 years, we’ve had many incredible opportunities to engage with game developers. From AAA studios to indie developers, the passion for slashing iteration times is significant. Amidst all the fantastic feedback we’ve received for Visual Studio, one sentiment has rung loud and clear: a desire to debug optimized C++ code without sacrificing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/cpp-dynamic-debugging-full-debuggability-for-optimized-builds 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Developer Tools with Authentication Brokers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve used any applications that required connecting your personal Microsoft or Entra ID account, you’re probably familiar with the typical “authentication dance” – you see a browser window pop up, you enter your credentials, then you can close the browser, and the application is magically authenticated. The next application you launch does the same […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//securing-developer-tools-with-authentication-brokers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSTest 3.8: Top 10 features to supercharge your .NET tests!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSTest 3.8 is here! It&#39;s built on your feedback and packed with powerful new features to simplify and smooth your testing experience.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mstest-3-8-highlights 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate generative AI capabilities into Microsoft Office using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we showcase a powerful solution that seamlessly integrates AWS generative AI capabilities in the form of large language models (LLMs) based on Amazon Bedrock into the Office experience. By harnessing the latest advancements in generative AI, we empower employees to unlock new levels of efficiency and creativity within the tools they already use every day.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-generative-ai-capabilities-into-microsoft-office-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From innovation to impact: How AWS and NVIDIA enable real-world generative AI success</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, I will share some of these customers’ remarkable journeys, offering practical insights for any organization looking to harness the power of generative AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/from-innovation-to-impact-how-aws-and-nvidia-enable-real-world-generative-ai-success/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screaming Architecture: Not Driven By Entities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “Manager”, “Builder”, “Factory”, or another technical name in your code structure isn’t Screaming Architecture or Vertical Slices. This post was inspired by the neverending posts I see on LinkedIn about software architecture styles and concepts. Let’s be real: The signal-to-noise ratio isn’t great, and many posts miss context and nuance. So, let’s unpack some thoughts… Read More »Screaming Architecture: Not Driven By Entities The post Screaming Architecture: Not Driven By Entities appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find the IDE features you need with GitHub Copilot and Search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever find yourself needing to locate a specific menu item, command, or option in Visual Studio, but you don’t know its name or location? Do you often struggle to find detailed instructions on using certain features effectively? Now, there’s a solution to get you the information you need right in the IDE. Visual Studio now […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/find-the-ide-features-you-need-with-github-copilot-and-search 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector Search with Azure SQL, Semantic Kernel and Entity Framework Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vector databases like Qdrant and Milvus are specifically designed to efficiently store, manage, and retrieve embeddings. However, many applications already use relational databases like SQL Server or SQL Azure. In such cases, installing and managing another database can be challenging, especially since these vector databases may not offer all the features of a modern relational […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vector-search-with-azure-sql-semantic-kernel-and-entity-framework-core 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Roadmap 2025: Updating the UI, TeamCity Recipes, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, the TeamCity team is working on a number of new initiatives, including updating the UI, TeamCity recipes, Jenkins migration tools, and many others. Read on to learn what our focus is for 2025. Modernizing the TeamCity Enterprise interface In 2025, we’re taking a major step forward in enhancing the TeamCity experience. The modern […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/teamcity-roadmap-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Q Business now available in Europe (Ireland) AWS Region</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Amazon Q Business—a fully managed generative-AI powered assistant that you can configure to answer questions, provide summaries and generate content based on your enterprise data—is now generally available in the Europe (Ireland) AWS Region.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-q-business-now-available-in-europe-ireland-aws-region/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can’t simulate keyboard input with PostMessage, revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If it didn&#39;t go through the input system, it only looks like input as much as the app allows itself to be fooled.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250319-00/?p=110979 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AI Agents for Notebook Debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 12:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debugging computational notebooks can be quite frustrating for a variety of reasons, including issues like out-of-order cell execution, missing data files, and library conflicts. Traditional AI tools often struggle with these problems due to the interactive nature of notebooks, but at JetBrains, we are exploring new solutions. Our research team has developed a prototype of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/using-ai-agents-for-notebook-debugging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Boosting  Performance with Span and Memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications can significantly improve performance by leveraging newer types in Microsoft .NET, such as Span and Memory. These types minimize memory allocation and provide faster data access, making them essential tools for optimizing performance-critical applications. In this article, I will show you Microsoft’s recommended approach for converting a byte[] array to Span and Memory, and … Continue reading Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Boosting Performance with Span and Memory →
Link to article: https://dotnettips.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Agentic Workflows with NVIDIA AgentIQ, Azure AI Foundry and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 03:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce our collaboration with NVIDIA. In Azure AI Foundry, we’ve integrated NVIDIA NIM microservices and the NVIDIA AgentIQ toolkit into Azure AI Foundry—unlocking unprecedented efficiency, performance, and cost optimization for your AI projects. Read more on the announcement here. Optimizing performance with NVIDIA AgentIQ and Semantic Kernel Once your NVIDIA NIM […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/accelerating-agentic-workflows-with-nvidia-agentiq-azure-ai-foundry-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running NVIDIA NeMo 2.0 Framework on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 20:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how to integrate NeMo 2.0 with SageMaker HyperPod to enable efficient training of large language models (LLMs). We cover the setup process and provide a step-by-step guide to running a NeMo job on a SageMaker HyperPod cluster.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/running-nvidia-nemo-2-0-framework-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeMo Retriever Llama 3.2 text embedding and reranking NVIDIA NIM microservices now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the NeMo Retriever Llama3.2 Text Embedding and Reranking NVIDIA NIM microservices are available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, you can now deploy NVIDIA’s optimized reranking and embedding models to build, experiment, and responsibly scale your generative AI ideas on AWS. In this post, we demonstrate how to get started with these models on SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/nemo-retriever-llama-3-2-text-embedding-and-reranking-nvidia-nim-microservices-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Streamlit application with Fabric SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building an application allows you to operationalize the data you have in Microsoft Fabric, such that it can be consumed by stakeholders in your organization to generate business insights. Streamlit is easy to use to build simple applications without needing to know front-end application frameworks like Flask, Django etc. It makes it easier to prototype […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-a-streamlit-application-with-fabric-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Updates for Azure Pipelines Agents Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 18:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To ensure our hosted agents in Azure Pipelines are operating in the most secure and up-to-date environments, we continuously update the supported images and phase out older ones. In October 2024, we announced support for Ubuntu-24.04. Soon, we plan to update the ubuntu-latest image to map to Ubuntu-24.04. Additionally, MacOS 15 Sequoia and Windows 2025 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/upcoming-updates-for-azure-pipelines-agents-images 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 2 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out about the new features in .NET 10 Preview 2 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, C#, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Guardrails announces IAM Policy-based enforcement to deliver safe AI interactions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 18:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re announcing a significant enhancement to Amazon Bedrock Guardrails: AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) policy-based enforcement. This powerful capability enables security and compliance teams to establish mandatory guardrails for every model inference call, making sure organizational safety policies are consistently enforced across AI interactions. This feature enhances AI governance by enabling centralized control over guardrail implementation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-guardrails-announces-iam-policy-based-enforcement-to-deliver-safe-ai-interactions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build your gen AI–based text-to-SQL application using RAG, powered by Amazon Bedrock (Claude 3 Sonnet and Amazon Titan for embedding)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 17:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore using Amazon Bedrock to create a text-to-SQL application using RAG. We use Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet model to generate SQL queries, Amazon Titan in Amazon Bedrock for text embedding and Amazon Bedrock to access these models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-your-gen-ai-based-text-to-sql-application-using-rag-powered-by-amazon-bedrock-claude-3-sonnet-and-amazon-titan-for-embedding/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleash AI innovation with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how SageMaker HyperPod, and its new features introduced at AWS re:Invent 2024, is designed to meet the demands of modern AI workloads, offering a persistent and optimized cluster tailored for distributed training and accelerated inference at cloud scale and attractive price-performance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleash-ai-innovation-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing clinical trials with the power of voice and AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the healthcare industry continues to embrace digital transformation, solutions that combine advanced technologies like audio-to-text translation and LLMs will become increasingly valuable in addressing key challenges, such as patient education, engagement, and empowerment. In this post, we discuss possible use cases for combining speech recognition technology with LLMs, and how the solution can revolutionize clinical trials.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-clinical-trials-with-the-power-of-voice-and-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Docker with TensorFlow Models &amp; TensorFlow.js for a Snake AI Game</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how TensorFlow.js can be used with Docker to run AI/ML in a web browser, using a real-world example of a Snake AI game.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/leveraging-docker-with-tensorflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your GitHub productivity with our new multi-account support!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing your GitHub identity in Visual Studio 2022 just got easier! Our latest update overhauls the GitHub account management experience and improves how you work with multiple accounts, especially for GitHub Copilot and version control scenarios. In this post, we’ll detail how these changes will make your GitHub workflow smoother, from the moment you start […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/boost-your-github-productivity-with-our-new-multi-account-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why didn’t Windows 95 setup use a miniature version of Windows 95 as its fallback GUI?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Avoiding an interim GUI environment.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250318-00/?p=110975 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Build Times with Build Insights: How Activision Cut Call of Duty’s Build Time by 50%</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Slow build times are a major headache for developers, especially in large, complex C++ codebases like game engines. Every minute spent waiting on a build is time that could be used to refine features, resolve issues, or push development forward. Activision faced this challenge with Call of Duty: Modern Warfare II, where prolonged build times […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/optimizing-build-times-with-build-insights-how-activision-cut-call-of-dutys-build-time-by-50 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of OpenID Connect external identity provider support for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the new OpenID Connect identity provider support in Microsoft Entra External ID, now generally available. Simplify user sign-in and partner integrations, and improve conversion rates and user satisfaction by federating with external identity providers like Okta, Amazon, Auth0, and Azure AD B2C.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/openid-connect-external-identity-provider-support-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shout-Out to Kotlin for Server-Side Content Creators!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re using Kotlin for server-side development and sharing your experiences – whether through blog posts, videos, or sample projects – know that we see you, and we want to highlight your work! Recent picks from the community 📖 [Article] From Java to Kotlin — a practical example of how to convert code – Paul […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/03/shout-out-to-kotlin-for-server-side-content-creators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Zero Trust: Never Trust, Always Verify</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft’s 2024 Digital Defense Report found that between July 2023 and July 2024, Microsoft customers faced an astounding 600 million attacks daily from both cybercriminals and nation-state actors. space In this high-risk and rapidly evolving environment, individuals and organizations must not only strengthen digital defenses at every level but also foster a deep and enduring […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/embracing-zero-trust-never-trust-always-verify 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Code Completion: Less Is More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 10:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve been following our journey, you might’ve read our recent blog post on the Complete the Un-Completable: The State of AI Completion in JetBrains IDEs. From that post, you might remember this cool chart on code completions. In April, something exciting happened: our acceptance rate went up while the explicit cancel rate dropped. In […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/ai-code-completion-less-is-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 10:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released another update for v2024.3! You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This new version that brings the following valuable improvements: To see the full list of issues addressed in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2024-3-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating provenance attestations for NuGet packages in GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss software provenance, what attestations say about your software, how they work, and how to create an attestation for a NuGet package
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-provenance-attestations-for-nuget-packages-in-github-actions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 24 and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 08:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA has supported Java 24 since an earlier release, with more enhancements being added in the later releases! I’m often asked, “What’s the best feature of Java 24?” My answer? Why pick just one? 🙂 Java 24 continues to enhance the language with improvements like Simple source files and instance main methods, Primitive Types […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/java-24-and-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Cloudflare Turnstile to an ASP.NET Core website</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 09:05:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have been using Captchas for several years on elmah.io. Not to annoy users (they ARE annoying, I know) but to avoid bots trying to automate password reset requests and similar. We have been using reCAPTCHA from Google but after they announced moving this feature to Google Cloud, we
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/adding-cloudflare-turnstile-to-an-asp-net-core-website/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Serve Restoration in Microsoft Dev Box</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 04:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers grapple with the anxiety of potential data loss due to unforeseen issues, such as accidental deletions, system failures, or even corrupt files. The Dev Box team is addressing this concern with the self-service restoration feature for the Dev Box, designed to put you back in control. This functionality streamlines recovery by allowing direct restorations […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/self-serve-restoration-in-microsoft-dev-box 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing ABAP Support in GitHub Copilot for Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 03:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest release of GitHub Copilot for Eclipse now includes support for ABAP! This update builds on the recent release of code completion and chat integration, offering a robust toolset for developers working within the SAP environment. ABAP remains a critical language in the enterprise space, powering a wide range of business applications, and its […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/introducing-abap-support-in-github-copilot-for-eclipse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to log to Azure Application Insights using ILogger in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Application Insights is a great tool for handling high volumes of logs. How can you configure an ASP.NET application to send logs to Azure Application Insights? What can I do to have Application Insights log my exceptions?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/azure-application-insights-ilogger-aspnetcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
