<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:57:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Elevate customer experience by using the Amazon Q Business custom plugin for New Relic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The New Relic AI custom plugin for Amazon Q Business creates a unified solution that combines New Relic AI’s observability insights and recommendations and Amazon Q Business’s Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) capabilities, in and a natural language interface for east of use. This post explores the use case, how this custom plugin works, how it can be enabled, and how it can help elevate customers’ digital experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker launches the updated inference optimization toolkit for generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, Amazon SageMaker is excited to announce updates to the inference optimization toolkit, providing new functionality and enhancements to help you optimize generative AI models even faster.In this post, we discuss these new features of the toolkit in more detail.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-launches-the-updated-inference-optimization-toolkit-for-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syngenta develops a generative AI assistant to support sales representatives using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Syngenta collaborated with AWS to develop Cropwise AI, a generative AI assistant powered by Amazon Bedrock Agents that helps sales representatives make better seed product recommendations to farmers across North America. The solution transforms the seed selection process by simplifying complex data into natural conversations, providing quick access to detailed seed product information, and enabling personalized recommendations at scale through a mobile app interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specification Usage with Marten for Repository-Free Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 17:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ll jump into real discussions about architecture later in this post, but let’s say that we’re starting the development of a new software system. And for a variety of reasons I’ll try to discuss later, we want to eschew the usage of repository abstractions and be able to use all the power of our persistence … Continue reading Specification Usage with Marten for Repository-Free Development →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/03/specification-usage-with-marten-for-repository-free-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing your AI apps with Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 16:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We previously introduced observability within the Semantic Kernel. For further insights, please refer to our previous blog post, and you can also explore our learn site for additional details. To summarize, observability is an essential aspect of your application stack, particularly in today’s landscape where AI plays a significant role in numerous applications. Given that […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/tracing-your-ai-apps-with-azure-ai-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Containers: Unveiling the Full Potential of Docker for Cloud-Native Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about what Docker does as a suite of software development tools to enhance productivity, improve security, and integrate seamlessly with CI/CD pipelines.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/what-does-docker-do/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks from product support: We’re not smart enough to debug the problem, can you help us?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s not you, it&#39;s me.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241203-00/?p=110601 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Copy Git Permalink Feature in Visual Studio 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the release of the Copy Git Permalink feature in Visual Studio 17.12. This new functionality streamlines the process of sharing code references, enhancing collaboration and ensuring that critical context is preserved. Effortless Code Sharing If you’ve found yourself needing to share code snippets with colleagues, you know the challenges of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-the-copy-git-permalink-feature-in-visual-studio-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Origin-Embedder-Policy: securing embedded resources: Understanding cross-origin security headers - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss the Cross-Origin-Embedder-Policy, the requirements it places on your resources, and why it&#39;s required for some JavaScript APIs
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/understanding-security-headers-part-3-cross-origin-embedder-policy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to bulk insert with EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 08:46:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You may have encountered a situation where your application must insert massive amounts of data at once. Scenarios such as analytics applications, IoT monitoring systems, legacy systems, and data migration critically require bulk insertion of records. Sometimes, you must deal with thousands of records simultaneously, so inserting them will significantly
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/how-to-bulk-insert-with-efcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up your AI inference workloads with new NVIDIA-powered capabilities in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At re:Invent 2024, we are excited to announce new capabilities to speed up your AI inference workloads with NVIDIA accelerated computing and software offerings on Amazon SageMaker. In this post, we will explore how you can use these new capabilities to enhance your AI inference on Amazon SageMaker. We&#39;ll walk through the process of deploying NVIDIA NIM microservices from AWS Marketplace for SageMaker Inference. We&#39;ll then dive into NVIDIA’s model offerings on SageMaker JumpStart, showcasing how to access and deploy the Nemotron-4 model directly in the JumpStart interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock cost savings with the new scale down to zero feature in SageMaker Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today at AWS re:Invent 2024, we are excited to announce a new feature for Amazon SageMaker inference endpoints: the ability to scale SageMaker inference endpoints to zero instances. This long-awaited capability is a game changer for our customers using the power of AI and machine learning (ML) inference in the cloud.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-cost-savings-with-the-new-scale-down-to-zero-feature-in-amazon-sagemaker-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your auto scaling for generative AI inference – Introducing Container Caching in SageMaker Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today at AWS re:Invent 2024, we are excited to announce the new Container Caching capability in Amazon SageMaker, which significantly reduces the time required to scale generative AI models for inference. This innovation allows you to scale your models faster, observing up to 56% reduction in latency when scaling a new model copy and up to 30% when adding a model copy on a new instance. In this post, we explore the new Container Caching feature for SageMaker inference, addressing the challenges of deploying and scaling large language models (LLMs).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Fast Model Loader in SageMaker Inference: Accelerate autoscaling for your Large Language Models (LLMs) – part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today at AWS re:Invent 2024, we are excited to announce a new capability in Amazon SageMaker Inference that significantly reduces the time required to deploy and scale LLMs for inference using LMI: Fast Model Loader. In this post, we delve into the technical details of Fast Model Loader, explore its integration with existing SageMaker workflows, discuss how you can get started with this powerful new feature, and share customer success stories.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Fast Model Loader in SageMaker Inference: Accelerate autoscaling for your Large Language Models (LLMs) – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a detailed, hands-on guide to implementing Fast Model Loader in your LLM deployments. We explore two approaches: using the SageMaker Python SDK for programmatic implementation, and using the Amazon SageMaker Studio UI for a more visual, interactive experience. Whether you’re a developer who prefers working with code or someone who favors a graphical interface, you’ll learn how to take advantage of this powerful feature to accelerate your LLM deployments.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: 2 ways to generate realistic data using Bogus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2024/03_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bogus is a library that generates realistic values for your data. When populating fake user names, instead of Foo and Bar, you can have John and Sarah. Let’s see two ways to define and reuse a Faker definition.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/bogus-data-generation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on nested app authentication and deprecation of Exchange Online legacy tokens</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 19:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this year, the Office Platform Team announced that Exchange Online legacy tokens are deprecated and will be turned off. This is part of Microsoft’s Secure Future Initiative (SFI) to give organizations the tools they need in the current threat landscape. We’ll begin turning off legacy tokens in February 2025. Publishers and developers are actively migrating their Outlook add-ins to use Entra ID tokens through nested app authentication (NAA) and Microsoft Graph instead of legacy tokens.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast and accurate zero-shot forecasting with Chronos-Bolt and AutoGluon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 18:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Chronos models are available for Amazon SageMaker customers through AutoGluon-TimeSeries and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. In this post, we introduce Chronos-Bolt, our latest FM for forecasting that has been integrated into AutoGluon-TimeSeries.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fast-and-accurate-zero-shot-forecasting-with-chronos-bolt-and-autogluon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Finance Automation built a generative AI Q&amp;A chat assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 18:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Finance Automation developed a large language model (LLM)-based question-answer chat assistant on Amazon Bedrock. This solution empowers analysts to rapidly retrieve answers to customer queries, generating prompt responses within the same communication thread. As a result, it drastically reduces the time required to address customer queries. In this post, we share how Amazon Finance Automation built this generative AI Q&amp;amp;A chat assistant using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-finance-automation-built-a-generative-ai-qa-chat-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility improvements in Microsoft 365 PDF export</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 16:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers can leverage the accessibility improvements in PDF export in Word, Excel, and PowerPoint to build more inclusive solutions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/accessibility-improvements-in-microsoft-365-pdf-export 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>使用Semantic Kernel来开启您的AI旅程</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Semantic Kernel (SK) 是由微软开发的一款开源开发工具包，旨在帮助开发者和企业利用最新的人工智能技术构建更智能和复杂的AI驱动解决方案，例如检索增强生成 (RAG) 和智能体 (Agent)。 核心概念 内核（Kernel） 您可以将SK的内核视为一个容器，该容器包含您所需的所有与AI相关的组件，如提示语模板、AI服务和插件。如果将所有的服务和插件提供给内核，则AI会根据需求自动使用它们。SK还提供多项企业级功能，使您可以保证您的AI符合安全要求且在部署后能够持续监控AI的表现。 提示语（Prompt Engineering） 提示语在使用大型语言模型中至关重要。优质的提示语能够显著提升用户体验。SK通过提示语模板（template）的方式来实现自然语言与AI插件的混合使用，让您的提示语变得更加的灵活。 AI服务（AI Services） SK支持多种AI应用场景，包括对话补全，文本生成，嵌入（embedding）生成，图像与文字转换，以及音频与文字转换。此外，SK兼容多个AI服务提供商，如OpenAI，Azure，Google AI， Amazon Bedrock， 以及提供本地推理服务的Ollama等。 插件（Plugins/Functions） SK通过插件支持扩展大型语言模型的功能。插件可以是代码或自然语言，并可集成外部系统，如数据库、API或其他云服务，以便AI解决方案获取动态信息。 矢量存储（Vector Stores） 矢量存储可以被视为存储嵌入的数据库。许多现代数据库已开始提供矢量存储服务，这在构建RAG方案的检索步骤中扮演着重要角色。SK支持市场上大部分的矢量数据库，比如说Azure AI Search，Azure Cosmos DB，Qdrant，Redis， 和Weaviate等。 企业组件（Enterprise Components） SK自项目启动之初便将企业级AI解决方案作为首要目标。SK提供一系列功能以增强AI的安全性，包括筛选器（Filter）和可观察性（Observability）。筛选器可用于过滤提示语，确保不处理不安全的提示，并在生成式AI的回答到达终端用户前进行适当过滤。可观察性确保您在将AI部署到分布式系统时，仍能了解系统内部的运行状态，包括token的使用情况、函数的运行时间、以及大型语言模型的输入输出等。 框架 除了上述核心功能外，SK还提供一下框架，以帮助您构建更复杂的AI解决方案： 智能体框架：利用了SK生态创建和管理AI智能体。 业务流框架：利用了SK生态使企业能更有效地创建，管理和部署完整的AI业务流程。 关于这两个框架的详细介绍，我将在后续文章中单独阐述，敬请期待！ 开始使用 目前，SK支持三种编程语言：C#，Python，和Java。SK的源代码托管在GitHub上。您可以访问我们的仓库以获取源代码，文档和开发示例： C#源代码：semantic-kernel/dotnet at main · microsoft/semantic-kernel C#示例：semantic-kernel/dotnet/samples at main · microsoft/semantic-kernel Python源代码：semantic-kernel/python at main · microsoft/semantic-kernel […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8semantic-kernel%e6%9d%a5%e5%bc%80%e5%90%af%e6%82%a8%e7%9a%84ai%e6%97%85%e7%a8%8b 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Entra External ID Custom URL Domains—now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover Microsoft Entra External ID Custom URL Domains, now generally available (GA). Learn how to enhance the authentication experience by branding login endpoints with your own domain name, creating a seamless, secure, and familiar experience for users.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/custom-url-domains-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message Broker per Tenant with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new feature shown in this post was built by JasperFx Software as part of a client engagement. This is exactly the kind of novel or challenging issue we frequently help our clients solve. If there’s something in your shop’s ongoing efforts where you could use some extra technical help, reach out to sales@jasperfx.net and … Continue reading Message Broker per Tenant with Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/02/message-broker-per-tenant-with-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: Azure Developers – Python Day</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Experience cloud computing with Python on Azure during Python Day 2024!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/azure-developers-python-day-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News flash: Desire for loud cars correlates with psychopathy and sadism</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            More research into loud vehicles.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241202-01/?p=110598 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An analogy about register preservation rules in calling conventions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            And tying it back to unwind codes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241202-00/?p=110595 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Multicloud Security Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enterprises are increasingly adopting multicloud strategies—leveraging a mix of cloud service providers such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services (AWS), and Google Cloud Platform (GCP)—to optimize costs, enhance resilience, and accelerate their digital transformation journeys. The cloud has become the backbone of innovation, scalability, and operational efficiency. With multicloud being such a large part of […] The article Accelerate Your Multicloud Security Strategy was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Insights: Streamlining Variable Analysis with GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tired of spending countless hours troubleshooting errors and unexpected values in your code? Visual Studio 2022 introduces GitHub Copilot Variable Analysis. This powerful tool makes inspecting and analyzing variables from Locals, Autos, watch windows and DataTips effortless, helping you solve issues faster and cutting down on time and frustration. Enhanced Debugging Experience Debugging can often […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/ai-powered-insights-streamlining-variable-analysis-with-github-copilot-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beginner’s Guide to Building Outdoor Light Shows Synchronized to Music with Open Source Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Docker staff solutions architect shares their experience building DIY holiday light displays synchronized to music, offering a step-by-step guide for anyone looking to create their own dazzling show.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/a-beginners-guide-to-building-outdoor-light-shows-open-source-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring in C&#43;&#43;: Top Techniques and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 13:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re a seasoned C++ developer or just starting out, refactoring is a key way you can make your code cleaner, more efficient, and easier to maintain. In this article, we’ll review common refactoring techniques in C++ and explore their benefits, from improving code readability to reducing technical debt. We’ll also look at the main […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/12/refactoring-in-cpp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowering Prices for TeamCity Pipelines | TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Great news – we’re cutting the cost of TeamCity Pipelines! Now, the prices start from USD 15/month. Check out all the pricing options on our website. Why the change? Because we’re committed to making modern, reliable CI/CD solutions affordable for teams of all sizes. Building and shipping great software shouldn’t break the bank. New UI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/lowering-prices-for-teamcity-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NuGet Packages: security risks and best practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NuGet packages offer a convenient way to share code, but many developers download them without reviewing the contents or verifying updates when new versions are released. When you install a NuGet package, you are: Downloading code from unknown authors that has likely not been thoroughly reviewed by others Running it with full permissions on your local machine, potentially exposing your personal data…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/nuget-packages-security-risks-and-best-practices.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Data Science 2024: 6 Key Data Science Trends</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI and LLMs have been hot topics this year, but are they affecting trends in data science and machine learning? What new trends in data science are worth following? Every year, JetBrains collaborates with the Python Software Foundation to carry out the Python Developer Survey, which can offer some useful insight into these questions. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/the-state-of-data-science/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: From Code to Clarity With the Redesigned Structure Tool Window</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Siva Reddy to explore the IDE’s redesigned Structure tool window, featuring insights for seamless code exploration and context-relevant actions. Date: December 12, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract As developers, we often find ourselves navigating through existing code far more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/new-livestream-from-code-to-clarity-with-the-redesigned-structure-tool-window/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ASP.NET Core with Azure Key Vault</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 06:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article looks at setting up an ASP.NET Core application to use Azure Key Vault. When deployed to Azure, it works like in the Azure documentation but when working on development PCs, some changes are required for a smooth developer experience. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/UsingAzureKeyVaultInDevelopment I develop using Visual Studio and manage multiple accounts and test environments. […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/12/02/using-asp-net-core-with-azure-key-vault/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Connect a SQLite Database to EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 06:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll discuss connecting a SQLite database to an ASP.NET Core Web API using EF Core. So, let’s get going. Introduction to SQLite SQLite is a compact and efficient relational database management system that can be embedded directly into applications. The entire database is self-contained in a single disk file. As a result, […] The post How to Connect a SQLite Database to EF Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Rerank 3.5 is now available in Amazon Bedrock through Rerank API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of Cohere’s advanced reranking model Rerank 3.5 through our new Rerank API in Amazon Bedrock. This powerful reranking model enables AWS customers to significantly improve their search relevance and content ranking capabilities. In this post, we discuss the need for Reranking, the capabilities of Cohere’s Rerank 3.5, and how to get started using it on Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cohere-rerank-3-5-is-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-through-rerank-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS DeepRacer: How to master physical racing?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, I will look at what makes physical AWS DeepRacer racing—a real car on a real track—different to racing in the virtual world—a model in a simulated 3D environment. I will cover the basics, the differences in virtual compared to physical, and what steps I have taken to get a deeper understanding of the challenge.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-deepracer-how-to-master-physical-racing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to subscribe to GitHub Enterprise with Advanced Security and Copilot Business/Enterprise: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As GitHub announced metered billing, anyone with an active Azure subscription can now self-provision a paid GitHub Enterprise Cloud account, with Advanced Security and GitHub Copilot Business/Enterprise. This post is a screenshot-based step-by-step guide on how you can do so. Pre-requisites Before we get started, ensure that you have the following: An active Microsoft Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-subscribe-to-github-enterprise-with-advanced-security-and-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s String Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, featuring a StringExtensions class that offers various string manipulation methods. This toolkit includes functions for string concatenation, hashing, splitting, validation, and encoding.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/12/01/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-string-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance AI System Accuracy using RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 04:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) systems, particularly generative models like GPT-4, have transformed numerous industries. However, these models sometimes struggle with accuracy, especially when generating outputs based on limited or outdated training data. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) is an innovative approach designed to address these challenges, combining the generative strengths of AI with the precision of retrieval systems. […] The article Enhance AI System Accuracy using RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing the Saga Pattern With MassTransit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_11_2024/30_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_11_2024/30_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Long-running business processes often require multiple services working together, but traditional distributed transactions can be problematic at scale. Learn how to implement the Saga pattern using MassTransit to break complex workflows into manageable steps with proper error handling and state management.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/implementing-the-saga-pattern-with-masstransit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily deploy and manage hundreds of LoRA adapters with SageMaker efficient multi-adapter inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 20:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new efficient multi-adapter inference feature of Amazon SageMaker unlocks exciting possibilities for customers using fine-tuned models. This capability integrates with SageMaker inference components to allow you to deploy and manage hundreds of fine-tuned Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) adapters through SageMaker APIs. In this post, we show how to use the new efficient multi-adapter inference feature in SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/easily-deploy-and-manage-hundreds-of-lora-adapters-with-sagemaker-efficient-multi-adapter-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve the performance of your Generative AI applications with Prompt Optimization on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 19:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the availability of Prompt Optimization on Amazon Bedrock. With this capability, you can now optimize your prompts for several use cases with a single API call or a click of a button on the Amazon Bedrock console. In this post, we discuss how you can get started with this new feature using an example use case in addition to discussing some performance benchmarks.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Public Preview of OpenID Connect external identity provider support for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 16:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the new OpenID Connect identity provider support in Microsoft Entra External ID, now in Public Preview. Simplify user sign-in and partner integrations, and improve conversion rates and user satisfaction by federating with external identity providers like Okta, Amazon, Auth0, and Azure AD B2C.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/openid-connect-external-identity-provider-support-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the attack complexity of a race condition security vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s not just how small the race window is, but how easy it is to hit the window.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241129-00/?p=110588 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Declarative Gradle in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last year Gradle announced a new experimental project called Declarative Gradle that aims to make Gradle build scripts easier to read and use. Instead of writing detailed instructions for how to build your project, Declarative Gradle allows you to describe what your software needs (like libraries, applications, or tests) in a clear and simple way. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/declarative-gradle-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel Learnings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A synopsis of our key learnings and findings from using Semantic Kernel.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/semantic-kernel-learnings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code in Rust for the Rest of Us</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 07:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m not a competitive programmer – far from it. I never received formal education in advanced algorithms and data structures. In fact, I can’t even implement Dijkstra’s algorithm without referring to Wikipedia. Yet, I still participate in Advent of Code competitions. I’ve never made it onto an official leaderboard; I’m too slow for that. Completing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/11/29/advent-of-code-in-rust-for-the-rest-of-us/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve Advent of Code 2024 Puzzles in Rust and Win Prizes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 07:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the fourth year in a row, JetBrains is a proud sponsor of the Advent of Code, and this year, alongside the Kotlin challenge, we invite all Rust developers to join. Test your skills at a comfortable pace or join the leaderboards for a chance to win a USD 100 Amazon Gift Card! What is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/11/29/solve-advent-of-code-2024-puzzles-in-rust-and-win-prizes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does my program successfully take foreground only when running under the debugger?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That&#39;s a special exception to the normal foreground rules.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241128-00/?p=110586 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Code Analysis in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 13:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This series of blog posts covers several ways that code analysis in IntelliJ IDEA can help you find and fix problems in your code. In the previous posts, we first looked at how the IDE can help you prevent problems while working with code in the editor before moving on to how to resolve problems […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/advanced-code-analysis-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform your debugging experience with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are your unit tests failing, and do you want to debug them more effectively? The latest feature in Visual Studio 2022, powered by GitHub Copilot, has the perfect solution for you. Introducing the Debug with Copilot button in Test Explorer, this feature takes the hassle out of debugging failed tests and gets you closer to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/transform-your-debugging-experience-with-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify ML Workflows With Hugging Face and PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 12:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ready to boost your workflows with pre-trained ML models? PyCharm‘s integration with Hugging Face is designed to bring a new level of productivity to your machine learning and development workflows. This integration helps you seamlessly find and use the best-fit model from the Hugging Face library, access model documentation, and manage models – all in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/11/hugging-face-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.23 with inspecting cloud API requests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 08:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share a new version of Dev Proxy to help you build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-23-with-inspecting-cloud-api-requests 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jakarta EE on Azure – November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 03:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the November 2024 update for Jakarta EE on Azure. It covers topics as new AZD template of Quarkus Apps on ACA, Cargo Tracker Deployment with AI integration, AI infused apps with Open Liberty on AKS, Java apps authentication with Microsoft Entra ID, and new features for JBoss EAP on Azure and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/jakarta-ee-on-azure-november-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embodied AI Chess with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 23:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate Embodied AI Chess with Amazon Bedrock, bringing a new dimension to traditional chess through generative AI capabilities. Our setup features a smart chess board that can detect moves in real time, paired with two robotic arms executing those moves. Each arm is controlled by different FMs—base or custom. This physical implementation allows you to observe and experiment with how different generative AI models approach complex gaming strategies in real-world chess matches.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properly cycling domain passwords with the JSonADDomain extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 22:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For those familiar with the JsonAdDomain extension, it provides an easy way to join VMs to your domain. However, one aspect that customers have been less crazy about is that the domain password must be shared in the protected settings (where it is at least encrypted) and, more importantly, the functionality of the extension doesn’t […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/properly-cycling-domain-passwords-with-the-jsonaddomain-extension 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So how many replicas should my VM Application use?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 21:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One great advantage of VM Applications is the ability to specify how many replicas you want for each VM Application version. While documentation exists on how to specify replicas, we don’t really provide advice on determining how many replicas to use. The goal of this post is to rectify that gap. First, the basics. When […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/so-how-many-replicas-should-my-vm-application-use 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (November 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 21:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure SDKs release every month. This post includes the month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-november-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently train models with large sequence lengths using Amazon SageMaker model parallel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 20:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how the Amazon SageMaker model parallel library (SMP) addresses this need through support for new features such as 8-bit floating point (FP8) mixed-precision training for accelerated training performance and context parallelism for processing large input sequence lengths, expanding the list of its existing features.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/efficiently-train-models-with-large-sequence-lengths-using-amazon-sagemaker-model-parallel/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Amazon Bedrock Agents custom orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 20:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock Agents simplify the orchestration of generative AI workflows, particularly with the introduction of the custom orchestrator feature. You can use the custom orchestrator to fine-tune and optimize agentic workflows that align more closely with specific business and operational needs. We outline the feature’s key benefits, including full control over orchestration, real-time adjustments, and reusability, followed by a breakdown of how it manages state transitions and contract-based interactions between Amazon Bedrock Agents and AWS Lambda.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Bedrock Agents for code scanning, optimization, and remediation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 19:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For enterprises in the realm of cloud computing and software development, providing secure code repositories is essential. As sophisticated cybersecurity threats become more prevalent, organizations must adopt proactive measures to protect their assets. Amazon Bedrock offers a powerful solution by automating the process of scanning repositories for vulnerabilities and remediating them. This post explores how you can use Amazon Bedrock to enhance the security of your repositories and maintain compliance with organizational and regulatory standards.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recordings from JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024 Are Now Live</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 19:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 7, 2024, we hosted our first-ever JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf, an exciting online event dedicated to plugin development for JetBrains products. We’d like to extend a huge thank you to everyone who joined us and made this event such a success! For those who couldn’t be there or who want to revisit their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/11/recordings-from-jetbrains-plugin-developer-conf-2024-are-now-live/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.43 Is Here With Improved Branches Menu, Context Retrieval and Slash Commands in AI Chat, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.43 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/11/fleet-1-43-is-here-with-improved-branches-menu-context-retrieval-and-slash-commands-in-ai-chat-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.1.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.1.0 release is out! This version introduces new language features, tooling updates, performance improvements, and important fixes. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.1.0 or the release notes on GitHub. Join the Kotlin 2.1.0 Livestream Do you want to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/kotlin-2-1-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dramatically faster package restores with .NET 9’s new NuGet resolver</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 9 introduces a new NuGet dependency graph resolver that dramatically improves package restore performance for large repositories. Learn how this reimagined approach reduces restore times from 30 minutes to just 2 minutes by creating a more efficient dependency graph with fewer nodes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-nuget-resolver 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking whether a URI refers to a Web site root</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let somebody else do the parsing.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241127-00/?p=110582 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code update – November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code v5.10.1 and the latest prerelease update. This patch brings impactful new features, enhancements, and critical bug fixes to improve your development experience. Let’s dive into what’s new. Teams Toolkit v5.10.1 This patch version updates included several important bug fixes: Terminology Update: The term Copilot Agent has […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/teams-toolkit-for-visual-studio-code-update-november-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a generative AI assistant with Slack and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Seamless integration of customer experience, collaboration tools, and relevant data is the foundation for delivering knowledge-based productivity gains. In this post, we show you how to integrate the popular Slack messaging service with AWS generative AI services to build a natural language assistant where business users can ask questions of an unstructured dataset.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-generative-ai-assistant-with-slack-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.5 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 13:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 – 2024.2.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/intellij-idea-2024-2-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates for C&#43;&#43; developers in Visual Studio 2022 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 17.12 is here and comes with a host of new features for C++ developers. We’ve made improvements across our toolchain, C++ Build Insights, Unreal Engine support, and more. This post gives a quick overview of what’s available; for all the details, see What’s New for C++ Developers in Visual Studio 2022 17.12 on […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/updates-for-c-developers-in-visual-studio-2022-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discontinuation of the SpaceCode Private Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 09:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dear customers, Today we are announcing the discontinuation of the SpaceCode Private Preview, which we launched in May 2024. On May 27, 2024, we announced that we had decided to discontinue Space and pivot it to a new product: SpaceCode. The plan was for SpaceCode to focus primarily on Git hosting and code reviews. For […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/space/2024/11/27/discontinuation-of-the-spacecode-private-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleash your Salesforce data using the Amazon Q Salesforce Online connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 23:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through configuring and setting up the Amazon Q Salesforce Online connector. Thousands of companies worldwide use Salesforce to manage their sales, marketing, customer service, and other business operations. The Salesforce cloud-based platform centralizes customer information and interactions across the organization, providing sales reps, marketers, and support agents with a unified 360-degree view of each customer. With Salesforce at the heart of their business, companies accumulate vast amounts of customer data within the platform over time.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing hallucinations in large language models with custom intervention using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Knowledge Bases, and the RAGAS evaluation metrics to build a custom hallucination detector and remediate it by using human-in-the-loop. The agentic workflow can be extended to custom use cases through different hallucination remediation techniques and offers the flexibility to detect and mitigate hallucinations using custom actions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/reducing-hallucinations-in-large-language-models-with-custom-intervention-using-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Meta Llama 3.1-8B on AWS Inferentia using Amazon EKS and vLLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through the steps to deploy the Meta Llama 3.1-8B model on Inferentia 2 instances using Amazon EKS. This solution combines the exceptional performance and cost-effectiveness of Inferentia 2 chips with the robust and flexible landscape of Amazon EKS. Inferentia 2 chips deliver high throughput and low latency inference, ideal for LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-meta-llama-3-1-8b-on-aws-inferentia-using-amazon-eks-and-vllm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving LLMs using vLLM and Amazon EC2 instances with AWS AI chips</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The use of large language models (LLMs) and generative AI has exploded over the last year. With the release of powerful publicly available foundation models, tools for training, fine tuning and hosting your own LLM have also become democratized. Using vLLM on AWS Trainium and Inferentia makes it possible to host LLMs for high performance […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/serving-llms-using-vllm-and-amazon-ec2-instances-with-aws-ai-chips/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate the quality of your AI applications with ease</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started with the new Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Evaluation library to kickstart your Intelligent Application eveluation journey.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/evaluate-the-quality-of-your-ai-applications-with-ease 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using LLMs to fortify cyber defenses: Sophos’s insight on strategies for using LLMs with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 18:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, SophosAI shares insights in using and evaluating an out-of-the-box LLM for the enhancement of a security operations center’s (SOC) productivity using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker. We use Anthropic’s Claude 3 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock to illustrate the use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-llms-to-fortify-cyber-defenses-sophoss-insight-on-strategies-for-using-llms-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in Azure DevTest Labs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 18:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DevTest labs now supports the capability to access Azure DevOps artifact repos through Managed Identities and GitHub artifact repos through GitHub app authentication. Additionally, you can now also access the lab storage account through Managed Identities. Until now users have accessed Artifact repos via personal access tokens (PATs) and storage accounts through Storage Access Shared […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/whats-new-in-azure-devtest-labs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced observability for AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia with Datadog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks you through Datadog’s new integration with AWS Neuron, which helps you monitor your AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia instances by providing deep observability into resource utilization, model execution performance, latency, and real-time infrastructure health, enabling you to optimize machine learning (ML) workloads and achieve high-performance at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhanced-observability-for-aws-trainium-and-aws-inferentia-with-datadog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a virtual stock technical analyst using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            n this post, we create a virtual analyst that can answer natural language queries of stocks matching certain technical indicator criteria using Amazon Bedrock Agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-virtual-stock-technical-analyst-using-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply Amazon SageMaker Studio lifecycle configurations using AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post serves as a step-by-step guide on how to set up lifecycle configurations for your Amazon SageMaker Studio domains. With lifecycle configurations, system administrators can apply automated controls to their SageMaker Studio domains and their users. We cover core concepts of SageMaker Studio and provide code examples of how to apply lifecycle configuration to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/apply-amazon-sagemaker-studio-lifecycle-configurations-using-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a read-through semantic cache with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a strategy for optimizing LLM-based applications. Given the increasing need for efficient and cost-effective AI solutions, we present a serverless read-through caching blueprint that uses repeated data patterns. With this cache, developers can effectively save and access similar prompts, thereby enhancing their systems’ efficiency and response times.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-read-through-semantic-cache-with-amazon-opensearch-serverless-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rad AI reduces real-time inference latency by 50% using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 16:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Ken Kao and Hasan Ali Demirci from Rad AI. Rad AI has reshaped radiology reporting, developing solutions that streamline the most tedious and repetitive tasks, and saving radiologists’ time. Since 2018, using state-of-the-art proprietary and open source large language models (LLMs), our flagship product—Rad AI Impressions— has significantly reduced the […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/rad-ai-reduces-real-time-inference-latency-by-50-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read graphs, diagrams, tables, and scanned pages using multimodal prompts in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 16:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use models on Amazon Bedrock to retrieve information from images, tables, and scanned documents. We provide the following examples: 1/ performing object classification and object detection tasks, 2/ reading and querying graphs, and 3/ reading flowcharts and architecture diagrams (such as an AWS architecture diagram) and converting it to text.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/read-graphs-diagrams-tables-and-scanned-pages-using-multimodal-prompts-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugger and Diagnostics updates in Visual Studio 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 16:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce a host of exciting new features in Visual Studio 17.12, designed to enhance your development experience and boost your productivity. Our team has been working diligently to address some of the most popular requests from our developer community, and we are confident that these updates will significantly improve your workflow. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/debugger-and-diagnostics-updates-in-visual-studio-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Crexi achieved ML models deployment on AWS at scale and boosted efficiency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 16:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Commercial Real Estate Exchange, Inc. (Crexi), is a digital marketplace and platform designed to streamline commercial real estate transactions. In this post, we will review how Crexi achieved its business needs and developed a versatile and powerful framework for AI/ML pipeline creation and deployment. This customizable and scalable solution allows its ML models to be efficiently deployed and managed to meet diverse project requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-crexi-achieved-ml-models-deployment-on-aws-at-scale-and-boosted-efficiency/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: Real estate and Airspace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Space on the screen and negotiating control over it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241126-00/?p=110575 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Roundup: Kodee’s Top Picks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone! Time flies, doesn’t it? It’s already my second edition of Kotlin Roundup, and I can’t wait to share the latest from the Kotlin ecosystem. Did you know that the JetBrains team regularly publishes a newsletter featuring major Kotlin ecosystem news? Sign up to stay up to date with all things Kotlin.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/kotlin-roundup-kodee-s-top-picks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Calisthenics #5: Other points of views</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You&#39;ve seen two implementations of calisthenics objects that differed in many ways, both in the way they applied the rules and in the solutions they proposed to meet the rules discussed in this article:Object Calisthenics #1: Elevating Code Quality with 9 Powerful RulesDiscover how Object Calisthenics
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/object-calisthenics-5-other-points-of-views/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Origin-Resource-Policy: preventing hotlinking and XSSI attacks: Understanding cross-origin security headers - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how to use the Cross-Origin-Resource-Policy to block cross-origin requests that would normally be allowed, such as in tags
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/understanding-security-headers-part-2-cross-origin-resource-policy-preventing-hotlinking/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing .NET Security: A Guide to Secure Password Hashing with Spargine’s SHA256PasswordHasher</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a collection of open-source .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages created for effective password hashing. The SHA256PasswordHasher class uses SHA-256 with unique salts to provide secure password management in applications. It includes methods for hashing and verifying passwords, promoting robust security practices in .NET development.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/26/enhancing-net-security-a-guide-to-secure-password-hashing-with-spargines-sha256passwordhasher/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 13 Features: What&amp;#x27;s New and How to Use It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 07:32:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# has always been one of the most popular programming languages among developers. It continuously evolves to meet timed features and trends. Its robustness and flexibility make it an all-purpose language and ideal for domains like desktop applications, enterprise systems, web development, games, and cross-platform and native mobile applications. With
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/c-13-features-whats-new-and-how-to-use-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Meta Llama 3.1 models cost-effectively in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart with AWS Inferentia and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the availability of Meta Llama 3.1 8B and 70B inference support on AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia instances in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. Trainium and Inferentia, enabled by the AWS Neuron software development kit (SDK), offer high performance and lower the cost of deploying Meta Llama 3.1 by up to 50%. In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy Meta Llama 3.1 on Trainium and Inferentia instances in SageMaker JumpStart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS achieves ISO/IEC 42001:2023 Artificial Intelligence Management System accredited certification</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to be the first major cloud service provider to announce ISO/IEC 42001 accredited certification for the following AI services: Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Q Business, Amazon Textract, and Amazon Transcribe. ISO/IEC 42001 is an international management system standard that outlines requirements and controls for organizations to promote the responsible development and use of AI systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-achieves-iso-iec-420012023-artificial-intelligence-management-system-accredited-certification/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
