<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 15:56:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximize your Amazon Translate architecture using strategic caching layers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 15:56:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how setting up a cache for frequently accessed translations can benefit organizations that need scalable, multi-language translation across large volumes of content. You’ll learn how to build a simple caching mechanism for Amazon Translate to accelerate turnaround times.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maximize-your-amazon-translate-architecture-using-strategic-caching-layers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2 EAP Digest #2: New TypeScript Engine, Ability to Run .ts Files, Git and Markdown Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re halfway through the Early Access Program for WebStorm 2024.2! It’s been a while since we walked you through the latest improvements and features in this release, so it’s about time for an update. Read on to learn about the key changes that made it into the EAP builds in the past few weeks. For […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/06/webstorm-2024-2-eap2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a Slack gateway for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced digital world, streamlining workflows and boosting productivity are paramount. That’s why we’re thrilled to share an exciting integration that will take your team’s collaboration to new heights. Get ready to unlock the power of generative artificial intelligence (AI) and bring it directly into your Slack workspace. Imagine the possibilities: Quick and efficient […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-a-slack-gateway-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Bring Science Into API Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 13:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced development environment, effective API documentation is not just a nice-to-have, but a necessity. This blog post explores how understanding pattern recognition and learning styles can revolutionize the way we create API documentation. By examining the different types of knowledge present in API references and recognizing diverse developer learning strategies, we can create […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/06/let-s-bring-science-into-api-documentation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Move From pandas to Polars</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 11:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Cheuk Ting Ho, a data scientist who contributes to multiple open-source libraries, such as pandas and Polars. You’ve probably heard about Polars – it is now firmly in the spotlight in the data science community. Are you still using pandas and would like to try out Polars? Are you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/06/how-to-move-from-pandas-to-polars/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>256 Seconds with dotNetDave: Documenting Code with Visual Studio and Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this episode of 256 Seconds with dotNetDave, learn to use Visual Studio and GitHub Copilot to swiftly create detailed XML comments for Microsoft .NET projects. Detailed commands for documenting classes are shared, along with a call to vote for displaying code examples in IntelliSense. Watch the demonstration here: https://player.vimeo.com/video/961522552?badge=0&amp;autopause=0&amp;player_id=0&amp;app_id=58479
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/19/256-seconds-with-dotnetdave-documenting-code-with-visual-studio-and-copilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use FakeLogger to Test Logging Code in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 06:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In software development, logging, and unit testing serve as foundational tools, each actively contributing to the reliability and functionality of our applications. While unit testing promptly alerts us to changes in our application’s business logic, logging actively monitors errors, performance metrics, and runtime execution flow. Despite their significance, many development workflows often overlook their incorporation. […] The post How to Use FakeLogger to Test Logging Code in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Step Forward for Gaming on Arm Devices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 02:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year at Microsoft Build 2024 we announced a new set of Windows devices, Copilot+ PCs. Copilot+ PCs are a new class of Windows 11 PCs, including Arm-powered devices that are powered by the Snapdragon® X Series. These new Arm devices have cutting-edge new processing power coming from the CPU,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/step-forward-for-gaming-on-arm-devices-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving air quality with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a solution that uses a generative artificial intelligence (AI) to standardize air quality data from low-cost sensors in Africa, specifically addressing the air quality data integration problem of low-cost sensors. The solution harnesses the capabilities of generative AI, specifically Large Language Models (LLMs), to address the challenges posed by diverse sensor data and automatically generate Python functions based on various data formats. The fundamental objective is to build a manufacturer-agnostic database, leveraging generative AI’s ability to standardize sensor outputs, synchronize data, and facilitate precise corrections.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use zero-shot large language models on Amazon Bedrock for custom named entity recognition</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Name entity recognition (NER) is the process of extracting information of interest, called entities, from structured or unstructured text. Manually identifying all mentions of specific types of information in documents is extremely time-consuming and labor-intensive. Some examples include extracting players and positions in an NFL game summary, products mentioned in an AWS keynote transcript, or […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-zero-shot-large-language-models-on-amazon-bedrock-for-custom-named-entity-recognition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguard a generative AI travel agent with prompt engineering and Guardrails for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a comprehensive solution for addressing the challenges of securing a virtual travel agent powered by generative AI. We provide an end-to-end example and its accompanying code to demonstrate how to implement prompt engineering techniques, content moderation, and various guardrails to make sure the assistant operates within predefined boundaries by relying on Guardrails for Amazon Bedrock. Additionally, we delve into monitoring strategies to track the activation of these safeguards, enabling proactive identification and mitigation of potential issues.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline financial workflows with generative AI for email automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explains a generative artificial intelligence (AI) technique to extract insights from business emails and attachments. It examines how AI can optimize financial workflow processes by automatically summarizing documents, extracting data, and categorizing information from email attachments. This enables companies to serve more clients, direct employees to higher-value tasks, speed up processes, lower expenses, enhance data accuracy, and increase efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-financial-workflows-with-generative-ai-for-email-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy and security improvements in .NET modernization tooling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the latest privacy and security-related updates to Azure Migrate application and code assessment and .NET Upgrade Assistant.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-modernization-privacy-security-improvements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily navigate code delegates while debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 15:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Delegates are everywhere in modern code; a delegate is a type that represents references to methods with a particular parameter list and return type. Developers use delegates to pass methods as arguments to other methods. One example you may be familiar with is with event handlers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/easily-navigate-code-delegates-while-debugging 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains to Integrate Google’s Gemini Models Into AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is planning to soon leverage Google Cloud’s Vertex AI by integrating Google’s Gemini models into its AI-powered coding tool, AI Assistant. This makes JetBrains AI Assistant the first of its kind to use multiple large language models (LLMs). JetBrains AI Assistant AI Assistant helps developers stay focused on creative challenges by handling routine tasks. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/06/jetbrains-to-integrate-google-s-gemini-models-into-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The time smart quotes prevented the entire Office division from committing code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Breaking your tools with your tools.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240618-00/?p=109910 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Style for Better Productivity – Tips and Tools from the Metalama Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 11:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While it may seem trivial, one of the first steps in creating a maintainable, team-friendly codebase is reaching a consensus on code style and ensuring its strict enforcement. This includes code formatting (spaces, blank lines, parentheses, and brackets), naming (casings, prefixes, suffixes, etc.), and usage of this, var and more. The ultimate goal? Make running […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/18/code-style-for-better-productivity-tips-and-tools-from-the-metalama-team/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand your C&#43;&#43; symbols using Copilot in Visual Studio’s Quick Info</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 09:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Navigating your codebase and forget what exactly that method does? Looking for quick, easy-to-digest information on your code at any point in your development journey? We are excited to announce that now when you hover over symbols in your codebase, you’ll be able to invoke Copilot conveniently within the Quick Info dialog to learn more about a given symbol and enhance existing or lacking code documentation.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/understand-your-c-symbols-using-copilot-in-visual-studios-quick-info 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the generated code: List&lt;T&gt; and fallback cases: Behind the scenes of collection expressions - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at the code generated when you use collection expressions with List or with types that can be used with collection initializers
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/behind-the-scenes-of-collection-expressions-part-2-exploring-the-generated-code-list-and-fallback-cases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently Handling Stored Procedures in EFCore: Practical Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 08:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover proven strategies and practical solutions for efficiently handling stored procedures in Entity Framework Core (EFCore) and optimize your database interactions.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/efficiently-handling-stored-procedures-efcore-practical-solutions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;Secret&amp;quot; elmah.io features #5 - Breadcrumbs leading up to errors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 09:36:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s time for a new post in the series about &amp;quot;secret&amp;quot; elmah.io features. This is the series where I highlight features that some of you may already know while others don&#39;t. For today&#39;s post, I want to highlight a feature that asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/secret-elmah-io-features-5-breadcrumbs-leading-up-to-errors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Ignore a Property in AutoMapper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 05:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore key techniques to ignore property in AutoMapper. We will use the Ignore() method, the Ignore attribute, and the DoNotValidate() method. We will also discuss when and how to use each of the methods mentioned. Without further ado, let’s start! When to Ignore a Property in AutoMapper Ignoring properties during […] The post How to Ignore a Property in AutoMapper appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Load testing with K6 on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Can your system withstand heavy loads? You can answer this question by running Load Tests. Maybe, using K6 as a free tool.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/k6-load-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Applied Skills Replacing Microsoft Certifications?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 22:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Learn Applied Skills credentials are not replacing Microsoft Certifications. Microsoft is expanding their credentialing portfolio to cater better to learners and customers, allowing validation of specific skill sets with this new offering. Microsoft Certifications are continuing to be role-based, and still assess a broad range of skills essential for success in key roles within […] The article Are Applied Skills Replacing Microsoft Certifications? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step by Step guide to develop AI Multi-Agent system using Microsoft Semantic Kernel and GPT-4o</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we want to highlight a recent Medium article published here: Step by Step guide to develop AI Multi-Agent system using Microsoft Semantic Kernel and GPT-4o | by Akshay Kokane | Jun, 2024 | Medium We’ve included a few excerpts below,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/step-by-step-guide-to-develop-ai-multi-agent-system-using-microsoft-semantic-kernel-and-gpt-4o 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Twilio used Amazon SageMaker MLOps pipelines with PrestoDB to enable frequent model retraining and optimized batch transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Shamik Ray, Srivyshnav K S, Jagmohan Dhiman and Soumya Kundu from Twilio. Today’s leading companies trust Twilio’s Customer Engagement Platform (CEP) to build direct, personalized relationships with their customers everywhere in the world. Twilio enables companies to use communications and data to add intelligence and security to every step of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-twilio-used-amazon-sagemaker-mlops-pipelines-with-prestodb-to-enable-frequent-model-retraining-and-optimized-batch-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactor your code with default lambda parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore opportunities to refactor your C# code with default lambda parameters, a new feature in C# 12.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/refactor-your-code-with-default-lambda-parameters 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Teams webinar integration with HubSpot marketing automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn why the integration of HubSpot with Microsoft Teams represents a significant new advancement for Teams webinar customers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-teams-webinar-integration-with-hubspot-marketing-automation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate deep learning training and simplify orchestration with AWS Trainium and AWS Batch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In large language model (LLM) training, effective orchestration and compute resource management poses a significant challenge. Automation of resource provisioning, scaling, and workflow management is vital for optimizing resource usage and streamlining complex workflows, thereby achieving efficient deep learning training processes. Simplified orchestration enables researchers and practitioners to focus more on model experimentation, hyperparameter tuning, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-deep-learning-training-and-simplify-orchestration-with-aws-trainium-and-aws-batch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosch widely adopts Visual Studio for their C&#43;&#43; remote Linux projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Bosch security camera team was seeking a unified development setup for their team and recently re-evaluated Visual Studio as a solution for their C++ projects and remote Linux development needs. Their experience with Visual Studio 2022 featured notable improvements relevant to their workflows such as seamless GDB integration and CMake/WSL integrations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/bosch-widely-adopts-visual-studio-for-their-c-remote-linux-projects 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 EAP 3: Improved GDB Performance and Enhancements for Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 15:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.2 EAP build (242.16677.29) is now out! It’s available from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 EAP Here are the highlights: The full release notes are available here. Find out more about our plans for this release in the CLion 2024.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/06/2024-2-eap-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I view the list of symbols available in a library?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A tool hiding inside another tool.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240617-00/?p=109905 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venerable Used Datalore to Reduce Eight-Hour Excel Analysis to Two Minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 09:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Caught in a spiderweb of spreadsheets Like many financial organizations, Venerable faced hurdles due to its dependence on Excel. Changes in a single spreadsheet often triggered a chain reaction of adjustments across countless others, leading to mistakes and a lot of manual work. This setup resulted in a time-consuming, error-prone process that was amplified when […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/06/17/venerable-used-datalore-to-reduce-eight-hour-excel-analysis-to-two-minutes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flattening Nested Collections in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 05:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore flattening nested collections in C#. We’ll examine different approaches for handling from simple to complex data structures, offering practical guidance to effectively flatten nested collections within our C# applications. Let’s get started. Importance of Flattening Nested Collections Nested collections can introduce unnecessary complexity, making it challenging to work with the […] The post Flattening Nested Collections in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Introducing FrozenSet in .NET 8: Benefits and Benchmark PerformanceCollection Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2024/16_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2024/16_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET version 8 introduced the FrozenSet type, offering immutable and hashable set collection with benefits including improved performance, memory efficiency, and thread safety. Benchmarks show comparable performance to List, outperforming HashSet and ImmutableHashSet. However, it is slightly slower than the latter in lookups. FrozenSet offers significant advantages for concurrent applications and memory optimization.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/16/collection-performance-introducing-frozenset-in-net-8-benefits-and-benchmark-performancecollection-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Do’s and Don’ts For Developers  – Dev Leader Weekly 48</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post AI Do’s and Don’ts For Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 48 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss ways you can leverage AI as a developer and things to avoid too! The post AI Do’s and Don’ts For Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 48 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/06/15/ai-dos-and-donts-for-developers-dev-leader-weekly-48/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Properly Set Connection Strings in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 06:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will delve into connection strings providing insights into their functionality, and best practices for safeguarding sensitive data. Let’s dive in! Purpose and Components of Connection Strings Connection strings are the backbone of a connection between our application and a database, encapsulating important information such as server address, database name, and authentication […] The post How to Properly Set Connection Strings in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Transaction Scripts to Domain Models: A Refactoring Journey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transaction Scripts organizes business logic by procedures where each procedure handles a single request from the presentation.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/from-transaction-scripts-to-domain-models-a-refactoring-journey 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 EAP 3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 20:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest installment in the Rider 2024.2 Early Access Program has just been released! Let’s take a look at the changes. Bundled .NET Watch Run Configuration plugin dotnet-watch is a .NET global tool specifically designed to monitor file changes during development and promptly reload or restart the target command. One of the standout features of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/14/rider-2024-2-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lock-free reference-counting a TLS slot using atomics, part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Keeping track of two things at once.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240614-00/?p=109902 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugger Upskill: Debug Without Breakpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 11:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a typical debugging scenario, you would set breakpoints to tell the debugger when to suspend your program. A breakpoint usually corresponds to the moment that marks the starting point for further investigation. Deciding where to set a breakpoint can be challenging. There might be situations where the exact line is unclear, or you might […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/debugger-upskill-debug-without-breakpoints/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C#12新功能合集三：使用任意类型别名重构C#代码</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 08:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译于David Pine的这篇文章: Refactor your code using alias any type。 这篇文章是四篇系列文章中的第三篇，主要探讨C# 12的各种功能。在这篇文章中，我们将深入探讨“别名任何类型”功能，该功能允许您使用 using 指令为任何类型创建别名。这个系列已经初具规模： 使用主构造函数重构 C# 代码 使用集合表达式重构 C# 代码 使用任意类型别名重构 C# 代码（本篇文章） 重构 C# 代码以使用默认 lambda 参数 所有这些功能都将继续我们的旅程，使我们的代码更具可读性和可维护性，这些被认为是开发人员应该知道的“日常 C#”功能。让我们深入了解吧！ 别名任意类型*️⃣ C# 12 引入了使用 using 指令为任意类型添加别名的功能。此功能允许您指定映射到其他类型的别名。这包括元组类型、指针类型、数组类型，甚至非开放泛型类型，所有这些类型都可以在您的代码中使用。此功能在以下场景特别有用： 当使用长或复杂的类型名称时。 当消除类型歧义并解决潜在的命名冲突时。 当定义要在程序集中共享的值元组类型时。 当希望通过使用更具描述性的名称来增加代码的清晰度时。 官方 C# 文档提供了很多有关如何使用此功能的示例，但我并不想在此重复这些示例，而是决定编写一个演示应用程序来示范该功能的各个方面。 可空引用类型 此功能支持大多数类型，但可空引用类型除外。也就是说，您无法为可空引用类型设置别名， C# 编译器会报告错误 CS9132：使用的别名不能是可空引用类型。以下内容摘自功能说明，以帮助澄清这一点： // This is not legal.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/c12%e6%96%b0%e5%8a%9f%e8%83%bd%e5%90%88%e9%9b%86%e4%b8%89%ef%bc%9a%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8%e4%bb%bb%e6%84%8f%e7%b1%bb%e5%9e%8b%e7%9a%84%e5%88%ab%e5%90%8d%e9%87%8d%e6%9e%84c%e4%bb%a3%e7%a0%81 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Boilerplate: An Inside Look Into Our .Net Clean Architecture Repo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will take an inner look at the clean architecture boilerplate and how it helps kickstart our projects rapidly.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/next-level-clean-architecture-boilerplate 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Differences Between Collections With the LINQ Except Method in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 06:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with collections in C#, we sometimes need to manipulate them by performing operations such as comparisons, mergers, or finding set differences between them. The LINQ Except method comes in handy when we want to find the set difference between two sequences, as it returns a new sequence containing elements in the first sequence […] The post Find Differences Between Collections With the LINQ Except Method in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye, long procedural code! Fix it with workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 20:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve all written long procedural code with many logic branches that must handle failures because it tries to execute a long business process with many actions. Better alternatives exist than writing a rat’s nest of complex procedural code. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video… Read More »Goodbye, long procedural code! Fix it with workflows The post Goodbye, long procedural code!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the public preview of the Microsoft AI Chat Protocol library for JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 19:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post details the public preview release of the AI Chat Protocol library, allowing users to build robust, streamed AI frontends in JavaScript.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/announcing-the-public-preview-of-the-microsoft-ai-chat-protocol-library-for-javascript 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The present and future of Copilot extensibility: Top 10 takeaways from Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 18:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dive into our key announcements from Build to discover new pathways to extend, customize, and amplify Copilot capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/the-present-and-future-of-copilot-extensibility-top-10-takeaways-from-build-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Generative AI apps with .NET 8 and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 18:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today’s we’d like to share a blog post from two members of the .NET team, Jordan Matthiesen and Luis Quintanilla, focused on Building Generative AI apps with .NET 8 – .NET Blog (microsoft.com). The future of AI is here, and .NET is ready for it!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/building-generative-ai-apps-with-net-8-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC vs. Docker: Which One Should You Use?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 18:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the key differences between Docker and LXC, including use cases and technical requirements, to determine which containerization technology best suits your project needs.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/lxc-vs-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 5: Jakarta Data Support, Extended JPA Support, Streamlined Cron Expressions Handling, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 17:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 5 is now available! It brings a range of exciting updates to the IDE’s integrations with popular frameworks such as Spring, Quarkus, and Micronaut, along with Jakarta Data specification support, and more. To try them out today, download the IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 5 build from our website, update directly from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PostgreSQL with .NET and Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Getting started with .NET and PostgreSQL, and using Entra ID to secure your app.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-postgre-sql-with-dotnet-and-entra-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lock-free reference-counting a TLS slot using atomics, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Getting it is easy. Getting rid of it is hard.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240613-00/?p=109892 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between Span and Memory in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 05:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll briefly explain the Span and Memory .NET types and mention their primary usage. Furthermore, we will explore the differences between Span and Memory in C# in depth and conclude with some general tips on when to use one type over another. What Is Span? The Span type is a value type […] The post Differences Between Span and Memory in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “Critter Stack” Just Leveled Up on Modular Monolith Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 02:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The goal for the “Critter Stack” tools is to be the absolute best set of tools for building server side .NET applications, and especially for any usage of Event Driven Architecture approaches. To go even farther, I would like there to be a day where organizations purposely choose the .NET ecosystem just because of the … Continue reading The “Critter Stack” Just Leveled Up on Modular Monolith Support →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI On Your Data with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 18:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, everyone! In the fast-paced world of technology, using artificial intelligence to get more out of your data is becoming essential. Azure OpenAI on Your Data is a feature that helps businesses do just that. It combines the advanced AI models from OpenAI with the strong data management tools of Azure,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/azure-openai-on-your-data-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The .NET MAUI Extension for Visual Studio Code is now Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Start developing .NET MAUI apps with the GA Visual Studio Code extension today!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/the-dotnet-maui-extension-for-visual-studio-code-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft.AspNetCore.OData 9 Preview Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 17:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the forthcoming major release of Microsoft.AspNetCore.OData, scheduled for June. In preparation for this significant update, we have made preview versions of the library available to gather early feedback from our community. The following preview release is now available on NuGet: Microsoft.AspNetCore.OData 9.0.0-preview.2 Key Update The primary change in this release is the update of the OData core libraries dependencies to the recently released OData Core 8.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a custom UI for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 16:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q is a new generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered assistant designed for work that can be tailored to your business. Amazon Q can help you get fast, relevant answers to pressing questions, solve problems, generate content, and take actions using the data and expertise found in your company’s information repositories and enterprise systems. When you […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-custom-ui-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 16:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-driven business landscape, the ability to efficiently extract and process information from a wide range of documents is crucial for informed decision-making and maintaining a competitive edge. However, traditional document processing workflows often involve complex and time-consuming manual tasks, hindering productivity and scalability. In this post, we discuss an approach that uses the […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scalable-intelligent-document-processing-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces Free Writing Assistance, Powered by JetBrains AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 16:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing assistance powered by JetBrains AI is now included in YouTrack 2024.2. All cloud and server customers with active subscriptions can use it for free to automatically check grammar, spelling, and punctuation and add precision and flair to their writing. We’ve also added improvements based on the most popular requests from teams using various parts […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/06/youtrack-introduces-free-writing-assistance-powered-by-jetbrains-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use weather data to improve forecasts with Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 15:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Photo by Zbynek Burival on Unsplash Time series forecasting is a specific machine learning (ML) discipline that enables organizations to make informed planning decisions. The main idea is to supply historic data to an ML algorithm that can identify patterns from the past and then use those patterns to estimate likely values about unseen periods […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-weather-data-to-improve-forecasts-with-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lock-free reference-counting a TLS slot using atomics, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            First, we do it with locks.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240612-00/?p=109887 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Education: Tailoring Tools and Techniques for Rust</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disclaimer: This article was created using JetBrains Grazie, an AI-based writing and communication companion. With its help, the core topics of this rich and nuanced livestream were conveniently distilled into a compact blog post format. In the world of programming languages, the ability to learn and understand a language is a critical factor for developers. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/06/12/programming-education-tailoring-tools-and-techniques-for-rust/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2024.2 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 12:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post marks the start of the Early Access Program for DataSpell 2024.2. The DataSpell 2024.2 EAP 1 build is now accessible for download, providing an early glimpse into the exciting updates on the horizon.You can download the new version from our website, update directly from inside the IDE or via the free Toolbox […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2024/06/2024-2-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch up on the latest Git tooling features in 17.10 GA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 07:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We believe that boosting the productivity of your development and team collaboration helps you produce better software solutions. That’s why the Visual Studio Version Control team has delivered new features, streamlining your inner loop and code review experiences. You’ll get AI support writing commit messages,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/catch-up-on-the-latest-git-tooling-features-in-17-10-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Custom Header Parameter to All API Endpoints in Swagger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 05:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Within the .NET ecosystem, Swagger stands out as an essential tool, enabling developers to produce interactive and comprehensive API documentation. Header parameters play a crucial role in carrying important metadata in HTTP requests. Specifically, this metadata includes information like authentication tokens and custom configurations, shaping how clients and services interact. In this article, we explore […] The post Adding a Custom Header Parameter to All API Endpoints in Swagger appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Unit Testable Code with Maintainable Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing maintainable code should be a goal in most software engineering projects. Although definitions and especially hard measurements of…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/comparing-unit-testable-code-with-maintainable-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
