<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 17:02:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Security best practices to consider while fine-tuning models in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 17:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we implemented secure fine-tuning jobs in Amazon Bedrock, which is crucial for protecting sensitive data and maintaining the integrity of your AI models. By following the best practices outlined in this post, including proper IAM role configuration, encryption at rest and in transit, and network isolation, you can significantly enhance the security posture of your fine-tuning processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/security-best-practices-to-consider-while-fine-tuning-models-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure a generative AI assistant with OWASP Top 10 mitigation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 15:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you an example of a generative AI assistant application and demonstrate how to assess its security posture using the OWASP Top 10 for Large Language Model Applications, as well as how to apply mitigations for common threats.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/secure-a-generative-ai-assistant-with-owasp-top-10-mitigation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief and incomplete comparison of memory corruption detection tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A short overview, definitely incomplete.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250124-00/?p=110805 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Large-Scale AI with Janusgraph and Azure Managed Instance for Apache Cassandra</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 13:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JanusGraph is a high-performance graph database that offers flexibility in choosing storage backends. Apache Cassandra is a distributed NoSQL database known for its scalability and fault tolerance. Combining these two technologies can create a robust and efficient graph database solution. You can use the Azure Managed Instance for Apache Cassandra which is a fully-managed offering […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/revolutionizing-large-scale-ai-with-janusgraph-and-azure-managed-instance-for-apache-cassandra 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: Top Courses and Projects of 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 08:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This International Day of Education, we’re celebrating that in 2024 over 340,000 new coders joined JetBrains Academy, making our community almost 1.5 million members strong. To mark this impressive milestone, we’re looking back at the most popular JetBrains Academy offerings of 2024 – including JetBrains IDE courses (designed exclusively for IDEs) and Hyperskill projects (available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/01/24/jetbrains-academy-top-courses-and-projects-of-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionising Customer Feedback: Harnessing Large Language Models for Retail Insights and Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we delve into techniques for extracting valuable insights from customer feedback using Large Language Models (LLMs). By identifying themes, sentiment, and competitor comparisons from feedback, businesses can gain a competitive edge.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/insights_generation_from_customer_feedback_using_llms 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 中的 OpenAPI 文档生成</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 05:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Mike Kistler的OpenAPI document generation in .NET 9 .NET 9 中的 ASP.NET Core 通过引入全新的对OpenAPI 文档生成功能的内置支持，简化了为 API 端点创建 OpenAPI 文档的过程。这项新功能旨在简化开发工作流程，并改善 OpenAPI 定义在 ASP.NET 应用中的集成。 OpenAPI 的广泛使用催生了丰富的工具和服务生态系统，它们能够帮助您更高效地构建、测试和记录 API。例如，Swagger UI、Kiota 客户端库生成器和 Redoc 等，当然还有许多其他工具。 为什么选择 OpenAPI？ OpenAPI 是定义和记录 HTTP API 的强大工具。它提供了一种标准化方式来描述 API 的端点、请求和响应格式、身份验证方案以及其他重要细节。这种标准化使开发人员能够更轻松地了解和与API进行交互，从而促进更好的协作并构建更强大的应用程序。 此外，许多大型语言模型（LLMs）已在 OpenAPI 文档上进行了训练，使其能够自动生成代码、测试用例和其他工件。通过为您的 API 生成 OpenAPI 文档，您可以利用这些 LLM 来加速开发流程。 .NET 9 中的新功能？ 在 .NET 9 中，我们引入了对 OpenAPI […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/net-9-%e4%b8%ad%e7%9a%84-openapi-%e6%96%87%e6%a1%a3%e7%94%9f%e6%88%90 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wringing More Scalability out of Event Sourcing with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software works with our customers to help wring the absolute best results out of our customer’s usage of the “Critter Stack.” We build several improvements in collaboration with our customers last year to both Marten and Wolverine specifically to improve scalability of large systems using Event Sourcing. If you’re concerned about whether or not … Continue reading Wringing More Scalability out of Event Sourcing with the Critter Stack →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Is Now Available on AWS Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 22:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity is officially listed on AWS Marketplace! This milestone makes it even easier for teams to integrate the power of TeamCity into their CI/CD pipelines while leveraging the scalability and flexibility of Amazon Web Services (AWS). TeamCity interface Whether you’re already an AWS user or exploring AWS for your next project, TeamCity on AWS Marketplace […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/01/teamcity-is-now-available-on-aws-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (January 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 18:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.01.13 registry release, 2025-01-11 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout January. This release includes minor improvements and bug fixes. Some stats for this period: There are now 2,524 total ports available in the vcpkg curated registry. A […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-january-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline custom environment provisioning for Amazon SageMaker Studio: An automated CI/CD pipeline approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 18:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to create an automated continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) pipeline solution to build, scan, and deploy custom Docker images to SageMaker Studio domains. You can use this solution to promote consistency of the analytical environments for data science teams across your enterprise.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-custom-environment-provisioning-for-amazon-sagemaker-studio-an-automated-ci-cd-pipeline-approach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing a free GitHub Copilot for Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce an all new free plan for GitHub Copilot, available for everyone today in Visual Studio. All you need is a GitHub account. No trial. No subscription. No credit card. With GitHub Copilot Free, you’ll receive: 2,000 code completions per month 50 chat messages per month Access to the latest AI models with […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/announcing-a-free-github-copilot-for-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve the “R” in RAG and embrace Agentic RAG in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 16:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The RAG (Retrieval Augmented Generation) pattern, which is commonly discussed today, is based on the foundational idea that the retrieval part is done using vector search. This ensures that all the most relevant information available to answer the given question is returned and then fed to an LLM to generate the final answer. While vector […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/improve-the-r-in-rag-and-embrace-agentic-rag-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance your customer’s omnichannel experience with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Lex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 16:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to set up Amazon Lex for an omnichannel chatbot experience and Amazon Bedrock to be your secondary validation layer. This allows your customers to potentially provide out-of-band responses both at the intent and slot collection levels without having to be re-prompted, allowing for a seamless customer experience.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-your-customers-omnichannel-experience-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-lex/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory corruption from outside the process looks like space aliens</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The write isn&#39;t visible to your process, just the effect of the write.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250123-00/?p=110800 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Junie, Your Coding Agent by JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 13:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we aim to enable and scale the next generation of technologies to make software development a more productive and enjoyable experience. To empower and support developers, we build a variety of products for professional development, including powerful AI tools and features that have already enhanced productivity and opened new horizons for creativity. But […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/junie/2025/01/meet-junie-your-coding-agent-by-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and Rider 2024.3.4 Bug-Fix Updates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download. ReSharper 2024.3.4 For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our issue tracker. Rider 2024.3.4 We’ve also fixed several issues affecting .NET MAUI development: For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/23/resharper-and-rider-2024-3-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Database Connectivity with EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether during application startup, multi-step workflows, or monitoring an application’s overall health, verifying database connectivity is essential for smooth operation and graceful handling of potential failures. It improves reliability and the overall user experience. In modern containerized environments, often managed by orchestrators like Kubernetes (K8S), it’s equally important for services to report their health status. […] The post Testing Database Connectivity with EF Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Creative Writing Assistant – a multi-agent app sample with Semantic Kernel &amp; .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 22:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re featuring a guest author, Ricardo Niepel, who’s a Senior Technical Specialist at Microsoft. He’s written an article we’re sharing below; we’ll turn it over to Ricardo to share more! If “Creative Writing Assistant” sounds familiar, it might be because we’ve previously released a similar multi-agent application built in Python during our Ignite conference […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-creative-writing-assistant-a-multi-agent-app-sample-with-semantic-kernel-net-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing multi-turn conversation with an agent node for Amazon Bedrock Flows (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 21:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce multi-turn conversation with an agent node (preview), a powerful new capability in Flows. This new capability enhances the agent node functionality, enabling dynamic, back-and-forth conversations between users and flows, similar to a natural dialogue in a flow execution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-multi-turn-conversation-with-an-agent-node-for-amazon-bedrock-flows-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video security analysis for privileged access management using generative AI and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 19:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you an innovative solution to a challenge faced by security teams in highly regulated industries: the efficient security analysis of vast amounts of video recordings from Privileged Access Management (PAM) systems. We demonstrate how you can use Anthropic’s Claude 3 family of models and Amazon Bedrock to perform the complex task of analyzing video recordings of server console sessions and perform queries to highlight any potential security anomalies.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2: Containerfile Support and Updates for Dockerfiles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 18:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2 is out! With a focus on improving workflows for environments like Docker containers and other remote solutions, this build introduces updates that simplify setup and enhance productivity in these scenarios. You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Cato Networks uses Amazon Bedrock to transform free text search into structured GraphQL queries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 17:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Accurately converting free text inputs into structured data is crucial for applications that involve data management and user interaction. In this post, we introduce a real business use case from Cato Networks that significantly improved user experience. By using Amazon Bedrock, we gained access to state-of-the-art generative language models with built-in support for JSON schemas and structured data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-cato-networks-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-transform-free-text-search-into-structured-graphql-queries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and OpenAI evolve partnership to drive the next phase of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to continue our strategic partnership with OpenAI and to partner on Stargate. Today’s announcement is complementary to what our two companies have been working on together since 2019. The key elements of our partnership remain in place for the duration of our contract through 2030, with our access to OpenAI’s IP, our The post Microsoft and OpenAI evolve partnership to drive the next phase of AI appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Docker Streamlines the  Onboarding Process and Sets Up Developers for Success</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker streamlines developer onboarding and helps organizations set up the right guardrails to give developers the flexibility to innovate within the boundaries of company policies.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-docker-streamlines-the-onboarding-process-and-sets-up-developers-for-success/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results of Google Summer of Code 2024 With the Kotlin Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 13:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2024 marked another exciting year with respect to the Kotlin Foundation’s participation in Google Summer of Code (GSoC). GSoC is a global online program that introduces new contributors to open-source development. This year, contributors worked to expand the Kotlin ecosystem under the guidance of mentors from Google, Gradle, Microsoft, and JetBrains. Join our Slack channel […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/01/google-summer-of-code-2024-with-kotlin-results/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coldplay evolves the fan experience with Microsoft AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This fan remix experience was built with a collection of Azure AI services available in Azure AI Foundry, Microsoft’s unified AI platform announced a few months ago at Microsoft Ignite. It integrates advanced AI services like natural language processing, computer vision, and machine learning to help organizations across industries create AI-powered solutions that accelerate innovation and differentiate them in the market. The post Coldplay evolves the fan experience with Microsoft AI appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Time Series</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 12:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How do you identify unusual patterns in data that might reveal critical issues or hidden opportunities? Anomaly detection helps identify data that deviates significantly from the norm. Time series data, which consists of data collected over time, often includes trends and seasonal patterns. Anomalies in time series data occur when these patterns are disrupted, making […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/anomaly-detection-in-time-series/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve forecasting challenges for the retail and CPG industry using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 20:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Amazon Web Services (AWS) helps in solving forecasting challenges by customizing machine learning (ML) models for forecasting. We dive into Amazon SageMaker Canvas and explain how SageMaker Canvas can solve forecasting challenges for retail and consumer packaged goods (CPG) enterprises.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/solve-forecasting-challenges-for-the-retail-and-cpg-industry-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling generative AI self-service using Amazon Lex, Amazon Bedrock, and ServiceNow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 20:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can integrate Amazon Lex with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and ServiceNow to provide 24/7 automated support and self-service options.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enabling-generative-ai-self-service-using-amazon-lex-amazon-bedrock-and-servicenow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing  Perpetual Licenses on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 18:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Marketplace provides various licensing models for paid plugins to suit different user preferences. Now, we are introducing a new option that may change how your users purchase your plugins – perpetual licensing. Licensing options on JetBrains Marketplace The current licensing schemes available on JetBrains Marketplace include: The licensing type (with or without fallback) and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/01/introducing-perpetual-licenses-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WinForms: Analyze This (Me in Visual Basic)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your WinForms code might have issues—maybe an Async call picked the wrong overload, or it’s leaking data into resource files. Time to call in a code-shrink! So, WinForms, Analyze This!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-winforms-analyzers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 17:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this release, you’ll find improvements to the UI, reworked internals for various components, and a binary-enabled textgen. MPS 2024.3 also brings enhanced support for icons, an applicability condition for quick-fixes, and numerous platform updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 What’s new Let’s check out the new features we’ve prepared for you in this release. Top-level folder […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/01/mps-2024-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Global Acceleration Program for RISE with SAP on Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SAP and Microsoft are excited to announce a global program, the SAP RISE Acceleration Program. The post Announcing Global Acceleration Program for RISE with SAP on Microsoft Azure appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/announcing-global-acceleration-program-for-rise-with-sap-on-microsoft-azure/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a bulge on my bicycle tire when I inflate it?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get the order of operations right.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250121-01/?p=110790 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn’t the Windows blue screen of death prominently identify the company that created the driver that crashed?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Because the driver that crashed may not be the one at fault.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250121-00/?p=110788 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Code Security in JetBrains IDEs and Qodana With Mend.io</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has partnered with Mend.io, a trusted name in application security. This collaboration will help us continue providing the tools you need to develop secure applications with ease and confidence in our IDEs and Qodana. For the best user experience, make sure to use the latest stable version 2024.3.2. Why Mend? Trusted by industry giants […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/maximize-code-security-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana-with-mend-io/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking MediatR Validation: Moving from Pipeline to Domain Objects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore why traditional MediatR pipeline validation might be hurting your .NET application&#39;s architecture. Discover how to move validation to domain objects with value objects, following the &#39;Parse, Don&#39;t Validate&#39; principle.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/rethinking-mediatr-pipeline-validation-pattern/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing MSBuild properties and user configuration from source generators: Creating a source generator - Part 13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how to read MSBuild settings from inside a source generator, and how to use this to allow user configuration of your generator
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-source-generator-part-13-providing-and-accessing-msbuild-settings-in-source-generators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Complex Types in Entity Framework: A Complete Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 08:08:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core (EF Core) is a handy tool for database operations in .NET applications. It is also so powerful that you will find everything you can do conventionally in SQL queries with easy LINQ methods. Today, we will explore an essential feature of Efcore that may help you organize
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-complex-types-in-entity-framework-a-complete-guide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Database Connectivity with EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 06:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether during application startup, multi-step workflows, or monitoring an application’s overall health, verifying database connectivity is essential for smooth operation and graceful handling of potential failures. It improves reliability and the overall user experience. In modern containerized environments, often managed by orchestrators like Kubernetes (K8S), it’s equally important for services to report their health status. […] The post Testing Database Connectivity with EF Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: How to create Custom Attributes, and why they are useful</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applying custom attributes to C# classes and interfaces can be useful for several reasons. Let’s learn how to create Custom Attributes in C#, and let’s explore some practical usage!
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/create-custom-csharp-attributes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder: When a C&#43;&#43; object fails to construct, the destructor does not run</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you need to run after a failed construction, you have to put it in a base class or member variable.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250120-00/?p=110783 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending Regular Expressions (Regex) Support on Azure SQL Managed Instance (MI)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 13:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce the Private Preview of Regular Expressions (Regex) support on Azure SQL Managed Instance (MI). This new feature brings powerful text processing capabilities to your SQL queries, enabling you to perform complex pattern matching and data manipulation with ease. Regex support in Azure SQL The Regex feature in Azure SQL follows […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/extending-regular-expressions-regex-support-on-azure-sql-managed-instance-mi 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release of TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines. Some highlights of this release include: We recommend upgrading to apply the latest improvements and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/01/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Roslyn to analyze and rewrite code in a solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve written a lot about Roslyn in the context of Roslyn Analyzers and Source Generators. You can also use Roslyn as a library to analyze and generate code. For instance, you can create a console application that loads a solution, find patterns, and rewrite code. While Roslyn Analyzers are tied to a single project, you can use Roslyn as a library to analyze a whole solution. Let&#39;s create the console…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Unreal Engine Project Issues With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you saw our blog post about using Qodana in Unity and .NET projects, you know that we’ve been striving to explore Qodana’s potential for game development. What’s our next stop on this mission? Seeing our code quality platform in action with Unreal Engine, one of the most popular engines for different types of projects […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/01/unreal-engine-project-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user application access token management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article looks at management application access tokens in an ASP.NET Core web application. Any application with or without a user can use application access tokens as long as the application can persist the tokens in a safe way. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/token-mgmt-ui-application Blogs in this series Setup The ASP.NET Core web application authenticates using OpenID Connect […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/01/20/asp-net-core-user-application-access-token-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s FastSortedList</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a set of open-source .NET 8 packages created by the author since .NET 2, currently in production. It includes the EncryptionHelper class, which offers efficient methods for data encryption, key generation, and password verification.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/01/20/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-fastsortedlist/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Replacing Mid-Level Engineers - Dev Leader Weekly 79</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss recent claims about AI replacing mid-level engineers.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/01/18/ai-replacing-midlevel-engineers-dev-leader-weekly-79 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Monoliths: A Practical Guide for Growing Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A well-designed monolith can scale remarkably well, despite industry trends pushing toward microservices. From database sharding to message queues, learn practical strategies to grow your monolithic system effectively.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/scaling-monoliths-a-practical-guide-for-growing-systems 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Tools (Safely) with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In previous posts in this series I&#39;ve shown how to call LLMs with C# using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI NuGet package. In this post I want to look at how you can enable the LLM to make calls into your own C# code by giving it &amp;quot;tools&amp;quot; it can use. And we&#39;ll also discuss some of the security implications as this can open up a number of concerning attack vectors. There are a number of reasons you might want to give an LLM the ability to call a tool.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.5-1 and 1.22.11-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds including security fixes is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-5-1-and-1-22-11-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Leap Forward with Modern AI using Microsoft 365 Agents SDK and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Leap Forward with Modern AI using Microsoft 365 Agents SDK and Semantic Kernel Today we’re featuring a guest author, Arafat Tehsin, who’s a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for AI. He’s written an article we’re sharing below, focused on how to Leap Forward with Modern AI using Microsoft 365 Agents SDK and Semantic Kernel. We’ll […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-leap-forward-with-modern-ai-using-microsoft-365-agents-sdk-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the crash when trying to erase an element from a std::set</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another kind of fiasco.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250117-00/?p=110777 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2025.1 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the launch of the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major release of ReSharper and the .NET Tools! This initial EAP build is now available for download and offers a preview of the upcoming features and enhancements. Your feedback is crucial in helping us refine these updates, so we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/resharper-2025-1-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 has just begun. This is your chance to preview the new features and enhancements we’ve been working on and share your feedback to help us shape the future of JetBrains Rider. There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: To see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/rider-2025-1-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Files View in Solution Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In modern development, repositories are much more than just .NET solutions. From TypeScript end-to-end tests and Docker compose files to global.json and Playwright configs – your codebase contains numerous essential files that live outside of your C# projects.While these files are fully supported in Rider, they can be hard to find when viewing your solution […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/new-files-view-in-solution-explorer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire小贴示 – 管理容器和数据生命周期</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 11:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自 James Montemagno 的 .NET Aspire Quick Tip – Managing Container &amp;amp; Data Lifetime .NET Aspire 凭借其强大的应用程序组合编排功能增强了本地开发流程。在 .NET Aspire 应用程序主机中，您可以在一个集中位置为应用程序指定所有项目、可执行文件、云资源和容器。当您运行应用程序主机项目时，.NET Aspire 将自动运行您的项目和可执行文件，根据需要配置云资源，并下载和运行应用程序依赖的容器。.NET Aspire 9 添加了新功能，让您可以更好地控制在本地计算机上管理容器生命周期的方式，从而在使用容器时加快开发速度。 .NET Aspire 容器 让我们看一个简单的 .NET Aspire 应用程序主机示例，该示例创建一个本地 Redis 容器资源，等待其可用后，为 Web 项目配置连接字符串： // Create a distributed application builder given the command line arguments. var builder = DistributedApplication.CreateBuilder(args); // Add a Redis server to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/net-aspire%e5%b0%8f%e8%b4%b4%e7%a4%ba-%e7%ae%a1%e7%90%86%e5%ae%b9%e5%99%a8%e5%92%8c%e6%95%b0%e6%8d%ae%e7%94%9f%e5%91%bd%e5%91%a8%e6%9c%9f 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re starting this year off with the opening of the RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program. In this blog post, you’ll find details about the new features and improvements we’ve been working on. What’s coming in RubyMine 2025.1? AI Assistant The 2024.3 release introduced enhanced cloud-based completion for Ruby code. The upcoming release will […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/01/the-rubymine-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
