<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 19:57:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Train and deploy AI models at trillion-parameter scale with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod support for P6e-GB200 UltraServers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 19:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we review the technical specifications of P6e-GB200 UltraServers, discuss their performance benefits, and highlight key use cases. We then walk though how to purchase UltraServer capacity through flexible training plans and get started using UltraServers with SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/train-and-deploy-ai-models-at-trillion-parameter-scale-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-support-for-p6e-gb200-ultraservers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 7 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the seventh preview release of .NET 10 with enhancements across the .NET Runtime, SDK, libraries, C#, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more. Check out the full release notes linked below and get started today. [cta-button align=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Download .NET 10 Preview 7&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;https://get
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-7 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Indegene’s AI-powered social intelligence for life sciences turns social media conversations into insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Indegene’s Social Intelligence Solution uses advanced AI to help life sciences companies extract valuable insights from digital healthcare conversations. Built on AWS technology, the solution addresses the growing preference of HCPs for digital channels while overcoming the challenges of analyzing complex medical discussions on a scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-indegenes-ai-powered-social-intelligence-for-life-sciences-turns-social-media-conversations-into-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking enhanced legal document review with Lexbe and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, Lexbe, a legal document review software company, demonstrates how they integrated Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services to transform their document review process, enabling legal professionals to instantly query and extract insights from vast volumes of case documents using generative AI. Through collaboration with AWS, Lexbe achieved significant improvements in recall rates, reaching up to 90% by December 2024, and developed capabilities for broad human-style reporting and deep automated inference across multiple languages.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate AIOps with SageMaker Unified Studio Projects, Part 2: Technical implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus on implementing this architecture with step-by-step guidance and reference code. We provide a detailed technical walkthrough that addresses the needs of two critical personas in the AI development lifecycle: the administrator who establishes governance and infrastructure through automated templates, and the data scientist who uses SageMaker Unified Studio for model development without managing the underlying infrastructure.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-aiops-with-sagemaker-unified-studio-projects-part-2-technical-implementation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate AIOps with Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio projects, Part 1: Solution architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents architectural strategies and a scalable framework that helps organizations manage multi-tenant environments, automate consistently, and embed governance controls as they scale their AI initiatives with SageMaker Unified Studio.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-aiops-with-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio-projects-part-1-solution-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 Now Available in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 17:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share that GPT-5, OpenAI’s latest frontier model, is now rolling out in GitHub Copilot for Visual Studio. GPT-5 offers faster responses and even better performance for writing and understanding code. This release brings a new level of capability to
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/gpt-5-now-available-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunting Living Secrets: Secret Validity Checks Arrive in GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 16:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever waded through a swamp of secret scanning alerts wondering, “Which of these are actually dangerous right now?” — this enhancement is for you. Secret validity checks in GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps (and the standalone Secret Protection experience) add a high‑signa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/hunting-living-secrets-secret-validity-checks-arrive-in-github-advanced-security-for-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI agents made easy with Goose and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI agents can be a complex task. But it also can be a fairly simple combination of answers to the following questions: What is the AI backend that powers my intelligent fuzzy computation? What tools do you need to give to the AI to access external systems or execute predefined software commands? What is...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-ai-agents-with-goose-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft is a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Container Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re proud to announce that Microsoft has once again been recognized as a Leader in the 2025 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Container Management, for the third year in a row. The post Microsoft is a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Container Management appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/microsoft-is-a-leader-in-the-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-container-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Security with Continuous Access Evaluation (CAE) comes to Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that Continuous Access Evaluation (CAE) is now supported on Azure DevOps, bringing a new level of near real-time security enforcement to your development workflows. 🔐 What Is CAE?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/real-time-security-with-continuous-access-evaluation-cae-comes-to-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell Is Now an AI-First Tool for Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From the 2025.2 version onward, every paid DataSpell subscription includes JetBrains AI Pro for free, reflecting our commitment to bringing AI into our data products. Please note that the bundled AI Pro plan is limited to use inside DataSpell. Download DataSpell 2025.2 AI Pro included at no extra cost! You now get JetBrains AI Pro […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/08/dataspell-is-now-an-ai-first-tool-for-data-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? A feature of C# is null-coalescing operators. The ?? operator (null-coalescing operator) returns the left-hand operand if it is not null; otherwise, it evaluates and returns the right-hand operand. The ??= operator (null-coalescing assignment operator) assigns the right-hand operand’s value to the left-hand operand only if the left-hand operand is null. Welcome to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/12/dotinsights-august-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free JetBrains Student Pack – Your Toolkit for a Future in Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For a successful career in tech, having the right tools from day one makes all the difference. That’s why we created the JetBrains Student Pack – all-in-one development kit designed to help you learn to code, build real-world projects, and kickstart your future career, using the same tools trusted by developers at Google, NASA, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/08/12/jetbrains-student-pack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 2: Using a &lt;code&gt;std::list&lt;/code&gt;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we worked out how we want a proposed &amp;quot;tracking pointer&amp;quot; to work. Now we can try implementing it. One idea is to give each trackable object a list of all the tracking pointers that a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250812-00/?p=111454 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mssql-python vs pyodbc: Benchmarking SQL Server Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 11:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/mssql-python-vs-pyodbc-benchmarking-sql-server-performance 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running .NET in the browser without Blazor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to run .NET in your browser without using Blazor, and instead rely on lower-level abstractions provided by [JSImport] and [JSExport]
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/running-dotnet-in-the-browser-without-blazor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains with its CLion IDE Is Now an Official ST Authorized Partner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re pleased to announce that JetBrains has joined the ST Partner Program. Through this collaboration, we aim to improve the experience of embedded developers working with ST microcontroller solutions in CLion. Here’s what developers get from this partnership: About ST ST (STMicroelectronics) is a European company that specializes in designing, developing, and manufacturing semiconductor technologies. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/st-authorized-partner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Audit Logs in EF Core Without Polluting Your Entities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:16:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most modern applications require the historical audit logging of changes made to database entities. The audit log provides you with insights into all changes made, including their timestamps and the users responsible for those changes. The logs ensure transparency, allowing stakeholders to observe what changes were made to business-critical data,
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/implementing-audit-logs-in-ef-core-without-polluting-your-entities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s letter to Governor Newsom on harmonized regulation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just sent a letter to Gov. Gavin Newsom calling for California to lead the way in harmonizing state-based AI regulation with national—and, by virtue of US leadership, emerging global—standards.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/letter-to-governor-newsom-on-harmonized-regulation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling accounting capacity with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Built with OpenAI o3, o3-Pro, GPT-4.1, and GPT-5, Basis’ AI agents help accounting firms save up to 30% of their time and expand capacity for advisory and growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/basis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Amazon Bedrock Pricing for a Chatbot Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 19:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll look at Amazon Bedrock pricing through the lens of a practical, real-world example: building a customer service chatbot. We&#39;ll break down the essential cost components, walk through capacity planning for a mid-sized call center implementation, and provide detailed pricing calculations across different foundation models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/demystifying-amazon-bedrock-pricing-for-a-chatbot-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune OpenAI GPT-OSS models on Amazon SageMaker AI using Hugging Face libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 19:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Released on August 5, 2025, OpenAI’s GPT-OSS models, gpt-oss-20b and gpt-oss-120b, are now available on AWS through Amazon SageMaker AI and Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we walk through the process of fine-tuning a GPT-OSS model in a fully managed training environment using SageMaker AI training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-openai-gpt-oss-models-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-using-hugging-face-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GA of Bicep templates support for Microsoft Entra ID resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that Bicep templates for Microsoft Entra ID resources is generally available from July 29th, 2025. Bicep templates bring declarative infrastructure as code (IaC) capabilities to Microsoft Graph resources. This new capability will initially be available for core Microsoft Entra ID resources. Bicep templat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/bicep-templates-for-microsoft-entra-id-resources-is-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling ≠ Glue: Why changing AI workflows still feels like duct tape</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s a weird contradiction in modern AI development. We have better tools than ever. We’re building smarter systems with cleaner abstractions. And yet, every time you try to swap out a component in your stack, things fall apart. Again. This isn’t just an inconvenience. It’s become the norm. You’d think with all the frameworks and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-changing-ai-workflows-still-feels-like-duct-tape/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 1: Concept art</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Suppose you have a C++ object, and you want to be able to create a &amp;quot;tracking pointer&amp;quot; that points to the object and follows it as it moves. // Concept art - final product may differ in significant ways struct Widget : trackable_object { ⟦ ... ⟧ }; Widget w; tracking_ptr p(w); asse
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250811-00/?p=111451 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify Date &amp; Time Formatting with Spargine’s DateTimeFormat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_08_2025/10_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_08_2025/10_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The DateTimeFormat type in Spargine simplifies date and time formatting for .NET developers. It provides a strongly typed set of options, reducing the need to memorize format strings. Available through the DotNetTips.Spargine.Extensions project, it streamlines formatting using the ToFormattedString() extension method for efficient coding.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/08/10/boost-your-net-projects-simplify-date-time-formatting-with-spargines-datetimeformat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remocal and Minimum Viable Models: Why Right-Sized Models Beat API Overkill</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 12:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A practical approach to escaping the expensive, slow world of API-dependent AI The $20K Monthly Reality Check You built a simple sentiment analyzer for customer reviews. It works great. Except it costs $847/month in API calls and takes 2.3 seconds to classify a single review. Your &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; document classifier burns through $3,200/month. Your chatbot feature?...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/remocal-minimum-viable-models-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Complex Side Projects With Purpose - Dev Leader Weekly 105</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss building side projects, adding complexity, and doing so intentionally!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/09/building-complex-side-projects-with-purpose-dev-leader-weekly-105 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-08-08</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 06:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/09/weekly-recap-20250808 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Most Common REST API Design Mistakes (and How to Avoid Them)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Five REST API design mistakes I see all the time, with practical fixes. Use consistent resource naming, evolve contracts instead of bumping versions, add envelopes, pagination and filtering, return Problem Details, and bake in auth, authz, and rate limits from day one.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-5-most-common-rest-api-design-mistakes-and-how-to-avoid-them 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Recipe AI Agent with Koog and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, I’m Philippe Charriere, a Principal Solutions Architect at Docker. I like to test new tools and see how they fit into real-world workflows. Recently, I set out to see if JetBrains&#39; Koog framework could run with Docker Model Runner, and what started as a quick test turned into something a lot more interesting than...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-a-recipe-ai-agent-with-koog-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under what conditions could a &lt;code&gt;Read­File&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Write­File&lt;/code&gt; fail to transfer all of the bytes, and how do I detect that?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to understand the conditions under which the Read­File and Write­File functions would fail to transfer all of the bytes, and how to detect that this has occurred. The obvious reason why the Read­File functions would fail to transfer all the bytes is if there aren&#39;t that man
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250808-00/?p=111447 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KotlinX RPC 0.9.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 13:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release of kotlinx.rpc introduces significant improvements aimed at the long-term stability, maintenance, and evolution of the library. We’ve focused on decoupling dependencies and simplifying the API to create a more robust and user-friendly experience. Ready to get started? Build your next project with the interactive generator at start.ktor.io, or check out our samples on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kotlinx-rpc-0-9-1-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Faster with dotNetTips.com Spargine 8: August 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am delighted to announce the release of Spargine 8 (v2025.8.8.6) on August 6th, 2025. Spargine, my open-source project, now offers NuGet packages for .NET 8 &amp;amp; 9. These enhancements have been integrated across all my projects, many of which are currently in production. I encourage you to explore these updates and share any feedback … Continue reading Coding Faster with dotNetTips.com Spargine 8: August 2025 Release →
Link to article: https://dotnettips.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code - August 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the August 2025 release of the Python, Pylance and Jupyter e
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-august-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Integrate Qodana Into TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are many compelling reasons to use TeamCity as your CI server. Thanks to its out-of-the-box features, smart test management capabilities, and great scalability for enterprises, TeamCity offers a robust and reliable CI solution. But if you’re really looking to increase compliance and improve code quality and security, you can couple it with Qodana. Integrating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/08/how-to-integrate-qodana-into-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The Supply Chain Attack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 2 of our MCP Horror Stories series, an in-depth look at real-world security incidents exposing the vulnerabilities in AI infrastructure, and how the Docker MCP Toolkit delivers enterprise-grade protection. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) promised to be the &amp;quot;USB-C for AI applications&amp;quot; – a universal standard enabling AI agents like ChatGPT, Claude,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-the-supply-chain-attack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Complete Playwright End to End Story, Tools, AI, and Real-World Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Introduction End to end testing has evolved dramatically, and Playwright stands at the forefront. Playwright offers a full ecosystem empowering developers to write, debug, and maintain tests with speed and reliability. From its po Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/the-complete-playwright-end-to-end-story-tools-ai-and-real-world-workflows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Assistant, Junie and Kineto Now Support GPT-5 by OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we are committed to delivering the best technologies to professional developers. We support multiple LLM providers across our AI products to ensure you have access to the right tools for your needs and the freedom to choose the ones you prefer. Today, we’re excited to announce that the latest model from OpenAI, GPT-5, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/08/07/gpt-5-support-in-ai-assistant-junie-kineto/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 in Azure AI Foundry: The future of AI apps and agents starts here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re announcing general availability of OpenAI’s new flagship, GPT-5, in Azure AI Foundry. This is more than a new model release; it is the most powerful large language model (LLM) ever released across key benchmarks. The post GPT-5 in Azure AI Foundry: The future of AI apps and agents starts here appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/gpt-5-in-azure-ai-foundry-the-future-of-ai-apps-and-agents-starts-here/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2025 (version 1.103)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code July 2025 Release (1.103) Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/july-2025-(version-1.103) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loosely Coupled Monolith – Software Architecture – 2025 Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 16:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over five years ago, back in 2020, I posted a series of blog posts and videos outlining what the Loosely Coupled Monolith is. I was recently tagged in a post saying they read those original posts and moved forward with the concept. In this article/video, I want to share with you the core ideas behind… Read More »Loosely Coupled Monolith – Software Architecture – 2025 Edition The post Loosely Coupled Monolith – Software Architecture – 2025 Edition appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DIVA logistics agent, powered by Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 16:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how DTDC and ShellKode used Amazon Bedrock to build DIVA 2.0, a generative AI-powered logistics agent.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-diva-logistics-agent-powered-by-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate enterprise workflows by integrating Salesforce Agentforce with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 16:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores a practical collaboration, integrating Salesforce Agentforce with Amazon Bedrock Agents and Amazon Redshift, to automate enterprise workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-enterprise-workflows-by-integrating-salesforce-agentforce-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.6-1 and 1.23.12-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 16:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-6-1-and-1-23-12-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect that Windows is running in S-Mode?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows S-Mode is a mode of Windows which restricts programs to those which came from the Microsoft Store. You might have a program that is available from the Microsoft Store (therefore is allowed to run in S-Mode), and you want to know whether to suggest that the user install a companion program that is not allowed in S-Mode. How can a pro
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250807-00/?p=111444 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Bedrock powers next-generation account planning at AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 13:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how we built Account Plan Pulse, a generative AI tool designed to streamline and enhance the account planning process, using Amazon Bedrock. Pulse reduces review time and provides actionable account plan summaries for ease of collaboration and consumption, helping AWS sales teams better serve our customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-bedrock-powers-next-generation-account-planning-at-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 and the new era of work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5 is OpenAI’s most advanced model—transforming enterprise AI, automation, and workforce productivity in the new era of intelligent work.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-new-era-of-work 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5 for developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing GPT-5 in our API platform—offering high reasoning performance, new controls for devs, and best-in-class results on real coding tasks.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-for-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from External Data Handling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Intro Our ISE team at Microsoft recently completed an engagement with a large industrial customer. The system we developed was distributed between the edge and the cloud and made use of technologies including Python, Azure IoT, Kubernetes, Redis and D
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/learnings-from-external-data-handling-learnings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v1.0 with new features for building robust AI-powered apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 06:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce Dev Proxy v1.0, with new language model-specific testing capabilities. This release introduces tools to help developers build more reliable AI-powered applications by simulating real-world scenarios and tracking resource usage. In this version: Language model failure simulation with 15 realistic failur
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v1-0-with-new-features-for-building-robust-ai-powered-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;HTTP header exceeding 8,192 bytes&#34; error when using the Azure SDK for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 01:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recent issue was identified in the azure-resourcemanager libraries for Java regarding HTTP headers exceeding 8,192 bytes. Following analysis, this was addressed within the Azure SDK for Java by increasing the maximum response header size limit of “reactor-netty-http
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/http-header-size-errors-in-the-azure-sdk-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From hard refusals to safe-completions: toward output-centric safety training</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how OpenAI&#39;s new safe-completions approach in GPT-5 improves both safety and helpfulness in AI responses—moving beyond hard refusals to nuanced, output-centric safety training for handling dual-use prompts.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-safe-completions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 System Card</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5 offers high reasoning performance, new controls for devs, and best-in-class results on real coding tasks.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-system-card 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are introducing GPT‑5, our best AI system yet. GPT‑5 is a significant leap in intelligence over all our previous models, featuring state-of-the-art performance across coding, math, writing, health, visual perception, and more.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pioneering AI workflows at scale: A deep dive into Asana AI Studio and Amazon Q index collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 21:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce the integration of Asana AI Studio with Amazon Q index, bringing generative AI directly into your daily workflows. In this post, we explore how Asana AI Studio and Amazon Q index transform enterprise efficiency through intelligent workflow automation and enhanced data accessibility.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pioneering-ai-workflows-at-scale-a-deep-dive-into-asana-ai-studio-and-amazon-q-index-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI for the payments industry – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the unique challenges facing the payments industry in scaling AI adoption, the regulatory considerations that shape implementation decisions, and practical approaches to applying responsible AI principles. In Part 2, we provide practical implementation strategies to operationalize responsible AI within your payment systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-for-the-payments-industry-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI for the payments industry – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of our series, we explored the foundational concepts of responsible AI in the payments industry. In this post, we discuss the practical implementation of responsible AI frameworks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-for-the-payments-industry-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process multi-page documents with human review using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to process multi-page documents with a human review loop using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Amazon SageMaker AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/process-multi-page-documents-with-human-review-using-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Copilot Chat Prompts .NET Devs Should Steal Today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial intelligence is quickly becoming a key part of the modern .NET developer’s toolkit. With GitHub Copilot Chat, you can save countless hours, eliminate friction, and unlock new levels of creativity by simply asking the right questions. But what exactly should you ask? Here are five GitHub Copilot Chat prompts every .NET dev shoul
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/5-copilot-chat-prompts-dotnet-devs-should-steal-today 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Browser Automation Tool (Preview) in Azure AI Foundry Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 15:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview T
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/announcing-the-browser-automation-tool-preview-in-azure-ai-foundry-agent-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating FedRAMP Compliance with Docker Hardened Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) compliance costs typically range from $450,000 to over $2 million and take 12 to 18 months to achieve, time your competitors are using to capture government contracts. While you’re spending months configuring FIPS cryptography, hardening security baselines, and navigating 400+ security controls, your competitors are already shipping to...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/fedramp-compliance-with-hardened-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I disable pieces of the property sheet for a service in the Services MMC snap-in?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was developing a service, and they didn&#39;t want users to be able to change the service&#39;s startup type (e.g. change it from auto-start to disabled). They saw that other services had the &amp;quot;Startup type&amp;quot; field disabled. How can they get in on that action? They found that that they could get close to the desired behavior by restricting
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250806-00/?p=111440 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next Evolution of Docker Hardened Images: Customizable, FedRAMP Ready, AI Migration Agent, and Deeper Integrations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We launched Docker Hardened Images (DHI) in May, and in just two and a half months, adoption has accelerated rapidly across industries. From nimble startups to global enterprises, organizations are turning to DHI to achieve near-zero CVEs, shrink their attack surface, and harden their software supply chain, all without slowing down developers. In a short...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/the-next-evolution-of-docker-hardened-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Drift: The Pitfall of Local Machines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve seen it before. Someone says, “It works on my machine,” and suddenly you’re deep in a rabbit hole trying to understand why a project that works perfectly on one machine fails to build or test on another. That’s configuration drift – when a developer’s actual environment starts to deviate from the project’s intended configuration. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/08/configuration-drift-the-pitfall-of-local-machines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 11:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this month’s Java Annotated Monthly – your pit stop for all things related to Java, Kotlin, frameworks, and the ever-shifting tech scene. From helpful reads to red-hot takes, we’ve lined up a range of articles for curious devs and ambitious teams. But wait, there’s more! As always, our AI corner is here, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/java-annotated-monthly-august-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a RAG application with LangChain and Local LLMs powered by Ollama</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Local large language models (LLMs) provide significant advantages for developers and organizations. Key benefits include enhanced data privacy, as sensitive information remains entirely within your own infrastructure, and offline functionality, enabling uninterrupted work even without internet access. While cloud-based LLM services are conveni
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/build-a-rag-application-with-langchain-and-local-llms-powered-by-ollama 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Fixed in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the first-ever standalone What’s Fixed overview of an IntelliJ IDEA release! We are always working hard to make the IDE even more stable, reliable, and enjoyable to use. In previous releases, information about this work was blended into the What’s New content, making it very long and sometimes hard to grasp. To address […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/whats-fixed-intellij-idea-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Notebook Meets IntelliJ Platform: Advancing IDE Plugin Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The value of extensibility The ability to extend and customize software, from game mods to browser extensions, gives users a sense of freedom and the chance to bring their ideas to life. JetBrains IDEs already provide this sense of freedom through their support for plugins. For some time now, creating plugins for JetBrains IDEs has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/08/kotlin-notebook-meets-intellij-platform-advancing-ide-plugin-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use EdDSA signatures to validate tokens in ASP.NET Core using OpenID Connect</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 09:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some identity providers use the EdDSA / ED25519 algorithm to sign and issue tokens. This post shows how to validate the tokens using the Nuget package from ScottBrady and ASP.NET Core. Using the default OpenID Connect setup, the keys are not read and the tokens cannot be validated. The error message could return something like […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/08/06/use-eddsa-signatures-to-validate-tokens-in-asp-net-core-using-openid-connect/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI for Beginners - Java Edition launched</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 08:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IN ONE hour, all ONLINE, complete our ne
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/generative-ai-for-beginners-java-edition-launched 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI assistant using Amazon Q Business with Amazon S3 clickable URLs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 01:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build an AI assistant using Amazon Q Business that responds to user requests based on your enterprise documents stored in an S3 bucket, and how the users can use the reference URLs in the AI assistant responses to view or download the referred documents, and verify the AI responses to practice responsible AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ai-assistant-using-amazon-q-business-with-amazon-s3-clickable-urls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Providing ChatGPT to the Entire U.S. Federal Workforce</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, OpenAI for Government is announcing a new partnership with the U.S. General Services Administration (GSA) to launch a transformative initiative. For the next year, ChatGPT Enterprise will be available to the entire federal executive branch workforce at essentially no cost.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/providing-chatgpt-to-the-entire-us-federal-workforce 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
