<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData with Qdrant and Azure AI Search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how to use Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData to implement semantic search using Qdrant and Azure AI Search
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/vector-data-qdrant-ai-search-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS re:Invent 2024 Highlights: Top takeaways from Swami Sivasubramanian to help customers manage generative AI at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We spoke with Dr. Swami Sivasubramanian, Vice President of Data and AI, shortly after AWS re:Invent 2024 to hear his impressions—and to get insights on how the latest AWS innovations help meet the real-world needs of customers as they build and scale transformative generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-top-takeaways-from-swami-sivasubramanian-to-help-customers-manage-generative-ai-at-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do we have header files &lt;pshpackN.h&gt; and &lt;poppack.h&gt; instead of just issuing the pragma directly?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Because the pragma may not work everywhere.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241216-00/?p=110645 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-tenant RAG with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are continuously seeking ways to use their proprietary knowledge and domain expertise to gain a competitive edge. With the advent of foundation models (FMs) and their remarkable natural language processing capabilities, a new opportunity has emerged to unlock the value of their data assets. As organizations strive to deliver personalized experiences to customers using […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multi-tenant-rag-with-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Use an AI Git Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We show how to create Git agent and use this Git agent to understand PR branches for a variety of user personas — without needing to know the ins and outs of Git.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-create-and-use-an-ai-git-agent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AI Assistants Can Decode GitHub Repos for UI Writers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Exploring AI-assisted tools for UI writers, we demonstrate how to enhance GitHub PR review workflows to identify user-facing text changes, and offer a step-by-step guide and insights into leveraging LLMs effectively.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-for-ui-writers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create internal GitHub repos for your team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 now includes support for creating internal repositories for GitHub organizations. This feature allows developers to work within their GitHub organization’s guidelines within the Visual Studio environment more effectively. Managing repositories involves configuring varying levels of visibility and permissions. Visual Studio 2022’s new feature aims to smooth this process by providing support for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/create-internal-github-repos-for-your-team 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Reasons You Should Use dbt Core in PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dbt Core is a modern data transformation framework. It doesn’t extract or load data and is only responsible for the T in the ELT (extract-load-transform) process. dbt connects to your data warehouse and helps you prepare your data so it can later be used to answer business questions. In this blog post, we’ll talk about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/dbt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating SBOM for NuGet packages</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) is a list of components in a piece of software. It is a critical part of the software supply chain, as it helps to identify and track the components used in a software project. In this post, I describe how to easily generate a Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) for NuGet packages. To generate an SBOM for NuGet packages, you can use the Microsoft.Sbom.Targets package.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming Language into Code: Building and Evaluating a Robotic Code Generation Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post explores the development and evaluation of an AI assistant that converts natural language into robotic code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/code-generation-evaluation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Rebus, NServiceBus, and MassTransit in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Messaging systems are the backbone of scalable and distributed applications in .NET. They allow different parts of an application, or even separate applications, to communicate efficiently and reliably. Choosing the right messaging library, Rebus, NServiceBus, or MassTransit, is essential to ensure our system’s performance and long-term maintainability. In this article, we will compare Rebus, NServiceBus, […] The post Comparison of Rebus, NServiceBus, and MassTransit in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Maximize Your .NET Performance with Spargine’s FastLogger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2024/15_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2024/15_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages, developed since .NET 2, featuring the FastLogger class for efficient logging. FastLogger significantly enhances logging speed (11x faster) while offering various logging methods.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/12/15/boost-your-net-projects-maximize-your-net-performance-with-spargines-fastlogger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid Using C# Events in ASP.NET Core Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2024/15_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2024/15_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is part of the C# Advent Calendar 2024 - check out all of the C# articles from this year! C# events are a powerful feature of the…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/avoid-using-csharp-events-in-aspnetcore-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal vs. Public APIs in Modular Monoliths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2024/14_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2024/14_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every article about modular monoliths tells you to use public APIs between modules, but they rarely explain why these APIs exist or how to design them properly. After building several large-scale modular monoliths, I&#39;ve learned that public APIs are not just about clean code - they&#39;re about controlling chaos.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/internal-vs-public-apis-in-modular-monoliths 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon trains sequential ensemble models at scale with Amazon SageMaker Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ensemble models are becoming popular within the ML communities. They generate more accurate predictions through combining the predictions of multiple models. Pipelines can quickly be used to create and end-to-end ML pipeline for ensemble models. This enables developers to build highly accurate models while maintaining efficiency, and reproducibility. In this post, we provide an example of an ensemble model that was trained and deployed using Pipelines.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-trains-sequential-ensemble-models-at-scale-with-amazon-sagemaker-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing login node load balancing in SageMaker HyperPod for enhanced multi-user experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a solution for implementing load balancing across login nodes in Slurm-based HyperPod clusters. By distributing user activity evenly across all available nodes, this approach provides more consistent performance, better resource utilization, and a smoother experience for all users. We guide you through the setup process, providing practical steps to achieve effective load balancing in your HyperPod clusters.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implementing-login-node-load-balancing-in-sagemaker-hyperpod-for-enhanced-multi-user-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Clearwater Analytics is revolutionizing investment management with generative AI and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Clearwater Analytics’ foray into generative AI, how they’ve architected their solution with Amazon SageMaker, and dive deep into how Clearwater Analytics is using LLMs to take advantage of more than 18 years of experience within the investment management domain while optimizing model cost and performance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-clearwater-analytics-is-revolutionizing-investment-management-with-generative-ai-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Twitch used agentic workflow with RAG on Amazon Bedrock to supercharge ad sales</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how we innovated to build a Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) application with agentic workflow and a knowledge base on Amazon Bedrock. We implemented the RAG pipeline in a Slack chat-based assistant to empower the Amazon Twitch ads sales team to move quickly on new sales opportunities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-twitch-used-agentic-workflow-with-rag-on-amazon-bedrock-to-supercharge-ad-sales/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate analysis and discovery of cancer biomarkers with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 19:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bedrock multi-agent collaboration enables developers to build, deploy, and manage multiple specialized agents working together seamlessly to address increasingly complex business workflows. In this post, we show you how agentic workflows with Amazon Bedrock Agents can help accelerate this journey for research scientists with a natural language interface. We define an example analysis pipeline, specifically for lung cancer survival with clinical, genomics, and imaging modalities of biomarkers. We showcase a variety of specialized agents including a biomarker database analyst, statistician, clinical evidence researcher, and medical imaging expert in collaboration with a supervisor agent.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2412.12 – Texture/Buffer/Visualizer improvements, Work Graph Shader Debugging, and many Timing Capture improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 19:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX on Windows version 2412.12, which can be downloaded here. This release includes several new improvements to GPU Captures and Timing Captures, including: GPU Captures: Custom Buffer/Texture/Mesh Visualizer Improvements Work Graph Shader Debugging (preview) VRS Shading Rate Visualizer Many bug fixes + smaller improvements Timing Captures: New Comparison Layout Range Details “v2” […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2412-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting to a derived class from the future: How to cast from a base class to an incomplete derived class?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deferring the definition until the class is complete.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241213-00/?p=110637 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Legacy to Cloud-Native: How Docker Simplifies Complexity and Boosts Developer Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how the Docker suite of products — including Docker Desktop, Docker Scout, and Docker Hub — helps you accelerate development, modernize legacy applications, and work more efficiently and securely.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/from-legacy-to-cloud-native-how-docker-simplifies-complexity-and-boosts-developer-productivity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackle These Key Software Engineering Challenges to Boost Efficiency with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the top most common software engineering challenges and how Docker’s tools streamline the inner loop of cloud-native workflows.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/tackle-software-engineering-challenges-to-boost-efficiency/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview the GitHub Copilot extension for Teams Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the GitHub Copilot for Teams Toolkit—your companion in Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, and GitHub.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/preview-the-github-copilot-extension-for-teams-toolkit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With the JetBrains Bazel Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 09:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large Bazel projects are becoming increasingly common in modern software development. Unfortunately, the IDE experience for these projects often leaves much to be desired. In this blog post, we’ll explore the new JetBrains Bazel plugin and how it can enhance your daily work with Bazel projects. We’ll begin with an overview of what Bazel users […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/getting-started-with-the-jetbrains-bazel-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4o: Revolutionizing Real-Time Speech Technology in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In an era where communication is more crucial than ever, real-time speech has evolved from a futuristic concept into an essential tool across many industries. With gpt-4o leading the way, organizations and developers are now leveraging AI to create interactive and seamless speech experiences. From customer support to retail, the impact of real-time speech applications […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/gpt-4o-revolutionizing-real-time-speech-technology-in-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotnet scaffold – .NET的下一代内容创建工具</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 01:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自微软首席产品经理Sayed Ibrahim Hashimi的dotnet scaffold – Next Generation Content Creation for .NET 。 在Visual Studio中，用于ASP.NET Core项目的Scaffolding是一个已经存在很久的功能，它在ASP.NET Core发布之后不久就已经添加。我们多年来也一直支持从命令行里进行Scaffolding。从命令行的使用体验中，我们听到了许多用户的反馈，他们希望我们为Scaffolding提供一个交互式的命令行界面 (CLI)。为此目标，我们一直在开发一个新的交互式CLI工具 dotnet scaffold。这个工具现在已经做为预览版发布。在这边文章中，我们将描述如果获取和使用这个新的命令行工具。此工具是开源的，您可以在scaffolding存储库 中查看代码。该存储库包含了 dotnet scaffold 工具的代码以及其他scaffolding相关的代码。 安装dotnet scaffold 我们将使用 dotnet tool 命令来安装此工具。您可以执行以下的命令来安装最新发布的版本： dotnet tool install --global Microsoft.dotnet-scaffold 如需安装特定的版本，请访问nuget.org上的软件包。有关如果管理dotnet工具的更多信息，请参阅 .NET 工具 – .NET CLI | Microsoft Learn 上的文档。在上面的命令中，我们正在全局安装该工具，但是您也可以将工具安装到本地文件夹中。.NET 工具的文档中包含了有关这两种方法的更多信息 .NET 工具 – .NET CLI | Microsoft Learn。 使用dotnet scaffold […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/dotnet-scaffold-net%e7%9a%84%e4%b8%8b%e4%b8%80%e4%bb%a3%e5%86%85%e5%ae%b9%e5%88%9b%e5%bb%ba%e5%b7%a5%e5%85%b7 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marten Improvements in 7.34</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 20:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Through a combination of Marten community members and in collaboration with some JasperFx Software clients, we’re able to push some new fixes and functionality in Marten 7.34 just today. For the F# Person in your Life You can now use F# Option types in LINQ Where() clauses in Marten. Check out the pull request for … Continue reading Marten Improvements in 7.34 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/12/marten-improvements-in-7-34/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing .NET Community Toolkit 8.4! Partial properties support for MVVM, new analyzers, and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re happy to announce the official launch of the .NET Community Toolkit 8.4 release, featuring support for partial properties for the MVVM Toolkit generators, new analyzers, bug fixes and enhancements, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-the-dotnet-community-toolkit-840 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your ML lifecycle using the new and improved Amazon SageMaker Python SDK – Part 2: ModelBuilder</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of this series, we introduced the newly launched ModelTrainer class on the Amazon SageMaker Python SDK and its benefits, and showed you how to fine-tune a Meta Llama 3.1 8B model on a custom dataset. In this post, we look at the enhancements to the ModelBuilder class, which lets you seamlessly deploy a model from ModelTrainer to a SageMaker endpoint, and provides a single interface for multiple deployment configurations.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your ML lifecycle using the new and improved Amazon SageMaker Python SDK – Part 1: ModelTrainer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus on the ModelTrainer class for simplifying the training experience. The ModelTrainer class provides significant improvements over the current Estimator class, which are discussed in detail in this post. We show you how to use the ModelTrainer class to train your ML models, which includes executing distributed training using a custom script or container. In Part 2, we show you how to build a model and deploy to a SageMaker endpoint using the improved ModelBuilder class.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Q Apps supports customization and governance of generative AI-powered apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we examine how these features enhance the capabilities of Amazon Q Apps. We explore the new customization options, detailing how these advancements make Amazon Q Apps more accessible and applicable to a wider range of enterprise customers. We focus on key features such as custom labels, verified apps, private sharing, and data collection apps (preview).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-q-apps-supports-customization-and-governance-of-generative-ai-powered-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answer questions from tables embedded in documents with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business launched support for tabular search, which you can use to extract answers from tables embedded in documents ingested in Amazon Q Business. Tabular search is a built-in feature in Amazon Q Business that works seamlessly across many domains, with no setup required from admin or end users. In this post, we ingest different types of documents that have tables and show you how Amazon Q Business responds to questions related to the data in the tables.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The last Early Access release of 2024 – content reuse ♻️ and more fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reusing content is one of the few things that software developers and technical writers are equally passionate about. Both know that avoiding duplication isn’t just a good practice, it’s essential – and it works for documentation, just as it does for code: When should you start reusing content in technical documentation? The general advice is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/12/the-last-early-access-release-of-2024-content-reuse-and-more-fixes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest in your Career With KotlinConf 2025 Workshops</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            KotlinConf workshops provide engineers with an opportunity to deepen their Kotlin programming skills. These hands-on sessions focus on real-world projects and solutions, guided by hosts who are either members of the JetBrains Kotlin development team or certified Kotlin trainers. These workshops will take place on May 21, 2025, in Copenhagen, and will cater to various […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/invest-in-your-career-with-kotlinconf-2025-workshops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your Git confidence with the new file rename notification</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever renamed a file in Solution Explorer and wondered if Git is tracking your changes correctly? You’re not alone. Many developers have found this process confusing and worry whether their changes are being properly staged in Git. But worry no more – there’s a solution! When you rename files in Solution Explorer, Visual […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/boost-your-git-confidence-with-the-new-file-rename-notification 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to Multi-Agent AI apps with Azure Cosmos DB and Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB was named by Bloomberg as the no. 1 Database of choice for Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and Large Language Model (LLM) customization. It is used by OpenAI to scale it’s ChatGPT service, and by many thousands of customers worldwide, serving billions of end-users with globally distributed apps at planet scale. In this […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/an-introduction-to-multi-agent-ai-apps-with-azure-cosmos-db-and-azure-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API naming principles for conditional operations: On, When, and If</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Describing when a condition is tested.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241212-00/?p=110632 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the New Bazel Plugin EAP for IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce the public Early Access Program (EAP) of the new Bazel plugin for IntelliJ IDEA. It is available on JetBrains Marketplace for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3. This initial release supports Bazel projects focusing exclusively on Java and Kotlin. Support for more languages including Python, Go, and Scala is coming soon, while C++ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/introducing-the-new-bazel-plugin-eap-for-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Get Containerized: Simplifying Complexity for Modern Businesses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adapt to rising tech costs with containers, enabling consistent, efficient app deployment across cloud and hybrid environments.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/lets-get-containerized/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From VDI to CDEs: Solving Remote Development Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) has been a popular solution for remote development, but it is not without challenges. At JetBrains, we’ve recently seen growing interest in Cloud Development Environments (CDEs) as an alternative. To understand why many are thinking about this shift, we contacted our customers and uncovered the key reasons behind the trend. In […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2024/12/from-vdi-to-cdes-solving-remote-development-challenges/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore 2024.5 Is Out With SQLite Support and an Improved Reporting Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 11:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2024.5 introduces SQLite support and an improved reporting experience that includes PDF export capabilities, new filters in interactive tables, and much more. Datalore Cloud customers have already received the new updates automatically, and Datalore On-Premises customers can upgrade by following these instructions. SQLite database support Datalore now offers native support for SQLite! You can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/12/12/datalore-2024-5-is-out-with-sqlite-support-and-an-improved-reporting-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Sentiment Analysis in Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 10:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sentiment analysis is one of the most popular ways to analyze text. It allows us to see at a glance how people are feeling across a wide range of areas and has useful applications in fields like customer service, market and product research, and competitive analysis. Like any area of natural language processing (NLP), sentiment […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/introduction-to-sentiment-analysis-in-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Javac support in Visual Studio Code Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 08:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, we are pleased to announce partial support of Javac as the underlying compiler in Visual Studio Code Java, JDT, and JDT-LS. The effort to provide this support has been a joint collaboration with Red Hat and Microsoft and is nearly a year in the making. This change aims to ensure timely support for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/annoucing-javac-support-in-visual-studio-code-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – December 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 20:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The December 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include a special review of docstring generation features from Pylance, the new Python Environments extension in preview, Pylance&#39;s &amp;quot;full&amp;quot; language server mode, and much more. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-december-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Boards Hub Rollout Expectations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although the process may seem slow, we are steadily progressing toward rolling out the New Boards Hub to all customers. Our plan is to deprecate the old Boards experience for all Azure DevOps service users by the end Q1 2025. The rollout is advancing on two fronts. First, we are setting the New Boards Hub […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-boards-hub-rollout-expectations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AWS sales uses Amazon Q Business for customer engagement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April 2024, we launched our AI sales assistant, which we call Field Advisor, making it available to AWS employees in the Sales, Marketing, and Global Services organization, powered by Amazon Q Business. Since that time, thousands of active users have asked hundreds of thousands of questions through Field Advisor, which we have embedded in our customer relationship management (CRM) system, as well as through a Slack application.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights from your Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL database using the Amazon Q Business connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through configuring and integrating Amazon Q for Business with Aurora PostgreSQL-Compatible to enable your database administrators, data analysts, application developers, leadership, and other teams to quickly get accurate answers to their questions related to the content stored in Aurora PostgreSQL databases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-from-your-amazon-aurora-postgresql-database-using-the-amazon-q-business-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tealium built a chatbot evaluation platform with Ragas and Auto-Instruct using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate the importance of generative AI in the collaboration between Tealium and the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) team by automating the following: 1/ Evaluating the retriever and the generated answer of a RAG system based on the Ragas Repository powered by Amazon Bedrock, 2/ Generating improved instructions for each question-and-answer pair using an automatic prompt engineering technique based on the Auto-Instruct Repository. An instruction refers to a general direction or command given to the model to guide generation of a response.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Box Ready-To-Code Dev Box images template</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft One Engineering System (1ES) team shares a sample for building Ready-To-Code Dev Box environments pre-configured with the necessary tools, repositories, and settings, ensuring consistency and reliability across teams.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/dev-box-ready-to-code-dev-box-images-template 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless publishing with Azure Functions Flex Consumption</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Struggling with complex deployment processes for your serverless applications? Visual Studio 2022 introduces a seamless solution with the new Azure Functions Flex Consumption hosting plan, now generally available. Imagine a world where deploying your serverless applications to a hosting plan that supports fast scaling and VNet is as simple as a right-click. With the Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/effortless-publishing-with-azure-functions-flex-consumption 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EBSCOlearning scales assessment generation for their online learning content with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate how EBSCOlearning partnered with AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to use the power of generative AI in revolutionizing their learning assessment process. We explore the challenges faced in traditional question-answer (QA) generation and the innovative AI-driven solution developed to address them.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ebscolearning-scales-assessment-generation-for-their-online-learning-content-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Single Jobs in TeamCity Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now debug individual jobs in TeamCity Pipelines. Instead of running the entire pipeline, just execute a specific job and get instant feedback without extra waiting. When you debug a single job, you can: When debugging one job, its dependencies will also be executed. Read more about job debugging in our docs. Bug fixes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/debug-single-jobs-in-teamcity-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the CONTINUE_IF_FAILED equivalent of RETURN_IF_FAILED?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Be careful how you write it, or better: Don&#39;t write it at all.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241211-00/?p=110629 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Developer Ecosystem 2024: The Unstoppable Rise of AI, Leading Languages, and Impact on Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year winds down, we’re taking a moment to reflect on what shaped the developer landscape in 2024. Drawing insights from over 23,000 developers worldwide, this year’s JetBrains State of Developer Ecosystem highlights significant trends shaping the development world. The prominence of AI in software is growing, with four out of five companies embracing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2024/12/11/the-state-of-developer-ecosystem-2024-unveiling-current-developer-trends-the-unstoppable-rise-of-ai-adoption-leading-languages-and-impact-on-developer-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixtral 12B is now available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Pixtral 12B (pixtral-12b-2409), a state-of-the-art vision language model (VLM) from Mistral AI that excels in both text-only and multimodal tasks, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. You can try this model with SageMaker JumpStart, a machine learning (ML) hub that provides access to algorithms and models that can be deployed with one click for running inference. In this post, we walk through how to discover, deploy, and use the Pixtral 12B model for a variety of real-world vision use cases.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invoking Async Power: What Awaits WinForms in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With .NET 9, we’re bringing a suite of new async APIs to WinForms, aimed at making UI updates, dialog interactions, and control management more efficient.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-winforms-async-apis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Organize Your Legal Team’s Work In YouTrack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s no secret that YouTrack is used by various sorts of teams, including legal ones. In conversations with our customers, legal technologies and legal operations are emerging as hot topics. YouTrack can help legal firms whose main areas of business are jurisprudence and providing legal services, as well as in-house legal departments at companies in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/12/how-to-organize-your-legal-team-s-work-in-youtrack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to your slide deck using multimodal foundation models on Amazon Bedrock – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Parts 1 and 2 of this series, we explored ways to use the power of multimodal FMs such as Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings, Amazon Titan Text Embeddings, and Anthropic’s Claude 3 Sonnet. In this post, we compared the approaches from an accuracy and pricing perspective.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/talk-to-your-slide-deck-using-multimodal-foundation-models-on-amazon-bedrock-part-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless publishing to Azure WebJobs on Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of the cumbersome process involved in publishing your .NET console applications to Azure WebJobs on Linux? For developers yearning for a seamless and efficient method to deploy their applications, Visual Studio 2022 introduces a much-anticipated solution. Visual Studio 2022 now supports right-click publishing to Azure WebJobs on Linux, making the deployment process […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/effortless-publishing-to-azure-webjobs-on-linux 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate actions across enterprise applications using Amazon Q Business plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a generative AI-powered assistant that enhances employee productivity by solving problems, generating content, and providing insights across enterprise data sources. Beyond searching indexed third-party services, employees need access to dynamic, near real-time data such as stock prices, vacation balances, and location tracking, which is made possible through Amazon Q Business plugins. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-actions-across-enterprise-applications-using-amazon-q-business-plugins/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compute scaling in Azure Fluid Relay</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the journey of identifying and fine-tuning the optimal Kubernetes autoscaling configuration for Azure Fluid Relay.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/compute-scaling-in-azure-fluid-relay 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ONNX GenAI Connector for Python (Experimental)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 16:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ONNX GenAI Connector for Python (Experimental) With the latest update we added support for running models locally with the onnxruntime-genai. The onnxruntime-genai package is powered by the ONNX Runtime in the background, but first let’s clarify what ONNX, ONNX Runtime and ONNX Runtime-GenAI are. ONNX ONNX is an open-source format for AI models, both for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/onnx-genai-connector-for-python-experimental 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It rather involved being on the other side of this airtight hatchway: Disabling anti-malware scanning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have already infiltrated the process, then you can disable things from the inside.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241210-00/?p=110626 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover JetBrains Consulting Partner Services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we are committed to empowering developers to do their best work with world-class tools. But even the best tools can deliver so much more when paired with expert guidance. That is why we’ve built a global network of Consulting Partners – professionals dedicated to helping you and your team maximize the value of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/12/10/discover-jetbrains-consulting-partner-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Dockerize a React App: A Step-by-Step Guide for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 12:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We show how to dockerize a React app to streamline your development process, eliminate &amp;quot;it works on my machine&amp;quot; problems, and ensure seamless deployments.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-dockerize-react-app/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books for Beginner Programmers: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous post, we explored some must-read books for anyone starting their programming journey. This time, we’re focusing on books for specific programming languages, helping you get comfortable with your chosen tech stack. Whether you’re learning Python, Java, Kotlin, or C, there’s something here for everyone. Let’s turn the page and get started!📚 Python […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/10/books-for-beginner-programmers-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Python 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Michael Kennedy, the founder of Talk Python and a PSF Fellow. Hey there. I’m Michael Kennedy, the founder of Talk Python and a Python Software Foundation (PSF) Fellow. I’m thrilled that the PyCharm team invited me to share my thoughts on the state of Python in 2024. If you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/the-state-of-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the YamlDotNet source generator for Native AOT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how you can use the YamlDotNet source generator to do strongly-typed serialization and deserialization, even in Native AOT apps
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/using-the-yamldotnet-source-generator-for-native-aot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: GraalVM and GraalPy Meet IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Fabio Niephaus to explore integrations for GraalVM, GraalPy, and other Graal Languages in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: December 19, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract GraalVM has become very popular in the Java community, not just because of its JIT compiler, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/new-livestream-from-code-to-clarity-with-the-redesigned-structure-tool-window-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execution Context Management with AsyncLocal and ThreadLocal in .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In modern distributed .NET applications, managing context across execution boundaries is a critical architectural concern. While both AsyncLocal and ThreadLocal provide mechanisms for maintaining contextual data, their implementations and use cases differ significantly in ways that impact system architecture, performance, and maintainability. This
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/execution-context-asynclocal-threadlocal-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Monitor Your App&amp;#x27;s Performance with .NET Benchmarking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:22:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Benchmarking is essential in application development, especially if you aim to scale up your app. Benchmarking enables you to evaluate your application&#39;s resource consumption, which helps you identify potential updates to speed up performance. If not scaling, you will need the application performance to be optimal to enhance
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/how-to-monitor-your-apps-performance-with-net-benchmarking/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marten Event Sourcing Gets Some New Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 22:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software has gotten the chance this work to build out several strategic improvements to both Marten and Wolverine through collaborations with our clients who have had some specific needs. This has been highly advantageous because it’s helped push some significant, long planned technical improvements while getting all important feedback as clients integrate the new … Continue reading Marten Event Sourcing Gets Some New Tools →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/09/marten-event-sourcing-gets-some-new-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Local AI models with .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s look at how to build and run local AI models with .NET Aspire.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/local-ai-models-with-dotnet-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating ML experimentation with enhanced security: AWS PrivateLink support for Amazon SageMaker with MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With access to a wide range of generative AI foundation models (FM) and the ability to build and train their own machine learning (ML) models in Amazon SageMaker, users want a seamless and secure way to experiment with and select the models that deliver the most value for their business. In the initial stages of an ML […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-ml-experimentation-with-enhanced-security-aws-privatelink-support-for-amazon-sagemaker-with-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Python in VS Code Wrapped</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year comes to a close, we would like to take the time to reflect and celebrate the incredible progress the Python extension for VS Code has made in the past year. From merging in top requested features to countless lines of code written and deleted, keep reading to get an inside look to all things
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/2024-python-vscode-wrapped 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a Unified Data Model is Critical: Lessons from Building Microsoft’s Semantic Layer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Some years ago, we were wrestling with a persistent issue in our data stack. Every team had their own way of collecting and structuring data. What was a simple query for one team became a debugging nightmare for another. Discovering the right dataset felt like looking for a needle in a haystack, and standardizing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/udm/unified-data-models-101 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Global System Integrators can make the most of their GitHub Copilot licenses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered code assistant tools like GitHub Copilot have revolutionized the development landscape. We’ve observed significant Copilot adoption among Global System Integrators (GSIs), who are leading the charge in harnessing its potential. While many developers are already utilizing GitHub Copilot in their internal projects, GSI’s are eager to integrate Copilot into their own application development lifecycles. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/dont-let-your-github-copilot-licenses-collect-dust-how-gsis-can-make-their-every-license-count 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep working with non-blocking Code Cleanup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of waiting for Code Cleanup to finish every time you save your work? Visual Studio 2022 will no longer lock up and get in the way of your tasks as it’s cleaning up the code under the covers. Every developer knows the importance of maintaining clean code. However, the traditional Code Cleanup […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/keep-working-with-non-blocking-code-cleanup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to read C&#43;&#43; compiler errors: Failing to create a shared_ptr</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding what you asked the compiler to do, and why it couldn&#39;t comply.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241209-00/?p=110619 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New! Security Analysis Plugin for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Application security is a critical requirement in modern software development. The latest release of IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 – along with the optional new Security Analysis by Qodana plugin – elevates your security efforts with advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for code written in Java and Kotlin. Trained on popular OWASP security benchmark projects, this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/security-analysis-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 – 2024.3.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. v2024.3.1 introduces advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for Java and Kotlin. This allows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/intellij-idea-2024-3-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the binary log to find the source of a .NET dependency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding where a dependency comes from can be tedious. This is especially true when you have a large project with many dependencies. Recently, .NET brings a new tool dotnet nuget why to help you understand why a package is installed in your project. However, there is a better way to do it, and it doesn&#39;t requires a recent SDK. dotnet nuget why can explain why a package is included in your project:…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 06:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about the Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern. We are going to see how to implement this pattern in C# and how it can solve certain design problems. Let’s start. What is The Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern? Chain of Responsibility is a behavioral pattern that helps us design a […] The post Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Entra External ID with an Auth0 OpenID Connect identity provider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at implementing an Open ID Connect identity provider in Microsoft Entra External ID. Auth0 is used as the identity provider and an ASP.NET Core application is used to test the authentication. Microsoft Entra External ID federates to Auth0. Client code: https://github.com/damienbod/EntraExternalIdCiam Microsoft Entra External ID supports federation using OpenID Connect and was […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/12/09/using-entra-external-id-with-an-auth0-openid-connect-identity-provider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Resilient Systems with Wolverine’s Transactional Outbox</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 03:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software is completely open for business to help you get the best possible results with the “Critter Stack” tools or really any type of server side .NET development efforts. A lot of what I’m writing about is inspired by work we’ve done with our ongoing clients. I think I’m at the point where I … Continue reading Build Resilient Systems with Wolverine’s Transactional Outbox →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/08/build-resilient-systems-with-wolverines-transactional-outbox/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
