<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:50:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhance call center efficiency using batch inference for transcript summarization with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce general availability of batch inference for Amazon Bedrock. This new feature enables organizations to process large volumes of data when interacting with foundation models (FMs), addressing a critical need in various industries, including call center operations. In this post, we demonstrate the capabilities of batch inference using call center transcript summarization as an example.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-call-center-efficiency-using-batch-inference-for-transcript-summarization-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Meta Llama 3.1 models for generative AI inference using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fine-tuning Meta Llama 3.1 models with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart enables developers to customize these publicly available foundation models (FMs). The Meta Llama 3.1 collection represents a significant advancement in the field of generative artificial intelligence (AI), offering a range of capabilities to create innovative applications. The Meta Llama 3.1 models come in various sizes, with 8 billion, 70 billion, and 405 billion parameters, catering to diverse project needs. In this post, we demonstrate how to fine-tune Meta Llama 3-1 pre-trained text generation models using SageMaker JumpStart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Sucks?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Serverless sucks… or does it? There is a neverending supply of people saying that serverless is trash and has no value. The issue often with these statements is they need to provide more context. As always, context is king, and understanding the use case to make decisions on when serverless might be appropriate. YouTube Check… Read More »Serverless Sucks? The post Serverless Sucks? appeared first on CodeOpinion.
Link to article: https://codeopinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your testing experience with MSTest.Analyzers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSTest ships with extensive suite of code analyzers to help you write well-formed, performant and error free tests.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/supercharge-your-testing-experience-with-ms-test-analyzers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyze customer reviews using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 17:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores an innovative application of large language models (LLMs) to automate the process of customer review analysis. LLMs are a type of foundation model (FM) that have been pre-trained on vast amounts of text data. This post discusses how LLMs can be accessed through Amazon Bedrock to build a generative AI solution that automatically summarizes key information, recognizes the customer sentiment, and generates actionable insights from customer reviews. This method shows significant promise in saving human analysts time while producing high-quality results.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accuracy evaluation framework for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 16:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative artificial intelligence (AI), particularly Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) solutions, are rapidly demonstrating their vast potential to revolutionize enterprise operations. RAG models combine the strengths of information retrieval systems with advanced natural language generation, enabling more contextually accurate and informative outputs. From automating customer interactions to optimizing backend operation processes, these technologies are not just […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accuracy-evaluation-framework-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate healthcare interaction and documentation with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Transcribe using Live Meeting Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 16:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, physicians spend about 49% of their workday documenting clinical visits, which impacts physician productivity and patient care. Did you know that for every eight hours that office-based physicians have scheduled with patients, they spend more than five hours in the EHR? As a consequence, healthcare practitioners exhibit a pronounced inclination towards conversational intelligence solutions, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-healthcare-interaction-and-documentation-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-transcribe-using-live-meeting-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the power of data governance and no-code machine learning with Amazon SageMaker Canvas and Amazon DataZone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 16:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon DataZone is a data management service that makes it quick and convenient to catalog, discover, share, and govern data stored in AWS, on-premises, and third-party sources. Amazon DataZone allows you to create and manage data zones, which are virtual data lakes that store and process your data, without the need for extensive coding or […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-the-power-of-data-governance-and-no-code-machine-learning-with-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-and-amazon-datazone/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate performance using a custom chunking mechanism with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 16:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Accenture used the customization capabilities of Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock to incorporate their data processing workflow and custom logic to create a custom chunking mechanism that enhances the performance of Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and unlock the potential of your PDF data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-performance-using-a-custom-chunking-mechanism-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does ERROR_KEY_DELETED mean?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You now have a handle to a key that doesn&#39;t exist, and there&#39;s nothing you can do with it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240821-46/?p=110160 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is AI Trained? Is My Data Safe with Generative AI, Copilot and OpenAI Solutions?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 14:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The adoption of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Large Language Models (LLMs) is rapidly increasing, and these technologies are being harnessed across various sectors to drive innovation, streamline operations, and enhance productivity. Generative AI, in particular, has emerged as a transformative technology, capable of creating new content, making predictions, and providing insights that were once the […] The article How is AI Trained? Is My Data Safe with Generative AI, Copilot and OpenAI Solutions?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper Tips &amp; Tricks with Matt Ellis – Livestream</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 13:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on September 12, 2024, at 2:00 PM UTC for another JetBrains livestream event. You can register for the event using the link below or subscribe to our YouTube channel, JetBrainsTV, to get a notification closer to the event. With over 20 years of ReSharper setting the standard for the .NET development experience, it’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/21/resharper-tips-tricks-with-matt-ellis-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing your Azure deployments with PSRule</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 13:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PSRule for Azure is a powerful tool designed to validate your Azure Infrastructure as Code (IaC). PSRule runs checks based on the Well-Architected Framework, helping you ensure your Azure solutions follow security best practices. See how to integrate PSRule into your workflow, and catch security issues in your IaC templates early.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/secure-azure-deployments-with-psrule 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Chatbots With LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 10:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Dido Grigorov, a deep learning engineer and Python programmer with 17 years of experience in the field. Chatbots have evolved far beyond simple question-and-answer tools. With the power of large language models (LLMs), they can understand the context of conversations and generate human-like responses, making them invaluable for customer […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/how-to-build-chatbots-with-langchain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New C&#43;&#43; features in Visual Studio v17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 version 17.11 is here and comes with a host of new features for C++ developers. We’ve made improvements across our toolchain, Unreal Engine support, Build Insights, CMake debugger, and more. This post gives a quick overview of what’s available;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-c-features-in-visual-studio-v17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between Record Struct and Record Class in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 05:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll discuss the differences between record struct and record class in C#. First, we will shortly explain each of the types. Afterward, we’ll show and describe each difference between them. Let’s start. Record Struct and Record Class in C# C# is built upon two categories of types: value types and reference types. […] The post Differences Between Record Struct and Record Class in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Ceremony Sagas with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 21:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine puts a very high emphasis on reducing code ceremony and tries really hard to keep itself out of your application code. Wolverine is also built with testability in mind. If you’d be interested in learning more about how Wolverine could simplify your existing application code or set you up with a solid foundation for sustainable … Continue reading Low Ceremony Sagas with Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/08/20/low-ceremony-sagas-with-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate Amazon SageMaker Data Wrangler flows to Amazon SageMaker Canvas for faster data preparation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 17:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how you can bring your existing SageMaker Data Wrangler flows—the instructions created when building data transformations—from SageMaker Studio Classic to SageMaker Canvas. We provide an example of moving files from SageMaker Studio Classic to Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) as an intermediate step before importing them into SageMaker Canvas.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/migrate-amazon-sagemaker-data-wrangler-flows-to-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-for-faster-data-preparation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Boards Hub Rollout Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 17:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in March, we shared an update on our initiative to make the New Boards Hub the default experience for all organizations. However, that rollout was delayed as we shifted priorities for several months. Today, we’re excited to announce that the rollout of the New Boards Hub is back on track.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-boards-hub-rollout-update-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: KPMG Clara AI and Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 16:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re featuring KPMG on our Semantic Kernel blog for their work on Clara AI in KPMG. You can learn more about the solution here: KPMG Partnership with Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel Here’s a quote from KPMG on the partnership, “Microsoft and KPMG entered a strategic alliance to modernize the work of KPMG professionals.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-kpmg-clara-ai-and-microsofts-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use IP-restricted presigned URLs to enhance security in Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While presigned URLs offer a convenient way to grant temporary access to S3 objects, sharing these URLs with people outside of the workteam can lead to unintended access of those objects. To mitigate this risk and enhance the security of SageMaker Ground Truth labeling tasks, we have introduced a new feature that adds an additional layer of security by restricting access to the presigned URLs to the worker’s IP address or virtual private cloud (VPC) endpoint from which they access the labeling task.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the power of structured data for enterprises using natural language with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss an architecture to query structured data using Amazon Q Business, and build out an application to query cost and usage data in Amazon Athena with Amazon Q Business. Amazon Q Business can create SQL queries to your data sources when provided with the database schema, additional metadata describing the columns and tables, and prompting instructions. You can extend this architecture to use additional data sources, query validation, and prompting techniques to cover a wider range of use cases.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.39 Is Out With Smart Mode for Single Files, the Ability to Compare Files, the Structure Tool Window, Automatic Language Detection for Untitled Files, and Other Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 14:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.39 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.39 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/08/fleet-1-39-is-out-with-smart-mode-for-single-files-the-ability-to-compare-files-the-structure-tool-window-automatic-language-detection-for-untitled-files-and-other-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another tribute to Microsoft history hiding in Building 41</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Logo touches.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240820-00/?p=110152 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Datalore Cloud Plans – What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 13:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Datalore has evolved over the years, we’ve added more and more pricing tiers to cater to different users in the cloud. The variety of tiers sometimes made choosing a plan complicated. Now, we’ve decided to revamp our subscription plans to simplify the process of finding the option that best fits your needs. You no […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/20/new-datalore-cloud-plans-what-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public preview of SharePoint Framework 1.20 – First release of upcoming features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 13:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the first preview of the upcoming SharePoint Framework 1.20. This time focus is primarily on the Microsoft Viva platform capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/public-preview-of-sharepoint-framework-1-20-first-release-of-upcoming-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Learned From the Perforce 2024 State of Game Technology Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 11:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The gaming industry has long been a hotbed of innovation, with developers consistently pushing the boundaries of what’s possible. But as we progress into 2024, it’s clear that game technology’s sphere of influence is expanding far beyond the realm of gaming. Technological advancements coming out of the game industry are quickly adopted by various other […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/perforce-2024-game-tech-report/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New debugging and diagnostic features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debugging and diagnostics are vital skills for any developer, but they can also be difficult and time-consuming to get proficient . That’s why we’ve added some fantastic new features and enhancements to Visual Studio 2022 v17.11 that will help you find and resolve bugs faster and easier than ever before.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-debugging-and-diagnostic-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding CDN supply-chain attacks with Subresource Integrity (SRI)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discus the recent pollyfill.io supply-chain attack and describe how to protect against similar attacks using Subresource Integrity (SRI)
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/avoiding-cdn-supply-chain-attacks-with-subresource-integrity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postman&#39;s pre-request scripts: how to perform HTTP POST requests (with JSON body) and how to set Cookie authentication.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Postman, you can define scripts to be executed before the beginning of a request. Can we use them to work with endpoints using Cookie Authentication?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/postman-prerequest-script-cookie-auth/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Azure DevOps Server Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While we recommend our hosted service for most customers due to its scalability and flexibility, we understand the importance of the on-premises version for many of our customers. Therefore, we remain committed to providing support and improvement for both versions. Previously,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-azure-devops-server-roadmap 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine is taking a leap forward with the first 3.0 Alpha Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 20:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why should you care about this Wolverine tool anyway? I’d say that if you’re building just about any kind of server side .NET application, that Wolverine will do more than any other existing server side .NET framework in the mediator, background processing, HTTP, or asynchronous messaging space to simplify your code, maximize the testability of … Continue reading Wolverine is taking a leap forward with the first 3.0 Alpha Release →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Rerank 3 Nimble now generally available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 16:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Cohere Rerank 3 Nimble foundation model (FM) is now generally available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. This model is the newest FM in Cohere’s Rerank model series, built to enhance enterprise search and Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) systems. In this post, we discuss the benefits and capabilities of this new model with some examples. Overview […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cohere-rerank-3-nimble-now-generally-available-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constructing nodes of a hand-made linked list, how hard can it be?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trying to force copy elision.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240819-00/?p=110145 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Code Arena: How Well Can AI Models Understand Your Entire Project?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the last couple of years, AI has found its way into virtually all aspects of software development. We know that AI models are getting smarter, and we can clearly see how they have become better at seemingly everything, but why is this happening? One factor that is changing is context size, which is how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/08/long-code-arena-how-well-can-ai-models-understand-your-entire-project/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New git tooling features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 v17.11 includes fantastic updates to everyone working with Git. They bring the richness of both GitHub and Azure DevOps into Visual Studio and part of your natural workflow. This greatly simplifies your inner loop, making you even more productive than before.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-git-tooling-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the PyCharm Databricks Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 08:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re introducing the Databricks integration with PyCharm Professional to make it easier for you to process, store, and analyze your data! The integration allows you to build your data and AI apps on the Databricks Data Intelligence Platform directly within PyCharm Professional, enhancing the data analytics platform with the powerful Python IDE by JetBrains. It […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/introducing-the-pycharm-databricks-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Debugging in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 06:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll be talking about advanced debugging and inspecting data in C#. We’ll be using Visual Studio 2022 to demonstrate all the debugging techniques. For more information about general debugging, we have another article on the basics of debugging, so feel free to check it out. Let’s start by creating a project that […] The post Advanced Debugging in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vital Role of QA: Why Independent Testing is Essential for Software Integrity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2024/18_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2024/18_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of real estate, rigorous inspections are essential for a safe and functional home. Similarly, in software development, Quality Assurance (QA) plays a crucial role in testing software for quality, security, and performance. While unit tests are important, they cannot replace the comprehensive testing provided by a dedicated QA team. Collaborative integration of QA from the beginning of a project, effective communication, and comprehensive documentation are essential for robust and reliable software.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build A Web API From Scratch – Dev Leader Weekly 57</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2024/17_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2024/17_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Build A Web API From Scratch – Dev Leader Weekly 57 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the basic building blocks for building a Web API in DotNet! The post Build A Web API From Scratch – Dev Leader Weekly 57 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/08/17/build-a-web-api-from-scratch-dev-leader-weekly-57/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete Guide to Amazon SQS and Amazon SNS With MassTransit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2024/17_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2024/17_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we&#39;ll explore how to use Amazon SQS and SNS for asynchronous messaging in .NET applications. We&#39;ll also see how MassTransit simplifies the process, enabling you to build robust message-driven systems.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/complete-guide-to-amazon-sqs-and-amazon-sns-with-masstransit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.0-1 Microsoft build now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 16:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-0-1-microsoft-build-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify development with Dev Container templates for Azure SQL Database – Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 15:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced software development landscape, having a reliable and efficient local development setup is crucial. Dev Containers provide developers with a seamless way to build and test applications locally before deploying them to the cloud. We are announcing the Public Preview of Dev Container templates for Azure SQL Database.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/azure-sql-dev-containers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Malware protection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 15:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read about the different ways that Microsoft 365 Certification validates anti-malware controls.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-malware-protection 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing a new learning module for evaluating and building with Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 15:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing a new learning module that helps you explore Microsoft Entra External ID. This module guides you through building a website for an online grocery store, demonstrating how to use External ID for customer sign-ups and sign-ins. It&#39;s a perfect starting point if you&#39;re new to External ID, offering a hands-on way to create a proof-of-concept project while discovering the platform&#39;s features and capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-id-learning-module 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the missing ordinal 380</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Untangling the error message and developing a theory.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240816-00/?p=110136 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking a JVM Application With IntelliJ IDEA’s Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 09:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in the day, computer games were different. Not only have their graphics and mechanics evolved, but they also had one characteristic that doesn’t seem very common in games today: cheat codes. Cheat codes were sequences of keys that would give you something extraordinary, such as infinite ammo or the ability to walk through walls. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/hacking-a-jvm-application-with-intellij-idea-s-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Router using Azure AI Search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Potential semantic routing solution using Azure AI Search for scalable query handling.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/semantic-routing-using-azure-ai-search 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perform generative AI-powered data prep and no-code ML over any size of data using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 03:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Canvas now empowers enterprises to harness the full potential of their data by enabling support of petabyte-scale datasets. Starting today, you can interactively prepare large datasets, create end-to-end data flows, and invoke automated machine learning (AutoML) experiments on petabytes of data—a substantial leap from the previous 5 GB limit. With over 50 connectors, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/perform-generative-ai-powered-data-prep-and-no-code-ml-over-any-size-of-data-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving OpenJDK Scalar Replacement – Part 3/3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 21:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the final part of our series on scalar replacement in OpenJDK. In the previous posts, we covered the basics of scalar replacement and detailed the improvements we introduced to the implementation. Now, it’s time to see these enhancements in action.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/improving-openjdk-scalar-replacement-part-3-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 Preview 7 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Try out the latest features in .NET 9 Preview 7 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, C#, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-preview-7 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot Content Exclusion Now Available in Visual Studio 2022 17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 17:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Copilot Content Exclusion is now available in Visual Studio 2022 17.11. This feature allows your admins to configure Copilot to ignore certain files in a repository or organization, giving you enterprise control that ensures sensitive information is protected while seamlessly integrating trusted AI for efficient coding.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/copilot-content-exclusion-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delight your customers with great conversational experiences via QnABot, a generative AI chatbot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 15:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            QnABot on AWS (an AWS Solution) now provides access to Amazon Bedrock foundational models (FMs) and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed end-to-end Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) workflow. You can now provide contextual information from your private data sources that can be used to create rich, contextual, conversational experiences. In this post, we discuss how to use QnABot on AWS to deploy a fully functional chatbot integrated with other AWS services, and delight your customers with human agent like conversational experiences.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create scripts with Power Platform CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Power Platform CLI is a great tool to use when you are working with the Power Platform. You can create Power Apps Component Framework (PCF) components with it, you can do tons of administrative actions, and much more! You can run these one by one in the console when you’re developing a Power Platform solution,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/create-scripts-with-power-platform-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code update – August 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 14:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the latest Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code updates including the capability to create declarative copilots.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/teams-toolkit-for-visual-studio-code-update-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instead of putting a hash in the Portable Executable timestamp field, why not create a separate field for the hash?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That would defeat the purpose.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240815-00/?p=110131 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2024.2 Versions of JetBrains IDEs Are Here With Enhanced FLCC and Remote Development, the New UI as the Default, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 09:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains IDEs, .NET tools, and AI Assistant are ready to be updated to the 2024.2 versions, which introduce a plethora of new features and improvements. We’ve seen high adoption rates for the new UI, and in the 2024.2 versions of JetBrains IDEs, the new UI is now the default for all users. The classic UI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/08/15/the-2024-2-versions-of-jetbrains-ides-are-here-with-enhanced-flcc-and-remote-development-the-new-ui-as-the-default-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotCover, dotMemory, dotPeek, and dotTrace 2024.2 Have Been Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dotCover 2024.2, dotMemory 2024.2, dotPeek 2024.2, and dotTrace 2024.2 have been released and are ready for download! Let’s take a look at what’s new with these .NET tools. dotMemory 2024.2 dotTrace 2024.2 dotCover 2024.2 dotPeek 2024.2 General enhancements Handling of external sources Build configuration detection If you’re also interested in learning more about ReSharper 2024.1 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/15/dotnet-tools-242-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2024.2: Deepened C#12 and Initial C#13 Support, New AI Capabilities, Localization, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, ReSharper 2024.2 and the latest versions of other JetBrains .NET tools have just been released. This release brings support for the .NET 9 Preview SDK, new C# and C++ features, localization updates, AI Assistant enhancements, and much more. In this article, we’ll cover the highlights of this major update for ReSharper and touch […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/15/resharper-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2: Full Line Code Completion, Reader Mode, Major Enhancements to Debugging, and More.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, We’re happy to announce the release of Rider 2024.2, which comes packed with a range of exciting features and improvements designed to elevate your .NET and game development experience. From enhanced language support to advanced AI capabilities, this update has something for everyone. Now, let’s dive into the details! Key features and enhancements […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/15/rider-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
