<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:23:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enable or disable ACL crawling safely in Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business recently added support for administrators to modify the default access control list (ACL) crawling feature for data source connectors. Amazon Q Business is a fully managed, AI powered assistant with enterprise-grade security and privacy features. It includes over 40 data source connectors that crawl and index documents. By default, Amazon Q Business […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enable-or-disable-acl-crawling-safely-in-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Contextual Tools for GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 17:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 17.11 now allows you to pass your entire workspace or specific classes and functions as context for GitHub Copilot Chat. By referencing your entire codebase, down to specific classes and functions, Copilot Chat can deliver refined and accurate results tailored to your code. @workspace for project references You can now use GitHub […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/new-contextual-tools-for-github-copilot-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us for JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 17:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey everyone! We’re introducing JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024, the first-ever virtual event dedicated to plugin development for JetBrains products! We invite you to join us on Thursday, November 7 for a full day of engaging sessions and insightful discussions. This conference brings together JetBrains experts and plugin developers to explore topics such as developing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/10/join-us-for-jetbrains-plugin-developer-conf-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the Scalable Vector Extension in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s take an in-depth look at how the team implemented the Scalable Vector Extension (SVE) for .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/engineering-sve-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SK Telecom improves telco-specific Q&amp;A by fine-tuning Anthropic’s Claude models in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how SKT customizes Anthropic Claude models for telco-specific Q&amp;amp;A regarding technical telecommunication documents of SKT using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/sk-telecom-improves-telco-specific-qa-by-fine-tuning-anthropics-claude-models-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Rufus, the Amazon generative AI-powered conversational shopping assistant with over 80,000 AWS Inferentia and AWS Trainium chips, for Prime Day</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into the Rufus inference deployment using AWS chips and how this enabled one of the most demanding events of the year—Amazon Prime Day.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scaling-rufus-the-amazon-generative-ai-powered-conversational-shopping-assistant-with-over-80000-aws-inferentia-and-aws-trainium-chips-for-prime-day/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring alternatives and seamlessly migrating data from Amazon Lookout for Vision</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we discuss how you can maintain access to Lookout for Vision after it is closed to new customers, some alternatives to Lookout for Vision, and how you can export your data from Lookout for Vision to migrate to an alternate solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/exploring-alternatives-and-seamlessly-migrating-data-from-amazon-lookout-for-vision/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 3.0 Is Now Available With New Features and Improved Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This new version uses Kotlin 2.0 and switches to kotlinx-io, making Ktor more up to date and better connected with other Kotlin tools. Ktor 3.0 works faster and gives you more options for building client-server applications. If you’re new to Ktor or need a reminder about how it works, our recent blog post, Ktor 101: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/ktor-3-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 EAP 4: New Embedded Development and Debugging Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new CLion 2024.3 EAP build, 243.19420.28, is out. You can download it for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 EAP This build includes new features for embedded development, such as debug servers, the ability to edit peripheral register values, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/10/clion-2024-3-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code Update – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the September update for Visual Studio Code for Java! In this blog, we will cover some important Spring feature updates and Gradle enhancements, let’s get started! Spring Updates Explain SpEL expressions, query statements, and AOP pointcut expressions with GitHub Copilot SpEL expressions, query statements, and AOP pointcut expressions can sometimes be […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-visual-studio-code-update-september-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code的更新 – 2024年9月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎来到 Visual Studio Code for Java 的九月更新！在本篇博客中，我们将介绍一些重要的 Spring 功能更新和 Gradle 增强功能，让我们开始吧！ Spring 更新 使用 GitHub Copilot 解释 SpEL 表达式、查询语句和 AOP 切入点表达式 SpEL 表达式、查询语句和 AOP 切入点表达式有时编写起来比较复杂，但如果你在 Visual Studio Code 环境中使用 GitHub Copilot，Spring 工具现在会在这些表达式上方显示CodeLense，让你快速让 GitHub Copilot 为你解释这些语句。相应的提示会先提供一个简短的摘要，随后是更详细的解释。这里有一个演示。 CRON 表达式的语法高亮和验证 当 CRON 表达式用于 @Scheduler 注解时，现在可以显示语法高亮，并且如果语法不正确，还会出现错误标记。演示如下。 查询参数名称的新嵌入提示 使用序号引用查询特定参数，现在会显示一个嵌入提示，告诉你该序号所引用的已解析方法参数的名称。 更多 Spring 注解获得内容辅助、跳转定义和查找引用支持 在 Java 源代码中使用 Spring 注解的工作每次发布都会变得更加快捷和轻松。最新的 Spring Boot 工具添加了以下注解的高级功能： […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-visual-studio-code-2024-09 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Security event logging, reviewing, and alerting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Microsoft 365 Certification validates security event logging best practices.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-security-event-logging-reviewing-and-alerting 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A correction to the awaitable lock for C&#43;&#43; PPL tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over-scoped lock.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241010-00/?p=110357 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Coding Workshop for the C&#43;&#43; Basics Course</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 12:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, October 22, 2024, at 3:00 pm UTC (check other timezones) for our free online workshop for the C++ Basics course. If you’ve wanted to learn C++ or have any questions about this language, you’ve come to the right place! C++ is a powerful, general-purpose programming language used to build everything from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/10/10/online-coding-workshop-for-the-c-basics-course/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I do Django APIs in PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 11:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I learn so much from watching conference talks, especially live, when I’m vibing with the crowd. But sometimes I watch and think: “Wow, I wish I could show you how awesome that would be in PyCharm.” That just happened. Here’s the explainer, with a little special something at the end. Hello, DjangoConf I recently attended […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/how-i-do-django-apis-in-pycharm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish MediatR Notifications in Parallel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 04:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore how publishing MediatR notifications in parallel works. Also, we will dive into the advantages and possible pitfalls of using parallel publishing. Let’s start. How MediatR Publishing Works by Default MediatR uses a sequential publishing strategy by default. This means that each handler is called one after the other, waiting […] The post Publish MediatR Notifications in Parallel appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilize Multiple Monitors for Microsoft Dev Box with the Windows App</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 22:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you use cloud-based developer environments like Microsoft Dev Box? Do you use multiple monitors in your setup? Did you know there a new app in Windows that will give you a great experience with multiple monitors and Microsoft Dev Box? Take a look at this video showing configuring multiple monitor setup with the Windows […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/utilize-multiple-monitors-for-microsoft-dev-box-with-the-windows-app 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the knowledge in your Slack workspace with Slack connector for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 22:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will demonstrate how to set up Slack connector for Amazon Q Business to sync communications from both public and private channels, reflective of user permissions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-the-knowledge-in-your-slack-workspace-with-slack-connector-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web-Queue-Worker Architecture Style for Scaling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Web-Queue-Worker is an excellent architecture pattern you can add to your toolbox. It’s just a pattern and can work with a monolith, modular monolith, microservices, or whatever. It provides many benefits for scaling by moving work into the background and if you have long-running jobs, workflows, or even recurring batch jobs. YouTube Check out my YouTube… Read More »Web-Queue-Worker Architecture Style for Scaling The post Web-Queue-Worker Architecture Style for Scaling appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.7 Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 20:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the availability of TypeScript 5.7 Beta. To get started using the beta, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@beta Let’s take a look at what’s new in TypeScript 5.7! Checks for Never-Initialized Variables For a long time, TypeScript has been able to catch issues […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-7-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning off Amazon Lookout for Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 20:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide an overview of the alternate AWS services that offer anomaly detection capabilities for customers to consider transitioning their workloads to.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transitioning-off-amazon-lookout-for-metrics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Queries More Efficiently with the Improved Error Messaging in Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 18:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer is a web-based tool available in the Azure Portal that allows you to manage data, as well as track and fix issues with your queries. In this blog post, we will focus on some of the new features in data explorer that improve the error messaging in the query editor, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/improved-error-messaging-in-azure-cosmos-db-data-explorer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 5: Extended Support for Kotlin Features, Updates to Find in Files, Option to Disable Pre-Commit Checks, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 17:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 5 is here! You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 5 If you haven’t seen our earlier overviews of the latest features, browse through […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Winners | Microsoft Developers Azure AI &amp; Azure Cosmos DB Learning Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 16:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB powers some of the world’s most popular intelligent apps like ChatGPT. In a recent hackathon, Over 9,500 developers engaged with Azure Cosmos DB and Azure AI services, making it one of the most popular on Devpost, ranking in the top 0.2% of all Devpost hackathons. Participants explored AI fundamentals and built their […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/meet-the-winners-microsoft-developers-azure-ai-azure-cosmos-db-learning-hackathon 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Data Explorer: Custom Columns, Filter History, and Query Views Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing large amounts of data is exciting. As a dataset grows in complexity and size, finding efficient ways to sort and analyze this info becomes more important. Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer is a tool to query, review, and manage your data. We’ve heard from your feedback in our NPS survey that there’s a need […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/data-explorer-custom-columns-filter-history-and-query-views-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easier localization with the new resource (.resx) manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 15:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re developing applications that target multiple languages and cultures, you probably know how challenging it can be to manage the resources for each localization. You need to keep track of all the strings, images, icons, and other assets that are specific to each culture, and make sure they are consistent and up to date […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/easier-localization-with-the-new-resource-resx-manager 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Improve Your DevOps Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 14:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to improve your DevOps automation to streamline processes across your software development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-improve-your-devops-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing RBAC Authentication and more for the Azure Cosmos DB Integrated Cache</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce new features for the Azure Cosmos DB! The integrated cache is built into the dedicated gateway, and now there’s new ways to authenticate your requests. Security is top of mind for many organizations, and you can now use Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) with Microsoft Entra ID to authenticate to the dedicated […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-rbac-authentication-and-more-for-the-azure-cosmos-db-integrated-cache 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Joint Bugfix Release for Five Recent MPS Versions Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 11:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re releasing updates for MPS 2022.2, 2022.3, 2023.2, 2023.3, and 2024.1, with numerous fixes included. In general, it’s safe to assume that all features and bug-fixes from the releases of older MPS versions have been included in the newer ones. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.1.1 There are two new features worth mentioning separately: Filter commented out nodes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/10/mps_joint_bug_fixreleases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.41 Is Here With New Bundled Keymaps, Unlimited Splits, Improved Typing Latency and Editor Responsiveness, and Many More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 11:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.41 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.41 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/10/fleet-1-41-is-here-with-new-bundled-keymaps-unlimited-splits-improved-typing-latency-and-editor-responsiveness-and-many-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana 2024.2 Release: Enhanced Android Linter, Hard-coded Password Detection, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 10:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get ready for new features and improvements with our latest Qodana 2024.2 release! This update introduces major enhancements that boost security, extend compatibility, and provide more convenience for development teams looking to increase code quality. Here’s what’s new: View Qodana 2024.2 Documentation Hardcoded password detection Hardcoded passwords can be a critical security issue because, when […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/10/qodana-2024-2-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Is Now Out of Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 09:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In March 2024, we announced the Beta release of TeamCity Pipelines, a new approach to CI/CD that offers blazing-fast pipelines to optimize your development flow. After six months of fine-tuning, adding features, and gathering feedback, we’re excited to announce that TeamCity Pipelines is officially going GA (General Availability) 🎉 This is a major milestone for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/teamcity-pipelines-out-of-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where To Get Data for Your Data Science Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re starting a new project or expanding an existing one, as a data scientist, you’re always on the lookout for new material to explore. Knowing where to get data for data science projects can be challenging, and finding “good data” can be even more difficult. In this article, we’ll look at what makes “good […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/how-to-get-data/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (September 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2024/09_10_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.09.23 and 2024.09.30 releases, 2024-09-18 and 2024-09-30 tool releases, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout September. This month’s release includes some minor changes and bug fixes, 18 new ports, and 319 updates to existing ports. When updating vcpkg, we […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-september-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Pre-training of Llama 3-like model architectures using torchtitan on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 22:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we collaborate with the team working on PyTorch at Meta to showcase how the torchtitan library accelerates and simplifies the pre-training of Meta Llama 3-like model architectures. We showcase the key features and capabilities of torchtitan such as FSDP2, torch.compile integration, and FP8 support that optimize the training efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/efficient-pre-training-of-llama-3-like-model-architectures-using-torchtitan-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 Release Candidate 2 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Try out the latest features in .NET 9 Release Candidate 2 across the .NET SDK, libraries, runtime, ASP.NET Core, SignalR, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-rc-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft DiskANN in Azure Cosmos DB Whitepaper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to publish a new whitepaper titled, Microsoft DiskANN in Azure Cosmos DB, where we examine the impressive capabilities of Microsoft DiskANN, a state-of-the-art indexing system designed for accurate and cost-efficient vector search at any scale. We start off with a review of key vector search and database concepts, then follow by describing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/microsoft-diskann-in-azure-cosmos-db-whitepaper 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft.Extensions.AI: Simplifying AI Integration for .NET Partners</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the launch of Microsoft.Extensions.AI for .NET! Our collaboration with the .NET team since the debut of Semantic Kernel has resulted in a powerful new feature that aligns with the best practices of both current and upcoming .NET releases. With the introduction of Microsoft.Extensions.AI, Independent Software Vendors (ISVs) and AI solution […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/microsoft-extensions-ai-simplifying-ai-integration-for-net-partners 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Private Preview: VS Code Extension of vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview We’re excited to introduce a new VS Code extension for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB ! This tool allows users to connect, query, and manage vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB directly within VS Code, streamlining your workflow. Limited Private Preview We’re currently offering a limited private preview of the VSCode extension for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-private-preview-vs-code-extension-of-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Microsoft.Extensions.AI Preview – Unified AI Building Blocks for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to introduce the Microsoft.Extensions.AI package available in preview today. This new package provides a unified abstraction layer that enables you to integrate AI services into your .NET applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-microsoft-extensions-ai-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series forecasting with Amazon SageMaker AutoML</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore a comprehensive approach to time series forecasting using the Amazon SageMaker AutoMLV2 Software Development Kit (SDK). SageMaker AutoMLV2 is part of the SageMaker Autopilot suite, which automates the end-to-end machine learning workflow from data preparation to model deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/time-series-forecasting-with-amazon-sagemaker-automl/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate user on-boarding for financial services with a digital assistant powered by Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a solution that harnesses the power of generative AI to streamline the user onboarding process for financial services through a digital assistant.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-user-on-boarding-for-financial-services-with-a-digital-assistant-powered-by-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework October 2024 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for October 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-october-2024-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Era at Docker: How We’re Investing in Innovation and Customer Relationships</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker&#39;s Chief Revenue Officer thanks customers for being part of our story, especially as we continue to evolve in a rapidly changing ecosystem.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-investing-innovation-customer-relationships/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing New Storage Sizes for vCore-Based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB: Unlock More Capacity and Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the preview of new storage sizes for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB, designed to provide more capacity and enhanced performance for your MongoDB workloads. Whether you’re managing large, complex datasets or high-throughput applications, these new storage tiers—8 TiB, 16 TiB, and 32 TiB per physical shard—offer the flexibility to scale […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-new-storage-sizes-for-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-unlock-more-capacity-and-performance 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: Run to ground</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Come to a resolution.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241008-00/?p=110351 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Testcontainers for Complex Integration Testing in Mattermost Plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 13:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Mattermost has embraced Testcontainers to overhaul its testing strategy, achieving greater automation, improved accuracy, and seamless plugin integration.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/leveraging-testcontainers-for-complex-integration-testing-in-mattermost-plugins/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Stars Join the JetBrains Developer Recognition Program 🌟</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 12:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub is the world’s leading AI-powered platform for developers who share their code, work together, and build amazing things. But out of the more than 100 million developers that call GitHub home, there are a few exceptional talents and technical experts who go above and beyond in helping others in the developer space – the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/08/github-stars-join-the-jetbrains-developer-recognition-program/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing Exceptions-as-flow-control with the result pattern: Working with the result pattern - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss why you might want to use the result pattern, demonstrate it with a simple example and show a naïve, ugly, solution
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/working-with-the-result-pattern-part-1-replacing-exceptions-as-control-flow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Repetitive Code With Metalama</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you write code in C#, you&#39;re probably also writing repetitive code against your will. Think of caching, security, precondition checking, exception handling, design patterns like Builder or Memento, deep cloning, INotifyPropertyChanged...In this article, I&#39;ll introduce Metalama, a new meta-programming framework my team and I
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/generating-repetitive-code-with-metalama/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering the Art of Public Speaking: Creating Captivating Technical Demos</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post emphasizes the importance of delivering effective technical presentations through engaging demos that reflect real-world scenarios. It suggests pre-recording demos to avoid failures caused by unreliable internet connections and stresses the significance of audience engagement over screen focus. Accessibility is highlighted through light mode and larger fonts for better visibility.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/08/mastering-the-art-of-public-speaking-creating-captivating-technical-demos/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting improved HTTP logging in ASP.NET Core 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:03:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A few years ago, I had a play with HTTP logging added in ASP.NET Core 6. ASP.NET Core 8 introduced a set of additional configuration options that I believe are essential to make this feature usable. I will recap the details from the previous post below, but for asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/revisiting-improved-http-logging-in-asp-net-core-8/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI Slack chat assistant using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Kendra</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 20:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we describe the development of a generative AI Slack application powered by Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Kendra. This is designed to be an internal-facing Slack chat assistant that helps answer questions related to the indexed content.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-generative-ai-slack-chat-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-kendra/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring your Azure Function with External ID as an identity provider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 15:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to configure Microsoft Entra External ID as an identity provider for Azure Functions. This blog post shows you how to integrate External ID seamlessly, allowing you to focus on building app features without worrying about infrastructure or authentication.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/azure-function-with-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate C&#43;&#43; Debugging with Enhanced Conditional Breakpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 15:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of waiting for your conditional breakpoints to hit in C++? Do you wish there was a way to speed up the debugging process and get to the root of the problem faster? If so, you’re in luck! We have some exciting news for you: Visual Studio 2022 has significantly improved the performance […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/accelerate-c-debugging-with-enhanced-conditional-breakpoints 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A popular but wrong way to convert a string to uppercase or lowercase</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Converting character by character isn&#39;t good enough any more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241007-00/?p=110345 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using an AI Assistant to Script Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this Docker Labs GenAI series installment, learn how to use an AI assistant to script a tool based on a specific definition.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/using-an-ai-assistant-to-script-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 EAP 3: OpenCV Image Viewer and the Ability to Attach the Debugger to an Unstarted Process</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The third CLion 2024.3 EAP build, 243.18137.40, is out. You can download it for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 EAP This build introduces an OpenCV image viewer for you to use while debugging. It also gives you the option […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/10/2024-3-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of the Kotlin Language and How You Can Contribute</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 10:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin’s evolution is significantly influenced by its active community. From early ideas to the final features, it’s shaped by feedback, discussions, and real-world use cases. We call this process KEEP – the Kotlin Evolution and Enhancement Process. To keep you informed about what’s coming next, we’ve created the new Kotlin Language Features and Proposals page. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/the-evolution-of-the-kotlin-language-and-how-emyou-em-can-contribute/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: How to !create a Plugin for JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 07:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode, where we discuss whether you always need to create a new plugin with Jakub Chrzanowski. Date: October 17, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract We all aim to deliver – be it through writing new code, fixing bugs, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Entra ID App-to-App security architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 07:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article looks at the different setups when using App-to-App security with Microsoft Entra ID (OAuth client credentials). Microsoft Entra App registrations are used to configure the OAuth clients and resources. For each tenant, an Enterprise application is created for the client App registration when the consent is granted. The claims in the access token […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/10/07/microsoft-entra-id-app-to-app-security-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing double clicks in Blazor components</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve built a number of online stores over the years and one thing remains true… Customers get pretty annoyed if you charge them twice for the same thing. So how can you avoid such calamity? Well you probably want to architect your backend to reduce the chances of an operation being called twice. For example you might use a session id and block an order from being created/placed if another one has already been created for that session id.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Spargine: Simplifying Real-World Data Generation for .NET Benchmarking and Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2024/06_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2024/06_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article explores Spargine, a set of open-source assemblies and NuGet packages designed to simplify real-world data generation for .NET benchmarking and testing. It covers the key features of Spargine, including methods for creating realistic person, address, and random data objects for unit tests and performance benchmarks.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/06/harnessing-spargine-simplifying-real-world-data-generation-for-net-benchmarking-and-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Destroying Momentum For Innovation – Dev Leader Weekly 64</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_10_2024/05_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_10_2024/05_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Destroying Momentum For Innovation – Dev Leader Weekly 64 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how focusing on roadblocks instead of solution seeking can grind engineering teams to a halt. The post Destroying Momentum For Innovation – Dev Leader Weekly 64 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/10/05/destroying-momentum-for-innovation-dev-leader-weekly-64/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing .NET 9: Key Performance Boosts and Pitfalls Compared to .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_10_2024/05_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_10_2024/05_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article discusses the performance enhancements and slowdowns in .NET 9 compared to .NET 8, highlighting specific areas of improvement through benchmark tests. Overall, .NET 9 is found to be approximately 1.11 times faster. The author encourages users to upgrade for better performance with no code changes required.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/05/unleashing-net-9-key-performance-boosts-and-pitfalls-compared-to-net-8/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing the Outbox Pattern</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_10_2024/05_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_10_2024/05_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how the Outbox pattern solves the dual-write problem in distributed systems, ensuring data consistency between your database and external components. This article provides practical strategies for implementing and scaling the Outbox pattern in .NET applications.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/implementing-the-outbox-pattern 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to your .NET applications with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction When interacting with a large language model (LLM), its knowledge comes from data used during its training, which is often mostly from public sources. As a result, the model’s knowledge may not fully reflect the most current information. This leads to three main issues: outdated information, no access to internal company data, and potential […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/add-retrieval-augmented-generation-rag-to-your-net-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create your fashion assistant application using Amazon Titan models and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 19:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we implement a fashion assistant agent using Amazon Bedrock Agents and the Amazon Titan family models. The fashion assistant provides a personalized, multimodal conversational experience.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-your-fashion-assistant-application-using-amazon-titan-models-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Azure Cosmos DB Integration with LangChain.js!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing Azure Cosmos DB Vector Store Integration with LangChain.js! We’re simplifying AI app development by integrating Azure Cosmos DB’s cost-effective and scalable vector search directly with LangChain.js! This powerful combination empowers JavaScript developers to efficiently manage fast and accurate data retrieval with Azure Cosmos DB’s scalability and efficient vector search capabilities. This offers a powerful […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-azure-cosmos-db-integration-with-langchain-js 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale Your Database Workloads with Multishard Clusters in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce significant enhancements to vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB with the release of multishard clusters preview, designed to take scalability and performance to the next level. This update brings several new capabilities that address the needs of demanding database workloads, making it easier than ever to manage large datasets and handle high-throughput […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/scale-your-database-workloads-with-multishard-clusters-in-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – October 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The October 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include Python test coverage support and a default Python problem matcher. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-october-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does the linker decide whether to call WinMain or wWinMain?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you don&#39;t tell it, it will try to figure it out.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241004-00/?p=110338 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete the Un-Completable: The State of AI Completion in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code completion has always been a standout feature in JetBrains IDEs, helping developers code faster, smarter, and with fewer mistakes. But what if it could do even more? What if it could predict not just the next element but entire lines of code – or even complete blocks? That’s exactly what we’ve been working on. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/10/complete-the-un-completable-the-state-of-ai-completion-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for SLNX Solution Files</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 12:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For nearly twenty years, the .NET community has enjoyed working with solution files (*.sln). Due to their tooling-centered format, manually changing these files has always been challenging. Merge conflicts in solution files—much like merging CSPROJ files—were commonplace and often resulted in corrupted files or lost changes. The structure of SLN files is overly verbose—an empty […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/10/04/support-for-slnx-solution-files/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – October 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 11:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, Java fans! Get ready for a treat – it’s time for our October 2024 Java Annotated Monthly! We’re buzzing with excitement about Java 23, and we’ve got a bunch of ace articles and videos to keep you updated about the newest features. We’re also exploring some tech stuff beyond Java, and IntelliJ IDEA is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/java-annotated-monthly-october-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Error Handling in Power Automate for Better Workflow Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores effective error handling strategies in Power Automate to enhance workflow reliability and maintainability through practical techniques and integrations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/power-automate-error-handling 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
