<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:00:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Instant GraphQL APIs with Hasura Data Connector for Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to partner with Hasura to launch a new Hasura native data connector that generates instant GraphQL APIs on Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL. Hasura DDN makes data access easy by enabling backend teams to effortlessly deliver a unified API on all your data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-instant-graphql-apis-with-hasuras-data-connector-for-azure-cosmos-db-nosql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of Office 365 connectors within Microsoft Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting August 15, 2024 we will be retiring the Office 365 connectors feature from Microsoft Teams and recommend Power Automate workflows as the solution to relay information into and out of Teams in a scalable, flexible, and secure way.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/retirement-of-office-365-connectors-within-microsoft-teams 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 8: Faster Time to Code, Language-Aware Sticky Lines, and Tags in The Version Control Widget</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 14:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 8 is now live! You can download the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 8 The Early Access Program for v2024.2 is nearing its end, but there’s still time to participate and preview the latest improvements for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-8/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Online Migration Capability for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB  in Azure Data Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce a significant enhancement to the Azure Cosmos DB Migration for MongoDB extension! Now, you can seamlessly migrate your MongoDB workloads to vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB with the added convenience of online migration capability. Let’s dive into the details.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-online-migration-capability-for-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-in-azure-data-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I produce a Windows Runtime asynchronous activity from C&#43;&#43;/CX?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Parallel Patterns Library has special support for C++/CX.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240703-00/?p=109953 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.37 Is Out! Introducing AI Code Completion for Java, Folding Imports by Default, Soft Wraps for Markdown and Asciidoc, and Other Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.37 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this latest version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at this update’s highlights. Download Fleet 1.37 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/07/fleet-1-37-is-out-introducing-ai-code-completion-java-folding-imports-by-default-soft-wraps-markdown-asciidoc-other-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Coding Workshop on Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Struggling to get started with Python? Join us on our Discord server for a free beginner-friendly online workshop, tailored to those with no or basic programming experience. In this live interactive session, you’ll see Python in action. We’ll cover essential concepts from our most popular course, Introduction to Python, and provide hands-on experience using integrated […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/03/online-coding-workshop-on-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Self-Hosted Is Out – Get 40% OFF This Static Code Analysis Team Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 09:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most developers use IDEs and code editors for local code quality analysis, but only 33% of developers use external static code analysis tools for every CI pipeline commit. Another 33% occasionally use automated analysis technology. As reported by our customers, the low adoption of static code analysis tools among developers poses a problem for companies, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/07/qodana-self-hosted-is-out-get-40-off-this-static-code-analysis-team-tool/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve productivity when processing scanned PDFs using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a generative AI-powered assistant that can answer questions, provide summaries, generate content, and extract insights directly from the content in digital as well as scanned PDF documents in your enterprise data sources without needing to extract the text first. Customers across industries such as finance, insurance, healthcare life sciences, and more need […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-productivity-when-processing-scanned-pdfs-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.21.12-1 and 1.22.5-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 23:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft builds of the Go security patches released today, are now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-21-12-1-and-1-22-5-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Amazon Bedrock in your .NET applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 20:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recent developments in generative Artificial Intelligence (generative AI) have made it easier and affordable to create applications and experiences that improve the way we live and work. Generative AI is helping businesses improve customer experiences through assistants and conversational analytics and boost employee productivity through automated generation of content, reports, and code. In this blog […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/getting-started-with-amazon-bedrock-in-net-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated PyTorch inference with torch.compile on AWS Graviton processors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 17:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Originally PyTorch used an eager mode where each PyTorch operation that forms the model is run independently as soon as it’s reached. PyTorch 2.0 introduced torch.compile to speed up PyTorch code over the default eager mode. In contrast to eager mode, the torch.compile pre-compiles the entire model into a single graph in a manner that’s optimal for […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerated-pytorch-inference-with-torch-compile-on-aws-graviton-processors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a CI/CD Pipeline for Android Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 17:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest article by Kumar Harsh, draft.dev. If you ship Android app releases frequently, you probably already understand the value of well-defined build, test, and deployment workflows. Without resilient, automated DevOps workflows in place, it can be difficult to maintain a high release velocity. Automating these through continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/07/cicd-for-android/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access control for vector stores using metadata filtering with Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 17:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In November 2023, we announced Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock as generally available. Knowledge bases allow Amazon Bedrock users to unlock the full potential of Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) by seamlessly integrating their company data into the language model’s generation process. This feature allows organizations to harness the power of large language models (LLMs) while […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/access-control-for-vector-stores-using-metadata-filtering-with-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accenture creates a custom memory-persistent conversational user experience using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Traditionally, finding relevant information from documents has been a time-consuming and often frustrating process. Manually sifting through pages upon pages of text, searching for specific details, and synthesizing the information into coherent summaries can be a daunting task. This inefficiency not only hinders productivity but also increases the risk of overlooking critical insights buried within […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accenture-creates-a-custom-memory-persistent-conversational-user-experience-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an end-to-end serverless digital assistant for semantic search with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the rise of generative artificial intelligence (AI), an increasing number of organizations use digital assistants to have their end-users ask domain-specific questions, using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) over their enterprise data sources. As organizations transition from proofs of concept to production workloads, they establish objectives to run and scale their workloads with minimal operational […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-an-end-to-end-serverless-digital-assistant-for-semantic-search-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbox App 2.4 Gets a Refreshed UI Theme, Right-Click Context Menu, and Other Updates.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Toolbox App 2.4 comes with a reworked UI theme, a new way to open the context menu for tools, and other updates. If you’re using Gitee, check out the JetBrains Toolbox browser extension update as well. New UI theme Toolbox App 2.4 got a facelift! The navigation remains the same, but we’ve reworked the interface […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/toolbox-app/2024/07/toolbox-app-2-4-gets-a-refreshed-ui-theme-right-click-context-menu-and-other-updates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dive into native Windows development with new WinUI workload and template improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At //Build 2024, the WinUI team announced a renewed focus on WinUI as one of the premier app development frameworks we recommend for native Windows app development. To make it as seamless and easy as possible to get into coding, we created a new Windows Dev Center page,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/dive-into-native-windows-development-with-new-winui-workload-and-template-improvements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now use role-based access control in Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer is a web-based tool that allows you to interact with your data, run queries, and visualize results in Azure Cosmos DB. It is available in the Azure Portal and as a standalone web app. RBAC allows you to use Microsoft Entra ID identities to control data access in Data Explorer,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-use-role-based-access-control-in-azure-cosmos-db-data-explorer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The history of Alt&#43;number sequences, and why Alt&#43;9731 sometimes gives you a heart and sometimes a snowman</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code pages and custom keyboard handling.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240702-00/?p=109951 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast and compliant routing in Azure Fluid Relay</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 13:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how about the optimal placement of the geographically distributed Azure Fluid Relay (AFR) servers and how we route the traffic to these servers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/fast-and-compliant-routing-in-azure-fluid-relay 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use the Tasks View in JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 13:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Task Parallel Library (TPL) is foundational to all .NET applications, as it allows frameworks to write and execute multithreaded and parallel code. Additionally, developers looking to get the most out of their resources may want to write custom code, taking advantage of the types found in System.Threading and System.Threading.Tasks. You must understand concurrency and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/02/how-to-use-the-tasks-view-in-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 EAP 4: Improvements for Remote Toolchain, a Fix for Settings Persistence in Nova, and Enhanced GDB Pretty Printers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 09:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.2 EAP 4 build (242.19533.43) is now out! It’s available from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 EAP Highlights: Your CLion teamJetBrainsThe Drive to Develop
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/07/2024-2-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the generated code: the spread element: Behind the scenes of collection expressions - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show what the compiler generates when you use collection expressions with the spread element and how it depends on the collections used
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/behind-the-scenes-of-collection-expressions-part-4-the-spread-element/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned after migrating Azure Functions to Isolated Functions on .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 08:25:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The In-process model of running Azure Functions is being retired in favor of the Isolated model in two years. A lot of components on elmah.io are running on Azure Functions. To ensure we are running on the most modern and supported platform (also in two years), we have spent asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/lessons-learned-after-migrating-azure-functions-to-isolated-functions-on-net-8/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 05:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to talk about a structural design pattern, the Bridge Pattern. We will discuss what problem this pattern solves and how to implement it in C#. If you want to read more about design patterns in C#, you can inspect our C# Design Patterns page. Let’s start. What is The Bridge Design […] The post Bridge Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davide&#39;s Code and Architecture Notes - Arc42 Documentation, for a comprehensive description of your project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How is your project structured? What are the driving forces? If you don’t know how to express this info, you should try the Arc42 template to create a strong foundation for your documentation.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/arc42-documentation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a self-service digital assistant using Amazon Lex and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations strive to implement efficient, scalable, cost-effective, and automated customer support solutions without compromising the customer experience. Generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered chatbots play a crucial role in delivering human-like interactions by providing responses from a knowledge base without the involvement of live agents. These chatbots can be efficiently utilized for handling generic inquiries, freeing up […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-self-service-digital-assistant-using-amazon-lex-and-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify idle endpoints in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker is a machine learning (ML) platform designed to simplify the process of building, training, deploying, and managing ML models at scale. With a comprehensive suite of tools and services, SageMaker offers developers and data scientists the resources they need to accelerate the development and deployment of ML solutions. In today’s fast-paced technological landscape, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/identify-idle-endpoints-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian language RAG with Cohere multilingual embeddings and Anthropic Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Media and entertainment companies serve multilingual audiences with a wide range of content catering to diverse audience segments. These enterprises have access to massive amounts of data collected over their many years of operations. Much of this data is unstructured text and images. Conventional approaches to analyzing unstructured data for generating new content rely on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/indian-language-rag-with-cohere-multilingual-embeddings-and-anthropic-claude-3-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2024.2 EAP 5: An Important Milestone and Other Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest installment in the Early Access Program for ReSharper 2024.2 has just been released! This preview build marks an important milestone – it is the first one to feature asynchronous typing, an important design change for ReSharper on its way to out-of-process operation. In addition to that, the update also brings several updates across […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/01/resharper-2024-2-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 EAP 5: Reader Mode, Monitoring for Game Dev, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2024.2 EAP 5 has just landed! This build brings a variety of new features and improvements to enhance your development experience. As always, your feedback is invaluable in helping us refine these updates, so we encourage you to try out the new build and share your thoughts. UX/UI Reader mode Reader mode is now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/01/rider-2024-2-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone! We’re back with an update on the state of the RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program. In preparation for the release, we’ve been working on improving AI Assistant, as well as providing support for Rails 8 features, Stimulus, and more.You can download the latest EAP build from our website, via the free Toolbox App, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/07/rubymine-2024-2-early-access-program-update/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Guided Projects in JetBrains Academy Plugin 2024.6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that Framework lessons have been renamed as Guided Projects. In this release, we’ve streamlined the process for educators to edit and synchronize changes within Guided Projects, addressing common issues faced when updating course content. To explore the latest improvements, install the JetBrains Academy plugin or update to the latest version from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/01/jetbrains-academy-plugin-2023-4-is-available-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2024.2 EAP Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we’ll explore the most significant features available in the latest EAP. You can try them by downloading and installing the EAP build side by side with a stable version of PhpStorm. Don’t forget to share your experience with us in the comments section below. Support for log files The PhpStorm 2024.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/07/phpstorm-2024-2-eap-highlights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If I register the same shell extension as both a context menu extension and a drag/drop extension, how do I know which one the system is using?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Who forced you to register the same shell extension for both?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240701-00/?p=109947 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Generative AI to Create Runnable Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the innovative realm of AI developer tools with Docker&#39;s GenAI Docker Labs series. Join us as we dive deep into the potential of AI. Discover how generative AI can assist with documentation, project-specific tasks, and more throughout the software lifecycle. Stay updated and get involved with Docker&#39;s latest projects and tools.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/using-generative-ai-to-create-runnable-markdown/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to output a SARIF file from a .NET project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SARIF (Static Analysis Results Interchange Format) is an OASIS Standard that defines an output file format. The SARIF standard is used to streamline how static analysis tools share their results. SARIF is a JSON-based format that is easy to parse. Lots of tools support it, including Visual studio Code or Visual Studio. GitHub also supports this file format to report static analysis results. You can upload…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/how-to-output-a-sarif-file-from-a-dotnet-project.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 7: Improved Code Completion in AI Assistant, String Variable Data Visualizers in the Debugger, And More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 10:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP build brings some exciting new features and improvements. AI Assistant’s code completion, both single- and multi-line, has been upgraded for more accurate suggestions and a streamlined user experience. The IDE now offers convenient debugging visualizers to help you better comprehend data stored in JSON, HTML, XML, and other data […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating hashes in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 08:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article looks at different ways to create hashes in .NET Core. Hashes are useful for one way encryption which can be used for password storage, JWT validation and some other security use cases. When storing hashes in a database, extra care must be taken and the recommended approach from Microsoft should be used when […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/07/01/creating-hashes-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let GitHub Copilot draft of your pull request description</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 07:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing good pull request descriptions is essential for effective code reviews and collaboration. But it’s time-consuming and tedious, especially when you have multiple commits or complex changes. That’s why we’re highlighting a feature that will make your life better with the help of GitHub Copilot: generated pull request descriptions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/let-github-copilot-draft-of-your-pull-request-description 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Functions vs Lambda Expressions in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 05:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll discuss the differences between local functions and lambda expressions in C#. Let’s start. Lambda Expressions Lambda expressions are anonymous functions. They are short blocks of code that accept parameters and return a value. We can assign the lambda expression to a variable or pass it as a parameter. We define lambda […] The post Local Functions vs Lambda Expressions in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the Power of Copilot: Enhancing Visual Studio with New Slash Commands</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2024/30_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2024/30_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 2024 at Microsoft Build, new Copilot features were introduced in Visual Studio, including helpful slash commands for tasks like adding comments, explaining code, proposing fixes, generating code, receiving assistance, optimizing code, and writing unit tests. Despite its benefits, caution is advised when accepting Copilot&#39;s suggestions. Stay tuned for updates as more commands are added.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/30/unleashing-the-power-of-copilot-enhancing-visual-studio-with-new-slash-commands/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Reflect: My Mid-Year Retrospective – Dev Leader Weekly 50</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2024/29_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2024/29_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How To Reflect: My Mid-Year Retrospective – Dev Leader Weekly 50 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss my mid-year retrospective and how retrospectives can help YOU! The post How To Reflect: My Mid-Year Retrospective – Dev Leader Weekly 50 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/06/29/how-to-reflect-my-mid-year-retrospective-dev-leader-weekly-50/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible PDF Reporting in .NET Using Razor Views</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2024/29_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2024/29_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we&#39;ll explore the power of using Razor views for flexible PDF reporting in .NET. We&#39;ll see how to create report templates with Razor views, convert them to HTML, and then transform that HTML into beautifully formatted PDF documents.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/flexible-pdf-reporting-in-net-using-razor-views 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Graph PowerShell and CLI are now verified</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 16:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Graph PowerShell and CLI now have Microsoft set as the verified publisher.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-graph-powershell-and-cli-are-now-verified 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your Writing with Grazie, Now Included in the AI Pro Subscription</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This week, we announced the general availability of Grazie, our AI writing companion for people in tech. We’re also excited to share that Grazie is now part of the AI Pro subscription at no extra cost. Grazie streamlines your non-coding tasks by integrating generative AI into your JetBrains IDEs, browsers, and other tools. Grazie’s main […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/06/enhance-your-writing-with-grazie-now-included-in-the-ai-pro-subscription/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 mid-year link clearance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Emptying out the junk drawer.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240628-01/?p=109945 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a remove_all_pointers type trait, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Factoring out the type resolution to after the dangerous part.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240628-00/?p=109942 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – June Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stay updated with the latest news in the JetBrains Academy Newsletter. Discover the newest version of the JetBrains Academy plugin, celebrate our students’ international achievements, and learn how to become a JetBrains ambassador. All this and more await you in this month’s newsletter
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/06/28/jetbrains-academy-june-digest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReadMeAI: An AI-powered README Generator for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReadMeAI tool allows users to upload a code file and describe their project. The tool generates documentation in Markdown code for immediate preview and editing.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/readmeai-an-ai-powered-readme-generator-for-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code的更新 – 2024年6月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎阅读Visual Studio Code for Java的六月更新！在这篇博客中，我们将分享项目设置项目的重要更新以及一系列Spring的功能改进，让我们开始吧！ 项目设置页面功能增强 编译器配置 在项目设置页面添加了一个新的编译器配置标签页。这使您可以方便地设置项目的Java编译器相关选项。目前的选项包括源代码和目标兼容性、用于交叉编译的–release选项以及类文件生成的自定义。请参见下方截图中的编译器部分。 Maven相关选项 除了编译器部分，我们还添加了Maven标签页，使用户可以轻松指向的Maven配置文件。用户只需点击“Maven”并输入Maven配置文件的名称。 Formatter配置 最后，许多用户需要使用格式化器(Formatter)来格式化代码。我们在项目部分添加了使用格式化器的跳转方式。点击“Formatter”后，Visual Studio Code Java将引导用户进入格式化器视图。如果用户当前没有格式化器的文件，Visual Studio Code Java将引导用户直接创建一个格式化器。请参见下方的演示。 更方便地访问项目设置页面 自从我们引入更新后的项目设置页面以来，我们收到了用户的积极反馈。因此，我们使项目设置页面更加易于访问，现在您可以通过Java状态菜单直接从状态栏进入该页面。请参见下方截图。 要使用上述所有功能，用户可以使用上面提到的状态栏，或直接使用Command Palette并输入&amp;gt;Java: Open Project Settings。 测试覆盖率 测试覆盖率是我们在4月份推出的新功能，该功能可以使Java开发人员可以在Visual Studio Code中轻松查看代码的测试覆盖率。最近，我们推出了一个新的视频，讲述了如何在我们的插件中使用该功能。用户可以直接点击以下链接查看该视频： Build Server for Gradle在Google Summer Projects中的项目 我们很高兴地分享，Google Summer Projects现已宣布，您可以在Gradle Build Tool的简讯中找到详细信息。今年，Visual Studio Code Java团队正在指导两个Gradle Build Server相关的项目。 Gradle构建服务器 –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-visual-studio-code-2024-06 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code Update – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 09:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the June update for Visual Studio Code for Java! In this blog we are going to share several user experience updates, as well as important Spring features improvements, so let’s get started! Project Settings Page Enhancements New Compiler Section A new compiler section was added to the project settings page.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-visual-studio-code-update-june-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Plugins to Enhance Your IntelliJ IDEA Experience in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 07:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Even though IntelliJ IDEA is powerful and self-sufficient, we love to customize it a bit with plugins. Why? Because they’re fun! In this blog post, we’ll share a list of cool plugins that will help you liven things up in your IDE. Let’s go! JetBrains AI Assistant AI has touched every industry over the past […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/10-plugins-to-enhance-your-intellij-idea-experience-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings around developing with Microsoft Graph Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learnings of Microsoft Graph Toolkit from our recent project, including data leaking and privacy concerns that can help developers get a jumpstart with Microsoft Graph Toolkit.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/developing-with-microsoft-graph-toolkit-learnings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditionally Add Middleware in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore different techniques on how to conditionally add middleware in ASP.NET Core applications. Let’s start! Conditional Middleware: Why and When? Conditional middleware in ASP.NET Core is crucial for dynamically adapting our application behavior based on the runtime environment or specific request details. Let’s take a look at the key scenarios where […] The post Conditionally Add Middleware in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of productivity agents with NinjaTech AI and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NinjaTech AI’s mission is to make everyone more productive by taking care of time-consuming complex tasks with fast and affordable artificial intelligence (AI) agents. We recently launched MyNinja.ai, one of the world’s first multi-agent personal AI assistants, to drive towards our mission. MyNinja.ai is built from the ground up using specialized agents that are capable of completing tasks on your behalf, including scheduling meetings, conducting deep research from the web, generating code, and helping with writing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications on Amazon Bedrock — the secure, compliant, and responsible foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has revolutionized industries by creating content, from text and images to audio and code. Although it can unlock numerous possibilities, integrating generative AI into applications demands meticulous planning. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that provides access to large language models (LLMs) and other foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies through a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-on-amazon-bedrock-the-secure-compliant-and-responsible-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Documentation for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 17:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to announce the updated documentation on the Semantic Kernel learn site here: Introduction to Semantic Kernel | Microsoft Learn. We’ve updated the docs to include in depth samples, updated pages focused on concepts and much more for your learning!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/updated-documentation-for-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.03.3 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 17:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2024.03.3 bug fix for TeamCity On-Premises is now available for download! This release includes a few performance and security fixes. Among others, we addressed the following issues: For the full list of the issues fixed in this version, please refer to our release notes. As with other minor updates, TeamCity 2024.03.3 shares the same […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/06/teamcity-2024-03-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational chatbot using different LLMs within single interface – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the advent of generative artificial intelligence (AI), foundation models (FMs) can generate content such as answering questions, summarizing text, and providing highlights from the sourced document. However, for model selection, there is a wide choice from model providers, like Amazon, Anthropic, AI21 Labs, Cohere, and Meta, coupled with discrete real-world data formats in PDF, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-conversational-chatbot-using-different-llms-within-single-interface-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a remove_all_pointers type trait, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Delaying the expansion to avoid infinite recursion.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240627-00/?p=109940 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBRX: Databricks Open Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DBRX is Databricks’ newest Large Language Model (LLM) is open source and designed to bring advanced AI capabilities to businesses across multiple industries. This model stands out for its powerful architecture, efficiency, and user-friendly design, making sophisticated AI accessible and adaptable for diverse applications. By combining cutting-edge technology with practical usability, DBRX aims to transform […] The article DBRX: Databricks Open Large Language Model was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.19 with simulating LLM APIs and new Azure API Center integrations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to share the launch of Dev Proxy v0.19 to help you to build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-19-with-simulating-llm-apis-and-new-azure-api-center-integrations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (June 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.06.15 release, 2024-06-10 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout June. This month’s release includes some error message improvements and bug fixes. Some stats for this period: There are now 2,441 total ports available in the vcpkg public registry.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-june-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tentative Roadmap for Wolverine 3.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By the way, JasperFx Software offers support contracts or tailored consulting engagements to help your shop maximize your success with Wolverine. It’s an unfortunate fact of long running software tooling projects like Wolverine that decisions made years earlier won’t hold up perfectly as the usage requirements, underlying platform, and other tools it’s integrated with change … Continue reading Tentative Roadmap for Wolverine 3.0 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/06/26/tentative-roadmap-for-wolverine-3-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluid Framework 2 is now production ready</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 19:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Fluid Framework 2 is now generally available and ready for production applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/fluid-framework-2-is-now-production-ready 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving OpenJDK Scalar Replacement – Part 2/3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous part of this blog series, we explored the foundational concepts and purpose of scalar replacement (SR) in OpenJDK, laying the groundwork for understanding how this optimization can boost the performance of Java applications. Now, in the second installment of the series,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/improving-openjdk-scalar-replacement-part-2-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate derivative confirms processing using AWS AI services for the capital markets industry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can automate and intelligently process derivative confirms at scale using AWS AI services. The solution combines Amazon Textract, a fully managed ML service to effortlessly extract text, handwriting, and data from scanned documents, and AWS Serverless technologies, a suite of fully managed event-driven services for running code, managing data, and integrating applications, all without managing servers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-derivative-confirms-processing-using-aws-ai-services-for-the-capital-markets-industry/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered assistants for investment research with multi-modal data: An application of Agents for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a follow-up to Generative AI and multi-modal agents in AWS: The key to unlocking new value in financial markets. This blog is part of the series, Generative AI and AI/ML in Capital Markets and Financial Services. Financial analysts and research analysts in capital markets distill business insights from financial and non-financial data, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-powered-assistants-for-investment-research-with-multi-modal-data-an-application-of-agents-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us for .NET Aspire Developers Day – Elevate Your Cloud Native Skills!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on July 23, 2024, for .NET Aspire Developers Day, a livestream event to elevate your .NET skills with keynotes, deep dives, and interactive sessions. Connect with experts and the community.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/join-us-for-dotnet-aspire-developers-day 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a built-in way in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT to get the string name for a Windows Runtime enum?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            No, and maybe you don&#39;t want to.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240626-00/?p=109936 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Where Conditions Work in Entity Framework Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core is a popular data access library in the .NET space that makes it easier to write, execute, and process SQL statements and the resulting data. If you’re new to the .NET space, this blog post will help you understand how to create filtered result sets using the Where operator and how to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/26/how-where-conditions-work-in-entity-framework-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Docker USER Instruction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover best practices and common pitfalls associated with the Docker USER instruction. Also get a hands-on demo to learn the importance of these practices.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/understanding-the-docker-user-instruction/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Grazie – The AI Writing Companion for People in Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Grazie, a new AI writing companion for people working in tech, is now generally available. With Grazie, you can streamline your non-coding tasks by integrating generative AI into your JetBrains IDEs, browsers, and other tools. Grazie helps transform your thoughts into clear, well-articulated text through features like instant proofreading, inline text completion, summarization, translation, rephrasing, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2024/06/introducing-grazie-the-ai-writing-companion-for-people-in-tech/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #3: YAML Configuration Settings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With this TeamCity Pipelines release, we’re introducing the option to store and load pipeline definitions in YAML format from your repositories. The search panel for the YAML editor now looks better than ever. Bugs were squashed, improvements made, and our users are happier than ever. Read on to learn what’s new! Storing and loading configuration […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/06/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is The HashiCorp Infrastructure Cloud?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The cloud is the standard for hosting applications and workloads. However, only a small percentage of organizations realize the full benefits such as cost reduction, enhanced resilience, and new revenue streams. Often, this is due to the complex nature of cloud environments. The HashiCorp Infrastructure Cloud aims to address these challenges, providing a unified platform […] The article What is The HashiCorp Infrastructure Cloud? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Innovation: Explore Exclusive Technology Graphics and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am a technology and software engineering enthusiast with decades of experience creating custom images, videos, and music. My unique designs add a touch of innovation and creativity to projects, crafted with attention to detail for high-quality visuals. Explore and purchase my work at McCarter Photography - Technology to enhance your projects.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/26/unlocking-innovation-explore-exclusive-technology-graphics-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jakarta EE on Azure – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the June 2024 update for Jakarta EE on Azure. The June update covers the following topics: The newly published High Availability and Disaster Recovery tutorials, which demonstrate how to implement HA/DR for different Jakarta EE applications on Azure using a simple and effective method.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/jakarta-ee-on-azure-june-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
