<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 12:15:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Powering Local AI Together: Docker Model Runner on Hugging Face</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 12:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Docker, we always believe in the power of community and collaboration. It reminds me of what Robert Axelrod said in The Evolution of Cooperation: “The key to doing well lies not in overcoming others, but in eliciting their cooperation.” And what better place for Docker Model Runner to foster this cooperation than at Hugging...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-on-hugging-face/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Better Agents: What’s New in Koog 0.3.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 07:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released Koog 0.3.0, which comes with many updates that make building, running, and managing intelligent agents easier. This version focuses on durability, speed, observability, and smoother integration with real-world systems. If you’ve been exploring how to develop your own intelligent agent that can handle complex workflows, the new and updated Koog could be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/07/building-better-agents-what-s-new-in-koog-0-3-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Day the Software Community Died: Let’s Stop Coding in Isolation and Start Creating Community—And Software—People Truly Love</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author reflects on the vital role of the software community in shaping their career as an engineer, emphasizing its decline post-COVID-19. They highlight the diminishing local user groups and conferences, attributing this to a lack of appreciation from younger developers and reduced corporate support, particularly from Microsoft. A call to action urges developers to engage, companies to invest, and veterans to mentor, reinforcing the importance of community in fostering quality software.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases now supports Amazon OpenSearch Service Managed Cluster as vector store</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 22:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases has extended its vector store options by enabling support for Amazon OpenSearch Service managed clusters, further strengthening its capabilities as a fully managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) solution. This enhancement builds on the core functionality of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases , which is designed to seamlessly connect foundation models (FMs) with internal data sources. This post provides a comprehensive, step-by-step guide on integrating an Amazon Bedrock knowledge base with an OpenSearch Service managed cluster as its vector store.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor agents built on Amazon Bedrock with Datadog LLM Observability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 22:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a new integration between Datadog LLM Observability and Amazon Bedrock Agents that helps monitor agentic applications built on Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we&#39;ll explore how Datadog&#39;s LLM Observability provides the visibility and control needed to successfully monitor, operate, and debug production-grade agentic applications built on Amazon Bedrock Agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/monitor-agents-built-on-amazon-bedrock-with-datadog-llm-observability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PayU built a secure enterprise AI assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 21:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PayU offers a full-stack digital financial services system that serves the financial needs of merchants, banks, and consumers through technology. In this post, we explain how we equipped the PayU team with an enterprise AI solution and democratized AI access using Amazon Bedrock, without compromising on data residency requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-payu-built-a-secure-enterprise-ai-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your First MCP Server with .NET and Publishing to NuGet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want to extend AI assistants with custom capabilities? In this post, we&#39;ll show you how to build a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server using .NET 10 and publish it to NuGet — making your AI tools discoverable and reusable by the entire .NET community. We&#39;ll also show you some new features we&#39;ve added to .NET 10 and NuGet to support this, and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mcp-server-dotnet-nuget-quickstart 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to Warning Suppressions in Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Code Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 18:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft C++ Code Analysis is a powerful static analysis tool integrated into Visual Studio that helps you identify and fix potential issues in your C++ code. Large projects require effective management of analysis warnings to maintain code quality and you sometimes need to suppress warnings, but must do so in a clear and auditable way.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/updates-to-warning-suppressions-in-microsoft-c-code-analysis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Platform API and SDKs: From UX-First to API-First</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Historically, Power Platform has empowered administrators through the Power Platform Admin Center (PPAC). This UX-first experience offered a seamless, intuitive interface for managing environments, automating everyday tasks, and discovering new capabilities within the platform. Today, we’re taking a bold step forward. We’re tran
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/power-platform-api-and-sdks-from-ux-first-to-api-first 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension concerns when replacing the OS disk</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One confusing area regarding extensions on Azure VMs is - what happens when the OS disk is swapped out? Well, in that case the extensions will run again. Is this the desired behavior? Well, we don&#39;t know. There are many types of extensions. Some handle monitoring and security, so those you&#39;ll probably want to keep. Some install applications
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/extension-concerns-when-replacing-the-os-disk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 6 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the sixth preview release of .NET 10 with enhancements across the .NET Runtime, SDK, libraries, C#, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more. Check out the full release notes linked below and get started today. [cta-button align=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Download .NET 10 Preview 6&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;https://get.d
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-6 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perhaps not a recommended usage for an emergency power outlet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is not uncommon for Microsoft employees who are aficionados of arcade video games to set up a unit in free play mode in a public space for anyone to play. For example, the Habitrail in the Building 16-18 complex
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250715-00/?p=111381 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge generative AI workflows with NVIDIA DGX Cloud on AWS and Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 13:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Andrew Liu, Chelsea Isaac, Zoey Zhang, and Charlie Huang from NVIDIA. DGX Cloud on Amazon Web Services (AWS) represents a significant leap forward in democratizing access to high-performance AI infrastructure. By combining NVIDIA GPU expertise with AWS scalable cloud services, organizations can accelerate their time-to-train, reduce operational complexity, and unlock […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/supercharge-generative-ai-workflows-with-nvidia-dgx-cloud-on-aws-and-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate generative AI inference with NVIDIA Dynamo and Amazon EKS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 13:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces NVIDIA Dynamo and explains how to set it up on Amazon EKS for automated scaling and streamlined Kubernetes operations. We provide a hands-on walkthrough, which uses the NVIDIA Dynamo blueprint on the AI on EKS GitHub repo by AWS Labs to provision the infrastructure, configure monitoring, and install the NVIDIA Dynamo operator.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-generative-ai-inference-with-nvidia-dynamo-and-amazon-eks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS doubles investment in AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, marking two years of customer success</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 12:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, AWS announces a $100 million additional investment in its AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, marking two years of successful customer collaborations across industries from financial services to healthcare. The investment comes as AI evolves toward more autonomous, agentic systems, with the center already helping thousands of customers drive millions in productivity gains and transform customer experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-doubles-investment-in-aws-generative-ai-innovation-center-marking-two-years-of-customer-success/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Debugger: Working With Dynamic Database Connections Just Got Simpler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 12:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While building Spring Boot applications, you can leverage Testcontainers to spin up any required services, such as a database or messaging broker, as Docker containers at application startup. This enables a ready-to-code setup, minimizing environment friction so you can focus on delivering high-quality, maintainable code. For database-driven development, IntelliJ IDEA provides enterprise-grade, professional-level tooling out […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/spring-debugger-working-with-dynamic-database-connections-just-got-simpler/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 10:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? Because of C#’s ability to use verbatim strings, you can use reserved keywords as variable names by prefixing them with the @ symbol. For example, var @class = new Class(); is a perfectly valid statement to make an instance of the Class class. But keep in mind – just because you could […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/15/dotinsights-july-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 14 extension members; AKA extension everything: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at the C#14 extension members feature. I show how to convert extension methods to the new syntax and how to add new types of extension.
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-3-csharp-14-extensions-members/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Claude Code Subagents for Complex Development Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 08:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Claude Code subagents create specialized AI teams for complex development. Complete guide with prompts, examples, and best practices.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/how-to-use-claude-code-subagents-tutorial/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesser-known C# features that can simplify your code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 08:27:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# is a robust OOP language that provides the foundation for building almost every application with .NET. As a C# developer, you are likely familiar with its fundamentals. However, like any legacy technology, it holds more depth to explore and enhance your code&#39;s maintainability and beauty. In this
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/lesser-known-c-features-that-can-simplify-your-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual freedom by design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT is designed to be useful, trustworthy, and adaptable—so you can make it your own.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/intellectual-freedom-by-design 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your EWS migration with AI and GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you running apps on Exchange Web Services (EWS)? With EWS support ending in October 2026, this is the perfect time to modernize. We’re excited to announce a new hands-on tutorial that helps you accelerate migrations from EWS to Microsoft Graph, using AI tools you already have access to. This tutorial
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/supercharge-your-ews-migration-with-ai-and-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI-driven policy creation for vehicle data collection and automation using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sonatus partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to develop a natural language interface to generate data collection and automation policies using generative AI. This innovation aims to reduce the policy generation process from days to minutes while making it accessible to both engineers and non-experts alike. In this post, we explore how we built this system using Sonatus’s Collector AI and Amazon Bedrock. We discuss the background, challenges, and high-level solution architecture.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rapid7 automates vulnerability risk scores with ML pipelines using Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Rapid7 implemented end-to-end automation for the training, validation, and deployment of ML models that predict CVSS vectors. Rapid7 customers have the information they need to accurately understand their risk and prioritize remediation measures.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-rapid7-automates-vulnerability-risk-scores-with-ml-pipelines-using-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build secure RAG applications with AWS serverless data lakes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a secure RAG application using serverless data lake architecture, an important data strategy to support generative AI development. We use Amazon Web Services (AWS) services including Amazon S3, Amazon DynamoDB, AWS Lambda, and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases to create a comprehensive solution supporting unstructured data assets which can be extended to structured data. The post covers how to implement fine-grained access controls for your enterprise data and design metadata-driven retrieval systems that respect security boundaries.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Testing: Using Docker Model Runner with Microcks for Dynamic Mock APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The non-deterministic nature of LLMs makes them ideal for generating dynamic, rich test data, perfect for validating app behavior and ensuring consistent, high-quality user experiences. Today, we’ll walk you through how to use Docker’s Model Runner with Microcks to generate dynamic mock APIs for testing your applications. Microcks is a powerful CNCF tool that allows...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-powered-mock-apis-for-testing-with-docker-and-microcks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Cosmos DB in Microsoft Fabric (Preview) with New Capabilities!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to unveil the open Public Preview of Cosmos DB in Microsoft Fabric, now available to all users! Since our initial announcement at Microsoft Build 2025, we’ve introduced an array of powerful new features to enhance your data workflows.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-cosmos-db-in-microsoft-fabric-preview-with-new-capabilities 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Code Quality at Scale with AI-Powered Code Reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 15:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft, we are constantly looking for ways to improve developer productivity and code quality. One of our most impactful innovations in this space is AI-powered code review assistant — an AI tool that augments pull request (PR) reviews. This AI Assistant started as an internal experiment and now has scaled to suppor
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/enhancing-code-quality-at-scale-with-ai-powered-code-reviews 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025 — Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 14:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Streaming worldwide 8 – 9 October 2025 Have you cracked a performance bottleneck?Built something clever with AI agents?Discovered a design pattern the .NET world should know? Share it with thousands of developers at JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025 – a free, community-driven event broadcast live around the globe. Submit your talk on Sessionize → TL;DR […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/14/jetbrains-net-days-online-2025-call-for-speakers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is a &lt;CODE&gt;std::&lt;WBR&gt;chrono::&lt;WBR&gt;high_&lt;WBR&gt;resolution_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt;, but no &lt;CODE&gt;low_&lt;WBR&gt;resolution_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The C++ standard provides a std::chrono::high_resolution_clock which provides the implementation&#39;s clock with the smallest tick period. This gives you the best resolution available to the implementation. But what if you don&#39;t need the best resolution available to the implementation? For examp
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250714-00/?p=111375 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Full Cross-Platform Support for the mssql-python Driver</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 11:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/announcing-full-cross-platform-support-for-the-mssql-python-driver 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Release of the MPS 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Ready</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 05:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today marks another milestone on our journey to MPS 2025.2. You can now download the second build of the MPS 2025.2 EAP and try it out! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.2 EAP It comes with bug fixes and improvements, such as: Java source and target compatibility was raised to Java 21. VCS libraries are now part of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/07/the-second-release-mps-2025-2-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Add Thread-Safety with ConcurrentHashSet from Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_07_2025/13_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_07_2025/13_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The HashSet in .NET is efficient for storing unique elements but is not thread-safe. To overcome this issue, ConcurrentHashSet was created, offering thread-safe operations while maintaining HashSet behavior. It features various constructors, supports custom comparers, and includes methods for adding, removing, and checking elements. Available via NuGet.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/13/boost-your-net-projects-add-thread-safety-with-concurrenthashset-from-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Mentor Mid-Level Engineers - Dev Leader Weekly 102</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2025/12_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2025/12_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to mentor mid-level engineers -- even if they are doing awesome already!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/12/how-to-mentor-midlevel-engineers-dev-leader-weekly-102 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-07-11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2025/12_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 06:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2025/12_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/12/weekly-recap-20250711 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Error Handling in ASP.NET Core: From Middleware to Modern Handlers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2025/12_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2025/12_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn How to handle errors globally in ASP.NET Core using middleware, IProblemDetailsService, and the new IExceptionHandler in .NET 8. This week&#39;s issue walks you through pragmatic approaches to error handling, with real-world tips for validation, chaining, and observability.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/global-error-handling-in-aspnetcore-from-middleware-to-modern-handlers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack Futures for the rest of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 22:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s the halfway point of 2025 some how, and we’ve now gotten past the big Marten 8.0 and Wolverine 4.0 releases. Right before I go on vacation next week, I thought it would be a good time to jot down some thoughts about where the Critter Stack might go for the rest of 2025 and … Continue reading Critter Stack Futures for the rest of 2025 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2507.11 - misc bug fixes &#43; improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 19:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2507.11, which can be downloaded here. This release includes everything in the previous 2505.30 release, plus the following bug fixes: GPU Captures (capture time
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2507-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Event-Driven Go applications with Azure Cosmos DB and Azure Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 17:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Go programming language is a great fit for building serverless applications. Go applications can be easily compiled to a single, statically linked binary, making deployment simple and reducing external dependencies. They start up quickly, which is ideal for serverless
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/building-event-driven-go-applications-with-azure-cosmos-db-and-azure-functions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced fine-tuning methods on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 17:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When fine-tuning ML models on AWS, you can choose the right tool for your specific needs. AWS provides a comprehensive suite of tools for data scientists, ML engineers, and business users to achieve their ML goals. AWS has built solutions to support various levels of ML sophistication, from simple SageMaker training jobs for FM fine-tuning to the power of SageMaker HyperPod for cutting-edge research. We invite you to explore these options, starting with what suits your current needs, and evolve your approach as those needs change.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline machine learning workflows with SkyPilot on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 17:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Zhanghao Wu, co-creator of SkyPilot. The rapid advancement of generative AI and foundation models (FMs) has significantly increased computational resource requirements for machine learning (ML) workloads. Modern ML pipelines require efficient systems for distributing workloads across accelerated compute resources, while making sure developer productivity remains high. Organizations need infrastructure solutions […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-machine-learning-workflows-with-skypilot-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent document processing at scale with generative AI and Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 16:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents an end-to-end IDP application powered by Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and other AWS services. It provides a reusable AWS infrastructure as code (IaC) that deploys an IDP pipeline and provides an intuitive UI for transforming documents into structured tables at scale. The application only requires the user to provide the input documents (such as contracts or emails) and a list of attributes to be extracted. It then performs IDP with generative AI.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational data assistant, Part 2 – Embedding generative business intelligence with Amazon Q in QuickSight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 16:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into how we integrated Amazon Q in QuickSight to transform natural language requests like “Show me how many items were returned in the US over the past 6 months” into meaningful data visualizations. We demonstrate how combining Amazon Bedrock Agents with Amazon Q in QuickSight creates a comprehensive data assistant that delivers both SQL code and visual insights through a single, intuitive conversational interface—democratizing data access across the enterprise.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational data assistant, Part 1: Text-to-SQL with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 16:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus on building a Text-to-SQL solution with Amazon Bedrock, a managed service for building generative AI applications. Specifically, we demonstrate the capabilities of Amazon Bedrock Agents. Part 2 explains how we extended the solution to provide business insights using Amazon Q in QuickSight, a business intelligence assistant that answers questions with auto-generated visualizations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-conversational-data-assistant-part-1-text-to-sql-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement user-level access control for multi-tenant ML platforms on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 16:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss permission management strategies, focusing on attribute-based access control (ABAC) patterns that enable granular user access control while minimizing the proliferation of AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) roles. We also share proven best practices that help organizations maintain security and compliance without sacrificing operational efficiency in their ML workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-user-level-access-control-for-multi-tenant-ml-platforms-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-running execution flows now supported in Amazon Bedrock Flows in public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 16:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We announce the public preview of long-running execution (asynchronous) flow support within Amazon Bedrock Flows. With Amazon Bedrock Flows, you can link foundation models (FMs), Amazon Bedrock Prompt Management, Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Bedrock Guardrails, and other AWS services together to build and scale predefined generative AI workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/long-running-execution-flows-now-supported-in-amazon-bedrock-flows-in-public-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraud detection empowered by federated learning with the Flower framework on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 16:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how SageMaker and federated learning help financial institutions build scalable, privacy-first fraud detection systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fraud-detection-empowered-by-federated-learning-with-the-flower-framework-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building intelligent AI voice agents with Pipecat and Amazon Bedrock – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of this series, you learned how you can use the combination of Amazon Bedrock and Pipecat, an open source framework for voice and multimodal conversational AI agents to build applications with human-like conversational AI. You learned about common use cases of voice agents and the cascaded models approach, where you orchestrate several components to build your voice AI agent. In this post (Part 2), you explore how to use speech-to-speech foundation model, Amazon Nova Sonic, and the benefits of using a unified model.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uphold ethical standards in fashion using multimodal toxicity detection with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the fashion industry, teams are frequently innovating quickly, often utilizing AI. Sharing content, whether it be through videos, designs, or otherwise, can lead to content moderation challenges. There remains a risk (through intentional or unintentional actions) of inappropriate, offensive, or toxic content being produced and shared. In this post, we cover the use of the multimodal toxicity detection feature of Amazon Bedrock Guardrails to guard against toxic content. Whether you’re an enterprise giant in the fashion industry or an up-and-coming brand, you can use this solution to screen potentially harmful content before it impacts your brand’s reputation and ethical standards.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code - July 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 14:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the July 2025 release of the Python, Pylance and Jupyter ext
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-july-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting and reporting all unhandled C&#43;&#43; exceptions as well as all unhandled structured exceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, attempted to intercept the ways that a C++ program could exit due to an unhandled exception by installing a custom unhandled str
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250711-00/?p=111368 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a GenAI App With Java Using Spring AI and Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 11:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When thinking about starting a Generative AI (GenAI) project, you might assume that Python is required to get started in this new space. However, if you’re already a Java developer, there’s no need to learn a new language. The Java ecosystem offers robust tools and libraries that make building GenAI applications both accessible and productive....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-genai-app-with-java-spring-ai-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EU Code of Practice and future of AI in Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI joins the EU Code of Practice, advancing responsible AI while partnering with European governments to drive innovation, infrastructure, and economic growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/eu-code-of-practice 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Rocks ØREDEV DEVELOPERS CONFERENCE 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dotNetDave will speak at the Øredev Developers Conference in Malmö, Denmark, from November 5-7, 2025. His session focuses on optimizing .NET code performance, sharing techniques to improve execution speed by up to 98%. Attendees will learn about effective memory management, enhancing application efficiency while gaining practical insights from his book series.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/11/dotnetdave-rocks-oredev-developers-conference-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Systems Mistakes Nobody Warns You About: Consistency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most common and very overlooked issues when writing a distributed system is consistency. You have one thing happening in one part of your system that triggers something else to happen in another part of the system, except it doesn’t happen. And that can be a nightmare to deal with. This problem is… Read More »Distributed Systems Mistakes Nobody Warns You About: Consistency The post Distributed Systems Mistakes Nobody Warns You About: Consistency appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New capabilities in Amazon SageMaker AI continue to transform how organizations develop AI models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 19:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share some of the new innovations in SageMaker AI that can accelerate how you build and train AI models. These innovations include new observability capabilities in SageMaker HyperPod, the ability to deploy JumpStart models on HyperPod, remote connections to SageMaker AI from local development environments, and fully managed MLflow 3.0.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-capabilities-in-amazon-sagemaker-ai-continue-to-transform-how-organizations-develop-ai-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate foundation model development with one-click observability in Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With a one-click installation of the Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS) add-on for SageMaker HyperPod observability, you can consolidate health and performance data from NVIDIA DCGM, instance-level Kubernetes node exporters, Elastic Fabric Adapter (EFA), integrated file systems, Kubernetes APIs, Kueue, and SageMaker HyperPod task operators. In this post, we walk you through installing and using the unified dashboards of the out-of-the-box observability feature in SageMaker HyperPod. We cover the one-click installation from the Amazon SageMaker AI console, navigating the dashboard and metrics it consolidates, and advanced topics such as setting up custom alerts.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating generative AI development with fully managed MLflow 3.0 on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon SageMaker now offers fully managed support for MLflow 3.0, streamlining AI experimentation and accelerating your generative AI journey from idea to production. This release transforms managed MLflow from experiment tracking to providing end-to-end observability, reducing time-to-market for generative AI development.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-generative-ai-development-with-fully-managed-mlflow-3-0-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker HyperPod launches model deployments to accelerate the generative AI model development lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we announce Amazon SageMaker HyperPod support for deploying foundation models from SageMaker JumpStart, as well as custom or fine-tuned models from Amazon S3 or Amazon FSx. This new capability allows customers to train, fine-tune, and deploy models on the same HyperPod compute resources, maximizing resource utilization across the entire model lifecycle.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-launches-model-deployments-to-accelerate-the-generative-ai-model-development-lifecycle/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your AI workflows by connecting to SageMaker Studio from Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI developers and machine learning (ML) engineers can now use the capabilities of Amazon SageMaker Studio directly from their local Visual Studio Code (VS Code). With this capability, you can use your customized local VS Code setup, including AI-assisted development tools, custom extensions, and debugging tools while accessing compute resources and your data in SageMaker Studio. In this post, we show you how to remotely connect your local VS Code to SageMaker Studio development environments to use your customized development environment while accessing Amazon SageMaker AI compute resources.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2025 Docker State of Application Development Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Executive summary The 2025 Docker State of Application Development Report offers an ultra high-resolution view of today’s fast-evolving dev landscape. Drawing insights from over 4,500 developers, engineers, and tech leaders — three times more users than last year — the survey explores tools, workflows, pain points, and industry trends. In this our third report, key...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/2025-docker-state-of-app-dev/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize AI responses from GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot along with its various models are capable of some amazing things. When in Agent mode the AI can create parts of or even entire applications from your written (or spoken!) instructions. You can just feel the vibes (coding), can&#39;t you? [alert type=&amp;quot;note&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Note&amp;quot;]GitHub Copilot Agent mode is more than code completi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/customize-ai-responses-from-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular Ktor: Building Backends for Scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ktor offers a lightweight, flexible approach to building web applications that differs from more opinionated all-in-one frameworks. While Ktor’s minimalist design might seem challenging at first, a little experience using our modules can go a long way towards building for scale. In this article, I’ll show you some techniques for introducing modularity to your Ktor […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/modular-ktor-building-backends-for-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use K8sGPT and Amazon Bedrock for simplified Kubernetes cluster maintenance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates the best practices to run K8sGPT in AWS with Amazon Bedrock in two modes: K8sGPT CLI and K8sGPT Operator. It showcases how the solution can help SREs simplify Kubernetes cluster management through continuous monitoring and operational intelligence.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-k8sgpt-and-amazon-bedrock-for-simplified-kubernetes-cluster-maintenance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rocket streamlines the home buying experience with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rocket AI Agent is more than a digital assistant. It’s a reimagined approach to client engagement, powered by agentic AI. By combining Amazon Bedrock Agents with Rocket’s proprietary data and backend systems, Rocket has created a smarter, more scalable, and more human experience available 24/7, without the wait. This post explores how Rocket brought that vision to life using Amazon Bedrock Agents, powering a new era of AI-driven support that is consistently available, deeply personalized, and built to take action.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an MCP application with Mistral models on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates building an intelligent AI assistant using Mistral AI models on AWS and MCP, integrating real-time location services, time data, and contextual memory to handle complex multimodal queries. This use case, restaurant recommendations, serves as an example, but this extensible framework can be adapted for enterprise use cases by modifying MCP server configurations to connect with your specific data sources and business systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-mcp-application-with-mistral-models-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build real-time conversational AI experiences using Amazon Nova Sonic and LiveKit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            mazon Nova Sonic is now integrated with LiveKit’s WebRTC framework, a widely used platform that enables developers to build real-time audio, video, and data communication applications. This integration makes it possible for developers to build conversational voice interfaces without needing to manage complex audio pipelines or signaling protocols. In this post, we explain how this integration works, how it addresses the historical challenges of voice-first applications, and some initial steps to start using this solution.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our first attempt to detect and report all unhandled C&#43;&#43; exceptions as well as all unhandled structured exceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we saw that installing an unhandled structured exception filter prevents the Microsoft Visual C++ runtime from converting unhandled C++ exceptions into
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250710-00/?p=111366 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Brings Compose to the Agent Era: Building AI Agents is Now Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 10:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agents are the future, and if you haven’t already started building agents, you probably will soon. Across industries and use cases, agents can act on our behalf, and offload repetitive work, because they can act on our behalf with judgment and context. But while agentic development is moving fast, today it’s tedious, hard, and not...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-ai-agents-with-docker-compose/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Agent to Update Dataverse Table Content</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Some time ago, I watched a demo of an AI agent updating a row in a table. The scenario was simple but effectively demonstrated the tool&#39;s capabilities and potential benefits for users. This made me wonder whether the same could be achieved using Microsoft Power Platforms. This article explores how to build an agent in Mi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/use-agent-to-update-dataverse-table 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize GitHub Copilot in JetBrains with Custom Instructions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 04:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, you can use Custom Instructions in JetBrains to speed up development while staying aligned with your team&#39;s coding standards and personal preferences.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/customize-github-copilot-in-jetbrains-with-custom-instructions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic configuration updates in .NET using Parameter Store and Secrets Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 03:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Loading configurations and secrets in .NET applications is a common practice. However, it comes with challenges in storing and accessing them securely and dynamically, without the need for application restart. AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store provides a centralized solution for storing and managing configurations and secrets data. This blog post explores an advanced approach to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/dynamic-configuration-updates-in-net-using-parameter-store-and-secrets-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS AI infrastructure with NVIDIA Blackwell: Two powerful compute solutions for the next frontier of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we announce general availability of Amazon EC2 P6e-GB200 UltraServers and P6-B200 instances, powered by NVIDIA Blackwell GPUs, designed for training and deploying the largest, most sophisticated AI models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-ai-infrastructure-with-nvidia-blackwell-two-powerful-compute-solutions-for-the-next-frontier-of-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock retail intelligence by transforming data into actionable insights using generative AI with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 20:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business for Retail Intelligence is an AI-powered assistant designed to help retail businesses streamline operations, improve customer service, and enhance decision-making processes. This solution is specifically engineered to be scalable and adaptable to businesses of various sizes, helping them compete more effectively. In this post, we show how you can use Amazon Q Business for Retail Intelligence to transform your data into actionable insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-retail-intelligence-by-transforming-data-into-actionable-insights-using-generative-ai-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the .NET MAUI Team uses GitHub Copilot for Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Around the time of Microsoft Build 2025, the new GitHub Copilot Coding Agent was unveiled and made widely available across GitHub. With AI evolving at a dizzying pace in recent months, we imagined a &amp;quot;dream scenario&amp;quot;: A GitHub
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/maui-team-copilot-tips 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Use AI Agents for COBOL Migration and Mainframe Modernization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Legacy modernization is one of the most frequently raised challenges customers approach us with. They want to eliminate technical debt and run applications cloud-native. Obviously, there are different levels of complexity in legacy modernization, but the most challenging cases remain mai
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-we-use-ai-agents-for-cobol-migration-and-mainframe-modernization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratize data for timely decisions with text-to-SQL at Parcel Perform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The business team in Parcel Perform often needs access to data to answer questions related to merchants’ parcel deliveries, such as “Did we see a spike in delivery delays last week? If so, in which transit facilities were this observed, and what was the primary cause of the issue?” Previously, the data team had to manually form the query and run it to fetch the data. With the new generative AI-powered text-to-SQL capability in Parcel Perform, the business team can self-serve their data needs by using an AI assistant interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases structured data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to make your Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL-Compatible Edition data available for natural language querying through Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases while maintaining data freshness.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/query-amazon-aurora-postgresql-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-structured-data/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure fine-grained access to Amazon Bedrock models using Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use SageMaker Unified Studio and AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) to establish a robust permission framework for Amazon Bedrock models. We show how administrators can precisely manage which users and teams have access to specific models within a secure, collaborative environment. We guide you through creating granular permissions to control model access, with code examples for common enterprise governance scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve conversational AI response times for enterprise applications with the Amazon Bedrock streaming API and AWS AppSync</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how integrating an Amazon Bedrock streaming API with AWS AppSync subscriptions significantly enhances AI assistant responsiveness and user satisfaction. By implementing this streaming approach, the global financial services organization reduced initial response times for complex queries by approximately 75%—from 10 seconds to just 2–3 seconds—empowering users to view responses as they’re generated rather than waiting for complete answers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-conversational-ai-response-times-for-enterprise-applications-with-the-amazon-bedrock-streaming-api-and-aws-appsync/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale generative AI use cases, Part 1: Multi-tenant hub and spoke architecture using AWS Transit Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            n this two-part series, we discuss a hub and spoke architecture pattern for building a multi-tenant and multi-account architecture. This pattern supports abstractions for shared services across use cases and teams, helping create secure, scalable, and reliable generative AI systems. In Part 1, we present a centralized hub for generative AI service abstractions and tenant-specific spokes, using AWS Transit Gateway for cross-account interoperability.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-generative-ai-use-cases-part-1-multi-tenant-hub-and-spoke-architecture-using-aws-transit-gateway/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing patches that impact the latest version of our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can dow
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/july-patches-for-azure-devops-server-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose your way with Provider services!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Docker Compose v2.36.0, we&#39;re excited to introduce a powerful new feature: provider services. This extension point opens up Docker Compose to interact not only with containers but also with any kind of external system, all while keeping the familiar Compose file at the center of the workflow. In this blog post,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-compose-with-provider-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker MCP Gateway: Open Source, Secure Infrastructure for Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since releasing the Docker MCP Toolkit, we’ve seen strong community adoption, including steady growth in MCP server usage and over 1 million pulls from the Docker MCP Catalog. With the community, we’re laying the groundwork by standardizing how developers define, run, and share agent-based workloads with Docker Compose. Now, we’re expanding on that foundation with...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-gateway-secure-infrastructure-for-agentic-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When I install an unhandled structured exception filter, why doesn&#39;t &lt;CODE&gt;std::&lt;WBR&gt;terminate&lt;/CODE&gt; get called?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For diagnostic and reliability purposes, a customer wanted to detect and report all all unhandled C++ exceptions as well as all unhandled structured exceptions. Their idea was to cover both exits: Use set_terminate to install a std::terminate handler, which is called when a C++ exception goes unhand
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250709-00/?p=111360 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.5-1 and 1.23.11-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 06:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-5-1-and-1-23-11-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam &amp; Jony</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building a family of AI products for everyone.
Link to article: https://openai.com/sam-and-jony 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
