<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:11:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot Chat now available in public preview for Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_03_2025/12_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, GitHub Copilot Chat is available in public preview for Eclipse! This release follows the initial public preview of GitHub Copilot in Eclipse, which only supported code completions, and is available for all Eclipse users with access to GitHub Copilot. After installing or updating GitHub Copilot for Eclipse, click on in the bottom right corner […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/github-copilot-chat-now-available-in-public-preview-for-eclipse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework March 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for March 2025.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-march-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing jackson-databind with azure-json and azure-xml</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 20:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post explains how azure-json and azure-xml replaced jackson-databind in the Azure SDK for Java.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/replacing-jackson-databind-with-azure-json-and-azure-xml 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: INCM transforms legal accessibility with an AI Search Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customer Case Study: INCM transforms legal accessibility with an AI Search Assistant The Imprensa Nacional-Casa da Moeda (INCM) is responsible for managing and publishing Portugal’s Diário da República (Official Gazette of the Republic of Portugal), which includes essential information for understanding laws, regulations, and legal processes. The quantity of information and the complex language used […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-incm-transforms-legal-accessibility-with-an-ai-search-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing patches that impact our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can download the latest version of the product, Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 from the Azure DevOps Server download page. The following versions of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/march-patches-for-azure-devops-server-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Boards Hub Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 18:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve reached a major milestone in the rollout of New Boards Hub this week by making it the default experience for all organizations and users. While many users can still temporarily switch back if they encounter a blocking issue, our telemetry shows that 97% of users are staying on New Boards without reverting. This is […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-boards-hub-update-spring-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you really need that abstraction or generic code? (YAGNI)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You Aren’t Gonna Need It. The essence of YAGNI is simple: don’t build something today that you assume you’ll need in the future. However, there’s a nuance here because we also don’t want to handcuff ourselves. Let’s explore how this principle applies both to features and technical implementation. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post… Read More »Do you really need that abstraction or generic code? (YAGNI) The post Do you really need that abstraction or generic code?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Chat History for AI Applications Using Azure Cosmos DB Go SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 15:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post covers how to build a chat history implementation using Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL Go SDK and langchaingo. If you are new to the Go SDK, the sample chatbot application presented in the blog serves as a practical introduction, covering basic operations like read, upsert, etc. It also demonstrates using the Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/implementing-chat-history-for-ai-applications-using-azure-cosmos-db-go-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4o Copilot code completion model available now in Visual Studio public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that the new GPT-4o Copilot code completion model is now available for GitHub Copilot users in Visual Studio starting in 17.14 Preview 2! This new model, based on GPT-4o mini, has undergone additional training on over 275,000 high-quality public repositories across more than 30 popular programming languages. As a result, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/gpt-4o-copilot-code-completion-model-available-now-in-visual-studio-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 10x Faster TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today I’m excited to announce the next steps we’re taking to radically improve TypeScript performance. The core value proposition of TypeScript is an excellent developer experience. As your codebase grows, so does the value of TypeScript itself, but in many cases TypeScript has not been able to scale up to the very largest codebases. Developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/typescript-native-port 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What an insightful observation, you get to wear “the hat”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maybe not so insightful.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250311-00/?p=110958 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunsetting Writerside IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 12:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In October 2023, we launched the Early Access Program for Writerside – a tool for authoring, testing, and publishing documentation. Built on the IntelliJ Platform, Writerside was available in two versions: a standalone tool and a plugin for JetBrains IDEs. Our goal was to serve two key audiences – developers who document their work and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2025/03/sunsetting-writerside-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Dependency Injection: Advanced Techniques Beyond the Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 10:15:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dependency injection (DI) is a powerful feature in .NET applications. It allows you the decoupling of dependencies by injecting required services at runtime, ensuring the modularity and testability of your code. You can create separate services or import them from NuGet packages by registering them into your application. However, injecting
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/net-dependency-injection-advanced-techniques-beyond-the-basics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running an ASP.NET Core app inside IIS in a Windows container</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how to run an ASP.NET Core app inside IIS in a Windows Docker container
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/running-an-aspnetcore-app-behind-iis-in-a-windows-container/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping the Conversation Flowing: Managing Context with Semantic Kernel Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 05:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the dynamic field of conversational AI, managing coherent and contextually meaningful interactions between humans and digital assistants poses increasingly complex challenges. As dialogue lengths extend, maintaining full conversational context becomes problematic due to token constraints and memory limitations inherent to large language models (LLMs). These constraints not only degrade conversational clarity but also compromise […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-python-context-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming financial analysis with CreditAI on Amazon Bedrock: Octus’s journey with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 20:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Octus migrated its flagship product, CreditAI, to Amazon Bedrock, transforming how investment professionals access and analyze credit intelligence. We walk through the journey Octus took from managing multiple cloud providers and costly GPU instances to implementing a streamlined, cost-effective solution using AWS services including Amazon Bedrock, AWS Fargate, and Amazon OpenSearch Service.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transforming-financial-analysis-with-creditai-on-amazon-bedrock-octuss-journey-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize reasoning models like DeepSeek with prompt optimization on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 20:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to optimize reasoning models like DeepSeek-R1 using prompt optimization on Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimize-reasoning-models-like-deepseek-with-prompt-optimization-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Essential Tools for JetBrains IDE Plugin Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for an insightful session on the top tools every plugin developer should know. IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Yann Cébron and Jakub Chrzanowski will walk you through essential utilities that streamline plugin development for JetBrains IDEs. During the webinar, you will discover how: No matter your level of experience, this webinar will equip you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/03/livestream-essential-tools-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-developmentlivestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock announces general availability of multi-agent collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re announcing the general availability (GA) of multi-agent collaboration on Amazon Bedrock. This capability allows developers to build, deploy, and manage networks of AI agents that work together to execute complex, multi-step workflows efficiently.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-announces-general-availability-of-multi-agent-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G3J Learn Semantic Kernel Show – A Deep Dive in Korean! | 세계로 뻗어갑니다: “G3J Learn Semantic Kernel” 쇼 – 한국어로 배우는 Semantic Kernel!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Global Expansion – “G3J Learn Semantic Kernel” Show – A Deep Dive in Korean! Localization Increases Demand Following the success of this multi-language delivery, we quickly noticed a surge in demand for localized content. Developers from different parts of the world have expressed interest in diving deeper into Semantic Kernel, and we couldn’t be more […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/g3j-learn-semantic-kernel-show-a-deep-dive-in-korean-%ec%84%b8%ea%b3%84%eb%a1%9c-%eb%bb%97%ec%96%b4%ea%b0%91%eb%8b%88%eb%8b%a4-g3j-learn-semantic-kernel-%ec%87%bc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft named a leader in The Forrester Wave: Public Cloud Platforms, 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 2010, we embarked on a journey to build a cloud platform that would empower organizations globally. In February, we celebrated 15 years of bringing Azure innovation to the world, and today, we celebrate Microsoft again being recognized as a leader in Forrester’s recently published report, The Forrester Wave™: Public Cloud Platforms, Q4 2024. We The post Microsoft named a leader in The Forrester Wave: Public Cloud Platforms, 2024 appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Assistant Comes to Kotlin Developers in Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin developers can now enhance their workflows in Android Studio with the new JetBrains AI Assistant plugin, which is now available in Beta. This plugin offers AI-powered coding assistance, including code suggestions, AI-driven explanations, refactorings, commit message generation, and more – all within Android Studio. Backed by large language models (LLMs) from both JetBrains and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/ai-assistant-comes-to-kotlin-developers-in-android-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I destroy an ABI pointer that I extracted from a C&#43;&#43;/WinRT object?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can clean it up the ABI way, whatever that is.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250310-00/?p=110952 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes on SharePoint Framework (SPFx) permission grants in Microsoft Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 13:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Changes on the SPFx permission management model in the Microsoft Entra ID.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/changes-on-sharepoint-framework-spfx-permission-grants-in-microsoft-entra-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Free Access to Cloud Academy: A New Benefit for Visual Studio Subscribers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m very excited to share some great news with you! Starting today, if you’re a Visual Studio Professional or Enterprise subscriber, you can get free access to Cloud Academy from QA—no trial, and no credit card required. This exclusive benefit is included with your Visual Studio subscription and provides 12 months of free access to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/cloud-academy-visual-studio-subscription-benefit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA’s Blog Feedback 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 10:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the years, the IntelliJ IDEA blog has become your go-to hub for expert insights, handy tips, and tech inspiration. But we want more – we’re heading to perfection, and we need your ideas to get there. Fill out this survey to let us know what rocks and what could be even better. It only […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-s-blog-feedback-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Disk Signature Collision in Azure VM After Cloning or Using Snapshots with Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 10:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When moving or duplicating Azure Virtual Machines (VMs), you may encounter an issue where the VM’s disk is offline due to a signature collision. This commonly happens when: Since Windows assigns a unique identifier (disk signature) to each disk, if two disks have identical signatures, Windows prevents conflicts by marking one disk as Offline. The […] The article Fixing Disk Signature Collision in Azure VM After Cloning or Using Snapshots with Windows was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Key to App Stability: Why Data Validation in Model Classes Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_03_2025/09_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_03_2025/09_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article emphasizes the critical importance of data validation within software development. It highlights that validation is often neglected, leading to significant issues related to application stability and data integrity. Multiple layers of validation are discussed, with a strong recommendation for prioritizing the Business Logic Layer to ensure consistent and secure data handling across applications.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/09/the-hidden-key-to-app-stability-why-data-validation-in-model-classes-matters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Manager REFUSES To Give Feedback! - Dev Leader Weekly 86</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to approach getting feedback form your manager.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/08/my-manager-refuses-to-give-feedback-dev-leader-weekly-86 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-03-07</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 04:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/08/weekly-recap-20250307 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Request Tracing with User Context in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_03_2025/08_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adding user context to request tracing in ASP.NET Core helps track issues and understand user behavior. This article shows how to implement middleware that enriches logs with user IDs for better troubleshooting and performance monitoring.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/better-request-tracing-with-user-context-in-asp-net-core 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration of AWS Bedrock Agents in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 21:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview of AWS Bedrock Agents AWS Bedrock Agents provide a managed service that facilitates the experimentation and rapid deployment of AI agents. Users can leverage proprietary AWS models as well as a diverse selection of models from various providers available on AWS Bedrock. Semantic Kernel’s Integration with AWS Bedrock Semantic Kernel now integrates with AWS […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/integration-of-aws-bedrock-agents-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating insurance policy reviews with generative AI: Verisk’s Mozart companion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 20:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-authored with Sundeep Sardana, Malolan Raman, Joseph Lam, Maitri Shah and Vaibhav Singh from Verisk. Verisk (Nasdaq: VRSK) is a leading strategic data analytics and technology partner to the global insurance industry, empowering clients to strengthen operating efficiency, improve underwriting and claims outcomes, combat fraud, and make informed decisions about global risks. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-insurance-policy-reviews-with-generative-ai-verisks-mozart-companion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the March release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-march-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing general availability of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases GraphRAG with Amazon Neptune Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, Amazon Web Services (AWS) announced the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases GraphRAG (GraphRAG), a capability in Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases that enhances Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) with graph data in Amazon Neptune Analytics. In this post, we discuss the benefits of GraphRAG and how to get started with it in Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/announcing-general-availability-of-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-graphrag-with-amazon-neptune-analytics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To some people, time zones are just a fancy way of sounding important, episode 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Words have meaning.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250307-00/?p=110946 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar – OSS Power-Ups: EntityFramework.Exceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 14:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Tuesday, March 18, 2025, 14:00 – 15:30 UTC (check other timezones) for our free live webinar, OSS PowerUps – EntityFramework.Exceptions, with Giorgi Dalakishvili. This is the fourtheenth episode of our series of OSS Power-Ups, where we put a spotlight on open-source .NET projects. Register now and get a reminder, or join on YouTube […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/03/07/webinar-oss-power-ups-entityframework-exceptions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Service Fabric: Is it still relevant? Service Fabric vs Microsoft Fabric?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Azure Service Fabric has been a foundational platform for building and managing microservices-based applications since its release. However, with the rise of Kubernetes and other container orchestration tools, its adoption has seen changes over the years. Additionally, Microsoft introduced Microsoft Fabric, a new data and analytics platform, leading to some confusion between the two […] The article Azure Service Fabric: Is it still relevant? Service Fabric vs Microsoft Fabric? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.3 Bug Fix Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 09:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.3 bug-fix update is out and ready to be installed on your servers! This update resolves over 10 issues and, as always, includes essential security and performance fixes. We highly recommend upgrading to keep your system secure and optimized. The list of resolved issues includes: See TeamCity 2024.12.3 Upgrade Notes for the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/teamcity-2024-12-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are OWASP Top 10 Checks and How Can Your Team Benchmark Security?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 09:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Businesses of different sizes have various motives for prioritizing code security. For an enterprise client, it might have to do with compliance. For a business that handles user data, there could be very imminent risk to customers and staff alike. Any development team could fall prey to the rise of cybercrime and attacks as detailed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/03/owasp-top-10/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.1-1 and 1.23.7-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 09:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-1-1-and-1-23-7-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET MAUI在 .NET 9 中的性能功能</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 06:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自 Jonathan 和 Simon 的 .NET MAUI Performance Features in .NET 9 .NET 多平台应用 UI (.NET MAUI) 随着各个版本的发布而不断发展，与此同时，.NET 9 重点引入了裁剪功能和一个新的受支持运行时：NativeAOT。这些功能可以帮助您减少应用程序大小、提高启动速度，并确保应用程序在各个平台上流畅运行。无论是希望优化 .NET MAUI 应用的开发者，还是 NuGet 包的作者，都可以在 .NET 9 中使用这些功能。 我们还将向开发人员介绍可用于测量 .NET MAUI 应用程序性能的选项。CPU 采样和内存快照可分别通过 dotnet-trace 和 dotnet-gcdump 获得。这些工具可以帮助您深入了解应用程序、NuGet 包的性能问题，甚至是我们需要关注的 .NET MAUI 问题。 背景 默认情况下， iOS 和 Android 上的 .NET MAUI 应用程序使用以下设置： “自包含”: 意味着应用程序中包含 BCL 和运行时的副本。 部分裁剪（TrimMode=partial），意味着默认情况下不修剪应用程序或 NuGet […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/net-maui%e5%9c%a8-net-9-%e4%b8%ad%e7%9a%84%e6%80%a7%e8%83%bd%e5%8a%9f%e8%83%bd 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to your agents! Introducing the Realtime API’s in Semantic Kernel!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 21:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing Realtime Agents in Semantic Kernel for Python! With release 1.23.0 of the Python version of Semantic Kernel we are introducing a new set of clients for interacting with the realtime multi-modal API’s of OpenAI and Azure OpenAI. They provide a abstracted approach to connecting to those services, adding your tools and running apps that […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/talk-to-your-agents-introducing-the-realtime-apis-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop 4.39: Smarter AI Agent, Docker Desktop CLI in GA, and Effortless Multi-Platform Builds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 18:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.39 brings Docker AI Agent for real-time help, plus Bake for faster builds and Multi-Node Kubernetes for better testing. Learn more!
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-39/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Angular Language Server: Understanding IDE Integration Approaches</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 18:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Language Server Protocol (LSP) has been a fundamental part of the code editor landscape for years, providing a consistent development experience across different editors. The Angular Language Server leverages this protocol to provide Angular-specific features to compatible editors. However, not all IDEs take the same approach to delivering these capabilities. Let’s look at the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/03/the-angular-language-server-understanding-ide-integration-approaches/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET AI Template Now Available in Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the first preview of the .NET AI Template, for Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, and the .NET CLI. Get started building amazing AI apps with .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-ai-template-preview1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Multi-Agent System with LangGraph and Mistral on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 17:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use LangGraph and Mistral models on Amazon Bedrock to create a powerful multi-agent system that can handle sophisticated workflows through collaborative problem-solving. This integration enables the creation of AI agents that can work together to solve complex problems, mimicking humanlike reasoning and collaboration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-multi-agent-system-with-langgraph-and-mistral-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Microsoft Copilot scales to millions of users with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is guest authored by Youssef Moussaoui, member of the technical staff, Microsoft Copilot. As part of the team developing Microsoft Copilot, we’re constantly looking for ways to improve the application and keep our millions of users engaged. With this in mind, we recently evaluated the structure of our backend and began looking for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/how-microsoft-copilot-scales-to-millions-of-users-with-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate RAG responses with Amazon Bedrock, LlamaIndex and RAGAS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 16:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we’ll explore how to leverage Amazon Bedrock, LlamaIndex, and RAGAS to enhance your RAG implementations. You’ll learn practical techniques to evaluate and optimize your AI systems, enabling more accurate, context-aware responses that align with your organization’s specific needs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-rag-responses-with-amazon-bedrock-llamaindex-and-ragas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: What’s new and what’s next</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code continues to evolve, bringing powerful new features and enhancements that make SQL development more seamless and efficient. In this update, we’re excited to share the latest improvements in v1.29.0 and give you a sneak peek at what’s coming next in our open roadmap. This extension is designed for developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/mssql-vs-code-whats-new-next 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortlessly Integrate xAI’s Grok with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 15:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For Semantic Kernel users, integrating xAI’s Grok API using the OpenAI connector is a breeze thanks to its compatibility with OpenAI’s API format. This tutorial focuses on setting up Grok in your Semantic Kernel projects with minimal fuss, using C# and Python examples. Why Grok? Grok, built by xAI, is a powerful AI model, offers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/integrate-sk-with-xai-grok-easily 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I choose a different C&#43;&#43; constructor at runtime?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Make somebody else do it, and then use copy elision.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250306-00/?p=110942 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 12:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this month’s Java Annotated Monthly! As always, we bring you the most interesting tutorials on Java, Kotlin, and other technologies, along with the latest news you don’t want to miss. We’re also excited to introduce a brand-new AI section, which we reserve for the most fascinating content on the topic. And this month, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/java-annotated-monthly-march-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try The New Toolbox App 2.6 EAP With Remote Development Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 10:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the latest update, the Toolbox App now supports remote development, allowing you to manage your JetBrains tools and projects both locally and on remote servers. This allows you to connect to cross-platform hosts, including Windows, macOS, and Linux, and use integrated OpenSSH for secure and customizable SSH connections. You can download the latest Toolbox […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/toolbox-app/2025/03/try-the-new-toolbox-app-2-6-eap-with-remote-development-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Guidelines Support Library v4.2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 09:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Version 4.2.0 of Microsoft&#39;s Guidelines Support Library brings performance improvements, safety features, modern compiler support.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/announcing-guidelines-support-library-v4-2-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi Root Workspaces in Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to manage multiple independent python projects, with different dependencies, inside Visual Studio Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/multi_root_workspaces_in_visual_studio_code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovating at speed: BMW’s generative AI solution for cloud incident analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how BMW uses generative AI to speed up the root cause analysis of incidents in complex and distributed systems in the cloud such as BMW’s Connected Vehicle backend serving 23 million vehicles. Read on to learn how the solution, collaboratively pioneered by AWS and BMW, uses Amazon Bedrock Agents and Amazon CloudWatch logs and metrics to find root causes quicker. This post is intended for cloud solution architects and developers interested in speeding up their incident workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series forecasting with LLM-based foundation models and scalable AIOps on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will guide you through the process of integrating Chronos into Amazon SageMaker Pipeline using a synthetic dataset that simulates a sales forecasting scenario, unlocking accurate and efficient predictions with minimal data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/time-series-forecasting-with-llm-based-foundation-models-and-scalable-aiops-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ground truth generation and review best practices for evaluating generative AI question-answering with FMEval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss best practices for applying LLMs to generate ground truth for evaluating question-answering assistants with FMEval on an enterprise scale. FMEval is a comprehensive evaluation suite from Amazon SageMaker Clarify, and provides standardized implementations of metrics to assess quality and responsibility. To learn more about FMEval, see Evaluate large language models for quality and responsibility of LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ground-truth-generation-and-review-best-practices-for-evaluating-generative-ai-question-answering-with-fmeval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Generative AI Uses Text Tokens to Generate a Response</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 19:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI systems using Large Language Models (LLMs) like GPT-4o process natural language input through a series of computational steps: tokenization, numerical representation, neural processing, and text generation. While these models have achieved impressive performance in understanding and generating text, they sometimes struggle with seemingly simple tasks, such as counting letters in a word. This […] The article How Generative AI Uses Text Tokens to Generate a Response was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – March 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 19:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The March 2025 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include improvements to shell integration, a new setting to change auto test discovery file patterns, inline values shown on hover, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-march-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoGen and Semantic Kernel, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 17:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following on from our blog post a couple months ago: Microsoft’s Agentic AI Frameworks: AutoGen and Semantic Kernel, Microsoft’s agentic AI story is evolving at a steady pace. Both Azure AI Foundry’s Semantic Kernel and AI Frontier’s AutoGen are designed to empower developers to build advanced multi-agent systems. The AI Frontier’s team is charging ahead […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-and-autogen-part-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 17:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta is now available! This means we’re in the final stretch before the major release, and you can try out all the new features and improvements right now. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing, Managing and Securing: Building with Microsoft Copilot Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 16:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you would like to start building an agent in Microsoft Copilot Studio, don’t worry we’ve got you covered! In our AI in Action: Building with Copilot Studio series on the Microsoft Power Platform YouTube channel, we have several episodes that guide you through how to get started in building an agent. This blog post […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/publishing-managing-and-securing-building-with-microsoft-copilot-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Debugging and Profiling Features in Visual Studio (v17.13)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 15:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest Visual Studio update (v17.13) brings a strong set of debugging and profiling features designed to speed up troubleshooting, making it more efficient. With AI-driven features in this release, variable analysis and data inspection are smarter and more intuitive, and problems are easier to identify and debug. Profiling tool improvements also deliver better support […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-debugging-and-profiling-features-in-visual-studio-v17-13 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Model Context Protocol Tools with Semantic Kernel: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 15:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes how to use Model Context Protocol tools with Semantic Kernel. Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open protocol that standardizes how applications provide context to LLMs. MCP standardizes the connection between AI models and various data sources and tools. The Model Context Protocol is significant because it enhances the way AI models […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/integrating-model-context-protocol-tools-with-semantic-kernel-a-step-by-step-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I tried to subscribe to a C&#43;&#43;/WinRT event, but my callback was never called</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check how you registered your event handler.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250305-00/?p=110934 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 13:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The [InternalsVisibleTo] attribute in .NET is a powerful feature that allows an assembly to expose its internal members (normally only accessible within the same assembly) to another specified assembly. This is typically used in scenarios like unit testing or multi-assembly projects where tight integration between assemblies is needed. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/03/05/dotinsights-march-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Creating Empty Arrays</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Arrays are a key collection type in .NET. There are three methods to create empty arrays: new string[0], Array.Empty(), and the concise [] expression. Benchmark tests show the [] expression is the fastest and most memory-efficient option. For improved performance, developers should adopt this method in their codebases.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/05/microsoft-net-code-analysis-creating-empty-arrays/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
