<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using type aliases to make code clearer with generics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you use generic types in C#, it is sometimes hard to understand what the generic argument can represent. For example, what do the strings represent in Dictionary&amp;lt;string, string&amp;gt;? To make the code clearer, you can use type aliases. // ❌ What does the string means? _ = new Dictionary&amp;lt;string, string&amp;gt;(); // Create aliases using UserId = string; using ProjectId = string; // Use the type aliases // ✅ It&#39;s…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Creating a List&lt;&gt; Using The Task.Parallel Library</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post discusses alternative approaches to adding items to a collection using For() or ForEach() from the Task Parallel Library.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/22/collection-performance-creating-a-list-using-the-task-parallel-library/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-In Rate Limiting in ASP.NET Core Web API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 05:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’re going to discuss Rate Limiting in ASP.NET Core, specifically version 8, and explore some ways of implementing it. So, Let’s start. What is Rate Limiting? Rate limiting controls the rate at which requests or events are allowed within a given time frame. In today’s world, where information flows at unprecedented rates, […] The post Built-In Rate Limiting in ASP.NET Core Web API appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Convert a String to Byte Array in C#: Encoding and Decoding Simplified</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How to Convert a String to Byte Array in C#: Encoding and Decoding Simplified appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how to effectively convert a string to a byte array in C#! While it might seem straightforward on the surface, we have encodings to consider! The post How to Convert a String to Byte Array in C#: Encoding and Decoding Simplified appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Represent the Relationship of Properties Using Property Mappings From AutoMapper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 05:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll take a look at what property mappings are and how to retrieve them from AutoMapper. AutoMapper is a free .NET library that streamlines object mapping, reducing manual coding to boost development speed and minimize the risk of errors. Additionally, it offers versatile configuration options and supports complex needs like conditional mapping, […] The post Represent the Relationship of Properties Using Property Mappings From AutoMapper appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Convention over Configuration for IaC Deployment Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 02:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Infrastructure as Code (IaC), every aspect of an organization’s infrastructure is defined and managed through code. This infrastructure deployment and configuration automation makes managing the organizations infrastructure much easier over time. Also, by committing the IaC code that configurations the infrastructure into source control, there are change tracking and other benefits for the organizations […] The article Benefits of Convention over Configuration for IaC Deployment Projects appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating API Gateways in Zuplo – Dev Leader Weekly 40</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Creating API Gateways in Zuplo – Dev Leader Weekly 40 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue sponsored by Zuplo, I share how I&#39;m putting an API gateway in front of my ASCII art API! The post Creating API Gateways in Zuplo – Dev Leader Weekly 40 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/20/creating-api-gateways-in-zuplo-dev-leader-weekly-40/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Minimal APIs Endpoint Organization With Carter in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 09:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look closely at the Carter library and how we can use it in our ASP.NET Core projects. Let’s get started! What Is the Carter Library The Carter library is an open-source project providing an abstraction layer for ASP.NET Core applications. This layer serves as a way to manage our minimal APIs […] The post Better Minimal APIs Endpoint Organization With Carter in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing automatic training for solutions in Amazon Personalize</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Personalize is excited to announce automatic training for solutions. Solution training is fundamental to maintain the effectiveness of a model and make sure recommendations align with users’ evolving behaviors and preferences. As data patterns and trends change over time, retraining the solution with the latest relevant data enables the model to learn and adapt, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-automatic-training-for-solutions-in-amazon-personalize/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Distributed Tracing With OpenTelemetry in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Distributed systems offer flexibility but introduce complexity, making troubleshooting a headache. Understanding how requests flow through your system is crucial for debugging and performance optimization. OpenTelemetry is an open-source observability framework that makes this possible.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/introduction-to-distributed-tracing-with-opentelemetry-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign up for the Microsoft Developers AI Learning Hackathon and Compete for $10,000 in Prizes!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 17:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you ready to learn about building your very own AI apps in Azure? Participate in the Microsoft Developers AI Learning Hackathon and discover how to build your own custom AI copilot using Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB and the Azure OpenAI API.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/sign-up-for-the-microsoft-developers-ai-learning-hackathon-and-compete-for-10000-in-prizes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Kubernetes Operators for new inference capabilities in Amazon SageMaker that reduce LLM deployment costs by 50% on average</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 16:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce a new version of the Amazon SageMaker Operators for Kubernetes using the AWS Controllers for Kubernetes (ACK). ACK is a framework for building Kubernetes custom controllers, where each controller communicates with an AWS service API. These controllers allow Kubernetes users to provision AWS resources like buckets, databases, or message queues […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-kubernetes-operators-for-new-inference-capabilities-in-amazon-sagemaker-that-reduce-llm-deployment-costs-by-50-on-average/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB design patterns – Part 9: Schema versioning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to Part 9 of our Azure Cosmos DB Design Patterns series, focusing on Schema Versioning. This edition is particularly useful for those new to NoSQL databases or looking to understand Azure Cosmos DB’s unique capabilities. Here, we will explore how schema versioning can help manage and evolve your database schema efficiently,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-design-patterns-part-9-schema-versioning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to your slide deck using multimodal foundation models hosted on Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of this series, we presented a solution that used the Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings model to convert individual slides from a slide deck into embeddings. We stored the embeddings in a vector database and then used the Large Language-and-Vision Assistant (LLaVA 1.5-7b) model to generate text responses to user questions based on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/talk-to-your-slide-deck-using-multimodal-foundation-models-hosted-on-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-sagemaker-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale AI training and inference for drug discovery through Amazon EKS and Karpenter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with the leadership team of Iambic Therapeutics. Iambic Therapeutics is a drug discovery startup with a mission to create innovative AI-driven technologies to bring better medicines to cancer patients, faster. Our advanced generative and predictive artificial intelligence (AI) tools enable us to search the vast space of possible drug […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-ai-training-and-inference-for-drug-discovery-through-amazon-eks-and-karpenter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize an existing Windows service to a .NET 8 gRPC service with Amazon ECS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 14:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction gRPC is a high-performance, cross-platform Remote Procedure Call (RPC) framework that allows for efficient communication between microservices. It was developed by Google and is now open-source. gRPC efficiently connects services in and across data centers with pluggable support for load balancing, tracing, health checking and authentication. For more information on gRPC, read the gRPC […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-an-existing-windows-service-to-a-net-6-grpc-service-with-amazon-ecs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Abandoning the background work if we know that it is pointless.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240419-00/?p=109689 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Gateways in Zuplo – Creating an ASCII Art API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post API Gateways in Zuplo – Creating an ASCII Art API appeared first on Dev Leader.Just how easy is it to make an API gateway in Zuplo? Zuper eazy. Check out how I&#39;m making an ASCII art API with Zuplo as my API gateway! The post API Gateways in Zuplo – Creating an ASCII Art API appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/19/api-gateways-in-zuplo-creating-an-ascii-art-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #210</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 08:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #210 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Computing code coverage for a .NET project [www.meziantou.net] Computing code coverage without any dependencies is now possible in .NET. Check this article by Gérald Barré to learn how to do it. WHY and […] The post Code Maze Weekly #210 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling Docker Compose services through Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A brief summary of how Crew Clark were able to profile performance using Visual Studio and within a Docker Compose environment.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/profiling-docker-compose-services-through-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Check the Total Number of Items Defined in an Enum</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 05:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we talk about enums and, more specifically, how to find the total number of items defined in the enum. But first of all, let’s define an enum. Let’s start. What is an Enum An enum, short for enumeration, serves as a lightweight data structure within a programming language. It encapsulates a set […] The post How to Check the Total Number of Items Defined in an Enum appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Edges of Technology in Software Development: Bleeding, Leading, Dull, and Rusting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the fast-evolving world of software development, keeping pace with technology trends is both a necessity and a challenge. Companies and…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/technology-edges-bleeding-leading-rusting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Code C&#43;&#43; Extension 1.19 Release: 3.6x faster Go To Symbol &amp; 1.5x faster colorization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With our recent 1.19 release, performance was our biggest focus for the C++ Extension in Visual Studio Code. This included features like progressive population of IntelliSense results and faster symbol searching. With these enhancements, you can begin writing C++ code when opening a file quicker than ever before.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/vs-code-c-extension-1-19-release-faster-go-to-symbol-and-colorization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate customized, compliant application IaC scripts for AWS Landing Zone using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 17:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As you navigate the complexities of cloud migration, the need for a structured, secure, and compliant environment is paramount. AWS Landing Zone addresses this need by offering a standardized approach to deploying AWS resources. This makes sure your cloud foundation is built according to AWS best practices from the start. With AWS Landing Zone, you eliminate the guesswork in security configurations, resource provisioning, and account management. It’s particularly beneficial for organizations looking to scale without compromising on governance or control, providing a clear path to a robust and efficient cloud setup.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Meeting Assistant with Amazon Transcribe, Amazon Bedrock, and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 17:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve likely experienced the challenge of taking notes during a meeting while trying to pay attention to the conversation. You’ve probably also experienced the need to quickly fact-check something that’s been said, or look up information to answer a question that’s just been asked in the call. Or maybe you have a team member that always joins meetings late, and expects you to send them a quick summary over chat to catch them up.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: Azure Developers – .NET Day</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on April 30th for a full day of online training and discover the latest services and features in Azure designed specifically for .NET developers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-azure-developers-dotnet-day-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Llama 3 models are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 16:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Meta Llama 3 foundation models are available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. The Llama 3 models are a collection of pre-trained and fine-tuned generative text models. In this post, we walk through how to discover and deploy Llama 3 models via SageMaker JumpStart. What is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/meta-llama-3-models-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector Search Optimization via KMeans, Voronoi Cells and Inverted File Index (aka “Cell-Probing”)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 16:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a previous article I already mentioned how vectors can be easily stored in Azure SQL already and how to calculate dot product and cosine distance using just T-SQL. In this article I will show how to improve the performance in vector search by using a technique that has many name but is really based on something very well know already: KMeans Clustering.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vector-search-optimization-via-kmeans-voronoi-cells-and-inverted-file-index-aka-cell-probing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Kernel Updates: A Closer Look at Our Redesigned Plugin and Function Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we approach a stable v1.0 version of the Python Semantic Kernel SDK, we analysed the methods used to add plugins and functions to the kernel. We realised that the variety of available methods might confuse developers. For instance, when should one use import_plugin_from_object() versus import_native_plugin_from_directory()?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/python-kernel-updates-a-closer-look-at-our-redesigned-plugin-and-function-integration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Service Weaver is a Bad idea</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing distributed applications like microservices can be challenging. I know, surprise, surprise. Performance, versioning, testing, and the list goes on are all aspects that make it difficult. So there’s got to be an answer in the form of tooling that can make this easier. Maybe there is with Google Service Weaver? YouTube Check out my YouTube… Read More »Google Service Weaver is a Bad idea The post Google Service Weaver is a Bad idea appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            First attempt to try to fix the race condition.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240418-00/?p=109685 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack delivers native and secure generative AI powered by Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Slack, a Salesforce company, has collaborated with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to power Slack AI’s initial search and summarization features and provide safeguards for Slack to use large language models (LLMs) more securely. Slack worked with SageMaker JumpStart to host industry-leading third-party LLMs so that data is not shared with the infrastructure owned by third party model providers. This keeps customer data in Slack at all times and upholds the same security practices and compliance standards that customers expect from Slack itself.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Key Authentication Middleware In ASP NET Core – A How To Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post API Key Authentication Middleware In ASP NET Core – A How To Guide appeared first on Dev Leader.Want to add API key authentication middleware into your ASP.NET Core application? Check out this article for a simple code example that shows you how! The post API Key Authentication Middleware In ASP NET Core – A How To Guide appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/18/api-key-authentication-middleware-in-asp-net-core-a-how-to-guide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baseline Styling in BenchmarkDotNet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 05:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to set a baseline for our benchmark in BenchmarkDotNet and discuss styling the baseline results. As software developers, benchmarking the performance of our methods is a crucial part of our day-to-day activities. With the BenchmarkDotNet library, we can accurately perform this operation. When we use this library for […] The post Baseline Styling in BenchmarkDotNet appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Debugging and Start Running in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NOTE: Watch the video above to see actual timings of starting with and without debugging. Vote for this feature request to make Run vs Debug…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/stop-debugging-start-running-visual-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Set of Bug Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2024.1 Are Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 17:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, The ReSharper and Rider 2024.1.1 bug-fix updates have just been released! If you haven’t upgraded to the 2024.1 versions of our products, we highly recommend that you check out these two blog posts: And now, let’s go over the most important fixes in 2024.1.1. ReSharper 2024.1.1 The first bug-fix update fixes the issue […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/04/17/the-first-set-of-bug-fixes-for-resharper-and-rider-2024-1-are-here/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a scalable gateway with .NET for Microsoft AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft AI - our journey to building a scalable gateway with YARP on .NET8
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/building-a-scalable-gateway-for-microsoft-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reliable Web App Pattern for Java with Enhanced Security and Scalability on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 16:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To help you understand and use the RWA pattern, we’ve created a comprehensive collection of materials that describe it in full. You can review the documentation and access the production-quality, ready-to-deploy web application – Reference Implementation. The latest update to The Reliable Web App Pattern for Java builds on its initial promise to facilitate the migration of legacy Java applications to Azure,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/the-reliable-web-app-pattern-for-java-with-enhanced-security-and-scalability-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncover hidden connections in unstructured financial data with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Neptune</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In asset management, portfolio managers need to closely monitor companies in their investment universe to identify risks and opportunities, and guide investment decisions. Tracking direct events like earnings reports or credit downgrades is straightforward—you can set up alerts to notify managers of news containing company names. However, detecting second and third-order impacts arising from events […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/uncover-hidden-connections-in-unstructured-financial-data-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-neptune/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open source observability for AWS Inferentia nodes within Amazon EKS clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks you through the Open Source Observability pattern for AWS Inferentia, which shows you how to monitor the performance of ML chips, used in an Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS) cluster, with data plane nodes based on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances of type Inf1 and Inf2.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/open-source-observability-for-aws-inferentia-nodes-within-amazon-eks-clusters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.1.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:49:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WebStorm 2024.1.1, the first update for WebStorm 2024.1, is now available! It contains fixes for two major issues that unfortunately made it into the latest release. We are sincerely sorry for this and have tried our best to rectify the situation quickly. These issues have highlighted problems in our own internal communication and QA process […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/04/webstorm-2024-1-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Where each notification depends on some state information.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240417-00/?p=109679 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Code Quality in JavaScript Projects With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 13:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s no doubt that code quality plays an important role in any team’s output. Whether you’re weeding out critical issues, improving your skills, or simply establishing standards as a team, it’s paramount to be on the same page when it comes to defining and executing high-quality projects. Having the right tools along the way can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/04/improving-code-quality-in-javascript-projects-with-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Hacks: How to Handle Exceptions in Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 11:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously, we explored how to throw exceptions in Java to signal error conditions in our code. But throwing exceptions is only half the story. To build robust and reliable applications, we also need to know how to handle them effectively. In this post, we’ll explore how you can handle exceptions in Java, and we’ll also […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/04/easy-hacks-how-to-handle-exceptions-in-java/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String Performance: Appending a Character using the StringBuilder</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The use of a single character with a StringBuilder from an ObjectPool can improve performance. Benchmark results show similar overall performance, but without an ObjectPool, using a character becomes more significant. It is recommended to use a character in such cases. EditorConfig setup can check for this issue using dotnet_diagnostic.CA1834.severity = warning.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/17/string-performance-appending-a-character-using-the-stringbuilder/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: 10 Strategies for Launching Students Into the Software Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 07:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Academy has started a series of livestreams crafted especially for teachers and educators. Join us on Tuesday, April 23, at 4:00 pm UTC for the first livestream of the series with our Developer Advocate, Garth Gilmour. He’ll discuss how to ensure students are well-equipped for success in the real world of the tech industry. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/04/17/10-strategies-for-launching-students-into-the-software-industry/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>利用 Redis 使 AI 驱动的 .NET 应用程序更加一致和智能</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 07:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Catherine Wang的Making AI powered .NET apps more consistent and intelligent with Redis – .NET Blog (microsoft.com) Redis 是一种流行的内存数据存储，可用于解决构建和扩展智能应用程序的关键挑战。 在本文中，你将了解如何使用Redis的 Azure 缓存来提高使用 Azure OpenAI 的应用程序的效率。 Redis 的Azure 缓存不受最近的 Redis 许可证更新的影响： “我们将持续的合作以确保 Azure 客户能够无缝地利用 Azure Cache for Redis的所有层级。 Azure Cache for Redis、Azure Cache for Redis Enterprise 和 Enterprise Flash 服务不会中断，客户将收到及时的更新和错误修复，以保持最佳性能。” – Julia Liuson，开发部总裁 本博客包括两个示例应用程序： 第一个是基于.NET 揭秘检索增强生成的演示聊天语义内核（Semantic Kernel）应用程序。我添加了使用 Redis 保存额外知识并启用聊天历史记录的功能。 完整示例位于 Chat App with Redis 第二个是一个演示应用程序，它在 .NET 8 中使用 Redis OM dotnet 进行 Redis 输出缓存，以提高生成式 AI 的一致性和弹性。 完整示例位于 OpenAI 的输出缓存中 Redis 为 OpenAI 模型提供了额外的知识 像 GPT 这样的 OpenAI 模型在大多数情况下都经过训练且知识渊博，但它们无法了解您公司的内部文档或最近的博客文章。 这就是为什么您需要 Redis 作为附加知识的语义内存存储。 语义内存存储有两个基本要求： 智能应用程序无法直接读取文本 blob、图像、视频等非结构化数据。语义内存存储需要支持向量嵌入的有效保存。 智能应用程序需要执行总结、比较、异常检测等任务。语义内存存储需要支持搜索功能。 这意味着用于查找相关数据的索引、距离算法和搜索查询。 Redis Enterprise 提供了 RediSearch 模块来满足这些需求。 您可以使用内置的 FLAT 和 HNSW 索引算法、余弦等距离算法以及 KNN 搜索查询在 Redis 中保存向量嵌入。 语义内核（ Semantic Kernel ）为 Redis 语义内存存储提供了一个连接器。 在语义内核中使用 Redis 作为语义内存存储的代码可能如下所示（来自 ChatAppRedis）： //Initialize the Redis connection ConnectionMultiplexer connectionMultiplexer = await ConnectionMultiplexer.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Difference Between Invariance, Contravariance and Covariance in Generics in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 05:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore the role, significance, usage, and impact of invariance , contravariance and covariance in our C# generics programming. Generics in C# enable us to design flexible, reusable classes and methods, providing type safety without the need for excessive casting or the risk of runtime errors. However, […] The post The Difference Between Invariance, Contravariance and Covariance in Generics in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Fluid Framework 2.0 Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 19:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fluid Framework 2.0 Preview enables you to start developing new apps and test updating the existing 1.x Fluid apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-fluid-framework-2-0-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build &amp; test resilient apps in .NET with Dev Proxy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to build and test resilient apps in .NET with Dev Proxy to simulate API failures, different network conditions, and a lot more from your local machine.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/build-test-resilient-apps-dotnet-dev-proxy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed training and efficient scaling with the Amazon SageMaker Model Parallel and Data Parallel Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the performance benefits of Amazon SageMaker (including SMP and SMDDP), and how you can use the library to train large models efficiently on SageMaker. We demonstrate the performance of SageMaker with benchmarks on ml.p4d.24xlarge clusters up to 128 instances, and FSDP mixed precision with bfloat16 for the Llama 2 model.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/distributed-training-and-efficient-scaling-with-the-amazon-sagemaker-model-parallel-and-data-parallel-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage your Amazon Lex bot via AWS CloudFormation templates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Lex is a fully managed artificial intelligence (AI) service with advanced natural language models to design, build, test, and deploy conversational interfaces in applications. It employs advanced deep learning technologies to understand user input, enabling developers to create chatbots, virtual assistants, and other applications that can interact with users in natural language. Managing your […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-your-amazon-lex-bot-via-aws-cloudformation-templates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A secure approach to generative AI with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative artificial intelligence (AI) is transforming the customer experience in industries across the globe. Customers are building generative AI applications using large language models (LLMs) and other foundation models (FMs), which enhance customer experiences, transform operations, improve employee productivity, and create new revenue channels. The biggest concern we hear from customers as they explore the advantages of generative AI is how to protect their highly sensitive data and investments. At AWS, our top priority is safeguarding the security and confidentiality of our customers&#39; workloads.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In search of the Ballmer Peak, and other results from SIGBOVIK 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing studies in silliness.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240416-01/?p=109672 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: Program allows its output to be exfiltrated</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Once the output is generated, the program can&#39;t control where it goes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240416-00/?p=109668 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Graph API for SharePoint Pages is now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the general availability of the Microsoft Graph API for SharePoint Pages, in all cloud instances.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-graph-api-for-sharepoint-pages-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Trends Report 2024: AI’s Growing Role in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The most recent Docker State of Application Development Survey results offer insights into how developers are adopting and utilizing AI, reflecting a shift toward more intelligent, efficient, and adaptable development methodologies.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-trends-report-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Podcast Copilot with Azure OpenAI Service, .NET, and Power Platform Workshop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 12:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unlocking Value with the Power Platform For years now, the Power Platform has been a low code tool that unlocks value across your business by accelerating application &amp;amp; automation development to meet business demand faster. Whether you’re a professional developer, an IT admin,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-the-podcast-copilot-with-azure-openai-service-net-and-power-platform-workshop 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub Copilot Chat in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot serves as an AI-powered coding assistant capable of operating across various development environments, assisting you with your everyday coding challenges. In this new series of content, we will demonstrate how GitHub Copilot functions in Visual Studio especially and how it boosts your efficiency.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-to-use-github-copilot-chat-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendering Math in HTML: MathML, MathML Core, and AsciiMath</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss how you can render math in the browser using MathML and MathML Core elements, and show AsciiMath as an easier way of writing equations
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/rendering-math-in-html-mathml-mathml-core-and-asciimath/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Checking Strings for Null</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses best practices for checking strings for null in coding. It outlines three common methods: using == null, is null, or string.IsNullOrEmpty().
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/16/code-it-any-way-you-want-checking-strings-for-null/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hangfire: A Feature-Rich Approach to Task Scheduling in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 08:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the vast landscape of .NET scheduling libraries, Hangfire stands tall as a formidable competitor. We&#39;ve previously explored the powerful Quartz library in our last article: From Theory to Practice: Implementing Robust Task Scheduling with Quartz.NETTask scheduling is a backbone feature in modern software development, enabling
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/hangfire-feature-rich-approach-task-scheduling-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with OpenTelemetry and distributed tracing in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 09:30:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenTelemetry is a collection of APIs, SDKs, tools, and integrations designed for the creation and management of telemetry data, including traces, metrics, and logs. In today&#39;s post, I&#39;m going to demonstrate how you can begin using OpenTelemetry (OTEL) and distributed tracing with .NET.
Link to article: https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/getting-started-with-opentelemetry-and-dotnet-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Strawberry Shake and GraphQL in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 05:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll get familiar with GraphQL and Strawberry Shake, a GraphQL tool that facilitates interaction with local and remote data. Subsequently, we will build an application using the .NET API, focusing on customers searching for available space in shipping containers using GraphQL. This article will not delve deeply into server-side implementation since we have […] The post Introduction to Strawberry Shake and GraphQL in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-resource metrics query support in the Azure Monitor Query libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to query metrics for multiple Azure resources at once using the Azure Monitor Query libraries.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/multi-resource-metrics-query-support-in-the-azure-monitor-query-libraries 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel Office Hours Recordings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 20:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Semantic Kernel Office Hour Recordings We are excited to update you on our new location for all Semantic Kernel Office Hours Recordings here: Semantic Kernel Office Hours – YouTube. Recordings from our Semantic Kernel Office Hours will be posted here one week after the session: Semantic Kernel Office Hours –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-office-hours-recordings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expand your app’s capabilities and reach on Microsoft Teams using API-based message extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 18:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the general availability of API-based message extensions, offering the easiest way to integrate your app into Microsoft Teams.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/expand-your-apps-capabilities-and-reach-on-microsoft-teams-using-api-based-message-extensions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline your container build and publish with .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 8 is a big step forward for building and using containers, with improvements for performance, security, and usability. Let&#39;s take a look at some enhancements to the .NET CLI for building and publishing containers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/streamline-container-build-dotnet-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build DR ready .NET Web APIs on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 16:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Disaster Recovery (DR) is an essential aspect of cloud computing. A solid DR strategy is required to ensure business continuity and less downtime in the event of unexpected disruptions. AWS, with its global infrastructure, provides the flexibility and scalability needed for effective DR. Multi-AZ (Availability Zone) deployments provide DR capability at the AZ level. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/build-dr-ready-net-web-apis-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 16:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These articles delves into indispensable tips that should consistently be integrated into your coding practices. Though these tips may seem small, their cumulative impact becomes pronounced, particularly when handling high message volumes. Embracing these fundamental practices can yield substantial benefits for overall performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/15/general-performance-tips/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Templates View for Build Insights in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 16:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Introducing the new Templates View feature of Build Insights! Templates View now allows you to capture data about how templates in your codebase are contributing to your build time. This feature is available in Visual Studio 2022 17.10 and later.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/templates-view-for-build-insights-in-visual-studio-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What were the tax consequences of letting Windows 95 team members keep a piece of software as long as they tested it?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It basically falls under the de minimis rule.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240415-47/?p=109663 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Collections &amp; DataTables</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 12:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Rider 2024.1, we’re shipping a highly requested feature: collection visualizers. Our very own Evgeny Terekhin has taken on the task of integrating DataGrip’s infrastructure to visualize data in the debugger. This makes it easier for .NET developers to inspect collections like List and Dictionary&amp;lt;TKey, TValue, as well as data-oriented objects such as DataSet, DataTable, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/04/15/exploring-collections-and-datatables/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Things I Wish I Understood Earlier In My Career</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post 8 Things I Wish I Understood Earlier In My Career appeared first on Dev Leader.This article is a list of things that I wish that I understood earlier in my career. There&#39;s no time machine, but I can share them with you! The post 8 Things I Wish I Understood Earlier In My Career appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/15/8-things-i-wish-i-understood-earlier-in-my-career/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing code coverage for a .NET project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In an older post, I wrote about how to compute code coverage for a .NET Core project with Coverlet. In this post, I&#39;ll show you how to get code coverage without any additional dependency. Indeed, the .NET SDK 8 now includes all you need to compute code coverage. Microsoft also provides a .NET tool to process the coverage files. Let&#39;s start by creating a new xUnit project and removing the dependency on…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use HttpOnly Cookie in .NET Core for Authentication and Refresh Token Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 11:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will show you how to use HttpOnly Cookie in .NET Core apps to secure our JWT or JSON Web Tokens, when implementing the authentication and refresh token actions. So, let’s start. The Standard Flow for the Authentication Logic Using JWT When we follow the usual flow with the JWTs: We can […] The post How to Use HttpOnly Cookie in .NET Core for Authentication and Refresh Token Actions appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Type &amp; Structure Performance: Hashing Classes, Records, and Structures</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A SHA256 hash can be generated for a class, record, or structure using a specific code. Performance analysis shows that hashing a class is 1.032 times faster than a structure and 1.048 times more efficient than a record. The memory allocations for record, reference, and value types are also provided in bytes.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/15/reference-type-structure-performance-hashing-classes-records-and-structures/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Java 22 and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 07:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Mala Gupta to explore how IntelliJ IDEA accelerates the adoption of Java 22 features. Date: April 24, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Get ready to use the new and updated features in Java 22 with IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1. Knowing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/04/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a secure Blazor Web application using OpenID Connect and security headers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 05:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article shows how to implement a secure .NET 8 Blazor Web application using OpenID Connect and security headers with CSP nonces. The NetEscapades.AspNetCore.SecurityHeaders nuget package is used to implement the security headers and OpenIddict is used to implement the OIDC server. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/BlazorWebOidc OpenIddict is used as the identity provider and an OpenID connect […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/04/15/implement-a-secure-blazor-web-application-using-openid-connect-and-security-headers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming on the 6-Month Roadmap for Java on Azure Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 02:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the March update of Java on Azure Tooling. In this update, we will share our investments for the next few months of Java on Azure Developer Tools. Besides, we will introduce the support for managing resources using connection strings.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-azure-tooling-update-march-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Azure 开发工具未来6个月路线图发布</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 02:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎阅读 Java on Azure 工具的三月更新。在本次更新中，我们将分享未来几个月对 Java on Azure 开发工具的投资。此外，我们还将介绍对使用Connection Strings管理资源。 我们希望您喜欢这些更新功能，并享受使用 Azure 工具包的流畅体验。请下载并安装 IntelliJ 的 Azure 工具包。让我们开始吧！ 路线图更新 我们很高兴宣布未来几个月的路线图。我们的目标是不断增强 Java 开发人员的 “代码到云 “体验，使他们能够无缝地构建和部署应用程序到 Azure，并在我们的工具中管理 Azure 资源。以下是我们投资领域的概述： 保持最新的 Azure 服务支持 支持最新的 Azure 服务始终是我们的首要任务之一。我们将在工具中持续提供 Azure Functions，Azure Web App，Azure Cosmos DB 和其他 Azure 服务的最新 Azure 功能，帮助开发人员更轻松地管理和部署应用程序。这将包括支持 Azure Flex Consumption、将 Azure Functions 的Java Runtime 运行时更新为 Java 21 以及为 Azure Cosmos DB 提供 Mongo vCore 支持等功能。 基于容器化服务构建云原生应用程序 对于在云原生环境中运行容器化应用程序的 Java 开发人员来说，我们知道他们大多选择在 Azure Container Apps (ACA) 或 Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) 上托管其工作负载。为了加强他们的代码到云之旅，我们计划对 Java on Azure Container Apps 进行深度集成 。这将使开发人员能够在云中运行容器化的 Java 应用程序，从源代码或工件文件中获得灵活的部署选项，并加强安全态势，更好地调整容器环境的内存配置。此外，我们还计划支持一系列容器化服务的关键功能，包括 ACA 上的 Azure Functions。 更好地引导智能应用程序体验 我们的下一个重点是增强在工具包中构建智能应用程序的体验。在之前的版本中，我们已经推出了对 Azure OpenAI 服务及其 Chat playground 的支持，Java 开发人员对此使用得很方便。为了进一步帮助希望使用 Azure OpenAI 服务创建智能应用程序的开发人员，我们计划投资支持更多模型，包括 Completions 和 DALL-E。 Azure SDK 增强 为了更好地帮助开发人员在 Java 项目中利用 Azure SDK，我们正在探索将 Azure SDK 编译工具集成到 Azure 工具包和 Maven 插件中。这一增强功能将使开发人员能够验证 Azure SDK 的正确使用，并检测其项目中过时的库。 最后几点，我们将继续更新 Azure 工具包的文档。此外，我们的团队正在努力将错误率和失败率降至最低，以提供更好的用户体验。我们希望这些改进将大大提高开发人员在我们工具中的工作效率。如果您对路线图有任何反馈或问题，请随时与我们分享！ Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ 更新 支持使用 Connection Strings 管理资源 当 Java 开发人员与 Azure 服务（如 Azure storage account）交互时，我们一直听到他们的反馈，即他们需要更多支持，以便使用连接字符串（connection strings）与 Azure 服务进行身份验证。在最新版本中，我们使您能够通过连接字符串在应用程序和 Azure 存储账户资源之间建立连接。这一增强功能提供了一种更简单的方法来验证应用程序与 Azure 存储账户的连接，并帮助您安全地管理资源。要使用此功能，只需将连接字符串（connection strings）直接粘贴到项目视图或服务视图中即可。下面是一个简短的演示。 Link to article: https://devblogs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
