<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 08:03:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>加入 .NET 智能组件生态系统</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 08:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于首席产品经理 Daniel Roth 的Join the .NET Smart Components ecosystem – .NET Blog (microsoft.com) .NET 智能组件是一组示例嵌入式 UI 组件，使得在应用中轻松添加 AI 启用的功能变得更加简单，例如从剪贴板数据自动填写表单、智能文本补全以及语义搜索等场景。.NET 智能组件演示了如何将基于 AI 的功能预先打包成可重用的组件，从而更容易将这些功能集成到现有应用程序中。我们将 .NET 智能组件源代码作为参考示例实现提供，以帮助启动一个充满活力的可重用 .NET AI 驱动组件生态系统。 现已开源 .NET 智能组件在 GitHub 上的 dotnet/smartcomponents repo 中有了新家，其中包含实现源代码、文档和示例应用程序。库作者可以使用示例组件来获得灵感，并将其作为如何打包 AI 驱动功能以方便使用的参考实现。如果您对如何改进 .NET 智能组件有想法，或者对希望添加的新 AI 组件有想法，请通过在 GitHub 上提出问题与我们分享。 使用语义内核的局部嵌入 .NET 智能组件包含用于在您的服务器上本地计算嵌入 (LocalEmbeddings)的示例便捷 API。这些API可用于比较文本的语义相似性。这些 API 现已更新，以将基于 ONNX 的嵌入支持包装在语义内核中，然后演示如何在其基础上构建更多功能，例如自动模型获取、简化的语义搜索和替代嵌入表示。如果您发现这些附加功能有用，则可以将它们包含在您自己的应用程序和库中。否则，您可以直接使用语义内核 API。 来自流行组件供应商的智能组件 一些流行的组件供应商已经开始投资构建自己的智能组件，以 .NET 智能组件中的理念为基础，并添加自己独特的创新和功能。让我们来看看他们正在研究的几个例子。 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e5%8a%a0%e5%85%a5-net-%e6%99%ba%e8%83%bd%e7%bb%84%e4%bb%b6%e7%94%9f%e6%80%81%e7%b3%bb%e7%bb%9f 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>推出适用于 .NET 的官方OpenAI库的稳定版本</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 07:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于.NET 团队的Announcing the stable release of the official OpenAI library for .NET – .NET Blog (microsoft.com) 早在 6 月份，我们就推出了适用于 .NET 的OpenAI 库的第一个测试版，使开发人员能够将高级 AI 模型集成到他们的应用程序中。今天，我们很高兴地宣布，适用于.NET 的官方 OpenAI 库的稳定版本现已上线。此版本可确保开发人员在其 .NET 应用程序中使用 OpenAI 和 Azure OpenAI 服务时获得顺畅可靠的集成体验。 主要特点 适用于.NET 的官方 OpenAI 库提供了强大的工具，可简化将 OpenAI 的高级模型集成到 .NET 应用程序中的过程，从而为开发人员提供简洁流畅的体验： 全面支持OpenAI REST API：包括 Assistants v2 和 Chat Completions，可实现灵活和先进的交互。 支持最新模型：OpenAI 的最新旗舰模型，包括 GPT-4o、GPT-4o mini、o1-preview […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e6%8e%a8%e5%87%ba%e9%80%82%e7%94%a8%e4%ba%8e-net-%e7%9a%84%e5%ae%98%e6%96%b9openai%e5%ba%93%e7%9a%84%e7%a8%b3%e5%ae%9a%e7%89%88%e6%9c%ac 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine 3.0 is Live!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just as the title says, Wolverine 3.0 is live and published to Nuget! I believe that this release addresses some of Wolverine’s prior weaknesses and adds some powerful new features requested by our users. The journey for Wolverine right now is to be the singular most effective set of tooling for building robust, maintainable, and … Continue reading Wolverine 3.0 is Live! →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/10/16/wolverine-3-0-is-live/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Pull Request Annotation for CodeQL and Dependency Scanning in GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of software development, security is paramount. As developers, we strive to write clean, efficient, and most importantly, secure code. GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps has always been at the forefront of providing tools that make it easier to build and release high-quality software. Today, we’re excited to announce a new feature […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/introducing-pull-request-annotation-for-codeql-and-dependency-scanning-in-github-advanced-security-for-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Error Messages for a GOOD Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 21:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debugging and troubleshooting are a big part of a developer’s day-to-day. Because of this, when designing your APIs, provide good API error messages as well as guide developers down a path of success and makes it easier for them to understand issues when they need to troubleshoot. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all… Read More »API Error Messages for a GOOD Developer Experience The post API Error Messages for a GOOD Developer Experience appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How DPG Media uses Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Transcribe to enhance video metadata with AI-powered pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how DPG Media is introducing AI-powered processes using Amazon Bedrock into its video publication pipelines. This solution is helping accelerate audio metadata extraction, create a more engaging user experience, and save time.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-dpg-media-uses-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-transcribe-to-enhance-video-metadata-with-ai-powered-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How SailPoint uses Anthropic’s Claude on Amazon Bedrock to automatically generate TypeScript code for SaaS connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we highlight how the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center collaborated with SailPoint Technologies to build a generative AI-based coding assistant that uses Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock to help accelerate the development of software as a service (SaaS) connectors.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-sailpoint-uses-anthropics-claude-on-amazon-bedrock-to-automatically-generate-typescript-code-for-saas-connectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map Earth’s vegetation in under 20 minutes with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the power of SageMaker geospatial capabilities by mapping the world’s vegetation in under 20 minutes. This example not only highlights the efficiency of SageMaker, but also its impact how geospatial ML can be used to monitor the environment for sustainability and conservation purposes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/map-earths-vegetation-in-under-20-minutes-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve your debugger game with editable expressions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you ever wish you could quickly test different queries on your collections or datasets while debugging? Do you want to save time and avoid writing code just to inspect your data? If you answered yes, then you will love the new editable expression feature in the Visual Studio debugger. This feature allows you to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/improve-your-debugger-game-with-editable-expressions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking insights and enhancing customer service: Intact’s transformative AI journey with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 17:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Intact&#39;s Call Quality solution used Amazon Transcribe and other AWS services to improve critical KPIs with AI-powered contact center call auditing and analytics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-insights-and-enhancing-customer-service-intacts-transformative-ai-journey-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we build GitHub Copilot into Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out how Visual Studio integrates GitHub Copilot, architectural detail, .NET implementation, and the importance of the indexing service for providing context-aware AI code suggestions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/building-github-copilot-into-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 control spotlight: Information security risk management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 16:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how Microsoft 365 Certification verifies information security risk management.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-control-spotlight-information-security-risk-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Best Practices: Using ARG and ENV in Your Dockerfiles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 14:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the ARG and ENV instructions and explore how to use them in your Dockerfiles to make your images more configurable and easier to maintain.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-best-practices-using-arg-and-env-in-your-dockerfiles/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of classic return address tricks on hardware-assisted return address protection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Return address manipulations that are possibly even more impermissible than they already were.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241016-00/?p=110378 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Docker IT Streamlined Docker Desktop Deployment Across the Global Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 13:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker IT deployed Docker Desktop to hundreds of macOS and Windows devices in 24 hours. Here&#39;s how they did it.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-docker-it-streamlined-docker-desktop-deployment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider Reveal Livestream: Big News for .NET and Game Devs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 12:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on October 24 for a special livestream where our Developer Advocates will reveal exciting news about JetBrains Rider. You won’t want to miss this! Set a reminder on YouTube and subscribe to our JetBrains channel to get notified when the livestream is about to start. We would appreciate it if you could spread […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/10/16/rider-reveal-livestream-big-news-for-dotnet-and-game-devs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Analysis for Your Projects With IntelliJ IDEA and Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we spend more time maintaining existing code than we do writing new code. Any tools that can help make this easier can save us a lot of time. In this blog post series, we’ll look at several ways that code analysis in IntelliJ IDEA can help you find and fix problems in your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/code-analysis-for-your-projects-with-intellij-idea-and-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.7.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 10:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Multiplatform is a declarative UI framework built by JetBrains that allows developers to share UI implementations across different platforms. The 1.7.0 release brings more components to common code, support for type-safe navigation, significant performance improvements on iOS, and changes from the latest Jetpack Compose update. Here are the highlights of this release: For the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/compose-multiplatform-1-7-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate migration portfolio assessment using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 22:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will harness the power of generative AI and Amazon Bedrock to help organizations simplify, accelerate, and scale migration assessments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-migration-portfolio-assessment-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve public speaking skills using a generative AI-based virtual assistant with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 20:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present an Amazon Bedrock powered virtual assistant that can transcribe presentation audio and examine it for language use, grammatical errors, filler words, and repetition of words and sentences to provide recommendations as well as suggest a curated version of the speech to elevate the presentation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-public-speaking-skills-using-a-generative-ai-based-virtual-assistant-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bria 2.3, Bria 2.2 HD, and Bria 2.3 Fast are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 20:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss Bria’s family of models, explain the Amazon SageMaker platform, and walk through how to discover, deploy, and run inference on a Bria 2.3 model using SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bria-2-3-bria-2-2-hd-and-bria-2-3-fast-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing SageMaker Core: A new object-oriented Python SDK for Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how the SageMaker Core SDK simplifies the developer experience while providing API for seamlessly executing various steps in a general ML lifecycle. We also discuss the main benefits of using this SDK along with sharing relevant resources to learn more about this SDK.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-sagemaker-core-a-new-object-oriented-python-sdk-for-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Organization Access Tokens</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker organization access tokens let customers manage access that each token has, instead of managing users and their placement within the organization.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-organization-access-tokens/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a data labeling project with Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth Plus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth is a powerful data labeling service offered by AWS that provides a comprehensive and scalable platform for labeling various types of data, including text, images, videos, and 3D point clouds, using a diverse workforce of human annotators. In addition to traditional custom-tailored deep learning models, SageMaker Ground Truth also supports generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-data-labeling-project-with-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-plus/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating industry-wide innovations in datacenter infrastructure and security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft drives innovation and contributes to the broader AI and datacenter community, benefitting the entire industry. The post Accelerating industry-wide innovations in datacenter infrastructure and security appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/accelerating-industry-wide-innovations-in-datacenter-infrastructure-and-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in System.Text.Json in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An overview of all new .NET 9 features in System.Text.Json for developers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/system-text-json-in-dotnet-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick introduction to return address protection technologies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Detecting attempts to manipulate the return address.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241015-00/?p=110374 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety and simplicity with LINQ: Working with the result pattern - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to clean up unreadable Switch()-based result pattern code using LINQ query syntax, giving both readability and safety
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/working-with-the-result-pattern-part-2-safety-and-simplicity-with-linq/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging .NET Collections with Span and MemoryExtensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article discusses optimizing code efficiency in .NET using Span and MemoryExtensions for collection operations. It highlights significant performance improvements in common tasks such as finding, sorting, and reversing collections, demonstrating that these tools minimize memory allocations and enhance speed. Benchmark results underscore substantial advantages in performance and efficiency.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/15/supercharging-net-collections-with-span-and-memoryextensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#x27;s new in .NET 9: Cryptography improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 08:38:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 9 is releasing in mid-November 2024. Like every .NET version, this introduces several important features and enhancements aligning developers with an ever-changing development ecosystem. In this blog series, I will explore critical updates in different areas of .NET. For today&#39;s post, I&#39;ll present some improvements asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/whats-new-in-net-9-cryptography-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: IEnumerable vs ICollection, and why it matters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with Lists in C#, you are working on a data structure that implements both ICollection and IEnumerable. What’s the difference between ICollection and IEnumerable? Why should you care about them, especially when exposing functionalities to external clients?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/ienumerable-vs-icollection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – October 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 19:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the October release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd), including configurable api-version for ACA.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-october-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a multimodal chatbot tailored to your unique dataset with Amazon Bedrock FMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to create a multimodal chat assistant on Amazon Web Services (AWS) using Amazon Bedrock models, where users can submit images and questions, and text responses will be sourced from a closed set of proprietary documents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-multimodal-chatbot-tailored-to-your-unique-dataset-with-amazon-bedrock-fms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design secure generative AI application workflows with Amazon Verified Permissions and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to design fine-grained access controls using Verified Permissions for a generative AI application that uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to answer questions about insurance claims that exist in a claims review system using textual prompts as inputs and outputs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/design-secure-generative-ai-application-workflows-with-amazon-verified-permissions-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch the highlights from Azure Developers – .NET Aspire Day 2024!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Watch the top sessions on demand for insights and practical guidance on building distributed applications with .NET Aspire!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/azure-developers-dotnet-aspire-day-recap 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ultimate chatbot?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 15:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RAG – Retrieval Augmented Generation – is by far one of the most common patterns today as it enables the creation of chatbots that can chat on your own data, as I described in my previous “Retrieval Augmented Generation with Azure SQL” blog post. As soon as you start to use it excitement grows, as […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/the-ultimate-chatbot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On naming things: The tension between naming something for what it is, what it does, or how it is used</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You are guaranteed to make someone upset.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241014-00/?p=110368 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding OverloadResolutionPriority attribute in C# 13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# 13 adds support for a new attribute: [OverloadResolutionPriority]. This attribute is niche, so most of you won&#39;t use it. However, it&#39;s a nice addition to the language, and it&#39;s worth knowing about it if you are writing libraries. Let&#39;s consider this simple example: Sample.Test(); // Print: Test 1 static class Sample { public static void Test() =&amp;gt; Console.WriteLine(&amp;quot;Test 1&amp;quot;); } Now, you want to update…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/understanding-overloadresolutionpriority-attribute-in-csharp-13.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Prevent Concurrent Execution of a Hangfire Job</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 05:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will see how we can prevent the concurrent execution of a Hangfire job. Hangfire is a wonderful tool for scheduling recurring background jobs. But, if we are not careful, we can encounter strange or intermittent errors caused by concurrent execution of a given job. We will first discuss potential problems related […] The post How to Prevent Concurrent Execution of a Hangfire Job appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s DateTime Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2024/13_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2024/13_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine offers open-source assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, including the DateTimeExtensions class. This class provides useful methods for DateTime and DateTimeOffset types, enhancing their functionality. The project encourages community involvement for continued improvement and welcomes feedback, suggestions, and contributions. Contact dotnetdave@live.com for more information.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/13/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-datetime-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radical Accountability vs Blame Culture – Dev Leader Weekly 65</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_10_2024/12_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_10_2024/12_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Radical Accountability vs Blame Culture – Dev Leader Weekly 65 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the differences between environments where there is blame vs radical accountability. The post Radical Accountability vs Blame Culture – Dev Leader Weekly 65 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/10/12/radical-accountability-vs-blame-culture-dev-leader-weekly-65/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling the Outbox Pattern (2B&#43; messages per day)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_10_2024/12_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_10_2024/12_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to supercharge your Outbox pattern implementation, scaling to 30,500 messages per second. Through strategic optimizations in database queries, message publishing, and parallel processing, I&#39;ll show you how to handle over 2.8 billion messages daily while maintaining system reliability.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/scaling-the-outbox-pattern 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost productivity by using AI in cloud operational health management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to create an AI-powered, event-driven operations assistant that automatically responds to operational events. The assistant can filter out irrelevant events (based on your organization’s policies), recommend actions, create and manage issue tickets in integrated IT service management (ITSM) tools to track actions, and query knowledge bases for insights related to operational events.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-productivity-by-using-ai-in-cloud-operational-health-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Indeed builds and deploys fine-tuned LLMs on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we describe how using the capabilities of Amazon SageMaker has accelerated Indeed’s AI research, development velocity, flexibility, and overall value in our pursuit of using Indeed’s unique and vast data to leverage advanced LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-indeed-builds-and-deploys-fine-tuned-llms-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve LLM application robustness with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Bedrock Guardrails can improve the robustness of the agent framework. We are able to stop our chatbot from responding to non-relevant queries and protect personal information from our customers, ultimately improving the robustness of our agentic implementation with Amazon Bedrock Agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-llm-application-robustness-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dive deep into vector data stores using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive deep into the vector database options available as part of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and the applicable use cases, and look at working code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dive-deep-into-vector-data-stores-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcement: Agent Framework Documentation Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Semantic Kernel Agent Framework revolutionizes how developers can interact with Large Language Models (LLMs) by embedding dynamic, multi-step agents into their applications. By combining the power of LLMs with structured programming, the framework allows developers to build intelligent systems that can autonomously carry out tasks, reason based on context, and collaborate across multiple agents. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcement-agent-framework-documentation-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I explicitly specialize a templated C&#43;&#43; constructor?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking for a C++ tag type for representing another type.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241011-00/?p=110365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal RAG with Vision: From Experimentation to Implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post delves into the experimentation journey of fine-tuning a multimodal RAG pipeline to best answer user queries that require both textual and image context. We ran our experiments by systematically testing various approaches, adjusting one configuration setting at a time and using clearly defined evaluation metrics to validate the performance of each component of the RAG pipeline in isolation, as well as the end-to-end inference flow.
Link to article: https://devblogs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable or disable ACL crawling safely in Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business recently added support for administrators to modify the default access control list (ACL) crawling feature for data source connectors. Amazon Q Business is a fully managed, AI powered assistant with enterprise-grade security and privacy features. It includes over 40 data source connectors that crawl and index documents. By default, Amazon Q Business […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enable-or-disable-acl-crawling-safely-in-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Contextual Tools for GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 17:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 17.11 now allows you to pass your entire workspace or specific classes and functions as context for GitHub Copilot Chat. By referencing your entire codebase, down to specific classes and functions, Copilot Chat can deliver refined and accurate results tailored to your code. @workspace for project references You can now use GitHub […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/new-contextual-tools-for-github-copilot-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us for JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 17:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey everyone! We’re introducing JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024, the first-ever virtual event dedicated to plugin development for JetBrains products! We invite you to join us on Thursday, November 7 for a full day of engaging sessions and insightful discussions. This conference brings together JetBrains experts and plugin developers to explore topics such as developing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/10/join-us-for-jetbrains-plugin-developer-conf-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the Scalable Vector Extension in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s take an in-depth look at how the team implemented the Scalable Vector Extension (SVE) for .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/engineering-sve-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SK Telecom improves telco-specific Q&amp;A by fine-tuning Anthropic’s Claude models in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how SKT customizes Anthropic Claude models for telco-specific Q&amp;amp;A regarding technical telecommunication documents of SKT using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/sk-telecom-improves-telco-specific-qa-by-fine-tuning-anthropics-claude-models-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Rufus, the Amazon generative AI-powered conversational shopping assistant with over 80,000 AWS Inferentia and AWS Trainium chips, for Prime Day</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into the Rufus inference deployment using AWS chips and how this enabled one of the most demanding events of the year—Amazon Prime Day.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scaling-rufus-the-amazon-generative-ai-powered-conversational-shopping-assistant-with-over-80000-aws-inferentia-and-aws-trainium-chips-for-prime-day/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring alternatives and seamlessly migrating data from Amazon Lookout for Vision</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we discuss how you can maintain access to Lookout for Vision after it is closed to new customers, some alternatives to Lookout for Vision, and how you can export your data from Lookout for Vision to migrate to an alternate solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/exploring-alternatives-and-seamlessly-migrating-data-from-amazon-lookout-for-vision/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 3.0 Is Now Available With New Features and Improved Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This new version uses Kotlin 2.0 and switches to kotlinx-io, making Ktor more up to date and better connected with other Kotlin tools. Ktor 3.0 works faster and gives you more options for building client-server applications. If you’re new to Ktor or need a reminder about how it works, our recent blog post, Ktor 101: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/ktor-3-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 EAP 4: New Embedded Development and Debugging Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new CLion 2024.3 EAP build, 243.19420.28, is out. You can download it for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 EAP This build includes new features for embedded development, such as debug servers, the ability to edit peripheral register values, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/10/clion-2024-3-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code Update – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the September update for Visual Studio Code for Java! In this blog, we will cover some important Spring feature updates and Gradle enhancements, let’s get started! Spring Updates Explain SpEL expressions, query statements, and AOP pointcut expressions with GitHub Copilot SpEL expressions, query statements, and AOP pointcut expressions can sometimes be […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-visual-studio-code-update-september-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code的更新 – 2024年9月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎来到 Visual Studio Code for Java 的九月更新！在本篇博客中，我们将介绍一些重要的 Spring 功能更新和 Gradle 增强功能，让我们开始吧！ Spring 更新 使用 GitHub Copilot 解释 SpEL 表达式、查询语句和 AOP 切入点表达式 SpEL 表达式、查询语句和 AOP 切入点表达式有时编写起来比较复杂，但如果你在 Visual Studio Code 环境中使用 GitHub Copilot，Spring 工具现在会在这些表达式上方显示CodeLense，让你快速让 GitHub Copilot 为你解释这些语句。相应的提示会先提供一个简短的摘要，随后是更详细的解释。这里有一个演示。 CRON 表达式的语法高亮和验证 当 CRON 表达式用于 @Scheduler 注解时，现在可以显示语法高亮，并且如果语法不正确，还会出现错误标记。演示如下。 查询参数名称的新嵌入提示 使用序号引用查询特定参数，现在会显示一个嵌入提示，告诉你该序号所引用的已解析方法参数的名称。 更多 Spring 注解获得内容辅助、跳转定义和查找引用支持 在 Java 源代码中使用 Spring 注解的工作每次发布都会变得更加快捷和轻松。最新的 Spring Boot 工具添加了以下注解的高级功能： […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-visual-studio-code-2024-09 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Security event logging, reviewing, and alerting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Microsoft 365 Certification validates security event logging best practices.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-security-event-logging-reviewing-and-alerting 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A correction to the awaitable lock for C&#43;&#43; PPL tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over-scoped lock.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241010-00/?p=110357 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Coding Workshop for the C&#43;&#43; Basics Course</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 12:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, October 22, 2024, at 3:00 pm UTC (check other timezones) for our free online workshop for the C++ Basics course. If you’ve wanted to learn C++ or have any questions about this language, you’ve come to the right place! C++ is a powerful, general-purpose programming language used to build everything from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/10/10/online-coding-workshop-for-the-c-basics-course/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I do Django APIs in PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 11:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I learn so much from watching conference talks, especially live, when I’m vibing with the crowd. But sometimes I watch and think: “Wow, I wish I could show you how awesome that would be in PyCharm.” That just happened. Here’s the explainer, with a little special something at the end. Hello, DjangoConf I recently attended […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/how-i-do-django-apis-in-pycharm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish MediatR Notifications in Parallel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 04:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2024/10_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore how publishing MediatR notifications in parallel works. Also, we will dive into the advantages and possible pitfalls of using parallel publishing. Let’s start. How MediatR Publishing Works by Default MediatR uses a sequential publishing strategy by default. This means that each handler is called one after the other, waiting […] The post Publish MediatR Notifications in Parallel appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
