<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating an already-completed asynchronous activity in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, part 6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let the conversion do the talking.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240716-00/?p=109973 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Tools for Java Developers in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 10:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just as an RPG player relies on a well-stocked bag of artifacts and tools to overcome obstacles and achieve goals, a Java developer also has a set of essential tools. Each tool performs a specific role in simplifying development and enhancing productivity. As Java has evolved, many tools have come and gone; what was popular […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/top-tools-for-java-developers-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Visual Studio a bit more visual</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Any web, desktop, or mobile developer works with images often. You reference them from C#, HTML, XAML, CSS, C++, VB, TypeScript, and even in code comments. Some images are local, and some exist online or on network shares, while others only exist as base64 encoded strings.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/making-visual-studio-a-bit-more-visual 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The YouTrack App Now Supports Helpdesk Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 09:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The YouTrack Helpdesk functionality has arrived in the YouTrack app! This means you can manage your customer support services on the go. Your agents and other team members can now work with support requests from their phones and tablets, and your reporters can submit and review tickets and public Knowledge Base articles in the app […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/07/the-youtrack-app-now-supports-helpdesk-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disambiguating types with the same name with extern alias</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how to solve Error CS0433, where you have two types with the exact same name and namespace coming from two different packages
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/disambiguating-types-with-the-same-name-with-extern-alias/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ComplexType vs JSON Columns: Choosing the Right Data Storage Approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 08:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the differences between complex types and JSON columns in .NET development. Make informed decisions on the optimal data storage approach for your .NET applications
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/complextype-vs-json-columns-choosing-right-data-storage-approach-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom model validation attributes in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 07:18:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While working on ASP.NET Core Web API, we have some customized business requirements for the user input. To implement those requirements, .NET provides a set of attributes to restrict users to input only validated data or return an error if the data inserted is invalid. In this blog, I asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/custom-model-validation-attributes-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: Mark a class as Sealed to prevent subclasses creation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The sealed keyword is often ignored, yet it can be important to define a proper class design.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/sealed-classes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose Between Azure Cosmos DB for Table and Azure Table Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 22:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Choosing the right database solution is critical for the performance and scalability of your applications. When working with NoSQL, Table data and Microsoft Azure, two prominent options for table storage are Azure Cosmos DB for Table and Azure Table Storage (aka Azure Storage Tables). Both services provide robust solutions for storing semi-structured table data, but […] The article How to Choose Between Azure Cosmos DB for Table and Azure Table Storage was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 Preview 6 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Try out the latest features in .NET 9 Preview 6 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-preview-6 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video auto-dubbing using Amazon Translate, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Polly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 17:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with MagellanTV and Mission Cloud. Video dubbing, or content localization, is the process of replacing the original spoken language in a video with another language while synchronizing audio and video. Video dubbing has emerged as a key tool in breaking down linguistic barriers, enhancing viewer engagement, and expanding market reach. However, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/video-auto-dubbing-using-amazon-translate-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-polly/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Mixbook used generative AI to offer personalized photo book experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 16:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Years ago, Mixbook undertook a strategic initiative to transition their operational workloads to Amazon Web Services (AWS), a move that has continually yielded significant advantages. This pivotal decision has been instrumental in propelling them towards fulfilling their mission, ensuring their system operations are characterized by reliability, superior performance, and operational efficiency. In this post we show you how Mixbook used generative artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities in AWS to personalize their photo book experiences—a step towards their mission.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Fluid Relay: Leveraging Azure Blob Storage to scale Git</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 15:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to leverage Git as a storage mechanism behind the globally available Azure Fluid Relay (AFR) service.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/azure-fluid-relay-leveraging-azure-blob-storage-to-scale-git 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2 EAP Digest #3: Bun Debugger, Language Server Updates for Vue and Astro, and Prettier Integration by Default</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 15:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s time for our last EAP digest of this release that will walk you through the new features and improvements in WebStorm 2024.2! For more information, check out our previous blog posts.The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the EAP builds and keep both your stable and EAP versions up to date. You […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/07/webstorm-2024-2-eap3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Hands-On with Visual Studio and Azure: Live at Microsoft HQ this August!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 14:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio LIVE! Microsoft HQ 2024 August 5-9 | Microsoft Conference Center, Redmond, WA There’s still time to register, join us, get your questions answered, and bring back a wealth of knowledge and excitement to your teams! We’re close to selling out for next month’s conference,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-live-2024-microsoft-hq 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an already-completed asynchronous activity in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, part 5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trying to fail more correctly.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240715-00/?p=109971 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Best Practices: Choosing Between RUN, CMD, and ENTRYPOINT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to optimize Docker command use with our best practices guide on RUN, CMD, and ENTRYPOINT Dockerfile instructions.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-best-practices-choosing-between-run-cmd-and-entrypoint/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How an AI Assistant Can Help Configure Your Project’s Git Hooks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Make Git hooks easier to configure and use by providing project-specific context to Docker&#39;s AI assistant.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-an-ai-assistant-can-help-configure-your-projects-git-hooks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable NuGet auditing for your .NET projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A security audit for package managers like NuGet is indeed a critical process for ensuring the security of software projects. NuGet has a feature to assist with this process. It can run a security audit with the dotnet restore command, which checks your dependencies against a list of known vulnerabilities from the GitHub Advisory Database. If vulnerabilities are found, you can update the affected packages…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/enable-nuget-auditing-for-your-dotnet-projects.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Shape the Future of Tech – Participate in the Developer Ecosystem Survey 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 11:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year’s Developer Ecosystem Survey is out now! This is your chance to contribute to a comprehensive, unbiased analysis of the software development landscape. Your insights and feedback are invaluable, and we can’t wait to hear from you. Offering you an opportunity to share your experiences as a developer, the survey will take around 30 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2024/07/15/help-shape-the-future-of-tech-participate-in-the-developer-ecosystem-survey-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Practical Debugging at Scale: Do You Really Know How to Debug Effectively?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Shai Almog, where we will delve into the capabilities of the debugger. Date: July 25, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Most of us didn’t learn debugging in university and just “picked it up on the job”. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Images Using OpenAI in an ASP.NET Core Application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 05:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to explore how to generate images in an ASP.NET Core application using OpenAI. Let’s get going. Introduction to OpenAI Models OpenAI has developed a range of specialized AI models, of which the GPT (Generative Pre-trained Transformer) series lays the groundwork for numerous natural language processing applications. Codex takes this […] The post Generate Images Using OpenAI in an ASP.NET Core Application appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering the Art of Public Speaking: Preparation is the Secret for Captivating Presentations and Flawless Demos</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2024/14_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2024/14_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Preparation is key for successful public speaking, requiring at least 40 hours of crafting and continual enhancement for presentations. Early preparation, thorough rehearsal, and leveraging tools like &amp;quot;cheat cards&amp;quot; and recordings are essential. Providing slide decks in advance for conference presenters encourages preparation and mentorship. The goal is to share knowledge that benefits developers and improves their applications.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/07/14/mastering-the-art-of-public-speaking-preparation-is-the-secret-for-captivating-presentations-and-flawless-demos/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday, Dev Leader Weekly! – Dev Leader Weekly 52</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_07_2024/13_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_07_2024/13_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Happy Birthday, Dev Leader Weekly! – Dev Leader Weekly 52 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the first full year of Dev Leader Weekly and how content creation changed my life. The post Happy Birthday, Dev Leader Weekly! – Dev Leader Weekly 52 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/07/13/happy-birthday-dev-leader-weekly-dev-leader-weekly-52/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your First Use Case With Clean Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_07_2024/13_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_07_2024/13_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a question I often hear: how do I design my use case with Clean Architecture? In this article, we&#39;ll explore a practical example of how to apply Clean Architecture principles by building a user registration feature.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/building-your-first-use-case-with-clean-architecture 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an already-completed asynchronous activity in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2024/12_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2024/12_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Failing is easy. Failing correctly is hard.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240712-00/?p=109967 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OData .NET 8 Release Candidate 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2024/12_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 08:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2024/12_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OData .NET 8.0 RC1 is now available, bringing numerous significant improvements to the following libraries: Microsoft.OData.Core Microsoft.OData.Edm Microsoft.Spatia Microsoft.OData.Client This is the final release candidate before the official launch of these libraries, scheduled for August 12th. Most of the planned features and changes are included in this release candidate and are ready for you to explore.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-odata-net-8-release-candidate-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document Summarization Solution Patterns using Azure Open AI &amp; Langchain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2024/12_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2024/12_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post lists the various solution patterns that can be applied for document summarization. Document summarization comes with its challenges related to token limitation and chunk sizes. This blog post discusses about the solutions to tackle those challenges.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/solution-patterns-for-document-summarization-azureopenai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Azure Logo Evolution Over Time (From 2009 to Today)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2024/12_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 05:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_07_2024/12_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There have been a few different logos used by Microsoft over the years for the Azure cloud platform; originally Windows Azure and later rebranded to Microsoft Azure. Let’s take a look at the various Microsoft Azure logos used over time; starting with the early days when the service as called Windows Azure all the way […] The article Microsoft Azure Logo Evolution Over Time (From 2009 to Today) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Beta Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 22:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the Beta version of IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2. This milestone brings us closer to the big release date, and you still have time to try out the new features through the Early Access Program. The Beta build includes all of the new functionality detailed in our IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP blog posts. Here’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Python Function Choice Behavior: Streamlining AI Model Configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 21:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Introducing Function Choice Behavior Today, we’re excited to introduce the Function Choice Behavior, an enhancement over the existing Function Call Behavior. This new feature streamlines configuration and supports specifying multiple required functions, simplifying code and enhancing functionality. One significant advantage of Function Choice Behavior is its abstraction at the base PromptExecutionSettings level,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/introducing-python-function-choice-behavior-streamlining-ai-model-configuration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure your Python applications with Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 18:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Integrate Microsoft Entra External ID with your Python Flask applications for secure user authentication. By leveraging External ID, you can securely manage access for external identities like business partners and customers, create custom branded sign-up experiences, and simplify user management. Follow this step-by-step guide to set up and run a sample Flask application using the Microsoft Authentication Library (MSAL).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/secure-python-apps-with-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and How to Execute GraphQL Queries in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to query a GraphQL API in .NET using Strawberry Shake from a console application
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/why-and-how-to-execute-graph-ql-queries-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Agents for Amazon Bedrock to interactively generate infrastructure as code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how Agents for Amazon Bedrock can be used to generate customized, organization standards-compliant IaC scripts directly from uploaded architecture diagrams. This will help accelerate deployments, reduce errors, and ensure adherence to security guidelines.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-agents-for-amazon-bedrock-to-interactively-generate-infrastructure-as-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve RAG accuracy with fine-tuned embedding models on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use Amazon SageMaker to fine tune a Sentence Transformer embedding model and deploy it with an Amazon SageMaker Endpoint. The code from this post and more examples are available in the GitHub repo.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-rag-accuracy-with-fine-tuned-embedding-models-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BRIA AI used distributed training in Amazon SageMaker to train latent diffusion foundation models for commercial use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Bar Fingerman from BRIA AI. This post explains how BRIA AI trained BRIA AI 2.0, a high-resolution (1024×1024) text-to-image diffusion model, on a dataset comprising petabytes of licensed images quickly and economically. Amazon SageMaker training jobs and Amazon SageMaker distributed training libraries took on the undifferentiated heavy lifting associated with infrastructure […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-bria-ai-used-distributed-training-in-amazon-sagemaker-to-train-latent-diffusion-foundation-models-for-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create custom images for geospatial analysis with Amazon SageMaker Distribution in Amazon SageMaker Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to extend Amazon SageMaker Distribution with additional dependencies to create a custom container image tailored for geospatial analysis. Although the example in this post focuses on geospatial data science, the methodology presented can be applied to any kind of custom image based on SageMaker Distribution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-custom-images-for-geospatial-analysis-with-amazon-sagemaker-distribution-in-amazon-sagemaker-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating model customization in Amazon Bedrock with AWS Step Functions workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models have become indispensable in generating intelligent and nuanced responses across a wide variety of business use cases. However, enterprises often have unique data and use cases that require customizing large language models beyond their out-of-the-box capabilities. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automating-model-customization-in-amazon-bedrock-with-aws-step-functions-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot Testing in .NET with Verify</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When writing tests, the ultimate goal should always be to deliver “value”. This value is not just about the number of tests written but about the quality and relevance of the tests. We aim to write, execute, and maintain valuable tests that instill confidence in our application’s ability to withstand the rigors of user production […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/11/snapshot-testing-in-net-with-verify/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an already-completed asynchronous activity in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generalizing to the four kinds of Windows Runtime asynchronous activities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240711-00/?p=109965 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Mode Now Available on NuGet.org</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 13:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We won’t keep you “in the dark” about this any longer… Dark Mode for NuGet.org is finally here! Your feedback has been invaluable in making this happen. We know that eye strain is a significant issue for many developers, and we’re excited to offer a solution.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/nuget/dark-mode-now-available-on-nuget-org 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Run Hugging Face Models Programmatically Using Ollama and Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how you can programmatically consume and run AI models from Hugging Face with Testcontainers and Ollama.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-run-hugging-face-models-programmatically-using-ollama-and-testcontainers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Emerging Data Job Trends in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 09:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog post by Thu Vu. The long-term outlook for data jobs – like data scientists, statisticians, and market research analysts – predicts explosive growth, much faster than most other fields. But here’s the catch: Despite the promising stats, data professionals are struggling to find jobs. AI is also shaking things up […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/11/5-emerging-data-job-trends-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2024.1 Release Candidate Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 08:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Release Candidate for MPS 2024.1 is now available for download. Grab it and experience the new functionality before the final 2024.1 release. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.1 RC You can learn about the new features in more detail in this blog post. The full list of fixed issues can be found here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/07/the-mps-2023-3-release-candidate-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Factory Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 04:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Abstract Factory design pattern is a creational pattern that handles object instantiations. It offers a framework to manage complex object creation scenarios and helps us achieve a more maintainable code structure. In this article, we’ll look into the Abstract Factory design pattern and how it helps us achieve modular and loosely coupled code. Let’s […] The post Abstract Factory Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock now supports advanced parsing, chunking, and query reformulation giving greater control of accuracy in RAG based applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that helps you implement the entire Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) workflow from ingestion to retrieval and prompt augmentation without having to build custom integrations to data sources and manage data flows, pushing the boundaries for what you can do in your RAG workflows. However, it’s […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-now-supports-advanced-parsing-chunking-and-query-reformulation-giving-greater-control-of-accuracy-in-rag-based-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Sourcing DXIL Validator Hash</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 21:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today the HLSL team is announcing plans to open source the DXIL validator hashing algorithm and include it in the DirectXShaderCompiler sources on GitHub. If you’re wondering what any of that means, strap in! DXIL Validator To understand the DXIL Validator you first need to understand a few basics of what DXIL is.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/open-sourcing-dxil-validator-hash 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline generative AI development in Amazon Bedrock with Prompt Management and Prompt Flows (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to introduce two powerful new features for Amazon Bedrock: Prompt Management and Prompt Flows, in public preview. These features are designed to accelerate the development, testing, and deployment of generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications, enabling developers and business users to create more efficient and effective solutions that are easier to maintain. You […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-generative-ai-development-in-amazon-bedrock-with-prompt-management-and-prompt-flows-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering everyone with GenAI to rapidly build, customize, and deploy apps securely: Highlights from the AWS New York Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine this—all employees relying on generative artificial intelligence (AI) to get their work done faster, every task becoming less mundane and more innovative, and every application providing a more useful, personal, and engaging experience. To realize this future, organizations need more than a single, powerful large language model (LLM) or chat assistant. They need a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/empowering-everyone-with-genai-to-rapidly-build-customize-and-deploy-apps-securely-highlights-from-the-aws-new-york-summit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A progress update on our commitment to safe, responsible generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Responsible AI is a longstanding commitment at Amazon. From the outset, we have prioritized responsible AI innovation by embedding safety, fairness, robustness, security, and privacy into our development processes and educating our employees. We strive to make our customers’ lives better while also establishing and implementing the necessary safeguards to help protect them. Our practical […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-progress-update-on-our-commitment-to-safe-responsible-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku in Amazon Bedrock to boost model accuracy and quality</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 15:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Frontier large language models (LLMs) like Anthropic Claude on Amazon Bedrock are trained on vast amounts of data, allowing Anthropic Claude to understand and generate human-like text. Fine-tuning Anthropic Claude 3 Haiku on proprietary datasets can provide optimal performance on specific domains or tasks. The fine-tuning as a deep level of customization represents a key […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-anthropics-claude-3-haiku-in-amazon-bedrock-to-boost-model-accuracy-and-quality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an already-completed asynchronous activity in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Making our function a coroutine.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240710-00/?p=109963 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try Full Line Code Completion in JetBrains Rider 2024.1.4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released the 2024.1 version of all our IDE products, including the dotUltimate family of products: ReSharper, Rider, dotMemory, dotTrace, dotCover, and dotPeek. Full Line Code Completion (FLCC), a local and fast AI model fine-tuned for product-specific programming languages, is one feature you may have heard of in this release. FLCC was released with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/10/full-line-code-completion-in-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Coverage in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 10:00:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post delves into the current .NET landscape when we aim to collect Code Coverage. We examine the most frequently used tools such as Coverlet, dotCover, and dotnet-coverage, among others. We discuss how to upload a Code Coverage report to a SaaS product like SonarQube. Lastly, we explain how to publish a Code Coverage report into an Azure Pipeline run or a GitHub Action.
Link to article: https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/code-coverage-in-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Microservices to Modular Monoliths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What do you do when you find yourself in microservice hell? How do you keep the gains you (hopefully) made in breaking up your legacy ball…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/from-microservices-to-modular-monoliths/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve up to ~2x higher throughput while reducing costs by up to ~50% for generative AI inference on Amazon SageMaker with the new inference optimization toolkit – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 21:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative artificial intelligence (AI) inference becomes increasingly critical for businesses, customers are seeking ways to scale their generative AI operations or integrate generative AI models into existing workflows. Model optimization has emerged as a crucial step, allowing organizations to balance cost-effectiveness and responsiveness, improving productivity. However, price-performance requirements vary widely across use cases. For […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-up-to-2x-higher-throughput-while-reducing-costs-by-up-to-50-for-generative-ai-inference-on-amazon-sagemaker-with-the-new-inference-optimization-toolkit-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve up to ~2x higher throughput while reducing costs by ~50% for generative AI inference on Amazon SageMaker with the new inference optimization toolkit – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 21:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, Amazon SageMaker announced a new inference optimization toolkit that helps you reduce the time it takes to optimize generative artificial intelligence (AI) models from months to hours, to achieve best-in-class performance for your use case. With this new capability, you can choose from a menu of optimization techniques, apply them to your generative AI […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-up-to-2x-higher-throughput-while-reducing-costs-by-50-for-generative-ai-inference-on-amazon-sagemaker-with-the-new-inference-optimization-toolkit-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet ranks number 1 for business and finance in S&amp;P AI Benchmarks by Kensho</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet currently ranks at the top of S&amp;amp;P AI Benchmarks by Kensho, which assesses large language models (LLMs) for finance and business. Kensho is the AI Innovation Hub for S&amp;amp;P Global. Using Amazon Bedrock, Kensho was able to quickly run Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet through a challenging suite of business and financial […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/anthropic-claude-3-5-sonnet-ranks-number-1-for-business-and-finance-in-sp-ai-benchmarks-by-kensho/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 RTW now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we released Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 RTW. This is our final release of Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 and will be the new supported version for the Azure DevOps Server 2022 server listing. You can directly install Azure DevOps Server 2022 Update 2 or upgrade from any version of Azure DevOps or TFS,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-server-2022-2-rtw-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 13: Explore the latest preview features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# 13 focuses on flexibility and performance, with top features like params collections for added flexibility, lock object for improved performance, and partial properties to support generators.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/csharp-13-explore-preview-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework July 2024 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for July 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-july-2024-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – July 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The July 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include a new tool for more performant environment discovery, improved support for reStructuredText docstrings, and community contributed Pixi support. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-july-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q2 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Flexible trial periods for paid plugins You can now customize trial periods for your paid plugins or simply disable them. Instead of the default 30-day trial, you can now set a shorter trial period or even none at all. Just select the preferred trial period while uploading your plugin to the Marketplace […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q2-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Column Selection DSL in Kotlin DataFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The Kotlin DataFrame library makes extracting values from structured data an easy task. As discussed in our documentation, there are four separate APIs that can be used for this purpose, with the optimal choice depending on your individual situation and requirements. To demonstrate, let’s read in a JSON document containing information about users: The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/07/enhanced-column-selection-dsl-in-kotlin-dataframe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an already-completed asynchonous activity in C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The simplest version.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240709-00/?p=109961 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip User Experience Survey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, DataGrip community! At JetBrains, delivering an excellent user experience is always a top priority. Today, we’re launching a survey to gather your feedback and explore how we can make DataGrip even better. Please take a few minutes to complete the DataGrip User Experience Survey. Your input will help us prioritize future improvements. As a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/07/09/datagrip-user-experience-survey/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in July</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This July, we’ve made some improvements to our courses to better serve your learning needs, added certificates for two more courses, and introduced new learning topics. Let’s take a closer look at these updates. Updated courses Our courses have been restructured to align with the latest job requirements. We’ve incorporated real interview questions and regularly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/09/jetbrains-academy-new-in-july/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding support for collection expressions to your own types: Behind the scenes of collection expressions - Part 5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this final post of the series I show how to add support for collection expressions to your own types that don&#39;t support them automatically
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/behind-the-scenes-of-collection-expressions-part-5-adding-support-for-collection-expressions-to-your-own-types/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open AI Whisper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 07:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Monu Bambroo explores Whisper, a speech to text model from OpenAI that you can use to transcribe audio files. The model is trained on a large dataset of English audio and text. The model is optimized for transcribing audio files that contain speech in English.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/open-ai-whisper 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Entity Framework Core Performance with Complex Types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 01:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, let’s explore what Complex Types are in Entity Framework Core and how we can use them to improve the performance of our .NET applications. Without further ado, let’s get started. What Are Complex Types in EF Core? To begin, let’s first understand what complex types are and why they were added to […] The post Improve Entity Framework Core Performance with Complex Types appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeding in-memory Entity Framework with realistic data with Bogus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You don’t need a physical database to experiment with ORMs. You can use an in-memory DB and seed the database with realistic data generated with Bogus.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/seed-inmemory-entityframework-bogus/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
