<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling Background Jobs With Quartz in .NET (advanced concepts)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2024/21_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2024/21_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Quartz.NET is a powerful job scheduling library, but integrating it properly with ASP.NET Core requires careful consideration. Here&#39;s what I learned about setting up Quartz.NET with proper observability, persistence, and job scheduling patterns.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/scheduling-background-jobs-with-quartz-in-dotnet-advanced-concepts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwrap some Semantic Kernel (Power)Toys this holiday season</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows PowerToys has always been one of my favorite productivity hacks, and its latest release adds Paste with Advanced AI, which takes it to a new level. This feature, powered by Semantic Kernel, transforms how you work with text, images, and data from your clipboard by applying AI-driven enhancements. What Does It Do? Advanced Paste uses […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/unwrap-some-semantic-kernel-powertoys-this-holiday-season 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IntelliJ Scala Plugin in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Year in Review Time flies. Only a year ago, we saw the release of Scala 3.4.0-RC1, and now we’re trying out Scala 3.6.2 with many new experimental features. The last 12 months have brought many new features to the IntelliJ Scala Plugin as well. A year ago we introduced X-Ray mode, which lets you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/12/20/the-intellij-scala-plugin-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe for Efficient Development: Simplify Collaboration and Security with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker empowers development teams to streamline collaboration, embed security, and accelerate delivery by simplifying workflows and providing tools like Docker Hub, Testcontainers Cloud, and Docker Scout for building high-quality, secure applications faster.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/recipe-for-efficient-development-simplify-collaboration-security-with-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>使用 Dependabot 管理 .NET SDK 更新</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自微软高级软件工程师 Jamie Magee 的Using Dependabot to Manage .NET SDK Updates 保持 .NET SDK 处于最新版本对维护安全高效的应用程序至关重要。现在，Dependabot 可以更新 global.json 中的 .NET SDK 版本，这使您可以比以往更轻松地确保自己的应用程序始终运行最新的安全补丁和改进。 定期的更新 SDK非常重要，因为它们包含： 已知漏洞（CVE）的安全补丁 错误修复和性能改进 最新的开发工具和功能 使用 global.json 管理 SDK 版本 要管理您的 .NET SDK 版本，您通常会在项目中使用 global.json 文件。此文件会指定项目应使用哪个版本的 SDK。以下是一个简单的 global.json 文件示例： { &amp;quot;sdk&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;9.0.100&amp;quot; } } 如果您正在使用 GitHub Actions以及 dotnet/setup-dotnet ，此文件将确保在您的 CI/CD 管道中使用了正确的 SDK 版本。 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8-dependabot-%e7%ae%a1%e7%90%86-net-sdk-%e6%9b%b4%e6%96%b0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack Year in Review for 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 01:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just for fun, here’s what I wrote as the My Technical Plans and Aspirations for 2024 detailing what I had hoped to accomplish this year. While there’s still just a handful of technical deliverables I’m trying to get out in this calendar year, I’m admittedly running on mental fumes rolling into the holiday season. Thinking back … Continue reading Critter Stack Year in Review for 2024 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Processing Meets AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ten years ago I wrote an article entitled Five Audio Processing Tasks that are a Lot Harder than you Think. It was borne out of my frustration that many users of my NAudio library had unrealistic expectations about what was achievable. But things have moved on a lot in a decade, and in particular the recent stunning advances in AI and machine learning have essentially solved many of these problems, and unlocked new possibilities I couldn&#39;t have imagined when I wrote that original post.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Expansion – “G3J Learn Semantic Kernel” Show – A Deep Dive in Korean!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 20:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Global Expansion – “G3J Learn Semantic Kernel” Show – A Deep Dive in Korean! Localization Increases Demand Following the success of this multi-language delivery, we quickly noticed a surge in demand for localized content. Developers from different parts of the world have expressed interest in diving deeper into Semantic Kernel, and we couldn’t be more […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/global-expansion-g3j-learn-semantic-kernel-show-a-deep-dive-in-korean 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a generative AI experience to your website or web application with Amazon Q embedded</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q embedded is a feature that lets you embed a hosted Amazon Q Business assistant on your website or application to create more personalized experiences that boost end-users’ productivity. In this post, we demonstrate how to use the Amazon Q embedded feature to add an Amazon Q Business assistant to your website or web application using basic HTML or React.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/add-a-generative-ai-experience-to-your-website-or-web-application-with-amazon-q-embedded/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to preparing your own dataset for LLM training</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we provide an introduction to preparing your own dataset for LLM training. Whether your goal is to fine-tune a pre-trained model for a specific task or to continue pre-training for domain-specific applications, having a well-curated dataset is crucial for achieving optimal performance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/an-introduction-to-preparing-your-own-dataset-for-llm-training/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design multi-agent orchestration with reasoning using Amazon Bedrock and open source frameworks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides step-by-step instructions for creating a collaborative multi-agent framework with reasoning capabilities to decouple business applications from FMs. It demonstrates how to combine Amazon Bedrock Agents with open source multi-agent frameworks, enabling collaborations and reasoning among agents to dynamically execute various tasks. The exercise will guide you through the process of building a reasoning orchestration system using Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Bedrock Agents, and FMs. We also explore the integration of Amazon Bedrock Agents with open source orchestration frameworks LangGraph and CrewAI for dispatching and reasoning.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside STL: The atomic shared_ptr</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There&#39;s a lock hiding inside the pointer.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241219-00/?p=110663 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Trust into Your Software with Verified Components</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker Hub and Docker Scout can help development teams ensure a more secure and compliant software supply chain.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-trust-into-your-software-with-verified-components/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2025.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.1, which we’ll introduce early next year. After reading through your valuable feedback and feature requests, and taking into account our own strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following areas for development: 🚀 The CLion Nova language engine 🛠️ The debugger 🤖 Embedded development 🏗️ Project formats and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/12/2025-1-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Fleet’s New Islands UI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We envisioned Fleet as a coding tool with a clear minimalist design that doesn’t overwhelm and helps keep you focused. Today we’re introducing a new, bolder look for Fleet. We believe that this new direction in Fleet’s UI will help make your developer experience more cohesive, intuitive, and, of course, productive. New islands layout The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/12/introducing-fleets-new-islands-ui/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.44 Is Here With New UI, Zig Language Support, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.44 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about Fleet […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/12/fleet-1-44-is-here-with-new-ui-zig-language-support-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot Free is here in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 18:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you haven’t already heard, GitHub just announced Copilot Free! And great news: you can already start using Copilot Free right now in Visual Studio. It’s available now, and we’re putting the finishing touches on a more streamlined experience in January. We’re excited to bring these benefits to the entire Visual Studio family. With Copilot […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/github-copilot-free-is-here-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.37: AI Catalog and Command-Line Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 17:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.37 streamlines AI-driven development with the new AI Catalog integration, command-line management capabilities, upgraded components, and enhanced stability to empower modern developers.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-37/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortlessly access cloud resources across Azure tenants without using secrets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 17:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the Public Preview of Managed Identities as Federated Identity Credentials for Microsoft Entra. Enhance security by removing secrets, simplify setup, and enable seamless cross-tenant access to Entra-protected resources like Azure and Microsoft Graph.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/access-cloud-resources-across-tenants-without-secrets 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Fastweb fine-tuned the Mistral model using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod as a first step to build an Italian large language model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fastweb, one of Italy’s leading telecommunications operators, recognized the immense potential of AI technologies early on and began investing in this area in 2019. In this post, we explore how Fastweb used cutting-edge AI and ML services to embark on their LLM journey, overcoming challenges and unlocking new opportunities along the way.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-fastweb-fine-tuned-the-mistral-model-using-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-as-a-first-step-to-build-an-italian-large-language-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using natural language in Amazon Q Business: From searching and creating ServiceNow incidents and knowledge articles to generating insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we’ll demonstrate how to configure an Amazon Q Business application and add a custom plugin that gives users the ability to use a natural language interface provided by Amazon Q Business to query real-time data and take actions in ServiceNow.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-natural-language-in-amazon-q-business-from-searching-and-creating-servicenow-incidents-and-knowledge-articles-to-generating-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a way to split the git history of a file or combine the histories of two files without a merge commit?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Studying how git recovers history.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241218-00/?p=110655 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Docker Builds Using AWS CodeBuild and Docker Build Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 13:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how integrating Docker Build Cloud into a CI/CD pipeline using AWS CodeBuild can dramatically reduce build times and improve release frequency.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/accelerate-your-docker-builds-using-aws-codebuild-and-docker-build-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Ambient Context Pattern in .NET: From Theory to Production</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 09:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntroductionIn our previous exploration of execution context in .NET Core, we delved into the intricacies of AsyncLocal and ThreadLocal.Execution Context Management with AsyncLocal and ThreadLocal in .NET CoreIntroduction In modern distributed .NET applications, managing context across execution boundaries is a critical architectural concern. While both AsyncLocal&amp;lt;
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/understanding-ambient-context-pattern-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Conf 2024 Recap – Celebrating .NET 9, AI, Community, &amp; More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Conf 2024 is over, but you can catch up with all the announcement and fun with video recordings, slides, demos, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-conf-2024-recap 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify multimodal generative AI with Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Data Automation in public preview, offers a unified experience for developers of all skillsets to easily automate the extraction, transformation, and generation of relevant insights from documents, images, audio, and videos to build generative AI–powered applications. In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock Data Automation in the AWS Management Console and the AWS SDK for Python (Boto3) for media analysis and intelligent document processing (IDP) workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How TUI uses Amazon Bedrock to scale content creation and enhance hotel descriptions in under 10 seconds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 16:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TUI Group is one of the world’s leading global tourism services, providing 21 million customers with an unmatched holiday experience in 180 regions. The TUI content teams are tasked with producing high-quality content for its websites, including product details, hotel information, and travel guides, often using descriptions written by hotel and third-party partners. In this post, we discuss how we used Amazon SageMaker and Amazon Bedrock to build a content generator that rewrites marketing content following specific brand and style guidelines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding models and dimensions: optimizing the performance to resource-usage ratio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 16:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since the release of vector preview, we’ve been working with many customers that are building AI solution on Azure SQL and SQL Server and one of the most common questions is how to support high-dimensional data, for example more than 2000 dimensions per vector. In fact, at the moment, the vector type supports “only” up […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/embedding-models-and-dimensions-optimizing-the-performance-resource-usage-ratio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing klibs.io: A New Way to Discover Kotlin Multiplatform Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin Multiplatform is growing rapidly, with its ecosystem expanding and the number of libraries increasing by 35% in 2024 alone. However, with more libraries available than ever, finding the right one for your use case and target platforms can still be a challenge. Whether you’re looking for a solution to handle permissions on iOS and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/introducing-klibs-io-a-new-way-to-discover-kotlin-multiplatform-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak terms that didn’t take hold: airspace, synthetics, and AOI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sometimes they don&#39;t stick.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241217-00/?p=110647 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Inspires Learners, IDEs Drive Them: Computer Science Education Trends 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Computer science education and literacy are skyrocketing in demand worldwide. To understand the latest trends, challenges, and motivations driving learners, as well as other factors shaping the field, we conducted the 2024 Computer Science Learning Curve Survey. More than 23,991 learners from 16 countries and seven broader regions completed our detailed questionnaire – equivalent to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/17/computer-science-education-trends-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker 2024 Highlights: Innovations in AI, Security, and Empowering Development Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We look at Docker’s 2024 milestones and innovations in security, AI, and more, as well as how we helped teams build, test, and deploy more easily and quickly than ever.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-2024-highlights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refresh your Find results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of having to repeatedly launch the Find window in Visual Studio to update your search results? Whether you’ve just refactored some code or pulled recent changes, having to redo a search to get updated results is no longer necessary. With the new refresh option, you can now update your Find results without […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/refresh-your-find-results 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building LaTeX projects on Windows easily with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how I build LaTeX projects on a Windows machine by using Docker and the blang/latex image
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/building-latex-projects-on-windows-easily-with-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create custom controls in .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:29:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET MAUI is a powerful cross-platform mobile app framework by Microsoft. It is a reliable feature-enriched option for developers of all types of mobile applications. Its community toolkit, XAML-based designing, and modern C# coding support stand out from MAUI among its competitors. One key feature it provides is the creation
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/how-to-create-custom-controls-in-net-maui/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Llama 3.3 70B now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the Llama 3.3 70B from Meta is available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. Llama 3.3 70B marks an exciting advancement in large language model (LLM) development, offering comparable performance to larger Llama versions with fewer computational resources. In this post, we explore how to deploy this model efficiently on Amazon SageMaker AI, using advanced SageMaker AI features for optimal performance and cost management.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Framework Migration to .NET9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have a large .NET Framework codebase that you want to migrate to .NET8 or beyond? Here’s some tips of my .NET Framework migration and things to consider. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in this post. Introduction to the Migration Journey My… Read More ».NET Framework Migration to .NET9 The post .NET Framework Migration to .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SQL ❤️ Python!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I recently presented at Python Day 2024 on Langchain integration. I created a slide deck that I believe can be useful beyond just the session, so I wanted to share it here for everyone’s benefit. The deck covers the most common topics for a Python developer: Is there a free version of SQL Server or […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/azure-sql-loves-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Microsoft Secure Future Initiative is Safeguarding Our Digital Tomorrow and Here’s Why it Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a world where cyber threats are evolving faster than ever, the need for robust, proactive, and future-focused security measures has never been greater. Enter the Microsoft’s Secure Future Initiative (SFI), a bold multiyear commitment designed to prioritize security across all aspects of the company’s ecosystem. Since its launch in late 2023, the initiative has […] The article How the Microsoft Secure Future Initiative is Safeguarding Our Digital Tomorrow and Here’s Why it Matters was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData with Qdrant and Azure AI Search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how to use Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData to implement semantic search using Qdrant and Azure AI Search
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/vector-data-qdrant-ai-search-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS re:Invent 2024 Highlights: Top takeaways from Swami Sivasubramanian to help customers manage generative AI at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We spoke with Dr. Swami Sivasubramanian, Vice President of Data and AI, shortly after AWS re:Invent 2024 to hear his impressions—and to get insights on how the latest AWS innovations help meet the real-world needs of customers as they build and scale transformative generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-top-takeaways-from-swami-sivasubramanian-to-help-customers-manage-generative-ai-at-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do we have header files &lt;pshpackN.h&gt; and &lt;poppack.h&gt; instead of just issuing the pragma directly?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Because the pragma may not work everywhere.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241216-00/?p=110645 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-tenant RAG with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are continuously seeking ways to use their proprietary knowledge and domain expertise to gain a competitive edge. With the advent of foundation models (FMs) and their remarkable natural language processing capabilities, a new opportunity has emerged to unlock the value of their data assets. As organizations strive to deliver personalized experiences to customers using […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multi-tenant-rag-with-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Use an AI Git Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We show how to create Git agent and use this Git agent to understand PR branches for a variety of user personas — without needing to know the ins and outs of Git.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-create-and-use-an-ai-git-agent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AI Assistants Can Decode GitHub Repos for UI Writers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Exploring AI-assisted tools for UI writers, we demonstrate how to enhance GitHub PR review workflows to identify user-facing text changes, and offer a step-by-step guide and insights into leveraging LLMs effectively.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-for-ui-writers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create internal GitHub repos for your team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 now includes support for creating internal repositories for GitHub organizations. This feature allows developers to work within their GitHub organization’s guidelines within the Visual Studio environment more effectively. Managing repositories involves configuring varying levels of visibility and permissions. Visual Studio 2022’s new feature aims to smooth this process by providing support for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/create-internal-github-repos-for-your-team 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Reasons You Should Use dbt Core in PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dbt Core is a modern data transformation framework. It doesn’t extract or load data and is only responsible for the T in the ELT (extract-load-transform) process. dbt connects to your data warehouse and helps you prepare your data so it can later be used to answer business questions. In this blog post, we’ll talk about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/dbt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating SBOM for NuGet packages</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) is a list of components in a piece of software. It is a critical part of the software supply chain, as it helps to identify and track the components used in a software project. In this post, I describe how to easily generate a Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) for NuGet packages. To generate an SBOM for NuGet packages, you can use the Microsoft.Sbom.Targets package.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming Language into Code: Building and Evaluating a Robotic Code Generation Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post explores the development and evaluation of an AI assistant that converts natural language into robotic code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/code-generation-evaluation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Rebus, NServiceBus, and MassTransit in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Messaging systems are the backbone of scalable and distributed applications in .NET. They allow different parts of an application, or even separate applications, to communicate efficiently and reliably. Choosing the right messaging library, Rebus, NServiceBus, or MassTransit, is essential to ensure our system’s performance and long-term maintainability. In this article, we will compare Rebus, NServiceBus, […] The post Comparison of Rebus, NServiceBus, and MassTransit in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Maximize Your .NET Performance with Spargine’s FastLogger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2024/15_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2024/15_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages, developed since .NET 2, featuring the FastLogger class for efficient logging. FastLogger significantly enhances logging speed (11x faster) while offering various logging methods.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/12/15/boost-your-net-projects-maximize-your-net-performance-with-spargines-fastlogger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid Using C# Events in ASP.NET Core Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2024/15_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2024/15_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is part of the C# Advent Calendar 2024 - check out all of the C# articles from this year! C# events are a powerful feature of the…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/avoid-using-csharp-events-in-aspnetcore-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal vs. Public APIs in Modular Monoliths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2024/14_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2024/14_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every article about modular monoliths tells you to use public APIs between modules, but they rarely explain why these APIs exist or how to design them properly. After building several large-scale modular monoliths, I&#39;ve learned that public APIs are not just about clean code - they&#39;re about controlling chaos.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/internal-vs-public-apis-in-modular-monoliths 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
