<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 21:25:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>So how many replicas should my VM Application use?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 21:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One great advantage of VM Applications is the ability to specify how many replicas you want for each VM Application version. While documentation exists on how to specify replicas, we don’t really provide advice on determining how many replicas to use. The goal of this post is to rectify that gap. First, the basics. When […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/so-how-many-replicas-should-my-vm-application-use 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (November 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 21:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure SDKs release every month. This post includes the month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-november-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently train models with large sequence lengths using Amazon SageMaker model parallel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 20:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how the Amazon SageMaker model parallel library (SMP) addresses this need through support for new features such as 8-bit floating point (FP8) mixed-precision training for accelerated training performance and context parallelism for processing large input sequence lengths, expanding the list of its existing features.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/efficiently-train-models-with-large-sequence-lengths-using-amazon-sagemaker-model-parallel/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Amazon Bedrock Agents custom orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 20:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock Agents simplify the orchestration of generative AI workflows, particularly with the introduction of the custom orchestrator feature. You can use the custom orchestrator to fine-tune and optimize agentic workflows that align more closely with specific business and operational needs. We outline the feature’s key benefits, including full control over orchestration, real-time adjustments, and reusability, followed by a breakdown of how it manages state transitions and contract-based interactions between Amazon Bedrock Agents and AWS Lambda.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Bedrock Agents for code scanning, optimization, and remediation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 19:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For enterprises in the realm of cloud computing and software development, providing secure code repositories is essential. As sophisticated cybersecurity threats become more prevalent, organizations must adopt proactive measures to protect their assets. Amazon Bedrock offers a powerful solution by automating the process of scanning repositories for vulnerabilities and remediating them. This post explores how you can use Amazon Bedrock to enhance the security of your repositories and maintain compliance with organizational and regulatory standards.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recordings from JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024 Are Now Live</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 19:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 7, 2024, we hosted our first-ever JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf, an exciting online event dedicated to plugin development for JetBrains products. We’d like to extend a huge thank you to everyone who joined us and made this event such a success! For those who couldn’t be there or who want to revisit their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/11/recordings-from-jetbrains-plugin-developer-conf-2024-are-now-live/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.43 Is Here With Improved Branches Menu, Context Retrieval and Slash Commands in AI Chat, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.43 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/11/fleet-1-43-is-here-with-improved-branches-menu-context-retrieval-and-slash-commands-in-ai-chat-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.1.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.1.0 release is out! This version introduces new language features, tooling updates, performance improvements, and important fixes. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.1.0 or the release notes on GitHub. Join the Kotlin 2.1.0 Livestream Do you want to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/kotlin-2-1-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dramatically faster package restores with .NET 9’s new NuGet resolver</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 9 introduces a new NuGet dependency graph resolver that dramatically improves package restore performance for large repositories. Learn how this reimagined approach reduces restore times from 30 minutes to just 2 minutes by creating a more efficient dependency graph with fewer nodes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-nuget-resolver 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking whether a URI refers to a Web site root</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let somebody else do the parsing.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241127-00/?p=110582 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code update – November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code v5.10.1 and the latest prerelease update. This patch brings impactful new features, enhancements, and critical bug fixes to improve your development experience. Let’s dive into what’s new. Teams Toolkit v5.10.1 This patch version updates included several important bug fixes: Terminology Update: The term Copilot Agent has […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/teams-toolkit-for-visual-studio-code-update-november-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a generative AI assistant with Slack and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Seamless integration of customer experience, collaboration tools, and relevant data is the foundation for delivering knowledge-based productivity gains. In this post, we show you how to integrate the popular Slack messaging service with AWS generative AI services to build a natural language assistant where business users can ask questions of an unstructured dataset.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-generative-ai-assistant-with-slack-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.5 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 13:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 – 2024.2.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/intellij-idea-2024-2-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates for C&#43;&#43; developers in Visual Studio 2022 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 17.12 is here and comes with a host of new features for C++ developers. We’ve made improvements across our toolchain, C++ Build Insights, Unreal Engine support, and more. This post gives a quick overview of what’s available; for all the details, see What’s New for C++ Developers in Visual Studio 2022 17.12 on […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/updates-for-c-developers-in-visual-studio-2022-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discontinuation of the SpaceCode Private Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 09:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dear customers, Today we are announcing the discontinuation of the SpaceCode Private Preview, which we launched in May 2024. On May 27, 2024, we announced that we had decided to discontinue Space and pivot it to a new product: SpaceCode. The plan was for SpaceCode to focus primarily on Git hosting and code reviews. For […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/space/2024/11/27/discontinuation-of-the-spacecode-private-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleash your Salesforce data using the Amazon Q Salesforce Online connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 23:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through configuring and setting up the Amazon Q Salesforce Online connector. Thousands of companies worldwide use Salesforce to manage their sales, marketing, customer service, and other business operations. The Salesforce cloud-based platform centralizes customer information and interactions across the organization, providing sales reps, marketers, and support agents with a unified 360-degree view of each customer. With Salesforce at the heart of their business, companies accumulate vast amounts of customer data within the platform over time.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing hallucinations in large language models with custom intervention using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Knowledge Bases, and the RAGAS evaluation metrics to build a custom hallucination detector and remediate it by using human-in-the-loop. The agentic workflow can be extended to custom use cases through different hallucination remediation techniques and offers the flexibility to detect and mitigate hallucinations using custom actions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/reducing-hallucinations-in-large-language-models-with-custom-intervention-using-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Meta Llama 3.1-8B on AWS Inferentia using Amazon EKS and vLLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through the steps to deploy the Meta Llama 3.1-8B model on Inferentia 2 instances using Amazon EKS. This solution combines the exceptional performance and cost-effectiveness of Inferentia 2 chips with the robust and flexible landscape of Amazon EKS. Inferentia 2 chips deliver high throughput and low latency inference, ideal for LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-meta-llama-3-1-8b-on-aws-inferentia-using-amazon-eks-and-vllm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving LLMs using vLLM and Amazon EC2 instances with AWS AI chips</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The use of large language models (LLMs) and generative AI has exploded over the last year. With the release of powerful publicly available foundation models, tools for training, fine tuning and hosting your own LLM have also become democratized. Using vLLM on AWS Trainium and Inferentia makes it possible to host LLMs for high performance […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/serving-llms-using-vllm-and-amazon-ec2-instances-with-aws-ai-chips/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate the quality of your AI applications with ease</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started with the new Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Evaluation library to kickstart your Intelligent Application eveluation journey.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/evaluate-the-quality-of-your-ai-applications-with-ease 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using LLMs to fortify cyber defenses: Sophos’s insight on strategies for using LLMs with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 18:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, SophosAI shares insights in using and evaluating an out-of-the-box LLM for the enhancement of a security operations center’s (SOC) productivity using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker. We use Anthropic’s Claude 3 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock to illustrate the use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-llms-to-fortify-cyber-defenses-sophoss-insight-on-strategies-for-using-llms-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in Azure DevTest Labs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 18:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DevTest labs now supports the capability to access Azure DevOps artifact repos through Managed Identities and GitHub artifact repos through GitHub app authentication. Additionally, you can now also access the lab storage account through Managed Identities. Until now users have accessed Artifact repos via personal access tokens (PATs) and storage accounts through Storage Access Shared […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/whats-new-in-azure-devtest-labs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced observability for AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia with Datadog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks you through Datadog’s new integration with AWS Neuron, which helps you monitor your AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia instances by providing deep observability into resource utilization, model execution performance, latency, and real-time infrastructure health, enabling you to optimize machine learning (ML) workloads and achieve high-performance at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhanced-observability-for-aws-trainium-and-aws-inferentia-with-datadog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a virtual stock technical analyst using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            n this post, we create a virtual analyst that can answer natural language queries of stocks matching certain technical indicator criteria using Amazon Bedrock Agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-virtual-stock-technical-analyst-using-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply Amazon SageMaker Studio lifecycle configurations using AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post serves as a step-by-step guide on how to set up lifecycle configurations for your Amazon SageMaker Studio domains. With lifecycle configurations, system administrators can apply automated controls to their SageMaker Studio domains and their users. We cover core concepts of SageMaker Studio and provide code examples of how to apply lifecycle configuration to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/apply-amazon-sagemaker-studio-lifecycle-configurations-using-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a read-through semantic cache with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a strategy for optimizing LLM-based applications. Given the increasing need for efficient and cost-effective AI solutions, we present a serverless read-through caching blueprint that uses repeated data patterns. With this cache, developers can effectively save and access similar prompts, thereby enhancing their systems’ efficiency and response times.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-read-through-semantic-cache-with-amazon-opensearch-serverless-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rad AI reduces real-time inference latency by 50% using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 16:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Ken Kao and Hasan Ali Demirci from Rad AI. Rad AI has reshaped radiology reporting, developing solutions that streamline the most tedious and repetitive tasks, and saving radiologists’ time. Since 2018, using state-of-the-art proprietary and open source large language models (LLMs), our flagship product—Rad AI Impressions— has significantly reduced the […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/rad-ai-reduces-real-time-inference-latency-by-50-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read graphs, diagrams, tables, and scanned pages using multimodal prompts in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 16:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use models on Amazon Bedrock to retrieve information from images, tables, and scanned documents. We provide the following examples: 1/ performing object classification and object detection tasks, 2/ reading and querying graphs, and 3/ reading flowcharts and architecture diagrams (such as an AWS architecture diagram) and converting it to text.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/read-graphs-diagrams-tables-and-scanned-pages-using-multimodal-prompts-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugger and Diagnostics updates in Visual Studio 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 16:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce a host of exciting new features in Visual Studio 17.12, designed to enhance your development experience and boost your productivity. Our team has been working diligently to address some of the most popular requests from our developer community, and we are confident that these updates will significantly improve your workflow. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/debugger-and-diagnostics-updates-in-visual-studio-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Crexi achieved ML models deployment on AWS at scale and boosted efficiency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 16:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Commercial Real Estate Exchange, Inc. (Crexi), is a digital marketplace and platform designed to streamline commercial real estate transactions. In this post, we will review how Crexi achieved its business needs and developed a versatile and powerful framework for AI/ML pipeline creation and deployment. This customizable and scalable solution allows its ML models to be efficiently deployed and managed to meet diverse project requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-crexi-achieved-ml-models-deployment-on-aws-at-scale-and-boosted-efficiency/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: Real estate and Airspace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Space on the screen and negotiating control over it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241126-00/?p=110575 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Roundup: Kodee’s Top Picks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone! Time flies, doesn’t it? It’s already my second edition of Kotlin Roundup, and I can’t wait to share the latest from the Kotlin ecosystem. Did you know that the JetBrains team regularly publishes a newsletter featuring major Kotlin ecosystem news? Sign up to stay up to date with all things Kotlin.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/kotlin-roundup-kodee-s-top-picks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Calisthenics #5: Other points of views</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You&#39;ve seen two implementations of calisthenics objects that differed in many ways, both in the way they applied the rules and in the solutions they proposed to meet the rules discussed in this article:Object Calisthenics #1: Elevating Code Quality with 9 Powerful RulesDiscover how Object Calisthenics
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/object-calisthenics-5-other-points-of-views/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Origin-Resource-Policy: preventing hotlinking and XSSI attacks: Understanding cross-origin security headers - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how to use the Cross-Origin-Resource-Policy to block cross-origin requests that would normally be allowed, such as in tags
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/understanding-security-headers-part-2-cross-origin-resource-policy-preventing-hotlinking/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing .NET Security: A Guide to Secure Password Hashing with Spargine’s SHA256PasswordHasher</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a collection of open-source .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages created for effective password hashing. The SHA256PasswordHasher class uses SHA-256 with unique salts to provide secure password management in applications. It includes methods for hashing and verifying passwords, promoting robust security practices in .NET development.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/26/enhancing-net-security-a-guide-to-secure-password-hashing-with-spargines-sha256passwordhasher/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 13 Features: What&amp;#x27;s New and How to Use It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 07:32:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# has always been one of the most popular programming languages among developers. It continuously evolves to meet timed features and trends. Its robustness and flexibility make it an all-purpose language and ideal for domains like desktop applications, enterprise systems, web development, games, and cross-platform and native mobile applications. With
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/c-13-features-whats-new-and-how-to-use-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Meta Llama 3.1 models cost-effectively in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart with AWS Inferentia and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the availability of Meta Llama 3.1 8B and 70B inference support on AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia instances in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. Trainium and Inferentia, enabled by the AWS Neuron software development kit (SDK), offer high performance and lower the cost of deploying Meta Llama 3.1 by up to 50%. In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy Meta Llama 3.1 on Trainium and Inferentia instances in SageMaker JumpStart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS achieves ISO/IEC 42001:2023 Artificial Intelligence Management System accredited certification</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to be the first major cloud service provider to announce ISO/IEC 42001 accredited certification for the following AI services: Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Q Business, Amazon Textract, and Amazon Transcribe. ISO/IEC 42001 is an international management system standard that outlines requirements and controls for organizations to promote the responsible development and use of AI systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-achieves-iso-iec-420012023-artificial-intelligence-management-system-accredited-certification/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve Advent of Code 2024 Puzzles in Kotlin and Win Prizes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DRAdvent of Code is the perfect opportunity to level up your Kotlin skills, whether you are a beginner or looking to finally tackle that advanced Kotlin feature you’ve been curious about. Here’s what’s in store: So join in, solve some Advent of Code puzzles, and enjoy the holiday coding spirit with Kotlin! About Advent of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/advent-of-code-2024-in-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAPI document generation in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the New OpenAPI Document Generation Feature in .NET 9. Let&#39;s take a look at what it is, how to use it, and how it streamlines API development in .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet9-openapi 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Semantic Kernel Office Hours Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Semantic Kernel Office Hours Update Over the upcoming Holidays period there are several office hours sessions that we’ll be cancelling. Below is an updated view of our upcoming office hours availability. We will resume with regularly scheduled Office Hours on January 8th for our weekly and monthly sessions. Office Hours Session Date and Time […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/microsoft-semantic-kernel-office-hours-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of Memory: Announcing General Availability of Semantic Kernel’s Memory Packages</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the General Availability (GA) of our Memory packages for .NET, Java, and Python! The Semantic Kernel team and our partners have been working hard to allow you to quickly connect to vector stores and make it easy for you to do embeddings and data retrieval between stores. Transforming Data Management […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/unlocking-the-power-of-memory-announcing-general-availability-of-semantic-kernels-memory-packages 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How 123RF saved over 90% of their translation costs by switching to Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how 123RF used Amazon Bedrock, Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku, and a vector store to efficiently translate content metadata, significantly reduce costs, and improve their global content discovery capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-123rf-saved-over-90-of-their-translation-costs-by-switching-to-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect SharePoint Online to Amazon Q Business using OAuth 2.0 ROPC flow authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to integrate Amazon Q Business with SharePoint Online using the OAuth 2.0 ROPC flow authentication method. We provide both manual and automated approaches using PowerShell scripts for configuring the required Azure AD settings. Additionally, we demonstrate how to enter those details along with your SharePoint authentication credentials into the Amazon Q console to finalize the secure connection.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/connect-sharepoint-online-to-amazon-q-business-using-oauth-2-0-ropc-flow-authentication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Snow Labs Medical LLMs are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that John Snow Labs’ Medical LLM – Small and Medical LLM – Medium large language models (LLMs) are now available on Amazon SageMaker Jumpstart. For medical doctors, this tool provides a rapid understanding of a patient’s medical journey, aiding in timely and informed decision-making from extensive documentation. This summarization capability not only boosts efficiency but also makes sure that no critical details are overlooked, thereby supporting optimal patient care and enhancing healthcare outcomes.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying error messages just got easier</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever been frustrated by the tedious process of copying error descriptions from the Error List? Previously with Visual Studio, copying an error would include all column headers and row values, which isn’t always what you want. If you were planning to search for the error online, it was a hassle to clean up […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/copying-error-messages-just-got-easier 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I know when a window has processed a message that I posted to it?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Best would be to have it tell you.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241125-00/?p=110568 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Container Security with Docker Scout and Secure Repositories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 14:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Docker Scout integrates with secure container repositories to ensure vulnerability-free and compliant images in highly secure environments.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/enhancing-container-security-with-docker-scout-and-secure-repositories/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build ChatGPT-like enterprise search on your own data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you find yourself drowning in company documentation, spending hours searching through SharePoint, knowledge bases, and contract repositories for one specific piece of information? You’re not alone. Organizations now have plenty of information – the challenge lies in finding the right information when you need it. We have built a packaged GitHub template that helps […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-build-chatgpt-like-enterprise-search-on-your-own-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of Intelligent, Multi-Agent AI Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Intelligent multi-agent AI systems stand out as a robust solution for solving problems requiring modularity, scalability, and specialized expertise. The rapid evolution of artificial intelligence has brought about the innovative approach of designing multi-agent AI systems that can tackle complex, dynamic, and distributed tasks. These systems rely on multiple AI agents collaborating to achieve goals […] The article Design of Intelligent, Multi-Agent AI Systems was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimistic Locking vs Pessimistic Locking in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 05:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since the invention of database systems, they have become the primary source of truth for almost every web application’s data. As user demands grow, applications scale, and so does the concurrency within the system. Ensuring data integrity and consistency along with effective locking mechanisms, becomes a major concern when multiple users attempt to access and […] The post Optimistic Locking vs Pessimistic Locking in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Fabric vs Azure Service Fabric: Understanding the Differences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2024/24_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 21:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2024/24_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Fabric and Azure Service Fabric share the term &amp;quot;Fabric&amp;quot; but serve different purposes. Microsoft Fabric is a unified data platform for analytics and integration, while Azure Service Fabric focuses on managing scalable microservices applications. Despite the shared name, they cater to distinct audiences and functionalities within the Microsoft ecosystem. The article Microsoft Fabric vs Azure Service Fabric: Understanding the Differences was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Object Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2024/24_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2024/24_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source collection of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, maintained since .NET 2. It includes the ObjectExtensions class, offering utility methods for object manipulation, performance optimization, and memory management.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/24/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-object-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (November 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2024/23_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 19:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2024/23_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.11.16 registry release, 2024-11-12 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout November. This release includes a command line option to force vcpkg to use classic mode even if a manifest file is found along with bug fixes. Some […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-november-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Async APIs in ASP.NET Core - The Right Way</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2024/23_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2024/23_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not every API request needs to finish right away. Learn how to build better APIs by moving long-running tasks to the background. This guide shows practical examples using image processing in ASP.NET Core 9.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/building-async-apis-in-aspnetcore-the-right-way 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Mixtral MoE fine-tuning on Amazon SageMaker with QLoRA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 22:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can address the challenges of model customization being complex, time-consuming, and often expensive by using fully managed environment with Amazon SageMaker Training jobs to fine-tune the Mixtral 8x7B model using PyTorch Fully Sharded Data Parallel (FSDP) and Quantized Low Rank Adaptation (QLoRA).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-mixtral-moe-fine-tuning-on-amazon-sagemaker-with-qlora/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker Inference now supports G6e instances</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            G6e instances on SageMaker unlock the ability to deploy a wide variety of open source models cost-effectively. With superior memory capacity, enhanced performance, and cost-effectiveness, these instances represent a compelling solution for organizations looking to deploy and scale their AI applications. The ability to handle larger models, support longer context lengths, and maintain high throughput makes G6e instances particularly valuable for modern AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-inference-now-supports-g6e-instances/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestrate generative AI workflows with Amazon Bedrock and AWS Step Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses how to use AWS Step Functions to efficiently coordinate multi-step generative AI workflows, such as parallelizing API calls to Amazon Bedrock to quickly gather answers to lists of submitted questions. We also touch on the usage of Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to optimize outputs and provide an extra layer of precision, as well as other possible integrations through Step Functions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/orchestrate-generative-ai-workflows-with-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-step-functions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications on Amazon Bedrock with the AWS SDK for Python (Boto3)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock with the AWS SDK for Python (Boto3) to programmatically incorporate FMs. We explore invoking a specific FM and processing the generated text, showcasing the potential for developers to use these models in their applications for a variety of use cases
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-on-amazon-bedrock-with-the-aws-sdk-for-python-boto3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve factual consistency with LLM Debates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the potential of large language model (LLM) debates using a supervised dataset with ground truth. In this post, we navigate the LLM debating technique with persuasive LLMs having two expert debater LLMs (Anthropic Claude 3 Sonnet and Mixtral 8X7B) and one judge LLM (Mistral 7B v2 to measure, compare, and contrast its performance against other techniques like self-consistency (with naive and expert judges) and LLM consultancy.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governing the ML lifecycle at scale, Part 3: Setting up data governance at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post dives deep into how to set up data governance at scale using Amazon DataZone for the data mesh. The data mesh is a modern approach to data management that decentralizes data ownership and treats data as a product. It enables different business units within an organization to create, share, and govern their own data assets, promoting self-service analytics and reducing the time required to convert data experiments into production-ready applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we excited to announce the availability of TypeScript 5.7! If you’re not familiar with TypeScript, it’s a language that builds on JavaScript by adding syntax for type declarations and annotations. This syntax can be used by the TypeScript compiler to type-check our code, and it can also be erased to emit clean, idiomatic JavaScript […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-7 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Flows is now generally available with enhanced safety and traceability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Flows (previously known as Prompt Flows). With Bedrock Flows, you can quickly build and execute complex generative AI workflows without writing code. Bedrock Flows makes it easier for developers and businesses to harness the power of generative AI, enabling you to create more sophisticated and efficient AI-driven solutions for your customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-flows-is-now-generally-available-with-enhanced-safety-and-traceability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement secure API access to your Amazon Q Business applications with IAM federation user access management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business provides a rich set of APIs to perform administrative tasks and to build an AI assistant with customized user experience for your enterprise. In this post, we show how to use Amazon Q Business APIs when using AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) federation for user access management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-secure-api-access-to-your-amazon-q-business-applications-with-iam-federation-user-access-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.36: New Enterprise Administration Features, WSL 2, and ECI Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 16:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about new features in Docker Desktop 4.36, including Desktop Settings Management and improvements to Enhanced Container Isolation and WSL 2.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-36/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In C&#43;&#43;, how can I make a default parameter be the this pointer of the caller?, revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Expanding on the previous pattern.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241122-00/?p=110560 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant Integrates Google Gemini and Local LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve now added Gemini 1.5 Pro and Gemini 1.5 Flash to the lineup of LLMs used by JetBrains AI Assistant. These LLMs join forces with OpenAI models and local models. What’s special about Google models? Gemini 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash on Google Cloud’s Vertex AI will deliver advanced reasoning and impressive performance, unlocking several […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/11/jetbrains-ai-assistant-integrates-google-gemini-and-local-llms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 GitHub Copilot Features in Visual Studio from Microsoft Ignite 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At this year’s Microsoft Ignite, it was truly exciting to see Scott, Dalia, and Jessie demo some of the most innovative features of GitHub Copilot that are transforming the developer experience in Visual Studio. From the breakout session, we highlighted five standout features that are pushing productivity to the next level. Whether you’re working on […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/top-5-github-copilot-features-in-visual-studio-from-microsoft-ignite-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Intelligent Application Templates in the Azure AI Gallery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 21:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is no longer a futuristic concept—it’s transforming how developers build and innovate applications today. To help Java developers harness the full potential of AI, Microsoft’s Azure AI App Templates gallery offers a growing collection of AI-powered application templates. These templates are designed to streamline development, showcase integration patterns, and accelerate your AI […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-intelligent-application-templates-in-the-azure-ai-gallery 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the GA Release of Filters for .NET and Python in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 21:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the General Availability (GA) release of Filters for our .NET and Python Semantic Kernel! This vital enhancement strengthens the control and visibility developers have when running functions, ensuring responsible AI practices are instilled from the ground up. Filters not only improve security but also contribute to building enterprise-ready solutions that […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-the-ga-release-of-filters-for-net-and-python-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: Announcing the Microsoft Semantic Kernel Elasticsearch Connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 19:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to feature the Elastic team to share more about their Semantic Kernel Elasticsearch connector. Read the entire announcement here. I’ll turn it over to Srikanth Manvi to dive into it. In collaboration with the Microsoft Semantic Kernel team, we are announcing the availability of Semantic Kernel Elasticsearch Vector Store connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel (.NET) users. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-announcing-the-microsoft-semantic-kernel-elasticsearch-connector 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the GA Release of the OpenAPI Plugin for .NET and Python in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 19:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the General Availability (GA) release of the OpenAPI package for Semantic Kernel, available for both .NET and Python! With this significant milestone, developers can easily integrate existing APIs as plugins, enhancing the capabilities of their AI agents while making them more versatile in real-world applications. Why OpenAPI Plugins Matter In […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-the-ga-release-of-the-openapi-plugin-for-net-and-python-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance speech synthesis and video generation models with RLHF using audio and video segmentation in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to implement an audio and video segmentation solution using SageMaker Ground Truth. We guide you through deploying the necessary infrastructure using AWS CloudFormation, creating an internal labeling workforce, and setting up your first labeling job. By the end of this post, you will have a fully functional audio/video segmentation workflow that you can adapt for various use cases, from training speech synthesis models to improving video generation capabilities.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using responsible AI principles with Amazon Bedrock Batch Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a practical, cost-effective approach for incorporating responsible AI guardrails into Amazon Bedrock Batch Inference workflows. Although we use a call center’s transcript summarization as our primary example, the methods we discuss are broadly applicable to a variety of batch inference use cases where ethical considerations and data protection are a top priority.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-responsible-ai-principles-with-amazon-bedrock-batch-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing knowledge management: VW’s AI prototype journey with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            we’re excited to share the journey of the VW—an innovator in the automotive industry and Europe’s largest car maker—to enhance knowledge management by using generative AI, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Kendra to devise a solution based on Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) that makes internal information more easily accessible by its users. This solution efficiently handles documents that include both text and images, significantly enhancing VW&#39;s knowledge management capabilities within their production domain.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune large language models with Amazon SageMaker Autopilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fine-tuning foundation models (FMs) is a process that involves exposing a pre-trained FM to task-specific data and fine-tuning its parameters. It can then develop a deeper understanding and produce more accurate and relevant outputs for that particular domain. In this post, we show how to use an Amazon SageMaker Autopilot training job with the AutoMLV2 […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-large-language-models-with-amazon-sagemaker-autopilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect which menu my item was invoked from?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just give them all different IDs. But this might itself by an XY problem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241121-00/?p=110554 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are the Latest Docker Desktop Enterprise-Grade Performance Optimizations?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the latest enterprise-grade performance optimizations in Docker Desktop, including Docker VMM for Apple Silicon, synchronized file sharing, and expanded support for RHEL and Windows Arm, all designed to deliver faster, more reliable development workflows.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/what-are-the-latest-docker-desktop-enterprise-grade-performance-optimizations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making you more productive with Visual Studio v17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 12th update to Visual Studio 2022 is packed with lots of exciting new features that users have been asking for! Here are some of the awesome highlights from this release that are some of my personal favorites. For all the details, be sure to check out our release notes. Copy from the Error List […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/making-you-more-productive-with-visual-studio-v17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never rewrite code?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Is it a bad idea to rewrite code or an entire system? At some point, developers want to rewrite for various reasons. Often, it’s because we simply don’t understand the existing codebase or think it’s a tire fire. But is the benefit there? Sometimes, yes. Sometimes, no. It’s a pretty nuanced topic around cost/benefit. YouTube… Read More »Never rewrite code? The post Never rewrite code? appeared first on CodeOpinion.
Link to article: https://codeopinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the enhanced MSSQL Extension for Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL extension for Visual Studio Code is designed to support developers in building applications that use Azure SQL (including Azure SQL Database, Azure SQL Managed Instance, and SQL Server on Azure VMs), SQL Database in Fabric (Preview) or SQL Server as backend databases. With a comprehensive suite of features for connecting to databases, designing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/mssql-extension-visual-studio-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Microsoft AI Shell Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 17:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            During Microsoft Ignite 2024, Microsoft announced the public preview of AI Shell, a groundbreaking innovation that integrates artificial intelligence directly into command-line workflows. With this release, Microsoft aims to bridge the gap between traditional shell interactions and the growing capabilities of AI, enabling developers and IT professionals to work smarter and faster. What is Microsoft […] The article New Microsoft AI Shell Public Preview was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unify structured data in Amazon Aurora and unstructured data in Amazon S3 for insights using Amazon Q</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-intensive business landscape, organizations face the challenge of extracting valuable insights from diverse data sources scattered across their infrastructure. Whether it’s structured data in databases or unstructured content in document repositories, enterprises often struggle to efficiently query and use this wealth of information. In this post, we explore how you can use Amazon […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unify-structured-data-in-amazon-aurora-and-unstructured-data-in-amazon-s3-for-insights-using-amazon-q/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Q&amp;A email responses with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate automating the responses to email inquiries by using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon Simple Email Service (Amazon SES), both fully managed services. By linking user queries to relevant company domain information, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases offers personalized responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-qa-email-responses-with-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline RAG applications with intelligent metadata filtering using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore an innovative approach that uses LLMs on Amazon Bedrock to intelligently extract metadata filters from natural language queries. By combining the capabilities of LLM function calling and Pydantic data models, you can dynamically extract metadata from user queries. This approach can also enhance the quality of retrieved information and responses generated by the RAG applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-rag-applications-with-intelligent-metadata-filtering-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotnet scaffold – Next Generation Project Creation for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing a new command line tool dotnet scaffold, a new interactive way to create projects in .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-dotnet-scaffold 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding secure generative AI in mission-critical public safety applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how Mark43 uses Amazon Q Business to create a secure, generative AI-powered assistant that drives operational efficiency and improves community service. We explain how they embedded Amazon Q Business web experience in their web application with low code, so they could focus on creating a rich AI experience for their customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/embedding-secure-generative-ai-in-mission-critical-public-safety-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How FP8 boosts LLM training by 18% on Amazon SageMaker P5 instances</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LLM training has seen remarkable advances in recent years, with organizations pushing the boundaries of what’s possible in terms of model size, performance, and efficiency. In this post, we explore how FP8 optimization can significantly speed up large model training on Amazon SageMaker P5 instances.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-fp8-boosts-llm-training-by-18-on-amazon-sagemaker-p5-instances/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the new Linux-based Azure Cosmos DB Emulator (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the preview release of the new Linux-based Azure Cosmos DB Emulator! This latest version is built to provide faster startup times and broader platform compatibility, addressing one of the most requested features in the Azure Cosmos DB User Voice community. The emulator can now seamlessly run on Apple silicon and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-the-new-linux-based-azure-cosmos-db-emulator-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I determine whether Explorer is showing or hiding file extensions?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can ask, but maybe you&#39;re asking the wrong question.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241120-00/?p=110547 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy files across instances of Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transferring code files between different instances of Visual Studio has often been a tedious task. To simplify this process, Visual Studio 2022 now includes a feature that allows you to easily copy and paste code files and folders between instances using the Solution Explorer. This enhancement aims to streamline workflow and save time. Until now, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/copy-files-across-instances-of-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Nova Improvements, Debug Servers, OpenCV Image Viewer, and Zephyr West Debugging in CLion 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 11:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion 2024.3 is now available. This latest version of the JetBrains IDE for C and C++ includes the following key features and updates: You can download CLion 2024.3 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu, or via a patch update from version 2024.2. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/11/2024-3-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Go Apps with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 11:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We live in a world where things change at a rapid pace, and the latest and greatest quickly becomes outdated. The same goes for deploying applications to servers. You used to have to physically travel to a data center to deploy your changes. Later on, we moved to VMs. Then containers came along and changed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/11/20/deploying-go-apps-with-kubernetes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally! Improved Blazor Server reconnection UX</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Caution! If you’ve built web apps with Blazor Server the following may cause distress! 😅 Attempting to reconnect to the server… Reconnection failed. Try reloading the page if you’re unable to reconnect. These are the standard Blazor error messages your users have likely complained about as they interact with your Blazor application. These errors occur because of the connected nature of Blazor server apps. A circuit runs on the server (for a given user interaction), and a SignalR (websocket) connection is maintained between the user’s browser and said circuit.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
