<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 19:50:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Revolutionizing AI Workflows: Multi-Agent Group Chat with Copilot Agent Plugins in Microsoft Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 19:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Revolutionizing AI Workflows: Multi-Agent Group Chat with Copilot Agent Plugins in Microsoft Semantic Kernel Copilot Agent Plugins (CAPs) are revolutionizing how developers interact with Microsoft 365 data. By transforming natural language into seamless CRUD actions using Microsoft Graph and Semantic Kernel, CAPs enable the creation of intelligent, AI-driven solutions. This sample demonstrates a multi-agent group […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-revolutionizing-ai-workflows-multi-agent-group-chat-with-copilot-agent-plugins-in-microsoft-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET MAUI Performance Features in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Optimize .NET MAUI application size and startup times with trimming and NativeAOT. Learn about dotnet-trace and dotnet-gcdump for measuring performance.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-performance-improvements-in-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool Calling is Now Enabled in GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 18:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever been frustrated when Copilot doesn’t understand you? While it can’t read your mind, we’ve been working hard to make your coding experience smoother. Previously, Copilot in Visual Studio could look at files in your repository, but you needed to specify the context of your code manually. We understand this wasn’t the most […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/function-calling-is-now-enabled-in-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate synthetic counterparty (CR) risk data with generative AI using Amazon Bedrock LLMs and RAG</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 17:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how you can use LLMs with advanced Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to generate high-quality synthetic data for a finance domain use case. You can use the same technique for synthetic data for other business domain use cases as well. For this post, we demonstrate how to generate counterparty risk (CR) data, which would be beneficial for over-the-counter (OTC) derivatives that are traded directly between two parties, without going through a formal exchange.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to TLS 1.2 for Azure Cosmos DB: Ensuring Secure Connections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 17:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Security and reliability are at the core of modern cloud applications. To strengthen data protection and align with industry best practices, we encourage all Azure Cosmos DB customers to transition to TLS 1.2. This post explains why this change is important, how to make the transition, and the benefits it brings to your applications. Why […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/moving-to-tls-1-2-for-azure-cosmos-db-ensuring-secure-connections 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turbocharging premium audit capabilities with the power of generative AI: Verisk’s journey toward a sophisticated conversational chat platform to enhance customer support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 17:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Verisk’s Premium Audit Advisory Service is the leading source of technical information and training for premium auditors and underwriters. In this post, we describe the development of the customer support process in PAAS, incorporating generative AI, the data, the architecture, and the evaluation of the results. Conversational AI assistants are rapidly transforming customer and employee support.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/turbocharging-premium-audit-capabilities-with-the-power-of-generative-ai-verisks-journey-toward-a-sophisticated-conversational-chat-platform-to-enhance-customer-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced In-Memory Text Vector Search in .NET with SharpVector and OpenAI Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 16:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The need to efficiently search and retrieve documents based on their semantic content is more important than ever—especially when building Generative AI systems that implement the Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) design pattern. One robust approach to achieve this is by using vector representations of text data. These vectors, generated using advanced embedding models like Azure […] The article Enhanced In-Memory Text Vector Search in .NET with SharpVector and OpenAI Embeddings was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: Intro, Dependencies, and First Integration Test</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 15:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following the enthusiastic response to our Plugin Testing: Performance, UI, and Functional Testing session at JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024, we’re launching a series of blog posts diving deeper into plugin testing strategies. This first post will guide you through setting up your testing environment and creating your first integration test, with detailed step-by-step instructions. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/02/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-intro-dependencies-and-first-integration-test/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code CMake Tools Extension 1.20 Release: Introducing Built-In CMake Language Services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 15:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The February release of CMake Tools in VS Code is now available. With this release, we have some new updates to the extension to improve CMake integrations with the extension’s support. Some updates include the built-in support for CMake Language services, addressing our most highly-upvoted issues in the CMake Tools extension, and CMake presets v9 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-code-cmake-tools-extension-1-20-release-introducing-built-in-cmake-language-services 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;/WinRT implementation inheritance: Notes on winrt::implements, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Untangling unwrap_implements_t.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250220-00/?p=110893 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doc-Powered AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 14:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with the 2024.3 version of JetBrains IDEs, AI Assistant can not only access the context from your project but also the IDE’s own documentation. Whenever you have a question about how to accomplish a task in a JetBrains IDE, such as WebStorm, IntelliJ IDEA, or PyCharm, AI Assistant is here to help. How do […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/doc-powered-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrumenting Apache Spark Structured Streaming jobs using OpenTelemetry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Apache spark monitoring using OpenTelemetry
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/spark_job_otel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying WebJobs to Azure Container Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 07:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debjyoti Ganguly walks through the process of migrating existing WebJobs to Azure Container App Jobs, highlighting the benefits and providing practical steps to implement this migration effectively Introduction As businesses scale, the need for a robust and scalable environment for running background jobs becomes essential. Azure Container App Jobs offer a modern, scalable, and containerized […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/deploying-webjobs-to-azure-container-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Agents for Beginners Course: 10 Lessons teaching you how to start building AI Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 22:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            10 Lessons teaching everything you need to know to start building AI Agents Today we want to highlight the AI Agents For Beginners course that was released. 🔗https://github.com/microsoft/ai-agents-for-beginners/tree/main 🗃️There are 10 Lessons available today teaching you the basics of building AI Agents, as shown below Lesson Link Intro to AI Agents and Use Cases Link […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/ai-agents-for-beginners-course-10-lessons-teaching-you-how-to-start-building-ai-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Tenant: Database Per Tenant or Shared?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 20:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building a multi-tenant application, one of the first decisions revolves around data management: Should you use a shared database or a database per tenant? YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in this post. Shared Database Let’s start with the shared database… Read More »Multi-Tenant: Database Per Tenant or Shared? The post Multi-Tenant: Database Per Tenant or Shared?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot for Azure DevOps users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 19:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure DevOps customers frequently ask us when GitHub Copilot will be available to them. What many don’t realize is that GitHub Copilot for Business is already accessible to all customers, including those using Azure DevOps. Even better, much of its powerful functionality is integrated into tools you already use, like Visual Studio and VS Code. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/github-copilot-for-azure-devops-users 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust in time! Announcing the Azure SDK for Rust Beta. 🎉</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 18:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the first beta release of the Azure SDK for Rust. This release includes libraries for Identity, Key Vault secrets &amp;amp; keys, Event Hubs, and Cosmos DB.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/rust-in-time-announcing-the-azure-sdk-for-rust-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Chroma DB C# SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started building AI applications using Chroma DB using the C# client SDK
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-chroma-db-csharp-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build verifiable explainability into financial services workflows with Automated Reasoning checks for Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 17:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Automated Reasoning checks work through various common FSI scenarios such as insurance legal triaging, underwriting rules validation, and claims processing.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-verifiable-explainability-into-financial-services-workflows-with-automated-reasoning-checks-for-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod task governance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 17:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide best practices to maximize the value of SageMaker HyperPod task governance and make the administration and data science experiences seamless. We also discuss common governance scenarios when administering and running generative AI development tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-for-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-task-governance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Unveils Majorana 1: A Quantum Leap in Computing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 17:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On February 19, 2025, Microsoft unveiled a revolutionary advancement in quantum computing: the Majorana 1 chip. This cutting-edge processor is built on a novel topological quantum architecture, leveraging the unique properties of the elusive Majorana particle. This breakthrough could propel quantum computing from theoretical research to practical, scalable solutions—an achievement that has eluded scientists for […] The article Microsoft Unveils Majorana 1: A Quantum Leap in Computing was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Code Referencing for GitHub Copilot Completions in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 16:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When GitHub Copilot completions (or “gray text”) pop up on your screen, have you ever wondered where does the completions come from and worried about if it matches with public code leading to license issues? If you have, we are introducing code referencing to support you and provide more transparency! We are excited to announce […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-code-referencing-for-github-copilot-completions-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Adaptive Cards documentation hub and new Adaptive Cards updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 16:11:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Adaptive Cards can transform your app with rich, interactive experiences that boost productivity and streamline workflows, in our new Adaptive Cards documentation hub.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-the-adaptive-cards-documentation-hub-and-new-adaptive-cards-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar – Uno Platform &amp; Hot Design for Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Tuesday, March 11, 2025, 15:00 – 16:30 UTC (check other timezones) for our free live webinar, Uno Platform &amp;amp; Hot Design for Rider, with Andres Pineda. Register now and get a reminder, or join on YouTube Hot Design is the industry’s first visual designer for cross-platform .NET applications. It transforms your running app […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/19/webinar-uno-platform-amp-hot-design-for-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Your React App Deployment With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial was brought to you by Kumar Harsh, a software developer and technical author. If you regularly work with React projects, you probably already know how tricky it can be to deploy them smoothly. Issues like manual errors, inconsistent deployment practices, and slow iteration cycles often turn React app deployment into a challenging process […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/automate-your-react-app-deployment-with-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSVC C&#43;&#43; Code Analysis: Updates in Visual Studio 2022 version 17.13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post details the latest updates in Visual Studio 2022 version 17.13 for MSVC C++ Code Analysis. Driven by internal team insights and developer community feedback, these improvements significantly reduce false positives and strengthen production code security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/msvc-c-code-analysis-updates-in-visual-studio-2022-version-17-13 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;/WinRT implementation inheritance: Notes on winrt::implements, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A closer look at the parameters to the implements template.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250219-00/?p=110889 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Azure Developer CLI (azd) for HashiCorp Terraform Infrastructure Deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure Developer CLI (azd) is a powerful tool for accelerating application deployment to Microsoft Azure. While azd defaults to Azure Bicep for Infrastructure as Code (IaC) deployment, you can configure it to work with HashiCorp Terraform too! This enables azd to be configured not just for Terraform deployments, but also to support cloud-agnostic IaC […] The article Configure Azure Developer CLI (azd) for HashiCorp Terraform Infrastructure Deployment was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoMapper 14.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 13:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I pushed out version 14.0 (!) of AutoMapper over the weekend:Release notesNuGetThis release targets .NET 8 (up from .NET 6 from the previous release). It&#39;s mainly a bug fix release, with some quality-of-life improvements in configuration validation where we gather up all the possible validation
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/automapper-14-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Optimizing Byte-to-Hex Conversions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Switching from BitConverter.ToString() to Convert.ToHexString() in .NET can significantly enhance performance and reduce memory usage for byte-to-hex conversions. This optimized method is faster and uses less memory, addressing best practices and CA1872 rule violations. For optimal results, consider updating your .editorConfig and exploring additional resources.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/02/19/microsoft-net-code-analysis-optimizing-byte-to-hex-conversions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces a New Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The YouTrack 2025.1 release introduces a bold new design that helps you navigate your projects and tasks more quickly. This new look and feel reflects years of learning about how teams work on projects. The new design introduces: Every day, hundreds of thousands of teams count on YouTrack to drive their business forward. We understand […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/02/youtrack-introduces-a-new-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Formula 1® uses generative AI to accelerate race-day issue resolution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 21:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how F1 and AWS have developed a root cause analysis (RCA) assistant powered by Amazon Bedrock to reduce manual intervention and accelerate the resolution of recurrent operational issues during races from weeks to minutes. The RCA assistant enables the F1 team to spend more time on innovation and improving its services, ultimately delivering an exceptional experience for fans and partners. The successful collaboration between F1 and AWS showcases the transformative potential of generative AI in empowering teams to accomplish more in less time.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go passwordless when calling Azure OpenAI from Azure SQL using Managed Identities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 19:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Security is a significant topic today, and the ability to access a service requiring authentication without using an API key, password, or secret is a common request from those concerned about the security of a solution, which includes all of us. In today’s digital landscape, cybersecurity threats are increasingly sophisticated and frequent, making it imperative […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/go-passwordless-when-calling-azure-openai-from-azure-sql-using-managed-identities 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powered by Docker: Streamlining Engineering Operations as a Platform Engineer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 18:40:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker streamlines developer onboarding and helps organizations set up the right guardrails to give developers the flexibility to innovate within the boundaries of company policies.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/streamlining-engineering-operations-as-platform-engineer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VisualStudio.Extensibility: Tagger support and updates to settings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 17:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We continue to invest in the VisualStudio.Extensibility SDK to allow users like you to create extensions that run faster and smoother than ever before! VisualStudio.Extensibility helps you build extensions that run outside the main Visual Studio IDE process for improved performance, reliability, and installation without restarting Visual Studio. Additional benefits include a sleek and intuitive […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visualstudio-extensibility-tagger-support-and-updates-to-settings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI App GraphQL Endpoint with SQL DB in Fabric</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 16:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to an exciting, new workshop where we blend the power of AI with the versatility of GraphQL and SQL databases in Microsoft Fabric. This guide will walk you through creating a set of GraphQL RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation) application APIs, leveraging relational data and Azure OpenAI. What You’ll Learn You’ll dive into querying and managing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/building-an-ai-app-graphql-endpoint-with-sql-db-in-fabric 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your statement is now available, just two hidden flyouts and five clicks away</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Beware of the leopard.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250218-00/?p=110881 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do LLMs Benefit Developer Productivity?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 13:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LLMs are everywhere! I am sure you have heard of large language models (LLMs) and may have seen demonstrations of what they can do. You may have even tried to play with some of the popular ones yourself. No matter your opinion of or experience with LLMs, you cannot deny that they are a popular […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/how-do-llms-benefit-developer-productivity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 5: More LLMs in JetBrains AI Assistant, Improved Gutter for VCS, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 12:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 5 is out! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 5 Let’s take a look at this week’s fresh additions! If you missed our previous overviews […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDEs Aren’t Just for Developers: How QA, Tech Writers, and Designers Benefit Too</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 12:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud development environments (CDEs) have become a game-changer for development teams, and for good reason. They simplify workflows, reduce project setup time, and eliminate configuration headaches. While most discussions about CDEs focus exclusively on software developers, in reality, the benefits of CDEs extend far beyond coders. They can boost productivity for every team member involved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/02/cdes-aren-t-just-for-developers-how-qa-tech-writers-and-designers-benefit-too/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: TDD and Generative AI – A Perfect Pairing?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 11:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Bouke Nijhuis, where we’ll explore how test-driven development (TDD) and AI can work together to generate production-ready code. Date: February 27, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this talk, we will explore whether generative AI can generate working code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/new-livestream-tdd-and-generative-ai-a-perfect-pairing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Is the Best Python Web Framework: Django, Flask, or FastAPI?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 10:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Search for Python web frameworks, and three names will consistently come up: Django, Flask, and FastAPI. Our latest Python Developer Survey Results confirm that these three frameworks remain developers’ top choices for backend web development with Python. All three frameworks are open-source and compatible with the latest versions of Python. But how do you determine […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/02/django-flask-fastapi/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting application environment variables in IIS without restarts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I outline how IIS works, describe how to add environment variables to app pools, and show how to prevent automatic app pool recycling on changes
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/setting-environment-variables-in-iis-and-avoiding-app-pool-restarts/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Tuples in C#: Real-World Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 09:10:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well, using OOP in development is a blessing. We define classes to leverage inheritance and abstraction. We easily represent one object as a model. However, using and maintaining these classes can sometimes be tedious for the developers and the application’s memory. You might need to define separate classes or
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/leveraging-tuples-in-c-real-world-use-cases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Semantic Search using Amazon Bedrock and RDS for PostgreSQL in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 18:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Large language models (LLMs) are driving the rapid growth of semantic search applications. Semantic search understands both user intent and content context, rather than just matching keywords. LLMs enhance this capability through their advanced language processing abilities. These AI models can process multiple content formats, including text, images, audio, and video. The users receive […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/implementing-semantic-search-using-amazon-bedrock-and-rds-for-postgresql-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create React App is Now Deprecated: Time to Migrate to Vite or Next.js</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 18:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The React team has officially announced the deprecation of Create React App (CRA) in favor of more modern and efficient tools like Vite and Next.js. If you’ve been using CRA to bootstrap your React applications, now is the time to explore better alternatives that provide improved performance, developer experience, and scalability. Why is Create React […] The article Create React App is Now Deprecated: Time to Migrate to Vite or Next.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Cloud Azure updates and troubleshooting tips for Java on AKS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 17:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows the latest Spring Cloud Azure updates.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/spring-cloud-azure-updates-and-troubleshooting-tips-for-java-on-aks 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon Rekognition to improve bicycle safety</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 16:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To better protect themselves, many cyclists are starting to ride with cameras mounted to the front or back of their bicycle. In this blog post, I will demonstrate a machine learning solution that cyclists can use to better identify close calls. The architecture of the solution uses Amazon Rekognition to detect vehicles in recorded bike ride videos. It then analyzes the video to determine if any vehicles are passing too close to the cyclist, within the 3-foot safe distance required by law.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API design note: Beware of adding an “Other” enum value</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What are you going to do when you add a new kind?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250217-00/?p=110873 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI vs. DeepSeek: Which AI Understands Kotlin Better?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 11:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI models are evolving fast, and DeepSeek-R1 is making waves as a serious competitor to OpenAI. But how well do these models understand Kotlin? Can they generate reliable code, explain tricky concepts, and help with debugging? JetBrains Research tested the latest AI models, including DeepSeek-R1, OpenAI o1, and OpenAI o3-mini, using KotlinHumanEval and a new […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/02/openai-vs-deepseek-which-ai-understands-kotlin-better/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Migrations in the Real World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 11:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Database migrations are critical to modern application development and deployment, enabling teams to evolve their database schema alongside their application code. However, as systems grow in complexity and scale, managing migrations becomes increasingly challenging. At scale, a simple schema update can impact several microservices, terabytes of data, and global user traffic. It requires careful planning, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/database-migrations-in-the-real-world/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keycloak Authentication With ASP.NET Core Web API and Blazor WebAssembly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 07:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to learn about integrating Keycloak authentication in a Blazor WebAssembly (WASM) frontend and a .NET Web API backend. With this setup, we will enable secure user authentication across both applications. Keycloak is an open-source identity and access management solution that provides authentication, authorization, and user management out of the […] The post Keycloak Authentication With ASP.NET Core Web API and Blazor WebAssembly appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing a single client sign-in using parameters in Duende IdentityServer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. In the previous post, the UI was customized per […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/02/17/customizing-a-single-client-sign-in-using-parameters-in-duende-identityserver/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Get User Principal Name (UPN) of User Running Deployment without Entra ID Read Permissions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_02_2025/16_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_02_2025/16_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I has a scenario where I needed to configure an Azure PostgreSQL Flexible Server to use Entra ID (Azure AD) authentication and add the Entra user running the HashiCorp Terraform deployment as the Azure PostgreSQL Administrator using the azurerm_postgresql_flexible_server_active_directory_administrator Terraform resource. Generally, you would use the azuread_user data resource in Terraform to get the Entra […] The article Terraform: Get User Principal Name (UPN) of User Running Deployment without Entra ID Read Permissions was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify File I/O with Spargine’s DirectoryHelper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_02_2025/16_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_02_2025/16_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages focused on file I/O efficiency, particularly the DirectoryHelper component. It simplifies directory operations on Windows and macOS, enhancing performance and error management.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/02/16/boost-your-net-projects-simplify-file-i-o-with-spargines-directoryhelper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supervised Learning (SSL) in AI Systems: Autonomous Machine Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 21:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is evolving at a rapid pace, with machine learning techniques becoming more sophisticated and efficient. One of the biggest challenges in traditional AI training is the heavy reliance on labeled datasets, which require extensive human effort and resources. However, Self-Supervised Learning (SSL) is revolutionizing the field by enabling AI models to learn […] The article Self-Supervised Learning (SSL) in AI Systems: Autonomous Machine Intelligence was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Functions Cost Considerations and Optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 18:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Functions is a powerful serverless compute service that enables organizations to build event-driven applications with minimal infrastructure management. While its scalability and flexibility make it an attractive choice for modern cloud applications, managing costs effectively is essential to avoid unexpected expenses. This article explores the key factors influencing Azure Functions pricing and provides a […] The article Azure Functions Cost Considerations and Optimization was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-02-14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 06:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/02/15/weekly-recap-20250214 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cursor Pagination and Why It&#39;s So Fast (Deep Dive)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While offset pagination is widely used, cursor-based pagination offers significant performance advantages - my tests show a 17x speedup when paginating through a million-record dataset in PostgreSQL. Let&#39;s take a deep dive into cursor pagination, compare it with offset pagination, and examine the SQL execution plans.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/understanding-cursor-pagination-and-why-its-so-fast-deep-dive 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating an argument-dependent lookup issue and working around it</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2025/14_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2025/14_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picking apart the language specification.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250214-00/?p=110868 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the .NET Ecosystem: A Visual Mind Map</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2025/14_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 11:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2025/14_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft .NET platform is a powerful and versatile ecosystem that enables developers to build a wide range of applications,… The post Exploring the .NET Ecosystem: A Visual Mind Map appeared first on Daily .NET Tips.
Link to article: https://dailydotnettips.com/net-ecosystem-mindmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 网络优化</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2025/14_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 10:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2025/14_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自 Máňa, Natalia 和 Anton 创作的 .NET 9 Networking Improvements 秉承我们的传统，我们很高兴与您分享这篇博客文章，以介绍新的 .NET 版本中网络领域相关的最新动态和最有趣的变化。今年，我们带来了 HTTP 领域的改变、新的 HttpClientFactory API、.NET Framework 兼容性优化等更多内容。 HTTP 在接下来的部分中，我们将介绍 HTTP 领域最具影响力的变化。其中包括连接池的性能优化、对多个HTTP/3连接的支持、Windows代理的自动更新，以及重要的社区贡献。 连接池 在此版本中，我们对HTTP连接池进行了两项显著的性能优化。 我们增加了对多个HTTP/3连接的可选支持。根据RFC 9114标准文档，由于连接可以多路复用并行请求，因此不鼓励使用多个HTTP/3连接到对等端。然而，在某些场景下，例如服务器到服务器的通信，即使请求多路复用，单一连接也可能成为瓶颈。我们在 HTTP/2 中看到了这样的限制（dotnet/runtime#35088），它同样具有在单一连接上多路复用的概念。出于同样的原因（dotnet/runtime#51775），我们决定为HTTP/3实现多连接支持（dotnet/runtime#101535）。 该实现本身尽可能贴近 HTTP/2 多连接机制的行为。当前，它的策略是优先填充已有连接，直到达到对端允许的请求上限后，才会创建新的连接。不过，需要注意的是，这是一个具体的实现细节，该行为在未来可能会有所变化。 结果是，我们的基准测试显示每秒请求数（RPS）有显著提升，以下是10,000个并行请求的对比结果： 客户端 单 HTTP/3 连接 多 HTTP/3 连接 最大CPU使用率(%) 35 92 最大核心使用率(%) 971 2572 最大工作集(MB) 3810 6491 最大私有内存(MB) 4415 7228 处理器数量 28 28 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/net-9-%e7%bd%91%e7%bb%9c%e4%bc%98%e5%8c%96 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot for Xcode Chat – Public Preview Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2025/14_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2025/14_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that GitHub Copilot for Xcode Chat is now in public preview, bringing the power of AI to help developers code more efficiently. With just a GitHub account, you can enable Copilot in Xcode and start leveraging AI-driven suggestions and interactive chat features today. GitHub Copilot is an AI-powered assistant that helps […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/github-copilot-for-xcode-chat-public-preview-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New restrictions on package loading</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 22:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Visual Studio transitions its core packages and services to an async loading/retrieval model, we’ve identified bugs in both the initial async implementation and the existing synchronous package loading mechanism. While most of these bug fixes have been transparent to extenders, one requires attention due to changed constraints. This post highlights that change. Note that […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-restrictions-on-package-loading 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.8 RC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 22:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the Release Candidate (RC) of TypeScript 5.8! To get started using the Release Candidate, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@rc Let’s take a look at what’s new in TypeScript 5.8! What’s New Since the Beta? Since our beta release, we have […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-8-rc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering .NET Developers: C# in Amazon SageMaker Jupyter Notebooks using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 21:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Razvan Pat contributed to this article. Introduction As .NET developers, we often find ourselves at a crossroads when venturing into the world of machine learning and AI. While Python dominates this space, what if you could leverage your C# skills in a powerful machine learning (ML) environment? That’s exactly what we’re exploring today: how to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/empowering-net-developers-c-in-amazon-sagemaker-jupyter-notebooks-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a dynamic, role-based AI agent using Amazon Bedrock inline agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build an application using Amazon Bedrock inline agents, demonstrating how a single AI assistant can adapt its capabilities dynamically based on user roles.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-dynamic-role-based-ai-agent-using-amazon-bedrock-inline-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use language embeddings for zero-shot classification and semantic search with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore what language embeddings are and how they can be used to enhance your application. We show how, by using the properties of embeddings, we can implement a real-time zero-shot classifier and can add powerful features such as semantic search.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-language-embeddings-for-zero-shot-classification-and-semantic-search-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Features for Enhanced Razor Productivity!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Extract to Component refactoring and the Roslyn tokenizer are two new features designed to help improve your productivity in Razor files.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/enhancing-razor-productivity-with-new-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database and AI: solutions for keeping embeddings updated</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 17:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous article of this series, it was discussed how embeddings can be quickly created from data already in Azure SQL. This is a useful starting point, but since data in a database changes frequently, a common question arises: “How can the vectors be kept updated whenever there is a change to the content […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/database-and-ai-solutions-for-keeping-embeddings-updated 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A sample implementation of the weak reference pattern for COM callbacks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A forwarder through a weak reference.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250213-00/?p=110865 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore 2025.1 Brings New Welcome Screen, Revamped Admin Panel for On-Premises, and Workspace Import From Git Repository</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.1 introduces a new Welcome screen, a redesigned admin panel for On-Premises installations, the ability to import workspaces from Git repositories, and more. Datalore Cloud customers have already received the new updates automatically, and Datalore On-Premises customers can upgrade by following these instructions. New Welcome screen The new Welcome screen simplifies onboarding. Here, you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/02/13/datalore-2025-1-brings-new-welcome-screen-revamped-admin-panel-for-on-premises-and-workspace-import-from-git-repository/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 3.1.0 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 12:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ktor 3.1.0 is here! This is the first minor release of the year, bringing exciting new features, performance improvements, and bug fixes. This release includes improvements to server-sent events (SSE), documentation enhancements, WebAssembly (Wasm) support, dependency injection design updates, and some initial steps toward gRPC integration. 🚀 Get started with Ktor 3.1.0 now! Ready to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/02/ktor-3-1-0-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.0-1 Microsoft build now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 09:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-0-1-microsoft-build-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Generative AI for Enterprise Scalability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reusable templates, pipelines, and tools to streamline the setup of GenAI projects, saving time and effort, and ensuring consistency and reliability across projects.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/scaling-genai-projects 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot for Eclipse: Code Completion Now in Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 02:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the Public Preview of GitHub Copilot for Eclipse. As part of the broader GitHub Copilot family, which enhances productivity in various IDEs, this latest integration ensures that developers using Eclipse can benefit from AI-assisted coding like never before. GitHub Copilot is an AI-powered code assistant designed to streamline software development […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/github-copilot-for-eclipse-code-completion-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
