<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 02:48:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>立即使用 .NET 和 DeepSeek R1 构建智能应用程序！</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2025/10_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 02:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2025/10_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Matt Soucoup的Build Intelligent Apps with .NET and DeepSeek R1 Today! 最近，DeepSeek R1 模型引起了广泛关注。我们被频繁问到的一个问题是：“我能在 .NET 应用程序中使用 DeepSeek 吗？”答案是：当然可以！接下来，我将带您了解如何通过 GitHub Models 上的 Microsoft.Extensions.AI（MEAI）库与 DeepSeek R1 结合使用，让您能够立即开始体验 R1 模型的功能。 MEAI 让使用 AI 服务变得简单 MEAI 库提供了一套统一的抽象和中间件，以简化 AI 服务在 .NET 应用程序中的集成。 换句话说，如果您使用 MEAI 开发应用程序，无论底层使用的是哪种模型，您的代码都将使用相同的 API。这降低了构建 .NET AI 应用程序的难度，因为无论使用哪个 AI 服务，您只需记住一个库（即 MEAI）的操作方式。 对于 MEAI，您将主要使用的接口是 IChatClient。 与 DeepSeek R1 聊天 GitHub Models […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e7%ab%8b%e5%8d%b3%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8-net-%e5%92%8c-deepseek-r1-%e6%9e%84%e5%bb%ba%e6%99%ba%e8%83%bd%e5%ba%94%e7%94%a8%e7%a8%8b%e5%ba%8f%ef%bc%81 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s InMemoryCache</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2025/09_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2025/09_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8 that includes the InMemoryCache type for efficient data caching. It enhances application performance by reducing database load and improving response times, while also addressing challenges like data volatility and management complexity.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/02/09/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-inmemorycache/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice For Junior Devs Who Aren&#39;t Quitting Because AI - Dev Leader Weekly 82</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2025/08_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2025/08_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss what junior developers can focus on as they approach their careers in development!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/02/08/advice-for-junior-devs-who-arent-quitting-because-ai-dev-leader-weekly-82 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-02-07</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2025/08_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 05:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2025/08_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/02/08/weekly-recap-20250207 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Conflating CQRS and MediatR</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2025/08_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2025/08_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET ecosystem has gradually fused CQRS and MediatR together, creating a reflexive assumption that they&#39;re inseparable, but this mental shortcut has led teams down a path of unnecessary complexity. This article dispels common misconceptions by explaining how CQRS and MediatR are distinct tools solving different problems, and demonstrates how to implement CQRS effectively with or without MediatR.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/stop-conflating-cqrs-and-mediatr 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port .NET Framework workloads to Linux with Amazon Q Developer, Part 1: Class libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 22:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In the .NET world, the modernization process for .NET Framework applications can be complex, presenting significant challenges for enterprise software development teams. Organizations with extensive .NET Framework codebases face critical decisions about migrating traditional applications to modern .NET and Linux, including careful analysis of dependencies and how to handle compatibility constraints. Existing libraries may […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/port-net-framework-workloads-to-linux-with-amazon-q-developer-part-1-class-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – February 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 20:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the February release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-february-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governing the ML lifecycle at scale, Part 4: Scaling MLOps with security and governance controls</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 20:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides detailed steps for setting up the key components of a multi-account ML platform. This includes configuring the ML Shared Services Account, which manages the central templates, model registry, and deployment pipelines; sharing the ML Admin and SageMaker Projects Portfolios from the central Service Catalog; and setting up the individual ML Development Accounts where data scientists can build and train models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/governing-the-ml-lifecycle-at-scale-part-4-scaling-mlops-with-security-and-governance-controls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your Amazon Q implementation: starter kits for SMBs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 17:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starter kits are complete, deployable solutions that address common, repeatable business problems. They deploy the services that make up a solution according to best practices, helping you optimize costs and become familiar with these kinds of architectural patterns without a large investment in training. In this post, we showcase a starter kit for Amazon Q Business. If you have a repository of documents that you need to turn into a knowledge base quickly, or simply want to test out the capabilities of Amazon Q Business without a large investment of time at the console, then this solution is for you.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the future of construction analytics: CONXAI’s AI inference on Amazon EKS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 17:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CONXAI Technology GmbH is pioneering the development of an advanced AI platform for the Architecture, Engineering, and Construction (AEC) industry. In this post, we dive deep into how CONXAI hosts the state-of-the-art OneFormer segmentation model on AWS using Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3), Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), KServe, and NVIDIA Triton.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-the-future-of-construction-analytics-conxais-ai-inference-on-amazon-eks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Untold Studios empowers artists with an AI assistant built on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 17:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Untold Studios is a tech-driven, leading creative studio specializing in high-end visual effects and animation. This post details how we used Amazon Bedrock to create an AI assistant (Untold Assistant), providing artists with a straightforward way to access our internal resources through a natural language interface integrated directly into their existing Slack workflow.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-untold-studios-empowers-artists-with-an-ai-assistant-built-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using alternate locales to get more interesting case mapping than the C</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking for something better.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250207-00/?p=110848 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is a Deep Research AI Agent Designed?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Deep Research AI Agent is an advanced AI-driven system designed to assist in conducting complex and large-scale research. It leverages cutting-edge artificial intelligence techniques such as natural language processing (NLP), machine learning (ML), and automation to analyze vast amounts of data, extract key insights, and generate summaries. These agents help professionals and organizations streamline […] The article How is a Deep Research AI Agent Designed? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and Rider 2024.3.5 Bug-Fix Updates Are Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 10:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download. ReSharper 2024.3.5 This update comes with the following fixes: For the full list of issues resolved, please see our issue tracker. Rider 2024.3.5 Notable fixes We’ve addressed an issue in the 2024.3.4 release where the Go to Class feature (Ctrl+N) did not display […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/07/the-resharper-and-rider-2024-3-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 EAP 3: Enhancements for Blazor WASM, User Experience, and the Decompiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 08:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Rider 2025.1 EAP 3 is out! You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Here’s what you can expect from this update: Proper support for Blazor WebAssembly publishing Rider 2025.1 EAP 3 introduces proper support for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/07/rider-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Fresh Picks to Begin 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 06:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, it’s Kodee! Missed me? I hope you had a fantastic break because it’s time for a new edition of Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup! I’ve got some exciting news from the past couple of months just for you. Kotlin YouTube spotlight Did you know there’s a Kotlin YouTube channel packed with awesome content? It’s been buzzing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/02/kodees-kotlin-roundup-fresh-picks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 4: Improvements for Kotlin Development, Automatic Plugin Updates, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 05:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 4 is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 4 Read on to learn about this week’s additions. If you missed our previous overviews […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect your DeepSeek model deployments with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 02:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post provides a comprehensive guide to implementing robust safety protections for DeepSeek-R1 and other open weight models using Amazon Bedrock Guardrails. By following this guide, you&#39;ll learn how to use the advanced capabilities of DeepSeek models while maintaining strong security controls and promoting ethical AI practices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/protect-your-deepseek-model-deployments-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – February 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 21:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The February 2025 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include .
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-february-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering automated testing in Power Platform: Evergreen concepts for robust solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 19:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get a deep dive into the concepts of automated testing within the Power Platform, along with insights and best practices to help you build robust and reliable solutions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/mastering-automated-testing-in-power-platform 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Data Studio Retirement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 19:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re announcing the upcoming retirement of Azure Data Studio (ADS) on February 6, 2025, as we focus on delivering a modern, streamlined SQL development experience. ADS will remain supported until February 28, 2026, giving developers ample time to transition. This decision aligns with our commitment to simplifying SQL development by consolidating efforts on Visual Studio Code (VS Code) with the MSSQL extension, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/azure-data-studio-retirement 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune and host SDXL models cost-effectively with AWS Inferentia2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 18:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As technology continues to evolve, newer models are emerging, offering higher quality, increased flexibility, and faster image generation capabilities. One such groundbreaking model is Stable Diffusion XL (SDXL), released by StabilityAI, advancing the text-to-image generative AI technology to unprecedented heights. In this post, we demonstrate how to efficiently fine-tune the SDXL model using SageMaker Studio. We show how to then prepare the fine-tuned model to run on AWS Inferentia2 powered Amazon EC2 Inf2 instances, unlocking superior price performance for your inference workloads.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 Networking Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing new networking features in .NET 9 including HTTP space, HttpClientFactory, security and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-networking-improvements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Aetion is using generative AI and Amazon Bedrock to translate scientific intent to results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 17:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aetion is a leading provider of decision-grade real-world evidence software to biopharma, payors, and regulatory agencies. In this post, we review how Aetion is using Amazon Bedrock to help streamline the analytical process toward producing decision-grade real-world evidence and enable users without data science expertise to interact with complex real-world datasets.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-aetion-is-using-generative-ai-and-amazon-bedrock-to-translate-scientific-intent-to-results/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Go 1.24 FIPS changes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 17:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Go 1.24 ships with many new FIPS-140 related features. Here&#39;s a closer look at the upcoming changes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-fips-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: How preezie’s AI shopping assistant is reshaping Blue Bungalow’s online store</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 16:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Blue Bungalow, one of Australia’s leading fashion retailers, faced a common challenge in eCommerce—how to create a more engaging, seamless, and personalised shopping experience for customers online. They wanted to implement AI-powered assistance to provide personalised product recommendations, accurate sizing guidance, product comparisons, and instant answers to customer questions—replicating the ease and support of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-how-preezies-ai-shopping-assistant-is-reshaping-blue-bungalows-online-store 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI o1, o1-mini, and o3-mini models now available in JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant streamlines your workflow and lets you focus on problem-solving instead of writing boilerplate and performing repetitive tasks. Now, we’ve added access to OpenAI o1, o1-mini, and o3-mini models to offer an even more adaptable and personalized experience with AI Assistant. What’s special about OpenAI o1? OpenAI’s o1 series of models are designed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/openai-o1-o1-mini-and-o3-mini-models-now-available-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP File updates for Request Variables and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many users have requested adding support for Request Variables in HTTP files in Visual Studio. With Request Variables, you can send an HTTP request and then use data from the response, or request, in any subsequent request that is sent from the HTTP file. We have also added support for a shared environment, $shared, which […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/http-file-updates-for-request-variables-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The default C locale is not a very interesting one</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It barely understands anything.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250206-00/?p=110846 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Option to Cancel Continuity Discounts for Paid Plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 14:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Marketplace is introducing changes to how continuity discounts are handled for paid plugins, giving plugin authors more flexibility in managing their pricing strategies. Here’s everything you need to know about the new option to cancel the continuity discount and how it affects your plugins. What is the continuity discount? The continuity discount is a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/02/option-to-cancel-continuity-discounts-for-paid-plugins/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference Between Completions and Embeddings in AI Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) models have rapidly evolved to perform various tasks ranging from text generation to natural language understanding. Among the different types of AI-driven models, Completions and Embeddings serve distinct purposes. While they both utilize machine learning techniques, their applications and functionality differ significantly. In this article, we’ll explore the differences between completions and […] The article Difference Between Completions and Embeddings in AI Models was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The JetBrains Platform Gets a New Community Space</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains products, including JetBrains IDEs, YouTrack, TeamCity, and others, are designed with extensibility in mind. While we try to provide our users with a wide feature set, it is impossible to cover all technologies and use cases in a dynamic market like software development. Many ecosystems get new frameworks and libraries every day, and developers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/02/the-jetbrains-platform-gets-a-new-community-space/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – February 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! As we start 2025, we bring you a roundup of the latest advancements in the world of tech. Stay in the loop with a curated list of must-attend events coming up in February, so you can plan your next learning and networking opportunities. Plus, we’re thrilled […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/java-annotated-monthly-february-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2025: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the February 2025 edition of our monthly developer update, summarizing the latest news and developments in Microsoft Entra. This month, we bring you feature updates, public previews, announcements, and other important updates. Read on to learn more and make the most of Microsoft Entra. What went Generally Available (GA) since January 2025? Microsoft […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-feb-25 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Functions vs. Indexers: AI Data Ingestion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article compares Azure Functions with pre-built indexers for data ingestion in Azure AI Search, with a focus on using Azure Functions for a flexible, scalable approach. It explores key steps like data migration, index creation, and deployment automation.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/unlock-ai-search-potential-the-case-for-azure-functions-in-data-ingestion 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trellix lowers cost, increases speed, and adds delivery flexibility with cost-effective and performant Amazon Nova Micro and Amazon Nova Lite models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 22:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses the adoption and evaluation of Amazon Nova foundation models by Trellix, a leading company delivering cybersecurity’s broadest AI-powered platform to over 53,000 customers worldwide.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/trellix-lowers-cost-increases-speed-and-adds-delivery-flexibility-with-cost-effective-and-performant-amazon-nova-micro-and-amazon-nova-lite-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistence Ignorance is Overrated</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 22:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re using an ORM and creating “domain entities” you’re likely trying to force your database structure into your domain model. That can work but the point of persistence ignorance is to let you domain model shine without knowing how it’s persisted. But you’re data structure will force you down a certain path if you… Read More »Persistence Ignorance is Overrated The post Persistence Ignorance is Overrated appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Bake is Now Generally Available in Docker Desktop 4.38!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker streamlines developer onboarding and helps organizations set up the right guardrails to give developers the flexibility to innovate within the boundaries of company policies.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ga-launch-docker-bake/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.38: New AI Agent, Multi-Node Kubernetes, and Bake in GA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.38 brings Docker AI Agent for real-time help, plus Bake for faster builds and Multi-Node Kubernetes for better testing. Learn more!
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-38/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Beta Launch of Docker’s AI Agent, Transforming Development Experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:36:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the beta release of the Docker AI Agent and how this context-aware assistant helps developers seamlessly integrate into the Docker suite.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/beta-launch-docker-ai-agent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Copyright for AI-Generated Content? What Businesses Need to Know About the Latest US Copyright Office Rule</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What’s the big deal between AI creation and copyright? Artificial Intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing the way businesses create content, from blog articles and marketing materials to art and software. However, a major decision by the U.S. Copyright Office has made waves: AI-generated content without human involvement cannot be copyrighted. This means that if a business […] The article No Copyright for AI-Generated Content? What Businesses Need to Know About the Latest US Copyright Office Rule was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the general availability of AWS .NET OpenTelemetry libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Observability has become a crucial aspect of modern software development, enabling developers to gain insights into the behavior and performance of their applications. The OpenTelemetry project, a Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) hosted project, has emerged as a powerful solution for generating, collecting, and exporting telemetry data, providing a vendor-neutral and standardized approach to observability. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/announcing-the-general-availability-of-aws-net-opentelemetry-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Let your Copilot Declarative Agent think deep with DeepSeek-R1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 20:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’d like to feature a guest author on our Semantic Kernel blog, Mahmoud Hassan, a Microsoft Valuable Professional (MVP) focused on AI. We’ll turn it over to him to dive into his work below. In recent days, there has been significant attention in the AI community regarding DeepSeek-R1 and its capabilities. Many people […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-let-your-copilot-declarative-agent-think-deep-with-deepseek-r1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OfferUp improved local results by 54% and relevance recall by 27% with multimodal search on Amazon Bedrock and Amazon OpenSearch Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 19:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how OfferUp transformed its foundational search architecture using Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings and OpenSearch Service, significantly increasing user engagement, improving search quality and offering users the ability to search with both text and images. OfferUp selected Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings and Amazon OpenSearch Service for their fully managed capabilities, enabling the development of a robust multimodal search solution with high accuracy and a faster time to market for search and recommendation use cases.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Azure Cosmos DB as a Docker container in CI/CD pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 18:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are lot of benefits to using Docker containers in CI/CD pipelines, especially for stateful systems like databases. For example, when you run integration tests, each CI job can start the database in an isolated container with a clean state, preventing conflicts between tests. This results in a testing environment that is reliable, consistent, and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/use-azure-cosmos-db-as-a-docker-container-in-ci-cd-pipelines 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: Windows MIDI Services Customer Preview 1!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 18:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re releasing the latest version of Windows MIDI Services to the Windows Insider Canary Channel, fully enabled for anyone to evaluate. We recommend this for technical users (as with any Canary release) and not for production use because we will have bugs. You can learn more about the Insider release here. The Windows Insider […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/announcing-windows-midi-services-customer-preview-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing LLM Capabilities with NeMo Guardrails on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 17:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Integrating NeMo Guardrails with Large Language Models (LLMs) is a powerful step forward in deploying AI in customer-facing applications. The example of AnyCompany Pet Supplies illustrates how these technologies can enhance customer interactions while handling refusal and guiding the conversation toward the implemented outcomes. This journey towards ethical AI deployment is crucial for building sustainable, trust-based relationships with customers and shaping a future where technology aligns seamlessly with human values.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a multi-interface AI assistant using Amazon Q and Slack with Amazon CloudFront clickable references from an Amazon S3 bucket</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 16:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There is consistent customer feedback that AI assistants are the most useful when users can interface with them within the productivity tools they already use on a daily basis, to avoid switching applications and context. Web applications like Amazon Q Business and Slack have become essential environments for modern AI assistant deployment. This post explores how diverse interfaces enhance user interaction, improve accessibility, and cater to varying preferences.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On exactly when XAML bindings are evaluated if an element is not yet loaded</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It depends on which abstraction you prefer.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250205-00/?p=110840 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of PHP 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 13:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PHP continues to be a cornerstone of web development, powering millions of websites around the world. Its vibrant and dedicated community values its flexibility and ease of use. But what does the current state of PHP development look like? To uncover deeper insights and trends shaping the ecosystem, we’ve turned to our in-house expert, Brent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/02/state-of-php-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Azure Blob Storage with Virtual Directories in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Blob Storage is designed as a flat storage system without a traditional hierarchical structure. However, by incorporating forward slashes (/) in blob names, you can simulate a directory-like organization, creating virtual directories within your containers. This approach enhances data organization and accessibility, especially when dealing with large datasets. Conclusion Azure Blob Storage, while inherently […] The article Organizing Azure Blob Storage with Virtual Directories in C# was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant Now Supports Claude Models via Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 11:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The wait is over! Anthropic’s Claude models are here for JetBrains AI Assistant, provisioned in Amazon Bedrock 🎉 With the rise of high-quality language models, each excelling in different tasks, developers need flexible options to meet diverse challenges. That’s why we’re focused on providing multi-model support, helping you create workflows that fit your needs. Anthropic’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/jetbrains-ai-assistant-now-supports-claude-models-via-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is DAST? A Guide to Dynamic Application Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 11:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was brought to you by Matt Keib, draft.dev. Dynamic application security testing (DAST) is a security testing method designed to identify vulnerabilities in applications while running. Unlike static testing methods, which analyze code at rest, DAST interacts with live applications and mimics real-world attacks to uncover security flaws. This makes DAST particularly effective […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/what-is-dast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Django Templates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Django templates are a crucial part of the framework. Understanding what they are and why they’re useful can help you build seamless, adaptable, and functional templates for your Django sites and apps. If you’re new to the framework and looking to set up your first Django project, grasping templates is vital. In this guide, you’ll […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/02/the-ultimate-guide-to-django-templates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Template for Online Job Postings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author expresses frustration with inconsistent job postings lacking essential details like tech stacks and qualifications. They propose a standardized job posting format, emphasizing clarity and usability through sections such as Job Overview, Skills, Tech Stack, Job Description, and Company Information. The goal is to streamline the job search for engineers.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/02/05/a-better-template-for-online-job-postings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure OpenAI Realtime API Support in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 05:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the new Realtime API support in the OpenAI JavaScript library, enabling developers to create highly interactive and responsive applications by instantly sending and receiving messages from Azure OpenAI models.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/introducing-azure-openai-realtime-api-support-in-javascript 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Cheuk Ting Ho – New Developer Advocate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 04:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, I am Cheuk, your AI Assistant assistant! Jokes aside, I am the new AI Developer Advocate here at JetBrains. My background is in data science and Python, although I have also recently started learning Rust. I am based in London, UK, and I am very excited to join the team. My home community […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/introducing-cheuk-ting-ho-new-developer-advocate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning AI Prompts into Playing Cards: A Platform Engineering Experiment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 03:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The inspiration for this project came from my desire to leverage AI to create a tangible product that you can hold, touch, and share. Cardmaker showcases the capabilities of modern AI as a tool to help its user craft a custom card deck. But that’s not all. It also provides a unique and tangible product […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/turning-ai-prompts-into-playing-cards-a-platform-engineering-experiment 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Azure OpenAI Chat Completion with data source and Function Calling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 01:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure OpenAI Chat Completion with data source provides powerful capabilities for integrating conversational AI into applications. However, using a data source and function calling in a single request is not supported yet. When both features are enabled, function calling is ignored, and only the data source is used. This presents a challenge when retrieving information, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/using-azure-openai-chat-completion-with-data-source-and-function-calling 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core on .NET Framework servicing release advisory: ASP.NET Core 2.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ASP.NET Core 2.1 has been reshipped as ASP.NET Core 2.3 to help users on the unsupported ASP.NET Core 2.2 move to a supported version.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/servicing-release-advisory-aspnetcore-23 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestrate seamless business systems integrations using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 17:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post showcases how generative AI can be used to logic, reason, and orchestrate integrations using a fictitious business process. It demonstrates strategies and techniques for orchestrating Amazon Bedrock agents and action groups to seamlessly integrate generative AI with existing business systems, enabling efficient data access and unlocking the full potential of generative AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/orchestrate-seamless-business-systems-integrations-using-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full web support for conditional access policies across Azure DevOps and partner web properties</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 17:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that we’ve made significant progress in updating our web authentication stack on Azure DevOps services and partner web properties to utilize Microsoft Entra tokens to handle web sessions. By replacing our previous cookies with Entra tokens, we’ve deepened the integration we have with Microsoft Entra ID on our web experience. This […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/full-web-support-for-conditional-access-policies-across-azure-devops-and-partner-web-properties 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Kiota support for Dart, now in public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 16:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is Kiota, why and how to use it to create API clients for any OpenAPI described APIs and the new language support, Dart.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/openapi/kiota-dart-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing, querying and keeping embeddings updated: options and best practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Embeddings and vectors are becoming common terms not only for engineers involved in AI-related activities but also for those using databases. Some common points of discussion that frequently arise among users familiar with vectors and embeddings include: How can I quickly “vectorize” the content already present in my database? How can I keep the vectors […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/storing-querying-and-keeping-embeddings-updated-options-and-best-practices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The original name for Flexible Single Master Operations in Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not that kind of F-word.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250204-00/?p=110834 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s Deep Research Agent: Automated Research and Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 14:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI has recently unveiled “Deep Research,” an advanced AI agent designed to autonomously conduct comprehensive research by synthesizing vast amounts of online information and executing multi-step tasks. This innovation aims to match the capabilities of human research analysts, delivering detailed reports in a fraction of the time traditionally required. Who Is It For? Deep Research […] The article OpenAI’s Deep Research Agent: Automated Research and Analysis was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps in Game Development With Rust and Bevy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 13:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some of us might remember this 15-year-old Abstruse Goose comic about our choices in life. Learning the theory of computations might not be the most direct path to video game development. However, you still need to learn programming, some math (at least geometry), and mechanics – or as it’s often somewhat erroneously labeled – physics. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/02/04/first-steps-in-game-development-with-rust-and-bevy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your fonts are now preserved when changing theme</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you find yourself adjusting your font settings every time you change themes in Visual Studio, We’ve made some changes that we think will help. The latest update in Visual Studio 2022 allows theme switching without affecting font settings. This feature maintains the selected font face and size regardless of the chosen theme, while font […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/your-fonts-are-now-preserved-when-changing-theme 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Podman and How Does it Compare to Docker?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker has long been the dominant container engine, but it’s not the only one. After all, Kubernetes moved away from Docker several years ago to a different engine. An alternative to Docker for running containers on your local machine has been gaining traction in recent years: Podman. Podman is an open-source container engine developed by […] The article What is Podman and How Does it Compare to Docker? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify Your Integration Testing with Test Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 09:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement Test Containers in .NET for robust integration testing. Discover best practices, practical examples, and advanced implementation techniques using Docker.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/test-containers-dotnet-simplify-integration-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting multiple .NET SDK versions in a source generator: Creating a source generator - Part 14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how I updated my NetEscapades.EnumGenerators projects to support multi-targeting two different .NET SDK versions
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-source-generator-part-14-supporting-multiple-sdk-versions-in-a-source-generator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel Roadmap H1 2025: Accelerating Agents, Processes, and Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 05:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we move into the first half of 2025, I’m excited to share our ambitious roadmap that we hope will enable you to build even more sophisticated AI applications with Semantic Kernel. Agent Framework 1.0 By the end of Q1 2025, the SK Agent Framework will transition from preview to general availability (GA). This milestone […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-roadmap-h1-2025-accelerating-agents-processes-and-integration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step-by-Step Guide: User Provisioning with SAML Authentication in GitHub Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 02:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide demonstrates how to seamlessly set up user access in GitHub Enterprise using Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) authentication. The process connects a user’s GitHub account with your organization’s identity provider (such as Microsoft Entra ID or Okta), enabling secure and streamlined access management. The diagram above describes the process when a user […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/step-by-step-guide-user-provisioning-with-saml 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D2: like Mermaid, but better. Syntax, installation, and practical usage tips</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            D2 is an open-source tool to design architectural layouts using a declarative syntax. It’s a textual format, which can also be stored under source control. Let’s see how it works, how you can install it, and some practical usage tips.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/d2-diagrams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctors generate faster, more accurate medical charts with Sayvant and Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 20:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is guest authored by Justin Mardjuki, CEO, Sayvant. Emergency rooms and urgent care facilities handle an estimated 350 million visits each year. Acute care environments are fast-paced, unpredictable, and high stakes. In these settings, providing care quickly is paramount. That’s why we created Sayvant, the leading clinical documentation AI solution for acute care. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/doctors-generate-faster-more-accurate-medical-charts-with-sayvant-and-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Kubernetes?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 18:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kubernetes is an open-source platform designed to manage, automate, and scale containerized applications efficiently. It has become the go-to solution for orchestrating containers in cloud environments. If you’ve ever wondered how large-scale applications like trading platforms handle fluctuating workloads, Kubernetes is the key player behind the scenes. To better understand Kubernetes, think of an orchestra. […] The article What is Kubernetes? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the ‘Simplify Microsoft Power Platform Deployments by Using Pipelines’ Learning Path</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 17:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Learn offers many Power Platform learn modules. Now, we are expanding the collection with a new release! Pipelines in Power Platform is a managed environments feature that has been released a while back now! Over time, it has improved significantly with updates like SPN support, deployment pages, extensibility, and personal pipelines. Many people requested […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-the-simplify-microsoft-power-platform-deployments-by-using-pipelines-learning-path 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate video Q&amp;A workflows using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Transcribe, and thoughtful UX design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 17:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The solution presented in this post demonstrates a powerful pattern for accelerating video and audio review workflows while maintaining human oversight. By combining the power of AI models in Amazon Bedrock with human expertise, you can create tools that not only boost productivity but also maintain the critical element of human judgment in important decision-making processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-video-qa-workflows-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-amazon-transcribe-and-thoughtful-ux-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost team innovation, productivity, and knowledge sharing with Amazon Q Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Q Apps can help maximize the value of existing knowledge resources and improve productivity among various teams, ranging from finance to DevOps to support engineers. We share specific examples of how the generative AI assistant can enable surface relevant information, distill complex topics, generate custom content, and execute workflows—all while maintaining robust security and data governance controls.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-team-innovation-productivity-and-knowledge-sharing-with-amazon-q-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stored Procedure Caching in Data API builder Now Supported</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing Procedure Cache Data API builder (DAB) has long supported Level 1 cache for tables and views. Level 1 is an in-memory cache that automatically stores frequent queries or slow-changing data in the API layer, bypassing several database queries. Today, Data API builder (DAB) also supports Level 1 cache for stored procedures. This is important. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/procedure-caching-in-data-api-builder-now-supported 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update to Azure DevOps Allowed IP addresses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce some important upgrades to our networking infrastructure that will enhance the performance and reliability of our service. As part of these infrastructure upgrades, we are introducing new IP addresses that you will need to allow list in your firewall configurations. What’s Changing And Why? We are transitioning from the current […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/update-to-ado-allowed-ip-addresses 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Trump’s Tariffs Threaten U.S. Dominance in Artificial Intelligence?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The U.S.A. has been the dominant force in Artificial Intelligence so far. The release of DeepSeek R1 recently from a Chinese company is showing to challenge this dominance. AI models aren’t the only factor for the United States to remain dominant in AI. Both AI training and running models are dependent on GPUs (graphics processing […] The article Will Trump’s Tariffs Threaten U.S. Dominance in Artificial Intelligence? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize your AI-generated git commit messages</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When it comes to collaborative software development, clear and effective communication is key. One area that often gets overlooked is the Git commit message. Poorly crafted commit messages can lead to confusion and inefficiencies within a team. That’s why we’ve built on the suggestions and feedback for the AI-generated commit messages, and now you can […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/customize-your-ai-generated-git-commit-messages 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On trying to log an exception as it leaves your scope</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can&#39;t watch it from an object on the outside.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250203-00/?p=110830 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – January Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 14:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2025 is here, and it’s brought lots of new educational content. Dive into the latest tech trends, learning opportunities, insightful events, and nifty plugins to boost your productivity. Happy reading.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/02/03/jetbrains-academy-december-january/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.2 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 13:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.2 bug-fix update is out and ready to be installed on your servers! This update addresses over 30 issues, including: See TeamCity 2024.12.2 Upgrade Notes for the complete list. Why update? Staying up to date with minor releases ensures your TeamCity instance benefits from: Compatibility TeamCity 2024.12.2 shares the same data format […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/teamcity-2024-12-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from MSTest to xUnit using a Roslyn analyzer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Both MSTest and xUnit are great test framework. If you are curious about, I&#39;ve written many blog posts about them MSTest series If you want to migrate to xUnit from MSTest, I&#39;ve written a Roslyn Analyzer. This analyzer reports all MSTest attributes and assertions in your code. It can also replace most of them with xUnit equivalent. Note that the goal of this analyzer is not to handle 100% of the cases,…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Debugging GraalVM Native Images With IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 11:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Dmitry Chuyko and Anton Arhipov, where we’ll explore the tools and workflows for debugging GraalVM Native Images with IntelliJ IDEA. Date: February 13, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract GraalVM Native Image allows you to transform your application into a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/new-livestream-debugging-graalvm-native-images-with-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Qt Renderers in CLion’s Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest CLion 2025.1 EAP build, 251.18673.49, includes one of the most requested features: support for Qt renderers (also known as Qt pretty printers and Qt debugging helpers) in the debugger. This feature allows you to view Qt variables such as QString, QByteArray, and other data types in a human-readable form. This enhancement makes it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/02/introducing-qt-renderers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple client sign-in customizations using Duende identity provider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 06:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/duende-multi-tenant Setup The solution is setup using three […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/02/03/multiple-client-sign-in-customizations-using-duende-identity-provider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
