<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:16:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The start of the new year is the perfect time to share our plans for JetBrains Rider 2025.1. These plans are subject to change based on available resources, evolving development priorities, and shifts in the .NET landscape. Some features and improvements may be postponed to a later release date. With that in mind, let’s dive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/08/rider-2025-1-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Plan Support for GitHub Copilot Available on JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, developers! Welcome to our very first blog post dedicated to GitHub Copilot Plugin for JetBrains IDEs in 2025. We are excited to share that the new Free Plan for GitHub Copilot has been available for everyone on JetBrains IDEs! Whether you use IntelliJ IDEA (Ultimate, Community, Educational), PyCharm(Professional, Community, Educational), WebStorm, PhpStorm, Rider, or […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/free-plan-support-for-github-copilot-available-on-jetbrains-ides 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new year has arrived, and we’re kicking it off with another handpicked selection of must-read tutorials and the latest news you won’t want to miss. This issue starts with an amazing featured content section with Donald Raab. Settle in and scroll your way to some fresh knowledge! Featured Content Greetings, Java Annotated Monthly readers! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/java-annotated-monthly-january-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>azd CDN changing January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 22:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post makes customers aware of a critical Content Delivery Network (CDN) change for azd (the Azure Developer CLI) because the CDN provider is changing from Edgio to Azure Front Door.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azd-cdn-changing-january-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Update: blog migration to quantum.microsoft.com</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 21:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that the Q# blog will be migrating to a new home at Azure Quantum in Feb 2025. This move will allow us to provide you with a more integrated and enhanced experience, featuring the latest updates and resources in the world of quantum computing. Stay tuned for more details and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/qsharp/important-update-blog-migration-to-quantum-microsoft-com 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire Quick Tip – Managing Container &amp; Data Lifetime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Aspire 9 adds new control over the lifetime of containers on your local developer environment. Let&#39;s look at how to manage them with the new APIs!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-aspire-container-lifetime 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Align and monitor your Amazon Bedrock powered insurance assistance chatbot to responsible AI principles with AWS Audit Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI applications should be developed with adequate controls for steering the behavior of FMs. Responsible AI considerations such as privacy, security, safety, controllability, fairness, explainability, transparency and governance help ensure that AI systems are trustworthy. In this post, we demonstrate how to use the AWS generative AI best practices framework on AWS Audit Manager to evaluate this insurance claim agent from a responsible AI lens.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/align-and-monitor-your-amazon-bedrock-powered-insurance-assistance-chatbot-to-responsible-ai-principles-with-aws-audit-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Stock Exchange Group uses Amazon Q Business to enhance post-trade client services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore a client services agent assistant application developed by the London Stock Exchange Group (LSEG) using Amazon Q Business. We will discuss how Amazon Q Business saved time in generating answers, including summarizing documents, retrieving answers to complex Member enquiries, and combining information from different data sources (while providing in-text citations to the data sources used for each answer).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/london-stock-exchange-group-uses-amazon-q-business-to-enhance-post-trade-client-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate large language models for your machine translation tasks on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post with accompanying code presents a solution to experiment with real-time machine translation using foundation models (FMs) available in Amazon Bedrock. It can help collect more data on the value of LLMs for your content translation use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-large-language-models-for-your-machine-translation-tasks-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parameta accelerates client email resolution with Amazon Bedrock Flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Parameta used Amazon Bedrock Flows to transform their manual client email processing into an automated, intelligent workflow that reduced resolution times from weeks to days while maintaining high accuracy and operational control.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/parameta-accelerates-client-email-resolution-with-amazon-bedrock-flows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gesellschaft zur Stärkung der Verben: The German Society for the Irregularization of Verbs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stand strong and proud.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250107-01/?p=110724 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergency power resets on Lenovo, HP, Dell, and Acer laptops</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking for the magic button.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250107-00/?p=110719 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up a Kubernetes Cluster on Docker Desktop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We walk through the steps to start a Kubernetes cluster on Docker Desktop and provide troubleshooting tips to ensure a smooth experience.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-set-up-a-kubernetes-cluster-on-docker-desktop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking with Visual Studio Profiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Visual Studio 17.13 Preview we have released our updated BenchmarkDotNet diagnosers, allowing you to use more of the tools in the performance profiler to analyze benchmarks. With this change it is super quick to dig into CPU usage and allocations of benchmarks making the measure, change, measure cycle quick and efficient. Benchmarking a real […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/benchmarking-with-visual-studio-profiler 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a High-Performance Message Queue with Redis Streams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Beyond Pub/Sub: Implementing Reliable Work Distribution with Redis When developers reach for Redis as a messaging solution, they typically gravitate toward its Pub/Sub capabilities. While Pub/Sub excels at broadcasting messages to multiple subscribers, it falls short for reliable work distribution scenarios. Messages are transient - any offline
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/building-a-high-performance-message-queue-with-redis-streams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an interceptor with a source generator: Creating a source generator - Part 11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how interceptors work, and how you can implement an interceptor using a source generator and the GetInterceptableLocation API
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-source-generator-part-11-implementing-an-interceptor-with-a-source-generator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Code Java中的JavaC支持发布！</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家新年好！我们很高兴宣布，Visual Studio Code Java、JDT 和 JDT-LS 现已部分支持使用 Javac 作为底层编译器。这项支持是红帽和微软经过近一年合作的成果。 此更改旨在确保对最新 Java 特性的及时支持，并使 VS Code 上的 Java 语言支持与常见构建工具（如 Maven、Gradle）更加一致。许多用户希望获得更无缝的开箱即用开发体验，我们相信引入 Javac 是实现这一目标的重要第一步。 用户可以从基于 Javac 的工具中获得以下好处： 更符合 Java 规范的编译器正确性 在 VS Code 和 Eclipse 中更快地支持新 Java 版本 减少 JDT 和 JDT-LS 团队的维护负担 更轻松地测试预览功能和尚未发布的 Java 版本 请注意，基于 Javac 的 JDT 是 ECJ 编译器的另一选项，并非要完全替代 ECJ。目前，VS Code Java 中的基于 Javac 的支持默认处于关闭状态，可以通过以下方式启用： […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/visual-studio-code-java-javc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Neural Rendering in DirectX: Cooperative Vector Support Coming Soon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Neural Rendering: A New Paradigm in 3D Graphics Programming In the constantly advancing landscape of 3D graphics, neural rendering technology represents a significant evolution. Neural rendering broadly defines the suite of techniques that leverage AI/ML to dramatically transform traditional graphics pipelines. These new methods promise to push the boundaries of what’s possible in real-time graphics. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/enabling-neural-rendering-in-directx-cooperative-vector-support-coming-soon 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Courses for Java Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tired of the same predictable and monotonous Java tutorials? So was I. I used to think all Java courses were the same. Endless tutorials where someone talks about getters and setters in a monotonous, robotic voice while you put all of your effort into just trying to stay awake. After months of intensive research and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/best-courses-for-java-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness Functions in Software Architecture: measuring things to ensure prosperity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Non-functional requirements matter, but we often forget to validate them. You can measure them by setting up Fitness Functions.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/fitness-functions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing images to LLMs in C# with Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I recently posted about how to get started calling LLMs with C# using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI NuGet package. The model we chose to use was gpt-4o-mini, which has the advantage of being &amp;quot;multimodal&amp;quot;, as it can accept not only text input, but images as well. In this post I&#39;ll show how you can pass an image to this model using Microsoft.Extensions.AI and ask it to describe the image. It&#39;s relatively straightforward, but as always seems to be the case with these things, there was a gotcha I ran into.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently build and tune custom log anomaly detection models with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through the process to build an automated mechanism using Amazon SageMaker to process your log data, run training iterations over it to obtain the best-performing anomaly detection model, and register it with the Amazon SageMaker Model Registry for your customers to use it.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/efficiently-build-and-tune-custom-log-anomaly-detection-models-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing personal access token (PAT) usage across Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the new year, we’ll be making moves towards strengthening Microsoft and our customers’ security posture in regards to the usage and creation of personal access tokens (PATs). If you’ve been following this blog, you may have noticed we’ve been distancing away from PATs as the recommended authentication method for Azure DevOps APIs by offering […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/reducing-pat-usage-across-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (December 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 18:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.12.16 registry release, 2024-12-09 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout December. This release includes a command line option to force vcpkg to use classic mode even if a manifest file is found along with bug fixes. Some […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-december-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) continues to permeate our daily lives, but the way we interact with these systems remains an evolving landscape. In a recent episode of the Hanselminutes podcast, host Scott Hanselman sat down with designer and technologist Maggie Appleton to explore a fascinating question: What is AI’s UI (User Interface)? Their conversation sheds light […] The article What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack Roadmap for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A belated Happy New Year’s to everybody! The “Critter Stack” had a huge 2024, and I listed off some of the highlights of the improvements we made in Critter Stack Year in Review for 2024. For 2025, we’ve reordered our priority order from what I was writing last summer. I think we might genuinely focus more … Continue reading Critter Stack Roadmap for 2025 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/01/06/critter-stack-roadmap-for-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I tell whether a change to a control was due to the user or due to my program?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You know when it was done by your program because you did it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250106-00/?p=110715 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking insights with Meter Histogram in the profiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you struggling with performance bottlenecks in your applications? Look no further! Visual Studio 2022 introduces the Meter Histogram feature in its performance profiling suite, providing you with the tools to analyze and visualize histogram data like never before. The Meter Histogram is a key enhancement to Visual Studio’s performance profiling suite. This feature enables […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/unlocking-insights-with-meter-histogram-in-the-profiler 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring CollectionsMarshal for Dictionary</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unlike ConcurrentDictionary, Dictionary does not have a GetOrAdd method. This method is useful when you want to add a key-value pair to the dictionary if the key does not exist, or return the value if the key already exists. The naive implementation of this method looks like this: public static TValue GetOrAdd&amp;lt;TKey, TValue&amp;gt;(this Dictionary&amp;lt;TKey, TValue&amp;gt; dict, TKey key, TValue value) where TKey : notnull {…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/exploring-collectionsmarshal-for-dictionary.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Parallel Processing of Collections in Microsoft .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses the performance of various parallelism techniques for iterating over collections in .NET, comparing parallel methods such as Parallel.For and AsParallel() with traditional approaches. It highlights that while parallel methods can enhance performance for large collections, traditional methods often outperform them, particularly with smaller collections. Recommendations and a new method, FastModifyCollection, are introduced for efficient processing.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/01/06/evaluating-the-parallel-processing-of-collections-in-microsoft-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persist Values With AsyncLocal in C# Async Flow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explain the AsyncLocal class and how to persist values across an async flow with the AsyncLocal class in C#. We’ll start by describing the challenge that AsyncLocal solves and continue with examples of how it does that. We’ll scratch the surface of the AsyncLocal inner workings and finish with the cases […] The post Persist Values With AsyncLocal in C# Async Flow appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JasperFx Software in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2025/05_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 18:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2025/05_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can contact JasperFx at any time by dropping us an email at sales@jasperfx.net. 2024 was a good year for JasperFx Software LLC for the simple fact that we’ve proven to have an effective business model and some staying power for the future. Along the way, we partnered with clients in eight different countries on … Continue reading JasperFx Software in 2025 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/01/05/jasperfx-software-in-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important: Switching CDN providers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2025/05_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2025/05_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The current content delivery network (CDN) provider Edgio, used by Azure DevOps is retiring. We’re urgently transitioning to a solution served by Akamai and Azure Front Door CDNs to maintain the responsiveness of our services. What this means for you For most of you, this transition will be seamless. To ensure that you can continue […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/important-switching-cdn-providers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling Azure OpenAI models from C# with Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2025/04_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2025/04_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI opens up a lot of exciting possibilities for developers to use its capabilities within their own applications, but it can feel a bit overwhelming getting started. You have a lot of choices around which models to use and how best to interact with them. In this post I want to go through the steps to implement a basic chat with an LLM hosted in Azure using C#, by taking advantage of the new Microsoft.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing Clean Architecture Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2025/04_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2025/04_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Drawing from years of experience, I share my battle-tested approach to unit testing Clean Architecture use cases in .NET, focusing on the critical balance between code coverage and test quality. Through practical examples and real-world scenarios, I&#39;ll demonstrate how to write effective tests that not only catch bugs but also provide confidence in your code deployments.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/unit-testing-clean-architecture-use-cases 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing an ERROR_KEY_DELETED error when trying to open HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just an exercise to show that it can be done, even though it&#39;s highly unlikely to occur in practice.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250103-00/?p=110704 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Peak Software Development Efficiency with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get the key to mastering software development efficiency for your team with Docker.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mastering-software-development-efficiency/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana 2024.3 Is Here Along With a Special Offer for New Users!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Happy New Year! In case you missed it, the Qodana team ended 2024 with a bang and released Qodana 2024.3. What’s in the latest release? New security functionality, a fresh set of Android linter rules, and more to help your team prioritize code excellence. Let’s take a look at what’s available in more detail. To […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/01/qodana-2024-3-is-here-along-with-a-special-offer-for-new-users/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated System Requirements for  Linux GNU C Library (glibc)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with v2025.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will require glibc 2.28 or higher on Linux x64 systems. This change is being made to address potential security vulnerabilities associated with building and running our software on outdated systems and to ensure our products evolve with modern frameworks and technologies. By enforcing a more recent glibc version, we aim to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/updated-system-requirements-for-linux-gnu-c-library-glibc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>探索Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData与Qdrant和Azure AI搜索的使用</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 05:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Bruno Capuano的Exploring Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData with Qdrant and Azure AI Search 了解如何使用 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData并通过 Qdrant 和 Azure AI 搜索实现语义搜索。 使用 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData 深入了解语义搜索：Qdrant 和 Azure AI 搜索 语义搜索正在改变应用程序查找和解释数据的方式，它专注于含义，而不仅仅是关键字匹配。随着 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData 的发布，.NET 开发人员拥有了一组新的构建模块，用于将基于向量的搜索功能集成到其应用程序中。在本文中，我们将探讨使用本地Qdrant和Azure AI搜索这两种实现方式来进行语义搜索。 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData 快速介绍 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData 是一组 .NET代码库，旨在管理 .NET 应用程序中基于向量的数据。这些库为与向量存储交互提供了一个统一的 C# 抽象层，使开发人员能够有效地处理嵌入并执行向量相似性查询。 要详细了解该库的架构和功能，推荐阅读 Luis 的精彩博客文章。 在这篇博客文章中，我们将展示两个实际用例： 在本地使用 Qdrant 进行语义搜索。 利用 Azure AI 搜索进行企业级向量搜索。 要运行这些演示，您需要使用 Ollama 为生成嵌入提供的模型之一。在本示例中，使用的模型是 all-minilm。 安装 Ollama。 下载 all-minilm 模型。 准备一个符合 OCI 标准的容器运行时，例如： Docker Desktop 或 Podman。 使用 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e6%8e%a2%e7%b4%a2microsoft-extensions-vectordata%e4%b8%8eqdrant%e5%92%8cazure-ai%e6%90%9c%e7%b4%a2%e7%9a%84%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Slice Architecture isn’t technical</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Migrate to a Vertical Slice Architecture from a monolith? Is it more like microservices? Does it replace Clean Architecture? None of the above. It’s about being driven by cohesion of business capabilities and business processes. It has nothing to do with layers or physical deployment concerns. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds… Read More »Vertical Slice Architecture isn’t technical The post Vertical Slice Architecture isn’t technical appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could I be getting ERROR_KEY_DELETED for HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software when the user logs off?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Probably not, but there are some edge cases.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250102-00/?p=110702 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Secure Development Environments Are Essential for Modern Software Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure development environments are the backbone of modern software teams, ensuring speed and innovation don’t come at the cost of vulnerabilities, inefficiencies, or eroded trust.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-secure-development-environments-are-essential-for-modern-software-teams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Ready</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Release Candidate for MPS 2024.3 is now available for download! Grab it and be among the first to experience the new functionality. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 RC You can learn about the new features in more detail in this blog post. The full list of fixed issues can be found here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/01/the-mps-2024-3-rc-ready/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is it possible to get ERROR_KEY_DELETED when I’m creating a key?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2025/01_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2025/01_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The key that got deleted is not the one you are trying to create.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250101-00/?p=110700 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
