<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:41:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Systems Mistakes Nobody Warns You About: Consistency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most common and very overlooked issues when writing a distributed system is consistency. You have one thing happening in one part of your system that triggers something else to happen in another part of the system, except it doesn’t happen. And that can be a nightmare to deal with. This problem is… Read More »Distributed Systems Mistakes Nobody Warns You About: Consistency The post Distributed Systems Mistakes Nobody Warns You About: Consistency appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New capabilities in Amazon SageMaker AI continue to transform how organizations develop AI models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 19:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share some of the new innovations in SageMaker AI that can accelerate how you build and train AI models. These innovations include new observability capabilities in SageMaker HyperPod, the ability to deploy JumpStart models on HyperPod, remote connections to SageMaker AI from local development environments, and fully managed MLflow 3.0.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-capabilities-in-amazon-sagemaker-ai-continue-to-transform-how-organizations-develop-ai-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate foundation model development with one-click observability in Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With a one-click installation of the Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS) add-on for SageMaker HyperPod observability, you can consolidate health and performance data from NVIDIA DCGM, instance-level Kubernetes node exporters, Elastic Fabric Adapter (EFA), integrated file systems, Kubernetes APIs, Kueue, and SageMaker HyperPod task operators. In this post, we walk you through installing and using the unified dashboards of the out-of-the-box observability feature in SageMaker HyperPod. We cover the one-click installation from the Amazon SageMaker AI console, navigating the dashboard and metrics it consolidates, and advanced topics such as setting up custom alerts.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating generative AI development with fully managed MLflow 3.0 on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon SageMaker now offers fully managed support for MLflow 3.0, streamlining AI experimentation and accelerating your generative AI journey from idea to production. This release transforms managed MLflow from experiment tracking to providing end-to-end observability, reducing time-to-market for generative AI development.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-generative-ai-development-with-fully-managed-mlflow-3-0-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker HyperPod launches model deployments to accelerate the generative AI model development lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we announce Amazon SageMaker HyperPod support for deploying foundation models from SageMaker JumpStart, as well as custom or fine-tuned models from Amazon S3 or Amazon FSx. This new capability allows customers to train, fine-tune, and deploy models on the same HyperPod compute resources, maximizing resource utilization across the entire model lifecycle.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-launches-model-deployments-to-accelerate-the-generative-ai-model-development-lifecycle/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your AI workflows by connecting to SageMaker Studio from Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI developers and machine learning (ML) engineers can now use the capabilities of Amazon SageMaker Studio directly from their local Visual Studio Code (VS Code). With this capability, you can use your customized local VS Code setup, including AI-assisted development tools, custom extensions, and debugging tools while accessing compute resources and your data in SageMaker Studio. In this post, we show you how to remotely connect your local VS Code to SageMaker Studio development environments to use your customized development environment while accessing Amazon SageMaker AI compute resources.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2025 Docker State of Application Development Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Executive summary The 2025 Docker State of Application Development Report offers an ultra high-resolution view of today’s fast-evolving dev landscape. Drawing insights from over 4,500 developers, engineers, and tech leaders — three times more users than last year — the survey explores tools, workflows, pain points, and industry trends. In this our third report, key...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/2025-docker-state-of-app-dev/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize AI responses from GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot along with its various models are capable of some amazing things. When in Agent mode the AI can create parts of or even entire applications from your written (or spoken!) instructions. You can just feel the vibes (coding), can&#39;t you? [alert type=&amp;quot;note&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Note&amp;quot;]GitHub Copilot Agent mode is more than code completi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/customize-ai-responses-from-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular Ktor: Building Backends for Scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ktor offers a lightweight, flexible approach to building web applications that differs from more opinionated all-in-one frameworks. While Ktor’s minimalist design might seem challenging at first, a little experience using our modules can go a long way towards building for scale. In this article, I’ll show you some techniques for introducing modularity to your Ktor […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/modular-ktor-building-backends-for-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use K8sGPT and Amazon Bedrock for simplified Kubernetes cluster maintenance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates the best practices to run K8sGPT in AWS with Amazon Bedrock in two modes: K8sGPT CLI and K8sGPT Operator. It showcases how the solution can help SREs simplify Kubernetes cluster management through continuous monitoring and operational intelligence.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-k8sgpt-and-amazon-bedrock-for-simplified-kubernetes-cluster-maintenance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rocket streamlines the home buying experience with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rocket AI Agent is more than a digital assistant. It’s a reimagined approach to client engagement, powered by agentic AI. By combining Amazon Bedrock Agents with Rocket’s proprietary data and backend systems, Rocket has created a smarter, more scalable, and more human experience available 24/7, without the wait. This post explores how Rocket brought that vision to life using Amazon Bedrock Agents, powering a new era of AI-driven support that is consistently available, deeply personalized, and built to take action.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an MCP application with Mistral models on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates building an intelligent AI assistant using Mistral AI models on AWS and MCP, integrating real-time location services, time data, and contextual memory to handle complex multimodal queries. This use case, restaurant recommendations, serves as an example, but this extensible framework can be adapted for enterprise use cases by modifying MCP server configurations to connect with your specific data sources and business systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-mcp-application-with-mistral-models-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build real-time conversational AI experiences using Amazon Nova Sonic and LiveKit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            mazon Nova Sonic is now integrated with LiveKit’s WebRTC framework, a widely used platform that enables developers to build real-time audio, video, and data communication applications. This integration makes it possible for developers to build conversational voice interfaces without needing to manage complex audio pipelines or signaling protocols. In this post, we explain how this integration works, how it addresses the historical challenges of voice-first applications, and some initial steps to start using this solution.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our first attempt to detect and report all unhandled C&#43;&#43; exceptions as well as all unhandled structured exceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we saw that installing an unhandled structured exception filter prevents the Microsoft Visual C++ runtime from converting unhandled C++ exceptions into
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250710-00/?p=111366 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Brings Compose to the Agent Era: Building AI Agents is Now Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 10:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agents are the future, and if you haven’t already started building agents, you probably will soon. Across industries and use cases, agents can act on our behalf, and offload repetitive work, because they can act on our behalf with judgment and context. But while agentic development is moving fast, today it’s tedious, hard, and not...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-ai-agents-with-docker-compose/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Agent to Update Dataverse Table Content</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Some time ago, I watched a demo of an AI agent updating a row in a table. The scenario was simple but effectively demonstrated the tool&#39;s capabilities and potential benefits for users. This made me wonder whether the same could be achieved using Microsoft Power Platforms. This article explores how to build an agent in Mi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/use-agent-to-update-dataverse-table 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize GitHub Copilot in JetBrains with Custom Instructions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 04:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, you can use Custom Instructions in JetBrains to speed up development while staying aligned with your team&#39;s coding standards and personal preferences.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/customize-github-copilot-in-jetbrains-with-custom-instructions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic configuration updates in .NET using Parameter Store and Secrets Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 03:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Loading configurations and secrets in .NET applications is a common practice. However, it comes with challenges in storing and accessing them securely and dynamically, without the need for application restart. AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store provides a centralized solution for storing and managing configurations and secrets data. This blog post explores an advanced approach to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/dynamic-configuration-updates-in-net-using-parameter-store-and-secrets-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS AI infrastructure with NVIDIA Blackwell: Two powerful compute solutions for the next frontier of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we announce general availability of Amazon EC2 P6e-GB200 UltraServers and P6-B200 instances, powered by NVIDIA Blackwell GPUs, designed for training and deploying the largest, most sophisticated AI models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-ai-infrastructure-with-nvidia-blackwell-two-powerful-compute-solutions-for-the-next-frontier-of-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock retail intelligence by transforming data into actionable insights using generative AI with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 20:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business for Retail Intelligence is an AI-powered assistant designed to help retail businesses streamline operations, improve customer service, and enhance decision-making processes. This solution is specifically engineered to be scalable and adaptable to businesses of various sizes, helping them compete more effectively. In this post, we show how you can use Amazon Q Business for Retail Intelligence to transform your data into actionable insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-retail-intelligence-by-transforming-data-into-actionable-insights-using-generative-ai-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the .NET MAUI Team uses GitHub Copilot for Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Around the time of Microsoft Build 2025, the new GitHub Copilot Coding Agent was unveiled and made widely available across GitHub. With AI evolving at a dizzying pace in recent months, we imagined a &amp;quot;dream scenario&amp;quot;: A GitHub
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/maui-team-copilot-tips 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Use AI Agents for COBOL Migration and Mainframe Modernization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Legacy modernization is one of the most frequently raised challenges customers approach us with. They want to eliminate technical debt and run applications cloud-native. Obviously, there are different levels of complexity in legacy modernization, but the most challenging cases remain mai
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-we-use-ai-agents-for-cobol-migration-and-mainframe-modernization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratize data for timely decisions with text-to-SQL at Parcel Perform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The business team in Parcel Perform often needs access to data to answer questions related to merchants’ parcel deliveries, such as “Did we see a spike in delivery delays last week? If so, in which transit facilities were this observed, and what was the primary cause of the issue?” Previously, the data team had to manually form the query and run it to fetch the data. With the new generative AI-powered text-to-SQL capability in Parcel Perform, the business team can self-serve their data needs by using an AI assistant interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases structured data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to make your Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL-Compatible Edition data available for natural language querying through Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases while maintaining data freshness.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/query-amazon-aurora-postgresql-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-structured-data/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure fine-grained access to Amazon Bedrock models using Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use SageMaker Unified Studio and AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) to establish a robust permission framework for Amazon Bedrock models. We show how administrators can precisely manage which users and teams have access to specific models within a secure, collaborative environment. We guide you through creating granular permissions to control model access, with code examples for common enterprise governance scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve conversational AI response times for enterprise applications with the Amazon Bedrock streaming API and AWS AppSync</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how integrating an Amazon Bedrock streaming API with AWS AppSync subscriptions significantly enhances AI assistant responsiveness and user satisfaction. By implementing this streaming approach, the global financial services organization reduced initial response times for complex queries by approximately 75%—from 10 seconds to just 2–3 seconds—empowering users to view responses as they’re generated rather than waiting for complete answers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-conversational-ai-response-times-for-enterprise-applications-with-the-amazon-bedrock-streaming-api-and-aws-appsync/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale generative AI use cases, Part 1: Multi-tenant hub and spoke architecture using AWS Transit Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            n this two-part series, we discuss a hub and spoke architecture pattern for building a multi-tenant and multi-account architecture. This pattern supports abstractions for shared services across use cases and teams, helping create secure, scalable, and reliable generative AI systems. In Part 1, we present a centralized hub for generative AI service abstractions and tenant-specific spokes, using AWS Transit Gateway for cross-account interoperability.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-generative-ai-use-cases-part-1-multi-tenant-hub-and-spoke-architecture-using-aws-transit-gateway/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing patches that impact the latest version of our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can dow
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/july-patches-for-azure-devops-server-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose your way with Provider services!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Docker Compose v2.36.0, we&#39;re excited to introduce a powerful new feature: provider services. This extension point opens up Docker Compose to interact not only with containers but also with any kind of external system, all while keeping the familiar Compose file at the center of the workflow. In this blog post,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-compose-with-provider-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker MCP Gateway: Open Source, Secure Infrastructure for Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since releasing the Docker MCP Toolkit, we’ve seen strong community adoption, including steady growth in MCP server usage and over 1 million pulls from the Docker MCP Catalog. With the community, we’re laying the groundwork by standardizing how developers define, run, and share agent-based workloads with Docker Compose. Now, we’re expanding on that foundation with...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-gateway-secure-infrastructure-for-agentic-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When I install an unhandled structured exception filter, why doesn&#39;t &lt;CODE&gt;std::&lt;WBR&gt;terminate&lt;/CODE&gt; get called?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For diagnostic and reliability purposes, a customer wanted to detect and report all all unhandled C++ exceptions as well as all unhandled structured exceptions. Their idea was to cover both exits: Use set_terminate to install a std::terminate handler, which is called when a C++ exception goes unhand
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250709-00/?p=111360 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.5-1 and 1.23.11-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 06:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-5-1-and-1-23-11-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam &amp; Jony</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building a family of AI products for everyone.
Link to article: https://openai.com/sam-and-jony 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate AI development with Amazon Bedrock API keys</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 20:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce a significant improvement to the developer experience of Amazon Bedrock: API keys. API keys provide quick access to the Amazon Bedrock APIs, streamlining the authentication process so that developers can focus on building rather than configuration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-ai-development-with-amazon-bedrock-api-keys/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework July 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for July 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of July 08, 2025. This update contains non-security
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-july-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Adds More Design Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 17:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new YouTrack 2025.2 release brings further design updates to make working on your projects easier. You also get a shared default dashboard and a growing set of useful apps. Here’s what’s new: Redesigned project page for all users Navigate to project information in one place Project overview pages now offer an advanced project-centric navigation, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/07/youtrack-adds-more-design-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.9 Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 17:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the availability of TypeScript 5.9 Beta. To get started using the beta, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@beta Let&#39;s take a look at what&#39;s new in TypeScript 5
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-9-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q2 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 16:13:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Community highlights Speak at JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2025 – Submit a Talk Plugin Developer Conf returns on November 5, 2025, and we’re looking for speakers to join the lineup! This free, one-day online event brings together the JetBrains plugin developer community to share insights on building and managing plugins. Last year’s online conference […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/07/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q2-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating data science innovation: How Bayer Crop Science used AWS AI/ML services to build their next-generation MLOps service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 16:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Bayer Crop Science manages large-scale data science operations by training models for their data analytics needs and maintaining high-quality code documentation to support developers. Through these solutions, Bayer Crop Science projects up to a 70% reduction in developer onboarding time and up to a 30% improvement in developer productivity.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-data-science-innovation-how-bayer-crop-science-used-aws-ai-ml-services-to-build-their-next-generation-mlops-service/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combat financial fraud with GraphRAG on Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 16:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to use Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases GraphRAG with Amazon Neptune Analytics to build a financial fraud detection solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/combat-financial-fraud-with-graphrag-on-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classify call center conversations with Amazon Bedrock batch inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 16:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build an end-to-end solution for text classification using the Amazon Bedrock batch inference capability with the Anthropic’s Claude Haiku model. We walk through classifying travel agency call center conversations into categories, showcasing how to generate synthetic training data, process large volumes of text data, and automate the entire workflow using AWS services.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/classify-call-center-conversations-with-amazon-bedrock-batch-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective cross-lingual LLM evaluation with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 15:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use the evaluation features of Amazon Bedrock to deliver reliable results across language barriers without the need for localized prompts or custom infrastructure. Through comprehensive testing and analysis, we share practical strategies to help reduce the cost and complexity of multilingual evaluation while maintaining high standards across global large language model (LLM) deployments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/effective-cross-lingual-llm-evaluation-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Embed 4 multimodal embeddings model is now available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 15:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Cohere Embed 4 multimodal embeddings model is now generally available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. The Embed 4 model is built for multimodal business documents, has leading multilingual capabilities, and offers notable improvement over Embed 3 across key benchmarks. In this post, we discuss the benefits and capabilities of this new model. We also walk you through how to deploy and use the Embed 4 model using SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoMapper and MediatR Roadmaps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 15:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of my main goals of commercialization of AutoMapper and MediatR was being able to finally invest time in these projects where basically all new work stopped when I lost corporate sponsorship. I wanted to take some time to share where I&#39;d like to take these projects now
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/automapper-and-mediatr-roadmaps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarter, workspace-aware code completions for C&#43;&#43; in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 14:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C++ code understanding Developing C++ code can be complex. C++ project structure, style, and convention can vary widely from repository to repository, and critical context for a given task often spans multiple files. This can require C++ developers to open and navigate across several files to fully understand a given project and auth
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/smarter-workspace-aware-code-completions-for-c-in-vs-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walkthrough of the original Microsoft Building 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I don&#39;t know why, but there is a Matterport walkthrough of the original Microsoft Building 3, which now no longer exists. This walkthrough appears to have been made not too long before the building was demolished to make room for the new Microsoft campus. I can tell by the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250708-00/?p=111357 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Docker Hub MCP Server: A New Way to Discover, Inspect, and Manage Container Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 12:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Hub has become an essential resource for developers worldwide, serving 11 billion monthly image downloads and hosting over 14 million container images. As agentic AI proliferates, we&#39;re seeing a significant shift in how developers work. More and more developers are leveraging MCP (Model Context Protocol) servers to power their AI agents and automated workflows....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-docker-hub-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes of dotnet run app.cs: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I looks at how the new single-file .NET run experience is implemented inside the .NET SDK, focusing on how the virtual-project file is built
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-2-behind-the-scenes-of-dotnet-run-app.cs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the Google x JetBrains Hackathon Tells Us About the Future of AI at JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 09:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In May, 145 JetBrains employees from across teams and time zones paused their regular work to participate in a 48-hour AI hackathon. With support from Google Cloud, the participants built a total of 41 prototypes from scratch. Some were practical, others experimental, but all explored how AI could change how developers work. The Google Cloud […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/07/what-the-google-x-jetbrains-hackathon-tells-us-about-the-future-of-ai-at-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claude Code Thinking Levels: From Think to Ultra-Think</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Claude Code represents Anthropic&#39;s first venture into agentic coding tools, available as a command-line interface that transforms how developers tackle complex engineering challenges. Unlike traditional AI assistants that provide suggestions, Claude Code actively collaborates by reading codebases, editing files, running tests, and even committing changes to repositories. The
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/claude-code-thinking-levels-think-ultrathink/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with 400,000 teachers to shape the future of AI in schools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI partners with the American Federation of Teachers to launch a 5-year initiative equipping 400,000 K-12 educators to lead AI innovation in classrooms.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/aft 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Biosensing AI-Native Apps on Azure with BCI, AI Foundry, and Agents Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 05:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Co‑Author:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/build-biosensing-ai-native-apps-on-azure-with-bci-ai-foundry-and-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How INRIX accelerates transportation planning with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 20:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            INRIX pioneered the use of GPS data from connected vehicles for transportation intelligence. In this post, we partnered with Amazon Web Services (AWS) customer INRIX to demonstrate how Amazon Bedrock can be used to determine the best countermeasures for specific city locations using rich transportation data and how such countermeasures can be automatically visualized in street view images. This approach allows for significant planning acceleration compared to traditional approaches using conceptual drawings.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qwen3 family of reasoning models now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Qwen3, the latest generation of large language models (LLMs) in the Qwen family, is available through Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, you can deploy the Qwen3 models—available in 0.6B, 4B, 8B, and 32B parameter sizes—to build, experiment, and responsibly scale your generative AI applications on AWS. In this post, we demonstrate how to get started with Qwen3 on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and SageMaker JumpStart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a just-in-time knowledge base with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Traditional Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) systems consume valuable resources by ingesting and maintaining embeddings for documents that might never be queried, resulting in unnecessary storage costs and reduced system efficiency. This post presents a just-in-time knowledge base solution that reduces unused consumption through intelligent document processing. The solution processes documents only when needed and automatically removes unused resources, so organizations can scale their document repositories without proportionally increasing infrastructure costs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents as escalators: Real-time AI video monitoring with Amazon Bedrock Agents and video streams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build a fully deployable solution that processes video streams using OpenCV, Amazon Bedrock for contextual scene understanding and automated responses through Amazon Bedrock Agents. This solution extends the capabilities demonstrated in Automate chatbot for document and data retrieval using Amazon Bedrock Agents and Knowledge Bases, which discussed using Amazon Bedrock Agents for document and data retrieval. In this post, we apply Amazon Bedrock Agents to real-time video analysis and event monitoring.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Support Arrives for Work Items</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After several months in private preview and many bug fixes along the way, we’re excited to announce that Markdown support in large text fields is now generally available! 🎉 🦄 How it works By default, all existing and new work items will continue using the HTML editor for large text fields. However, you now have the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/markdown-support-arrives-for-work-items 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Dev to Deploy: Compose as the Spine of the Application Lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 16:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Nobody wants a spineless application development process. What do I mean by this? The spine is the backbone that supports and provides nerve channels for the human body. Without it, we would be floppy, weaker, and would struggle to understand how our extremities were behaving. A slightly tortured analogy, but consider the application lifecycle of...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-compose-powering-the-full-app-lifecycle/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: If I perform this complex series of manual steps, I can crash a program I am running</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A security vulnerability report arrived that went roughly like this. In Program X, click on the triangle icon and hold the mouse down. Drag the triangle icon to the green box in the corner, and while still holding the mouse down, press Alt+F4 to close the window. The program will
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250707-00/?p=111351 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Troubleshooting Spring Boot Applications with the Spring Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 08:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Marco Belher and explore how to uncover and fix Spring Boot bugs using the Spring Debugger in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: July 17, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Spring Boot hides a lot of complexity to help you build applications […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/new-livestream-troubleshooting-spring-boot-applications-with-the-spring-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft build of Go Telemetry - Helping Us Build Better Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 08:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with Go 1.25, we&#39;re enabling telemetry collection in the Microsoft build of Go to help us better understand how developers use our tools and prioritize future improvements. This data collection will provide valuable insights into usage patterns, performance characteristics, and common workflows that will directly i
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/microsoft-go-telemetry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid the Wrong Job: The Ultimate .NET Interview Question Playbook</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2025/06_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2025/06_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The content provides guidance for Microsoft .NET software engineers preparing for interviews, emphasizing the importance of asking insightful questions to assess a company&#39;s culture, technical processes, and growth potential. It outlines key topics to inquire about, such as code review practices, deployment processes, team dynamics, and performance management, stressing that well-formed questions can reveal the organization&#39;s commitment to quality and support for career development.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/06/avoid-the-wrong-job-the-ultimate-net-interview-question-playbook/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You&#39;re STUCK at Senior Software Engineer - Dev Leader Weekly 101</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss why you might be stuck as a senior software engineer and what to do about it.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/05/why-youre-stuck-at-senior-software-engineer-dev-leader-weekly-101 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-07-04</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 06:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/05/weekly-recap-20250704 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using .NET Aspire With the Docker Publisher</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A practical walkthrough of using .NET Aspire&#39;s Docker publisher to generate Docker Compose files from C# code. Learn how to set up an API with Postgres and Redis, publish to Docker Compose, and deploy to a VPS with minimal configuration.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/using-dotnet-aspire-with-the-docker-publisher 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (June 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.06.13 registry release, 2025-04-16,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn&#39;t &lt;CODE&gt;LVIF_&lt;WBR&gt;INDENT&lt;/CODE&gt; work without an image list?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The LVIF_INDENT property of the Win32 classic listview control lets you indent an item in report view. The units of indentation are the size of the image list. But that requires an image list. Why does it require an image list? The indentation feature of the classic listview control was added for Internet Mail an
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250704-00/?p=111348 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 10:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the July edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This issue is packed with fresh articles, helpful tips, and ideas to keep you inspired and motivated in your work. We’re excited to feature Aicha Laafia, a Java engineer passionate about writing clean, green code and empowering women in tech. She’ll share how sustainable coding practices […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/java-annotated-monthly-july-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Secure and Scalable AI Deployments on Azure with HashiCorp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While the promise of AI continues to generate momentum, many organizations face a familiar challenge: getting AI projects beyond the prototype phase. According to Gartner, only 30% of AI initiatives make it into production, and RAND reports that up to 80% fail to deliver expected outcomes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/automating-secure-and-scalable-ai-deployments-on-azure-with-hashicorp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Practices for Building, Testing, and Packaging MCP Servers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently launched a new, reimagined Docker MCP Catalog with improved discovery and a new submission process. Containerized MCP servers offer a secure way to run and scale agentic applications and minimize risks tied to host access and secret management. Developers can submit servers in two ways: Docker-built servers, which include our full security suite...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-server-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.43: Expanded Model Runner, Reimagined MCP Catalog, MCP Server Submissions, and Smarter Gordon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.43 just rolled out a set of powerful updates that simplify how developers run, manage, and secure AI models and MCP tools. Model Runner now includes better model management, expanded OpenAI API compatibility, and fine-grained controls over runtime behavior. The improved MCP Catalog makes it easier to discover and use MCP servers, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-43/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming network operations with AI: How Swisscom built a network assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Swisscom developed their Network Assistant. We discuss the initial challenges and how they implemented a solution that delivers measurable benefits. We examine the technical architecture, discuss key learnings, and look at future enhancements that can further transform network operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transforming-network-operations-with-ai-how-swisscom-built-a-network-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End model training and deployment with Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we guide you through the stages of customizing large language models (LLMs) with SageMaker Unified Studio and SageMaker AI, covering the end-to-end process starting from data discovery to fine-tuning FMs with SageMaker AI distributed training, tracking metrics using MLflow, and then deploying models using SageMaker AI inference for real-time inference. We also discuss best practices to choose the right instance size and share some debugging best practices while working with JupyterLab notebooks in SageMaker Unified Studio.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>German language cheat sheet: On changing quantities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Somehow, I must have missed out on learning phrases of changes in quantity in German, so I need a cheat sheet. Trend
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250703-01/?p=111337 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If the &lt;code&gt;Format­Message&lt;/code&gt; function fails, and I requested that it allocate a buffer, do I have to free the buffer?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer called the Format­Message function with the FORMAT_MESSAGE_ALLOCATE_BUFFER flag, and they weren&#39;t sure what to do if the function fails (by returning 0). Do they have to free the buffer by calling Local­Free? No, you don&#39;t have to free the buffer. In fact, on f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250703-00/?p=111335 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: A Carefully Curated June Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 13:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s time for another edition of Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup! If June flew by while you were deep in development, don’t worry – I’ve gathered all the ecosystem highlights for you in one handy digest. Here’s what you might have missed. Kotlin YouTube highlights That’s all for June! While you’re rewatching conference talks or experimenting with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/kodees-kotlin-roundup-june-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Why Kakao Pay Chose Kotlin for Backend Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 05:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is a JetBrains translation of the original post by katfun.joy, a backend developer at Kakao Pay. Kakao Pay leverages Kotlin with Spring for backend development across various services, including its insurance offerings. Check out Kakao Pay’s story to see how Kotlin helps it address the complex requirements of the insurance industry and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/case-study-why-kakao-pay-chose-kotlin-for-backend-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
