<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 08:35:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Testing AI Coding Agents With TeamCity and SWE-bench</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 08:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction AI coding agents are no longer research experiments. They are quickly becoming practical tools that can help developers solve real problems. But how do you know whether an agent is good enough for serious use? How do you measure progress when its answers are not always predictable and when there may be various correct […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/testing-ai-coding-agents-with-teamcity-and-swe-bench/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Storage APIs gain Entra ID and RBAC support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 18:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            API Updates To align with security best practices, Microsoft Entra ID and RBAC (role-based access control) support is now generally available for the following Azure Storage data plane APIs: Get Ac
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-storage-apis-gain-entra-id-and-rbac-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.07.2 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing our second bug-fix release for the 2025.07 major release —TeamCity On-Premises 2025.07.2. This update ships a considerable number of bug fixes, including the following: Apart from resolving regular bugs, all TeamCity bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements. For that reason, we recommend that you never ignore bug-fix releases and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/teamcity-2025-07-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TII Falcon-H1 models now available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of the Technology Innovation Institute (TII)’s Falcon-H1 models on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, developers and data scientists can now use six instruction-tuned Falcon-H1 models (0.5B, 1.5B, 1.5B-Deep, 3B, 7B, and 34B) on AWS, and have access to a comprehensive suite of hybrid architecture models that combine traditional attention mechanisms with State Space Models (SSMs) to deliver exceptional performance with unprecedented efficiency.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oldcastle accelerates document processing with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Oldcastle partnered with AWS to transform their document processing workflow using Amazon Bedrock with Amazon Textract. We discuss how Oldcastle overcame the limitations of their previous OCR solution to automate the processing of hundreds of thousands of POD documents each month, dramatically improving accuracy while reducing manual effort.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/oldcastle-accelerates-document-processing-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How London Stock Exchange Group is detecting market abuse with their AI-powered Surveillance Guide on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how London Stock Exchange Group (LSEG) used Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic&#39;s Claude foundation models to build an automated system that significantly improves the efficiency and accuracy of market surveillance operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-london-stock-exchange-group-is-detecting-market-abuse-with-their-ai-powered-surveillance-guide-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build trustworthy AI agents with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Observability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through implementation options for both agents hosted on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime and agents hosted on other services like Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2), Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), AWS Lambda, or alternative cloud providers. We also share best practices for incorporating observability throughout the development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-trustworthy-ai-agents-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-observability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The documentation says that CompanyName version information is required, but my program seems to work without it, so how required is it?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer observed that the documentation for version resources describes strings like CompanyName and ProductName as &amp;quot;required&amp;quot;. But they found that if they omitted those strings, nothing bad seemed to happen
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250910-00/?p=111582 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Language Updates in MSVC Build Tools v14.50</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C++ Language Updates in MSVC Build Tools v14.50 It has been some time since we have provided an update on MSVC progress, and this one comes with the latest major update to our IDE: Visual Studio 2026 version 18.0. This version of Visual Studio ships with the MSVC Build Tools version 14.50, which incl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-language-updates-in-msvc-build-tools-v14-50 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Hallucinations to Prompt Injection: Securing AI Workflows at Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How developers are embedding runtime security to safely build with AI agents Introduction: When AI Workflows Become Attack Surfaces The AI tools we use today are powerful, but also unpredictable and exploitable. You prompt an LLM and it generates a Dockerfile. It looks correct. A shell script? Reasonable. You run it in dev. Then something...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/secure-ai-agents-runtime-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Improvements in .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            My kids love &amp;quot;Frozen&amp;quot;. They can sing every word, re-enact every scene, and provide detailed notes on the proper sparkle of Elsa&#39;s ice dress. I&#39;ve seen the movie more times than I can recount, to the point where, if you&#39;ve seen me do any live coding, you&#39;ve probably seen my subconscious incorporate an Arendelle reference or two. After
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/performance-improvements-in-net-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Azure Cosmos DB Account Overview Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Simpler Way to Navigate, Learn, and Optimize your Azure Cosmos DB Account within the Azure Portal.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-the-azure-cosmos-db-account-overview-hub 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.2.20 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 09:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.2.20 release is out, delivering important changes for web development. Kotlin/Wasm is now Beta, with improvements to exception handling in JavaScript interop, npm dependency management, built-in browser debugging support, and a new shared source set for js and wasmJs targets. Additionally, here are some main highlights: For the complete list of changes, see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/kotlin-2-2-20-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie Is Now Available in CLion: Supercharge Your C and C&#43;&#43; Development Today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 07:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with version 2025.2.1, CLion now supports Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, thanks to an integration that is currently in Beta. Developers working on embedded systems, projects written in C or C++, or performance-critical software can now experience the full benefit of Junie’s project insights and tooling, directly in CLion. With Junie, you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/09/junie-availability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel announces undo support for 3rd-party Copilot declarative agents &amp; web add-ins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 07:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share a major milestone with our partner community: Excel now supports Undo for 3rd-party Copilot declarative agents and web add-ins! This long-awaited capability unlocks a more seamless, professional experience for both developers and end users and addresses one of the top requests from our ISV ecosystem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/excel-announces-undo-support-for-3rd-party-copilot-declarative-agents-web-add-ins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare your VBA projects for VBScript deprecation in Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 03:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In May 2024, Microsoft announced the phased deprecation of VBScript in Windows, as detailed in the official Windows IT Pro Blog. This change impacts VBA developers who rely on VBScript, particularly for reference libr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/how-to-prepare-vba-projects-for-vbscript-deprecation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get ready –the first Insiders release of Visual Studio 2026 has arrived! In this new evolution of Visual Studio, we’re continuing our commitment to building the best integrated developer environment for C++ developers on Windows. [video src=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; poster=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;] Visual Studio 2026 features a fresh UI, f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-2026-insiders-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing .NET 10 Release Candidate 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 Release Candidate 1 is now available. This is our first of two release candidates which come with a go-live support license so you can confidently use this release for your production applications. This release of .NET 10 is supported in the new
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-rc-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework September 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for September 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of September 05, 2025. This update contains no
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-september-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering innovation at scale: How AWS is tackling AI infrastructure challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative AI continues to transform how enterprises operate—and develop net new innovations—the infrastructure demands for training and deploying AI models have grown exponentially. Traditional infrastructure approaches are struggling to keep pace with today’s computational requirements, network demands, and resilience needs of modern AI workloads. At AWS, we’re also seeing a transformation across the technology […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/powering-innovation-at-scale-how-aws-is-tackling-ai-infrastructure-challenges/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here - and it marks one of the most ambitious steps forward we’ve taken with the IDE. This release brings AI woven directly into the developer workflow, performance improvements that reset expectations for speed at enterprise scale, and a modern design that makes the environment feel lighter
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2026-insiders-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your model training with managed tiered checkpointing on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS announced managed tiered checkpointing in Amazon SageMaker HyperPod, a purpose-built infrastructure to scale and accelerate generative AI model development across thousands of AI accelerators. Managed tiered checkpointing uses CPU memory for high-performance checkpoint storage with automatic data replication across adjacent compute nodes for enhanced reliability. In this post, we dive deep into those concepts and understand how to use the managed tiered checkpointing feature.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-your-model-training-with-managed-tiered-checkpointing-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MPS 2025.2 brings quality and stability improvements across the board, along with several notable upgrades. This release adds the ability to start MPS with OS-native launchers, introduces a modernized Show Node Info dialog, and improves how resolve-info is handled when references are copy-pasted. You can now provide icons using factory methods, and the platform has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/09/mps-2025-1-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A suggestion to people who assign nicknames to meeting rooms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is common for Microsoft buildings to assign nicknames to meeting rooms to make them easier to remember. Instead of &amp;quot;We will be in room 1728&amp;quot; you can say &amp;quot;We will be in the Magellan room.&amp;quot; The new Microsoft Building 3 has a series of meeting rooms labeled 1.3A through 1.3E. (The number 1.3 means &amp;quot;first floor, zone 3.&amp;quot;) These meeti
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250909-00/?p=111578 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating IntelliJ Platform UI Freezes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You have probably seen this picture occasionally and wondered what is happening with your IDE and why it freezes! This is a tricky question, and many types of bugs and performance issues may lead to UI freezes. JetBrains IDEs are built on top of a UI framework (the Java AWT) that uses a single thread, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/investigating-intellij-platform-ui-freezes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging self-contained and native AOT .NET tools for NuGet: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we look at the new support for platform-specific .NET tools, so that you can pack your tools as self-contained or Native AOT packages
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-7-packaging-self-contained-and-native-aot-dotnet-tools-for-nuget/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping smarter agents with every new model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how SafetyKit leverages OpenAI GPT-5 to enhance content moderation, enforce compliance, and outpace legacy safety systems with greater accuracy .
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/safetykit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize HyperPod Cluster utilization with HyperPod task governance fine-grained quota allocation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the general availability of fine-grained compute and memory quota allocation with HyperPod task governance. With this capability, customers can optimize Amazon SageMaker HyperPod cluster utilization on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), distribute fair usage, and support efficient resource allocation across different teams or projects. For more information, see HyperPod task governance best […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maximize-hyperpod-cluster-utilization-with-hyperpod-task-governance-fine-grained-quota-allocation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Runtime JAR inspector in 10 hours</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last Friday I was reviewing our backlog items in the Java Engineering Group, and found an idea we had when Log4Shell happened. To this day, there is still no main stream solution to &amp;quot;find in production where a given JAR is being used&amp;quot;.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/building-a-runtime-jar-inspector-in-10-hours 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and scale adoption of AI agents for education with Strands Agents, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and LibreChat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to quickly build sophisticated AI agents using Strands Agents, scale them reliably with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and make them accessible through LibreChat’s familiar interface to drive immediate user adoption across your institution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-and-scale-adoption-of-ai-agents-for-education-with-strands-agents-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-and-librechat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skai uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to significantly improve customer insights by revolutionized data access and analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Skai (formerly Kenshoo) is an AI-driven omnichannel advertising and analytics platform designed for brands and agencies to plan, launch, optimize, and measure paid media across search, social, retail media marketplaces and other “walled-garden” channels from a single interface. In this post, we share how Skai used Amazon Bedrock Agents to improve data access and analysis and improve customer insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/skai-uses-amazon-bedrock-agents-to-significantly-improve-customer-insights-by-revolutionized-data-access-and-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change to data visibility for Microsoft Graph callRecords APIs in GCC High and DoD</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a continuation of changes previously announced for global customers, we will be making cha
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/change-to-data-visibility-for-microsoft-graph-callrecords-apis-in-gcc-high-and-dod 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“GoLand Can Do That?” Ten Secret Superpowers You Might Not Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Note: This is a guest post from John Arundel, a Go writer and teacher who blogs at bitfieldconsulting.com. His most recent book is The Deeper Love of Go. How do you break it to someone that they’ve wasted most of their life? Well, I worked with a guy who didn’t know how to copy and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/09/08/goland-can-do-that-ten-secret-superpowers-you-might-not-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of AI in driving personalized product discovery at Snoonu</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Snoonu, a leading ecommerce platform in the Middle East, transformed their product discovery experience using AI-powered personalization. In this post, we share how Snoonu, a leading ecommerce platform in the Middle East, transformed their product discovery experience using AI-powered personalization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-power-of-ai-in-driving-personalized-product-discovery-at-snoonu/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A People-First AI Fund: $50M to support nonprofits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications are now open for OpenAI’s People-First AI Fund, a $50M initiative supporting U.S. nonprofits advancing education, community innovation, and economic opportunity. Apply by October 8, 2025, for unrestricted grants that help communities shape AI for the public good.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/people-first-ai-fund 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why didn&#39;t Windows 95 simply special-case the laptops that locked up when it executed the &lt;code&gt;HLT&lt;/code&gt; instruction?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 80386 HLT instruction tells the CPU to stop executing instructions until a hardware interrupt occurs. This was traditionally the instruction performed by the operating system when it had no work to do, allowing the CPU to go into a low-power mode. (In modern times, operating systems use other instructions like MWAIT
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250908-00/?p=111572 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Mellum Now Available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace – For Free</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 12:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Production-grade code completion at your fingertips – deploy Mellum instantly with full control and zero extra model fees JetBrains Mellum – our focused large language model (LLM) for code completion – is now available on the Amazon Bedrock Marketplace. This means Mellum is easier than ever to use in real-world applications, with instant access via […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/jetbrains-mellum-now-available-on-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-for-free/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Efficient Byte Array Conversions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_09_2025/07_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_09_2025/07_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with byte arrays in performance-critical applications, every nanosecond and allocation counts. Fortunately, in .NET, there is a class that provides several high-performance methods that can significantly improve speed and reduce memory overhead when converting and manipulating arrays.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/09/07/boost-your-net-projects-efficient-byte-array-conversions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Stress When Leading Projects - Dev Leader Weekly 108</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2025/06_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2025/06_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to work on managing stress when leading engineering projects.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/09/06/managing-stress-when-leading-projects-dev-leader-weekly-108 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-09-05</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2025/06_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 06:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2025/06_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/09/06/weekly-recap-20250905 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Semantic Search with Amazon S3 Vectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2025/06_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2025/06_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to add semantic search to your website using Amazon S3 Vectors - a new vector database service that&#39;s 90% cheaper than alternatives. Complete implementation guide using Semantic Kernel and .NET, from generating embeddings to querying vector indexes.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/building-semantic-search-with-amazon-s3-vectors 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating HPC and AI research in universities with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how a research university implemented SageMaker HyperPod to accelerate AI research by using dynamic SLURM partitions, fine-grained GPU resource management, budget-aware compute cost tracking, and multi-login node load balancing—all integrated seamlessly into the SageMaker HyperPod environment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-hpc-and-ai-research-in-universities-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Real-Time Race Track with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the Real-Time Race Track (RTRT), an interactive experience built using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock, that lets fans design, customize, and share their own racing circuits. We highlight how generative AI capabilities come together to deliver strategic racing insights such as pit timing and tire choices, and interactive features like an AI voice assistant and a retro-style racing poster.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/exploring-the-real-time-race-track-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect MCP Servers to Junie in PhpStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open standard introduced by Anthropic. Think of it as a USB-C port for AI: a consistent way to plug the AI models your AI agent uses into specific tools and data sources. You can connect Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, to a wide variety of officially […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/09/connect-mcp-servers-to-junie-in-phpstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneak Peek at the SignalR Integration in Wolverine 5.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this week I did a live stream on the upcoming Wolverine 5.0 release where I just lightly touched on the concept for our planned SignalR integration with Wolverine. While there wasn’t that much to show yesterday, a big pull request just landed and I think the APIs and the approach has gelled enough that … Continue reading Sneak Peek at the SignalR Integration in Wolverine 5.0 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the crash on a null pointer even though we checked it for null</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A colleague was investigating a crash. The stack at the point of the crash looks like this: contoso!winrt::impl::consume_Windows_Foundation_Collections_IVectorView&amp;lt; winrt::Windows::Foundation::Collections::IVectorView, int&amp;gt;::Size+0x30 contoso!winrt::Contoso::implementation::Widget::
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250905-00/?p=111560 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Acquisition of MCP Defender Helps Meet Challenges of Securing the Agentic Future</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker, Inc.®, a provider of cloud-native and AI-native development tools, infrastructure, and services, today announced the acquisition of MCP Defender, a company founded to secure AI applications. The rapid evolution of AI-from simple generative models to powerful agentic tools-has transformed software development in extraordinary ways. But as with all powerful technologies, new capabilities bring new...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-acquires-mcp-defender-ai-agent-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why language models hallucinate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s new research explains why language models hallucinate. The findings show how improved evaluations can enhance AI reliability, honesty, and safety.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/why-language-models-hallucinate 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 bio bug bounty call</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI invites researchers to its Bio Bug Bounty. Test GPT-5’s safety with a universal jailbreak prompt and win up to $25,000.
Link to article: https://openai.com/gpt-5-bio-bug-bounty 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – September 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 08:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month’s Java Annotated Monthly comes with a fresh mix of Java, Kotlin, AI, and tech news, plus a look at some great events you won’t want to miss. We’ve also got a featured section by Marit van Dijk, covering the new Java 25 release, the latest IntelliJ IDEA updates, and a playful take on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/java-annotated-monthly-september-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and Greek Government launch ‘OpenAI for Greece’</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and the Greek Government have launched “OpenAI for Greece” to bring ChatGPT Edu into secondary schools and support responsible AI learning. This partnership aims to boost AI literacy, fuel local start-ups, and drive national economic growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/openai-for-greece 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (August 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 03:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.08.27 registry release as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout August. There were no tool chang
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-august-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build your own Microsoft Docs AI assistant with Azure Container Apps and Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 22:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to deploy a self-hosted AI assistant that leverages Microsoft Learn content via the Model Context Protocol (MCP) and Azure OpenAI. It’s fast, secure, and ready for developer use in real-world apps. Prerequisite
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/build-your-own-microsoft-docs-ai-assistant-with-azure-container-apps-and-azure-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉Enhancing security and streamlining configuration with Lab Secrets in Azure DevTest Labs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 18:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For platform engineers, securely managing sensitive information across dev and test environments is a critical responsibility. Each workflow, from provisioning virtual machines to deploying artifacts and automating environment setup, often involves handling credentials, SSH keys, and API tokens.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/%f0%9f%8e%89enhancing-security-and-streamlining-configuration-with-lab-secrets-in-azure-devtest-labs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Static Code Analysis Can Improve Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 18:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developer experience is not only about nice editors and fast build times. It is about reducing friction so developers can focus on solving problems rather than fighting with tools. Among the most effective developer experience tools available today is static code analysis. By examining code without running it, static analysis surfaces potential issues early and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/09/improve-developer-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build character consistent storyboards using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we take an animated short film, Picchu, produced by FuzzyPixel from Amazon Web Services (AWS), prepare training data by extracting key character frames, and fine-tune a character-consistent model for the main character Mayu and her mother, so we can quickly generate storyboard concepts for new sequels like the following images.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-character-consistent-storyboards-using-amazon-nova-in-amazon-bedrock-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build character consistent storyboards using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The art of storyboarding stands as the cornerstone of modern content creation, weaving its essential role through filmmaking, animation, advertising, and UX design. Though traditionally, creators have relied on hand-drawn sequential illustrations to map their narratives, today’s AI foundation models (FMs) are transforming this landscape. FMs like Amazon Nova Canvas and Amazon Nova Reel offer […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-character-consistent-storyboards-using-amazon-nova-in-amazon-bedrock-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Set of Updates and Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 15:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first bug-fix update for 2025.2. This build brings important fixes and quality improvements to both ReSharper and Rider, along with some targeted performance optimizations. If you haven’t upgraded to the 2025.2 versions of our products, we highly recommend that you check out these two blog posts: ReSharper 2025.2: Out-of-Process mode, support for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/04/resharper-and-rider-2025-2-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains JavaScript Day 2025 Registration Is Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey everyone! We’re thrilled to invite you to the fifth edition of JetBrains JavaScript Day – a free online event for everyone passionate about JavaScript. Five years in, we’re celebrating by bringing together some of the most inspiring voices in the JavaScript world. They’ll share their stories, ideas, and lessons learned – giving you practical […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/09/jetbrains-javascript-day-2025-registration-is-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I write a C&#43;&#43;/WinRT &lt;CODE&gt;IAsyncOperation&lt;T&gt;&lt;/CODE&gt; where &lt;CODE&gt;T&lt;/CODE&gt; is not a Windows Runtime type?, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we smuggled an arbitrary C++ value inside an IInspectable but noted the lack of safety. So let&#39;s add some safety. To ensur
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250904-00/?p=111557 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composing Data from Multiple Services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 13:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most common questions I get is how to compose data when different services each own their own data. You might have product details owned by the catalog service, pricing owned by sales, reviews owned by a reviews service, shipping information somewhere else, and order counts somewhere else. How do you get all… Read More »Composing Data from Multiple Services The post Composing Data from Multiple Services appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid AI Isn’t the Future — It’s Here (and It Runs in Docker)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running large AI models in the cloud gives access to immense capabilities, but it doesn’t come for free. The bigger the models, the bigger the bills, and with them, the risk of unexpected costs. Local models flip the equation. They safeguard privacy and keep costs predictable, but their smaller size often limits what you can...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hybrid-ai-and-how-it-runs-in-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Sense of Your Output Window with Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever found yourself staring at the Output Window, overwhelmed by endless lines of logs and cryptic messages? You&#39;re
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/make-sense-of-your-output-window-with-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Annotation Handling in Kotlin 2.2: Less Boilerplate, Fewer Surprises</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 11:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many developers have run into subtle issues with annotations when working with Kotlin and frameworks like Spring or JPA-based persistence frameworks. For instance, an annotation applied to a constructor parameter might not always end up in the property or backing field where the framework expects it. This often means annotations don’t land where they’re needed. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/improved-annotation-handling-in-kotlin-2-2-less-boilerplate-fewer-surprises/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding economic opportunity with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is launching a Jobs Platform and new Certifications to connect workers with jobs, training, and certifications. Learn how we’re expanding economic opportunity and making AI skills more accessible.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/expanding-economic-opportunity-with-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Test Run Hub in Azure Test Plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 09:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Delivering high-quality software is a necessity and that’s why Azure Test Plans has introduced the all-new Test Run Hub, an enabler for teams who want to take control of their testing process and drive continuous improvement.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-test-run-hub 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v1.1 with improved support for Microsoft Graph batching</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 07:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the release of Dev Proxy v1.1. This update delivers critical fixes for Microsoft Graph batch request simulation, resolves authentication plugin issues, and enhances the MinimalPermissionsGuidancePlugin with new reporting capabilities. In this version: Fixed Microsoft Graph batch response handling
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v1-1-with-improved-support-for-microsoft-graph-batching 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.1-1 and 1.24.7-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 03:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-1-1-and-1-24-7-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Stream Previewing Wolverine 5.0 on Thursday</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 01:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ll be doing a live stream tomorrow (Thursday) August 4th to preview some of the new improvements coming soon with Wolverine 5.0. The highlights are: And of course anything else folks want to discuss on the live stream as well. Check it out here, and the recording will be up later tomorrow anyway:
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/03/live-stream-previewing-wolverine-5-0-on-thursday/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
