<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 19:45:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What I use for interacting with Git</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2024/01_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 19:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2024/01_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A friend of mine asked me at lunch this week what I was using to interact or manipulate Git, and I think he might have been disappointed with my lack of sophistication. At this point, I’m not willing to cast aspersions on whatever folks use as long as they’re being effective in their own environment, … Continue reading What I use for interacting with Git →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/01/what-i-use-for-interacting-with-git/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surviving and Thriving in Tech: Timeless Advice from Three Decades in Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2024/01_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2024/01_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, a seasoned software engineer shares insights gained from three decades in the industry. He emphasizes continuous learning, staying marketable, developing soft skills, engaging in the local programming community, and working on personal projects. He also warns against companies that discourage community involvement and invites beginners to comment on future article topics.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/09/01/surviving-and-thriving-in-tech-timeless-advice-from-three-decades-in-software-engineering/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Biggest Fear In My Software Engineering Career – Dev Leader Weekly 59</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2024/31_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2024/31_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post My Biggest Fear In My Software Engineering Career – Dev Leader Weekly 59 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the importance of working in areas you&#39;re uncomfortable in to gain more experience. The post My Biggest Fear In My Software Engineering Career – Dev Leader Weekly 59 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/08/31/my-biggest-fear-in-my-software-engineering-career-dev-leader-weekly-59/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Event Sourcing for .NET Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2024/31_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2024/31_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover event sourcing in .NET through a beginner&#39;s eyes. Explore core concepts, benefits, and real-world challenges.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/introduction-to-event-sourcing-for-net-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for prompt engineering with Meta Llama 3 for Text-to-SQL use cases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 20:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a solution that uses the vector engine ChromaDB and Meta Llama 3, a publicly available foundation model hosted on SageMaker JumpStart, for a Text-to-SQL use case. We shared a brief history of Meta Llama 3, best practices for prompt engineering with Meta Llama 3 models, and an architecture pattern using few-shot prompting and RAG to extract the relevant schemas stored as vectors in ChromaDB.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing advanced prompt engineering with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 20:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide insights and practical examples to help balance and optimize the prompt engineering workflow. We focus on advanced prompt techniques and best practices for the models provided in Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models from leading AI companies such as Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Mistral AI, Stability AI, and Amazon through a single API. With these prompting techniques, developers and researchers can harness the full capabilities of Amazon Bedrock, providing clear and concise communication while mitigating potential risks or undesirable outputs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure AI Inference Connector for Azure AI Studio Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 16:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction With the latest launch of the Azure AI Inference SDK for Azure AI Studio Models Catalog, we are happy to announce that we have also made available our dedicated Azure AI Inference Semantic Kernel Connector. This connector is specially designed on top of the published Azure AI Inference SDK and is targeted to allow easy access to a comprehensive suite of AI models in the Azure AI Model Catalog for inferencing for use in your Semantic Kernel projects.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Graph APIs for Teams webinar registration now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 14:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how to use Microsoft Graph APIs to programmatically schedule online meetings with the appropriate meeting options.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-graph-apis-for-teams-webinar-registration-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Windows kernel, what is a LUID, and what makes it loo-ey?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s a locally-unique ID, for a specific definition of &amp;quot;local&amp;quot;.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240830-00/?p=110198 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – August Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 13:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the new academic year approaching, the JetBrains Academy team is excited to bring you fresh updates! Discover new programs and courses designed to advance your tech career. And for computer science tutors we have curated a playlist of videos packed with fun teaching ideas. Dive in now!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/08/30/jetbrains-academy-july-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing ASP.NET Core OData 9 Official Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that ASP.NET Core OData 9 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.AspNetCore.OData 9.0.0 The major highlight of this release is the update of the OData .NET dependencies to the 8.x major version. By updating the dependencies,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-asp-net-core-odata-9-official-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>使用 MSTest.Analyzers 增强您的测试体验</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 06:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Jakub Jareš的Supercharge your testing experience with MSTest.Analyzers – .NET Blog (microsoft.com) MSTest 附带一组分析器，用于检查您的测试代码并指出常见的错误和陷阱。这些错误可能很微妙，并导致测试框架完全忽略您的测试。 我们从 3.2.0 版本就开始提供这些分析器了，但在最新的 3.5.1 版本中，我们添加了一些我们认为您不应错过的分析器。 遗漏的测试 一个常见问题是当您忘记在类上添加 [TestClass] 时。MSTest 将无法知道类中有测试，也不会运行它们： public class MyTests { [TestMethod] public async Task TestMethod1() { Assert.Fail(); } } 如果没有 MSTest.Analyzers，此代码在构建时不会出现警告或信息提示。运行测试时也不会出现测试失败的情况。由于类上没有 [TestClass] 属性，MSTest 会出于性能原因跳过整个类，并且您的测试将永远不会被找到。 但是使用分析器时您会在构建过程中收到一条信息提示： 我们建议将此信息提示升级为警告，甚至是构建错误。可以通过在 .editorconfig 文件中添加以下这行代码来实现 [*.cs] # MSTEST0030: Type containing &#39;[TestMethod]&#39; should be marked with &#39;[TestClass]&#39; dotnet_diagnostic.MSTEST0030.severity = warning 为什么默认情况下这不是警告？ 您可能会问为什么 MSTEST0030 默认是一条信息提示而不是默认的警告。原因是我们不能在 MSTest v3 中引入重大变更，而上述代码是一个常见的模式，用于从基类重用测试。 public class MyTestsBase { [TestMethod] public async Task CommonTestMethod() { } } [TestClass] public class MyTests : MyTestsBase { [TestMethod] public async Task TestMethod1() { Assert.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Generative AI Inference with NVIDIA NIM Microservices on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 22:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a walkthrough of how customers can use generative artificial intelligence (AI) models and LLMs using NVIDIA NIM integration with SageMaker. We demonstrate how this integration works and how you can deploy these state-of-the-art models on SageMaker, optimizing their performance and cost.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-started-with-nvidia-nim-inference-microservices-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are deprecating earlier versions of Visual Studio for Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 22:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Abstract Microsoft will no longer be shipping or supporting the Visual Studio extensions supporting development work against Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, and for the Power Platform tools, for Visual Studio versions other than Visual Studio 2022. What will change?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/we-are-deprecating-earlier-versions-of-visual-studio-for-dynamics-365-for-finance-and-operations-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and How Marten is a Great Document Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 21:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just a reminder, JasperFx Software offers support contracts and consulting services to help you get the most out of the “Critter Stack” tools (Marten and Wolverine). If you’re building server side applications on .NET, the Critter Stack is the most feature rich tool set for Event Sourcing and Event Driven Architectures around. And as I hope to prove to you in this … Continue reading Why and How Marten is a Great Document Database →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the final AWS DeepRacer  League championship and road ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 19:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS DeepRacer League is the world’s first autonomous racing league, open to everyone and powered by machine learning (ML). AWS DeepRacer brings builders together from around the world, creating a community where you learn ML hands-on through friendly autonomous racing competitions. As we celebrate the achievements of over 560,000 participants from more than 150 countries who sharpened their skills through the AWS DeepRacer League over the last 6 years, we also prepare to close this chapter with a final season that serves as both a victory lap and a launching point for what’s next in the world of AWS DeepRacer.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.07.2 Bug Fix Is Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2024.07.2 bug fix for TeamCity On-Premises just rolled out — download now and keep your servers at peak performance! With every minor update, we deliver a significant number of bug fixes, resolve performance issues, and, most importantly, address security issues. Version 2024.07.2 addresses over 30 issues, including matrix build failures, incorrect information about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-2024-07-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grazie: What’s New in August</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As August draws to a close, we’re eager to share the latest enhancements to the Grazie browser extension. Introducing Text Playground Meet Text Playground – your new space to refine and polish your writing with AI-powered suggestions for spelling, grammar, and style. To try it, click on the Grazie icon in your browser’s toolbar and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2024/08/grazie-what-s-new-in-august/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.1 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release brings support for a variety of Java 23 language features, including module import declarations, basic Markdown comments, and primitive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/intellij-idea-2024-2-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing .NET Aspire 8.2 – Goodbye Components, Hello Integrations!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Aspire 8.2 is here with some nice updates for components... we mean integrations! Learn more about this rename, what it means for you, and what the teams has been adding to testing in .NET Aspire!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-aspire-8-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide a personalized experience for news readers using Amazon Personalize and Amazon Titan Text Embeddings on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can recommend breaking news to a user using AWS AI/ML services. By taking advantage of the power of Amazon Personalize and Amazon Titan Text Embeddings on Amazon Bedrock, you can show articles to interested users within seconds of them being published.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/provide-a-personalized-experience-for-news-readers-using-amazon-personalize-and-amazon-titan-text-embeddings-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector Support EAP extended to Azure SQL MI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you are looking forward to build AI-enabled applications on your own data, you’ll be excited to know that the Early Adopter Preview announced for Azure SQL DB on native vector capabilities is now available also for those who have data stored in Azure SQL Managed Instance!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vector-support-eap-extended-to-azure-sql-mi 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New GitHub Copilot features in Visual Studio 2022 17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 17.11 now brings exciting advancements from GitHub Copilot! This release significantly improves how GitHub Copilot integrates into your development workflow, offering smarter and more intuitive coding assistance. Discover the new GitHub Copilot features in Visual Studio, such as enhanced context understanding,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-github-copilot-features-in-visual-studio-2022-17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.2.1: What’s New!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.2.1 is here! This release’s key features include initial support for Python 3.13, improvements to the Data View tool window, and enhanced code assistance for Django. Don’t forget to visit our What’s New page to get all the new updates. Download the latest version from our website, or update your current version through our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/pycharm-2024-2-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is the Windows.Foundation.Uri.Domain property different from Host?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s an educated guess.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240829-00/?p=110192 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.20 with improved simulating API errors and a new API for building integrations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 06:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover what&#39;s new in the latest version of Dev Proxy to help you build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-20-with-improved-simulating-api-errors-and-a-new-api-for-building-integrations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Flags are more than just Toggles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 21:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Feature Flags are just conditional statements but can be much more powerful. Use them so you can integrate features before they are ready to be used in production. But they have a lot more utility than just being simple toggles. Here are different ways of thinking and using feature flags. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where… Read More »Feature Flags are more than just Toggles The post Feature Flags are more than just Toggles appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing tenant isolation using Agents for Amazon Bedrock in a multi-tenant environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will show you how to implement tenant isolation using Amazon Bedrock agents within a multi-tenant environment. We’ll demonstrate this using a sample multi-tenant e-commerce application that provides a service for various tenants to create online stores. This application will use Amazon Bedrock agents to develop an AI assistant or chatbot capable of providing tenant-specific information, such as return policies and user-specific information like order counts and status updates.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect the Amazon Q Business generative AI coding companion to your GitHub repositories with Amazon Q GitHub (Cloud) connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to perform natural language queries over the indexed GitHub (Cloud) data using the AI-powered chat interface provided by Amazon Q Business. We also cover how Amazon Q Business applies access control lists (ACLs) associated with the indexed documents to provide permissions-filtered responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/connect-the-amazon-q-business-generative-ai-coding-companion-to-your-github-repositories-with-amazon-q-github-cloud-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate customer experience through an intelligent email automation solution using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use Amazon Bedrock to automate email responses to customer queries. With our solution, you can identify the intent of customer emails and send an automated response if the intent matches your existing knowledge base or data sources. If the intent doesn’t have a match, the email goes to the support team for a manual response.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-customer-experience-through-an-intelligent-email-automation-solution-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an end-to-end RAG solution using Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock and the AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to seamlessly automate the deployment of an end-to-end RAG solution using Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock and the AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), enabling organizations to quickly set up a powerful question answering system.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-end-to-end-rag-solution-using-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-and-the-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Patch management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 19:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Microsoft 365 Certification validates patching best practices for enterprise-ready apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-patch-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BinaryFormatter removed from .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with .NET 9, we no longer include an implementation of BinaryFormatter in the runtime. This post covers what options you have to move forward.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/binaryformatter-removed-from-dotnet-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline your workflow: Embracing Adaptive Cards Templating</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 15:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to continue our journey with the adaptivecards-templating package, a more robust and streamlined approach to creating Adaptive Cards.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/streamline-your-workflow-embracing-adaptive-cards-templating 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting against Prompt Injection Attacks in Chat Prompts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 15:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Semantic Kernel allows prompts to be automatically converted to ChatHistory instances. Developers can create prompts which include tags and these will be parsed (using an XML parser) and converted into instances of ChatMessageContent. See mapping of prompt syntax to completion service model for more information.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/protecting-against-prompt-injection-attacks-in-chat-prompts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the strange status of wchar_t in classic MIDL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From the era before wchar_t was a standard type.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240828-00/?p=110188 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Training on DDD with Vertical Slice Architecture in Munich</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve got another training event coming up focusing on Domain-Driven Design with Vertical Slice Architecture in Munich on October 21-23rd.A little different than the previous times I&#39;ve given this course is an option for either a 2-day or 3-day version. I had received feedback that
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/upcoming-training-on-ddd-with-vertical-slice-architecture-in-munich/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Gaming Productivity Update for Visual Studio 2022 version 17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In Visual Studio 2022 version 17.11, you will find brand new productivity enhancements for your game development workflows. From faster conditional breakpoints to a swath of Unreal Engine enhancements, we have added various productivity boosters based on your feedback. Once again,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/c-gaming-productivity-update-for-visual-studio-2022-version-17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us for JetBrains GameDev Days 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 08:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We invite you to JetBrains GameDev Days 2024, a hybrid event we’re hosting on October 9-10, 2024. Once a year, we invite community speakers to cover topics they are passionate about. We’ve lined up experts from different fields to deliver talks, lead discussions, and share helpful tips on creating exceptional games. Topics will include CI/CD […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/28/join-us-for-jetbrains-gamedev-days-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 07:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Workspace Model, which serves as the internal storage for project models, has exited its experimental phase. Plugin developers can now safely access and modify the workspace model, benefiting from a centralized API, bulk updates, coroutines, and a persistent data structure. This update is particularly relevant for developers working on build tool integration plugins, such […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/08/workspace-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Implement Log4net in C#/.NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 05:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to implement Log4net, a logging framework for C# applications, and how to use it effectively. Knowing how to log properly helps us to be more efficient while debugging, monitoring, and maintaining our applications. Let’s begin. Why Log4net? Log4net is a popular logging framework for .NET applications. It’s flexible […] The post How to Implement Log4net in C#/.NET appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index website contents using the Amazon Q Web Crawler connector for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 22:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to create an Amazon Q Business application and index website contents using the Amazon Q Web Crawler connector for Amazon Q Business. We use two data sources (websites) here. The first data source is an employee onboarding guide from a fictitious company, which requires basic authentication. We demonstrate how to set up authentication for the Web Crawler. The second data source is the official documentation for Amazon Q Business.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with cross-region inference in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are happy to announce the general availability of cross-region inference, a powerful feature allowing automatic cross-region inference routing for requests coming to Amazon Bedrock. This offers developers using on-demand inference mode, a seamless solution for managing optimal availability, performance, and resiliency while managing incoming traffic spikes of applications powered by Amazon Bedrock. By opting in, developers no longer have to spend time and effort predicting demand fluctuations.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Pinecone .NET SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started building AI applications in .NET using the Pinecone Vector DB and the Pinecone .NET SDK.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-pinecone-dotnet-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Terminal Preview 1.22 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 18:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello friends, we have a new Windows Terminal Preview release! Windows Terminal Preview 1.22 is a large release that contains new features such as Sixel image support (a LARGE community contribution!), Grapheme Cluster Support, the Snippets Pane, Quick Fixes in CMD,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/windows-terminal-preview-1-22-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (August 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 18:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure SDKs release every month. This post includes the month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building automations to accelerate remediation of AWS Security Hub control findings using Amazon Bedrock and AWS Systems Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 18:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will harness the power of generative artificial intelligence (AI) and Amazon Bedrock to help organizations simplify and effectively manage remediations of AWS Security Hub control findings.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-automations-to-accelerate-remediation-of-aws-security-hub-control-findings-using-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-systems-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Community Toolkit 8.3 is here! NativeAOT, .NET 8 enhancements, and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re happy to announce the official launch of the .NET Community Toolkit 8.3 release, featuring .NET 8 and NativeAOT support, performance improvements, several bug fixes and enhancements, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-the-dotnet-community-toolkit-830 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Dev Kit update brings enhanced Razor IntelliSense, Project Status, and New Config Options</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Boost your dev workflow with the C# Dev Kit August 2024 release, which brings enhanced Razor IntelliSense, updated Project Status Bar, and new Project Configuration Options!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/whats-new-in-csharp-dev-kit-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliable Web App – Reliability Patterns</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 16:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            (Only got 5 minutes? The completed example is available here) As applications migrate to the cloud, they must be designed to handle inevitable failures gracefully. Network issues, service outages, and other transient faults are common in distributed systems. Without proper handling mechanisms,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/reliable-web-app-reliability-patterns 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #6: Introducing Self- Hosted Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 14:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want total control over your CI/CD pipeline? We’re introducing self-hosted agents in TeamCity Pipelines! Define your own build environments, manage your resources, and scale effortlessly. No more waiting in line for shared agents. You can now choose whether to run jobs on JetBrains-hosted agents or your own. You can also add various requirements for the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue6-self-hosted-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Microsoft/IBM joint development was built on mutual respect, wait, is respect the right word?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maybe it&#39;s some other word.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240827-00/?p=110186 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Local Development with Dev Containers and Testcontainers Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 13:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to run Testcontainers-based tests or services from within dev containers and how to leverage Testcontainers Cloud securely and efficiently to make interacting with Docker even easier.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/streamlining-local-development-with-dev-containers-and-testcontainers-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build customized Power BI dashboards with user insights data in External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 12:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The user insights feature in Microsoft Entra External ID, now generally available, provides valuable metrics on user behavior through Microsoft Graph APIs and dashboards in the Microsoft Entra admin center. This blog post will guide you through building a customized Power BI dashboard using user insights to analyze metrics like total user count, active users, and MFA usage.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-id-user-insights-and-power-bi 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Azure Storage Queue messages with Azure Functions and [QueueTrigger]</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss using Azure Storage Queue as a message queue and how you can process Storage Queue messages using an Azure Functions app
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/using-azure-storage-queues-with-azure-functions-and-queuetrigger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Introduction to Workspaces in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 06:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode, where we will explore how to take advantage of the new workspace functionality in your IntelliJ IDEA projects with Andrey Belyaev. Date: September 12, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract This session will provide a comprehensive overview of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding .NET stack traces - A guide for developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 08:44:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stack traces are important for debugging and understanding exceptions in .NET applications. They provide detailed information about the error and the call stack when an exception occurs, allowing us as developers to investigate why an error happened. In this post, I&#39;ll walk you through the basics of reading asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-net-stack-traces-a-guide-for-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: 2 ways to use custom equality rules in a HashSet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With HashSet, you can get a list of different items in a performant way. What if you need a custom way to define when two objects are equal?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/hashset-custom-equality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure RAG applications using prompt engineering on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 20:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss existing prompt-level threats and outline several security guardrails for mitigating prompt-level threats. For our example, we work with Anthropic Claude on Amazon Bedrock, implementing prompt templates that allow us to enforce guardrails against common security threats such as prompt injection. These templates are compatible with and can be modified for other LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/secure-rag-applications-using-prompt-engineering-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get the most from Amazon Titan Text Premier</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 20:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the new Amazon Titan Text Premier model, specifically optimized for enterprise use cases, such as building Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and agent-based applications. Such integrations enable advanced applications like building interactive AI assistants that use enterprise APIs and interact with your propriety documents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-the-most-from-amazon-titan-text-premier/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenASL: Generative AI-powered American Sign Language avatars</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 19:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into the architecture and implementation details of GenASL, which uses AWS generative AI capabilities to create human-like ASL avatar videos. GenASL is a solution that translates speech or text into expressive ASL avatar animations, bridging the gap between spoken and written language and sign language.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/genasl-generative-ai-powered-american-sign-language-avatars/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing AI Application Development with Docker Desktop and NVIDIA AI Workbench</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about Docker&#39;s collaboration with NVIDIA, which enhances your ability to leverage Docker containers and improves your overall experience of building and developing AI/ML applications.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/optimizing-ai-application-development-docker-desktop-nvidia-ai-workbench/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IDE features in Visual Studio v17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 15:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Visual Studio 2022 v17.11, you’ll discover several new features that address specific issues developers have reported. These updates don’t belong to a distinct category, but we’re dedicated to sharing them with you in this blog post. You can download the update and view the comprehensive release notes for full details.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/new-ide-features-in-visual-studio-v17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains JavaScript Day 2024 Registration Is Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 15:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey everyone! JetBrains JavaScript Day is back for year four, and this edition promises to be our best one yet! Let’s face it, keeping up with the rapid changes in the JavaScript ecosystem is no easy task – it can be hard for us, too. That’s exactly why we created JetBrains JavaScript Day! This year, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/08/jetbrains-javascript-day-2024-registration-is-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Augmented Generation with Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 15:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Retrieval Augmented Generation, or RAG, is one of the hottest topics at the moment as it opens up the possibility of interacting with data using natural language, which is a long-time dream finally coming true. It is very likely that a lot of your data is already stored or will be stored in Azure SQL,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/rag-with-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track and Analyze GitHub Star Growth With  Kandy and Kotlin DataFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin DataFrame and Kandy are two powerful tools for data analysis in Kotlin. Kotlin DataFrame simplifies data manipulation and processing, while Kandy allows you to create visualizations directly within your Kotlin projects. In this post, we’ll show you how these tools can be used together within Kotlin Notebook to analyze the star history of GitHub […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/08/track-and-analyze-github-star-growth-with-kandy-and-kotlin-dataframe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Guide to Credit Risk Analysis With Python and Datalore AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog post by Ryan O’Connell, CFA, FRM. Understanding the relationships between various economic indicators is crucial for navigating the financial landscape. These relationships significantly impact the overall state of the economy, affecting businesses, investors, and individuals alike. We’ll analyze data spanning over two decades of financial history, leveraging the power of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/26/a-complete-guide-to-credit-risk-analysis-with-python-and-datalore-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS empowers sales teams using generative AI solution built on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Through this series of posts, we share our generative AI journey and use cases, detailing the architecture, AWS services used, lessons learned, and the impact of these solutions on our teams and customers. In this first post, we explore Account Summaries, one of our initial production use cases built on Amazon Bedrock. Account Summaries equips our teams to be better prepared for customer engagements. It combines information from various sources into comprehensive, on-demand summaries available in our CRM or proactively delivered based on upcoming meetings.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on finding the essential elements of a set</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another binary search, but searching a different way.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240826-00/?p=110181 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aug 2024: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 13:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An overview of the latest updates in Microsoft Entra for Aug 2024. Discover how these new capabilities can be integrated into your projects for optimal performance and security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-aug-24 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix ESLint Violations with AI Assistance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 13:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use GenAI to fix ESLint violations, without installing Node.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-fix-eslint-violations-with-ai-assistance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspaces in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 09:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Better late than never! This idiom is probably the best way to describe the functionality we’ll introduce in this article, specifically, support for workspaces in IntelliJ IDEA. Intro In a nutshell, a workspace is a meta-project that allows you to manage multiple projects simultaneously. This feature is useful for various reasons, from coordinating complex development […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/workspaces-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Change the ServiceLifetime of a Registered Service in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 05:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing dependencies is essential in modern application development. .NET provides a powerful Dependency Injection (DI) system, with ServiceCollection at its core. Typically, we register a service and use it as is. However, there are instances when we need to change the ServiceLifetime of services after registration. This article explores methods for changing ServiceLifeTime, providing practical […] The post Dynamically Change the ServiceLifetime of a Registered Service in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a software developer, you might spend most of your time immersed in code, solving problems, and building innovative solutions. But have…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/you-should-blog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Observability with OpenTelemetry – Part 3: Distributed Tracing using AWS X-Ray</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2024/25_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 12:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2024/25_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Traces capture requests through services and components, and are essential for understanding application workflows. They are key for pinpointing bottlenecks and identifying hotspots. Particularly vital in microservices, traces reveal the interplay in modern applications, aiding developers and operators in visualizing request paths for effective issue diagnosis. In the first post of this series, we instrumented […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/net-observability-with-opentelemetry-part-3-distributed-tracing-using-aws-x-ray/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Efficiency and Savings: Stop Reinventing the Wheel in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2024/25_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2024/25_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When developing software, prioritize speed and cost, but consider the impact on meeting consumer needs. Leverage existing solutions like Microsoft .NET and third-party tools to avoid costly custom development. For enhanced productivity, explore UI frameworks and essential tools like CodeRush and GhostDoc in Visual Studio development. Embrace third-party products for better quality code, faster feature development, and cost savings.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/08/25/maximize-efficiency-and-savings-stop-reinventing-the-wheel-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
