<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 10:48:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Remote Closer to Local: 2025.2 Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 10:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our goal is to make remote development with JetBrains IDEs feel just as reliable and consistent as working locally does. Recently, we’ve made progress towards this goal in core areas like the editor, tool windows, plugin behavior, and settings synchronization. Editor All the changes made to the editor in the 2025.2 release are based on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/07/bringing-remote-closer-to-local-2025-2-highlights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Tracking Improvements in Marten</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2025/27_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 21:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2025/27_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We just released a new batch of improvements in the Marten 8.4 release that improved Marten‘s already strong support for tracking metadata on event persistence. Override Event Metadata on Individual Events This work was done at the behest of a JasperFx Software client. They only needed to vary header values between events, but while the … Continue reading Metadata Tracking Improvements in Marten →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/07/27/metadata-tracking-improvements-in-marten/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Enhance Drive Management with DriveHelper in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2025/27_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2025/27_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Microsoft .NET, managing files and directories can lead to errors. The Spargine library, featuring the DriveHelper class, simplifies this task with methods to retrieve drive information and manage drives. Additional utility types, like DirectoryHelper and FileProcessor, enhance file and path management, improving efficiency and reliability in .NET applications.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/27/boost-your-net-projects-enhance-drive-management-with-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Mentors As A Junior Software Engineer - Dev Leader Weekly 103</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how junior software engineers can approach finding mentorship!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/26/finding-mentors-as-a-junior-software-engineer-dev-leader-weekly-103 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-07-25</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 05:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/26/weekly-recap-20250725 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Named Query Filters in EF 10 (multiple query filters per entity)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2025/26_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            EF 10 introduces named query filters, allowing multiple filters on a single entity and letting you selectively disable specific filters without turning off all query filters. This article explains how the feature works, shows practical examples for combining soft deletion and multi-tenancy, highlights best practices like using constants for filter names, and explores where such fine-grained control is particularly useful.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/named-query-filters-in-ef-10-multiple-query-filters-per-entity 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Container Options: Matching Services to Operational Responsibility</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customers are looking to modernize their application on cloud and ask us for guidance on which Azure container services to choose. Should you choose A or B container services or A+B container services? Some choose both (A + B) or use A or B appr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/azure-container-options-matching-services-to-operational-responsibility 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Data Governance &amp; Compliance with UDM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 20:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why Data Governance Matters In today’s data-driven world, governance isn’t just a technical requirement—it’s foundational to successful business operations. Good governance ensures data is not only accurate and compliant but also discoverable and usable at scale. At the heart of this approach lies robust, high-quality meta
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/udm/scalable-data-governance-compliance-with-udm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent eDiscovery solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 17:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build an intelligent eDiscovery solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents for real-time document analysis. We show how to deploy specialized agents for document classification, contract analysis, email review, and legal document processing, all working together through a multi-agent architecture. We walk through the implementation details, deployment steps, and best practices to create an extensible foundation that organizations can adapt to their specific eDiscovery requirements.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PerformLine uses prompt engineering on Amazon Bedrock to detect compliance violations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 17:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PerformLine operates within the marketing compliance industry, a specialized subset of the broader compliance software market, which includes various compliance solutions like anti-money laundering (AML), know your customer (KYC), and others. In this post, PerformLine and AWS explore how PerformLine used Amazon Bedrock to accelerate compliance processes, generate actionable insights, and provide contextual data—delivering the speed and accuracy essential for large-scale oversight.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-performline-uses-prompt-engineering-on-amazon-bedrock-to-detect-compliance-violations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.9 RC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 16:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the Release Candidate (RC) of TypeScript 5.9! To get started using the Release Candidate, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@rc Let&#39;s take a look at what&#39;s new
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-9-rc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Migration Strategies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 14:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Database migrations gone wrong. You deploy a new feature in your app and suddenly half of it breaks. You start digging through your logs and realize it’s a database schema change that’s causing all the issues. Now you’re scrambling, wondering if you can roll back your code changes. Nope, the damage is done. You have… Read More »Database Migration Strategies The post Database Migration Strategies appeared first on CodeOpinion.
Link to article: https://codeopinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I confirm in the Windows debugger that I&#39;m looking at a COMDAT-folded function?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, we learned about identical COMDAT folding (and also
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250725-00/?p=111409 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Changes to JetBrains .NET Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re making some changes to our .NET tools, and we want to give you an overview of what’s happening and the reasons behind the changes. Some features you might be using are being discontinued or transformed, while others are getting significant refinements. We believe that these changes will allow us to build better tools for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/25/upcoming-changes-to-dotnet-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Manual Testing to AI-Generated Automation: Our Azure DevOps MCP &#43; Playwright Success Story</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 06:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced software development cycles, manual testing often becomes a significant bottleneck. Our team was facing a growing backlog of test cases that required repetitive manual execution—running the entire test suite every sprint. This consumed valuable time that could be better spent on exploratory testing and higher-value
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/from-manual-testing-to-ai-generated-automation-our-azure-devops-mcp-playwright-success-story 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Microsoft.PowerShell.PlatyPS 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 21:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re pleased to announce the general availability (GA) release of Microsoft.PowerShell.PlatyPS v1.0.0. PlatyPS is the tool that Microsoft uses to create the PowerShell content you get from Get
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/announcing-platyps-100 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost cold-start recommendations with vLLM on AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 20:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use vLLM for scalable inference and use AWS Deep Learning Containers (DLC) to streamline model packaging and deployment. We’ll generate interest expansions through structured prompts, encode them into embeddings, retrieve candidates with FAISS, apply validation to keep results grounded, and frame the cold-start challenge as a scientific experiment—benchmarking LLM and encoder pairings, iterating rapidly on recommendation metrics, and showing clear ROI for each configuration
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Amazon Nova: A comprehensive analysis through MT-Bench and Arena-Hard-Auto</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The repositories for MT-Bench and Arena-Hard were originally developed using OpenAI’s GPT API, primarily employing GPT-4 as the judge. Our team has expanded its functionality by integrating it with the Amazon Bedrock API to enable using Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet on Amazon as judge. In this post, we use both MT-Bench and Arena-Hard to benchmark Amazon Nova models by comparing them to other leading LLMs available through Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example of Using Alba for HTTP Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Before Marten took off and we pivoted to using the “Critter Stack” naming motif, the original naming theme for the JasperFx OSS tool suite were some of the small towns near where I grew up in Southwest Missouri. Alba, MO is somewhat famous as the hometown of the Boyer brothers. I’m taking a little time … Continue reading Example of Using Alba for HTTP Testing →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/07/24/example-of-using-alba-for-http-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I wait until a named object (say a mutex) is created?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer used a named mutex as a way to detect that another instance of the program is already running. This is pretty standard. They also used the presence of the mutex to indicate that the program is ready to receive work requests: When the program creates the mutex, this prevents new instances from running, and it also announce
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250724-00/?p=111406 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.2 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper and .NET tools 2025.2 Release Candidates are ready for you to try. This release introduces the public preview of ReSharper’s Out-of-Process mode, adds support for the latest C# 14 and C++26 features, and brings a range of improvements for performance, refactorings, and inspections. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/24/resharper-dot-net-tools-2025-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2025.2 Release Candidate Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2025.2 is shaping up to be a big release – especially if you’re a game developer. This update introduces powerful new debugging features for Unity, Unreal Engine, and Godot, including source-level shader debugging, mixed-mode debugging for native and managed code, and stepping time improvements. Beyond game dev, Rider 2025.2 delivers a range of enhancements […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/24/the-rider-2025-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in TeamCity 2025.07: Public Recipes, Pipelines, Dependency Control, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 11:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the launch of TeamCity 2025.07! This release brings a range of improvements across the UI, Perforce integration, recipes, and more. It is also the first version to include pipelines: a reimagined TeamCity experience that focuses on a healthy balance of functionality and an intuitive design-first workflow. Read on to learn what’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/07/teamcity-202507/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Combine MP4 Files on Windows Using FFmpeg</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Merging multiple MP4 files into one can be useful when working with ripped DVDs, split movie parts, or recorded gameplay. On Windows, the…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/combine-mp4-files-ffmpeg-windows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving digital threats 100x faster with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Outtake uses GPT-4.1 and OpenAI o3 to power AI agents that detect and resolve digital threats 100x faster than before.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/outtake 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: Agent Mode Updates, Colored Connections, and Schema Designer Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code keeps getting better—bringing thoughtful updates that make SQL development more conversational, more visual, and more local. In version v1.34.0, we’ve focused this release on deepening
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-agent-mode-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker MCP Catalog: Finding the Right AI Tools for Your Project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 19:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As large language models (LLMs) evolve from static text generators to dynamic agents capable of executing actions, there&#39;s a growing need for a standardized way to let them interact with external tooling securely. That’s where Model Context Protocol (MCP) steps in, a protocol designed to turn your existing APIs into AI-accessible tools. My name is...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/finding-the-right-ai-developer-tools-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize Amazon Nova in Amazon SageMaker AI using Direct Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 19:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the AWS Summit in New York City, we introduced a comprehensive suite of model customization capabilities for Amazon Nova foundation models. Available as ready-to-use recipes on Amazon SageMaker AI, you can use them to adapt Nova Micro, Nova Lite, and Nova Pro across the model training lifecycle, including pre-training, supervised fine-tuning, and alignment. In this post, we present a streamlined approach to customize Nova Micro in SageMaker training jobs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Build Agent2Agent Communication on MCP? Yes!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 17:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MCP has evolved significantly beyond its original goal of &amp;quot;providing context to LLMs.&amp;quot; With recent enhancements including resumable streams, elicitation,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//can-you-build-agent2agent-communication-on-mcp-yes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-tenant RAG implementation with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon OpenSearch Service for SaaS using JWT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce a solution that uses OpenSearch Service as a vector data store in multi-tenant RAG, achieving data isolation and routing using JWT and FGAC. This solution uses a combination of JWT and FGAC to implement strict tenant data access isolation and routing, necessitating the use of OpenSearch Service.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multi-tenant-rag-implementation-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-opensearch-service-for-saas-using-jwt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance generative AI solutions using Amazon Q index with Model Context Protocol – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore best practices and integration patterns for combining Amazon Q index and MCP, enabling enterprises to build secure, scalable, and actionable AI search-and-retrieval architectures.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-generative-ai-solutions-using-amazon-q-index-with-model-context-protocol-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bob’s Used Books: Build a .NET Serverless Application on AWS, Part 1: Deployment and Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Bob’s Used Books is an eCommerce application developed to provide the .NET community with a real world .NET application sample that uses multiple AWS frameworks and services. The original monolithic version of Bob’s Used Books was discussed in a previous blog series, Bob’s Used Books: A .NET Sample Application (Part1, Part2 and Part3), with […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/bobs-used-books-build-a-net-serverless-application-on-aws-part-1-deployment-and-setup/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.4 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released another update for v2025.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This version brings the following refinements: To see the full list of issues addressed in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/intellij-idea-2025-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring possible solutions to the inconsistency in how Windows searches case-insensitively for named resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I explained why Windows has trouble finding Win32 resources with accented characters. It boils down to an ambiguity in the Portable Executable sp
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250723-00/?p=111403 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OpenAI DevDay 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI DevDay returns on October 6, 2025 in San Francisco—bringing together 1,500+ developers to preview new tools, hear from OpenAI leaders, and shape the future of AI.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/announcing-devday-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP C# SDK Gets Major Update: Support for Protocol Version 2025-06-18</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) continues to evolve, and we&#39;re excited to announce that the MCP C# SDK now supports the latest specification version 2025-06-18. This update brings significant new capabilities to .NET developers building AI applications, including an imp
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mcp-csharp-sdk-2025-06-18-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond accelerators: Lessons from building foundation models on AWS with Japan’s GENIAC program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 16:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 2024, the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry (METI) launched the Generative AI Accelerator Challenge (GENIAC)—a Japanese national program to boost generative AI by providing companies with funding, mentorship, and massive compute resources for foundation model (FM) development. AWS was selected as the cloud provider for GENIAC’s second cycle (cycle 2). It provided infrastructure and technical guidance for 12 participating organizations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/beyond-accelerators-lessons-from-building-foundation-models-on-aws-with-japans-geniac-program/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Editing Evolved: Schema-Driven and Context-Aware</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every day, thousands of developers are creating and editing Compose files. At Docker, we are regularly adding more features to Docker Compose such as the new provider services capability that lets you run AI models as part of your multi-container applications with Docker Model Runner. We know that providing a first-class editing experience for Compose...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/compose-editing-evolved-schema-driven-and-context-aware/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline deep learning environments with Amazon Q Developer and MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 14:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q Developer and Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers to streamline DLC workflows to automate creation, execution, and customization of DLC containers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-deep-learning-environments-with-amazon-q-developer-and-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Learning Paths Now Available on Pluralsight for VS Subscribers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve been thrilled to see so many of you jump back into your Pluralsight benefit after our April 3rd announcement about extended access. Your enthusiasm for learning and leveling up with Visual Studio inspires us every day. If you
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/vss-pluralsight-2025-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being more adamant about reporting that C&#43;&#43;/WinRT was unable to resume execution on a dispatcher thread</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we saw what happens if C++/WinRT is unable to resume execution on a dispatcher thread: If you use winrt::resume_foreground with a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250722-00/?p=111400 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Result&amp;lt;T&amp;gt; or OneOf&amp;lt;T&amp;gt; for Better Error Handling in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:02:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of debugging vague errors or overusing try-catch? Traditional exception-based workflows can be messy, highly compromising code readability and maintainability. In this post, I will introduce you to Result and OneOf. Two powerful patterns that make success and failure contracts explicit. Whether
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/using-result-t-or-oneof-t-for-better-error-handling-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pioneering an AI clinical copilot with Penda Health</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Penda Health debut an AI clinical copilot that cuts diagnostic errors by 16% in real-world use—offering a new path for safe, effective AI in healthcare.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/ai-clinical-copilot-penda-health 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving the source generator &#39;marker attribute&#39; problem in .NET 10: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss a new source generator API, AddEmbeddedAttributeDefinition(), added in .NET 10, which makes it easier to embed generated attributes
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-4-solving-the-source-generator-marker-attribute-problem-in-dotnet-10/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate AI Prompts with Claude Code Custom Commands</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 08:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Claude Code custom commands eliminate prompt repetition and standardize AI workflows. Complete tutorial with examples, $ARGUMENTS usage, and team implementation strategies.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/automate-ai-prompts-claude-code-custom-commands/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Nerd Fonts and Icons in PowerShell 7 on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to Install Nerd Fonts and Icons in PowerShell 7 on Windows 11 If you&#39;re setting up a polished dev terminal experience with icons, custom…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/install-nerd-fonts-terminal-icons-pwsh-7-win-11/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s new economic analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Analysis provides insights into ChatGPT’s impact on the economy. OpenAI also launches new research collaboration to study AI’s broader effects on the labor market and productivity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/new-economic-analysis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stargate advances with 4.5 GW partnership with Oracle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Oracle and OpenAI have entered an agreement to develop 4.5 gigawatts of additional Stargate data center capacity in the U.S. This investment will create new jobs, accelerate America’s reindustrialization, and help advance U.S. AI leadership. It also marks a major milestone for Stargate, OpenAI’s AI infrastructure platform and long-term vision to deliver the benefits of AI to everyone.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/stargate-advances-with-partnership-with-oracle 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Unveils the Future of Agentic Apps at WeAreDevelopers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 22:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agentic applications - what actually are they and how do we make them easier to build, test, and deploy? At WeAreDevelopers, we defined agentic apps as those that use LLMs to define execution workflows based on desired goals with access to your tools, data, and systems. While there are new elements to this application stack,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/wearedevelopers-docker-unveils-the-future-of-agentic-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java OpenJDK July 2025 Patch &amp; Security Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 22:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello Java customers! We are happy to announce the latest July 2025 patch &amp;amp; security update release for the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK. Download and install the binaries today. OpenJDK 21.0.8 OpenJDK 17.0.16 OpenJDK 11.0.28 Check our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-openjdk-july-2025-patch-security-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI-powered automated summarization system with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Transcribe using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces a serverless meeting summarization system that harnesses the advanced capabilities of Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Transcribe to transform audio recordings into concise, structured, and actionable summaries. By automating this process, organizations can reclaim countless hours while making sure key insights, action items, and decisions are systematically captured and made accessible to stakeholders.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ai-powered-automated-summarization-system-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-transcribe-using-terraform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyruus builds a generative AI provider matching solution on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Kyruus Health uses AWS services to build Guide. We show how Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed service that provides access to foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies and Amazon through a single API, and Amazon OpenSearch Service, a managed search and analytics service, work together to understand everyday language about health concerns and connect members with the right providers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/kyruus-builds-a-generative-ai-provider-matching-solution-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use generative AI in Amazon Bedrock for enhanced recommendation generation in equipment maintenance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the manufacturing world, valuable insights from service reports often remain underutilized in document storage systems. This post explores how Amazon Web Services (AWS) customers can build a solution that automates the digitisation and extraction of crucial information from many reports using generative AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-generative-ai-in-amazon-bedrock-for-enhanced-recommendation-generation-in-equipment-maintenance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Mode vs Agent Mode - Choosing the Right Copilot Experience for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a .NET developer, productivity and problem-solving are at the heart of your workflow. GitHub Copilot Chat offers two powerful modes, Ask Mode and Agent Mode, that can dramatically accelerate your development, but knowing when to use each is essential to getting the most out of this tool. In this post, we’ll break down the differences,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/ask-mode-vs-agent-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Smarter with the Microsoft 365 Agents Toolkit MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI agents become central to how we build and interact with modern productivity apps, developers need tools that are flexible, standard-based, and deeply integrated with AI. That’s where the Microsoft 365 Agents Toolkit MCP Server
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-smarter-with-the-microsoft-365-agents-toolkit-mcp-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI: From Dev to Prod with One Click</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how to implement a &amp;quot;build once, deploy everywhere&amp;quot; pattern using Azure Developer CLI (azd) that provisions environment-specific infrastructure and promotes applications from dev to prod with t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-developer-cli-from-dev-to-prod-with-one-click 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration testing for Go applications using Testcontainers and containerized databases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 15:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Integration testing has always presented a fundamental challenge: how do you test your application against real dependencies without the complexity of managing external services? Traditional approaches often involve either mocking dependencies (which can miss integration issues) or maintaining separate test environments (which can be expensive
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/integration-testing-for-go-applications-using-testcontainers-and-containerized-databases 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happens if C&#43;&#43;/WinRT is unable to resume execution on a dispatcher thread?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The C++/WinRT library provides the winrt::resume_foreground() function for resuming a coroutine on the foreground thread of a dispatcher. It supports three types of dispatchers: Windows.UI.Core.CoreDispatcher, Windows.System.DispatcherQueue, Micros
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250721-00/?p=111396 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code CMake Tools Extension 1.21 Release: Multi-root improvements, CMake Presets v10, and more…</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 12:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the latest 1.21 release of the CMake Tools extension for Visual Studio Code. This update brings a host of new updates, including addressing one of our top-voted issues for multi-root improvements and adding
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-code-cmake-tools-extension-1-21-release-multi-root-improvements-cmake-presets-v10-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Test Roslyn Source Generators</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When developing a Roslyn Source Generator, it&#39;s important to verify that it works as intended. There are several approaches to testing: you can compare the generated code output (for example, with snapshot testing), or you can go further and ensure that the generated code behaves correctly when executed. In this post, I&#39;ll show example for both ways. Note that I strongly recommend to use the second…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/how-to-test-roslyn-source-generators.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and UK Government announce strategic partnership to deliver AI-driven growth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI partners with the UK Government to boost AI adoption, drive economic growth, and enhance public services for a thriving AI ecosystem in the UK.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/openai-and-uk-government-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Building Multi-Agent Solutions with Semantic Kernel and A2A Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 08:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the rapidly evolving landscape of AI application development, the ability to orchestrate multiple intelligent agents has become crucial for building sophisticated, enterprise-grade solutions. While individual AI agents excel at specific tasks, complex business scenarios often require coordination between specialized agents running on differ
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-building-multi-agent-solutions-with-semantic-kernel-and-a2a-protocol 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI as the greatest source of empowerment for all</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve always considered myself a pragmatic technologist—someone who loves technology not for its own sake, but for the direct impact it can have on people’s lives. That’s what makes this job so exciting, since I believe AI will unlock more opportunities for more people than any other technology in history. If we get this right, AI can give everyone more power than ever.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/ai-as-the-greatest-source-of-empowerment-for-all 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
