<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 16:13:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Git: Merge Repositories with History</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 16:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Merging two Git repositories together in not a common task. In my own consulting work, this is a task that does come up every so often when the code I’m working on needs to be moved from an initial Git repository, whether it’s GitHub or Azure DevOps, to another Git repository that will be the […] The article Git: Merge Repositories with History appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced templating in Semantic Kernel for Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 15:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello to all Python enthusiasts working with Semantic Kernel! We are very happy to share some of the latest work we have been doing, namely we introduced not one but two new options for templates: Handlebars and Jinja2. And we also made some updates to the ‘semantic-kernel’
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/enhanced-templating-in-semantic-kernel-for-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ancient world before computers had stacks or heaps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A lot of computing got done even before we had stacks and heaps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240401-00/?p=109599 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Json schema validation in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is often useful to validate JSON documents against a JSON schema. For example, you may want to validate the JSON document that you receive from a REST API or a configuration file written by a user. In this post, I describe how to validate JSON data against a JSON schema in .NET. Using PowerShell, you can use the Test-Json cmdlet to validate JSON data against a JSON schema. .NET doesn&#39;t support JSON…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start using ChatGPT instantly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re making it easier for people to experience the benefits of AI without needing to sign-up
Link to article: https://openai.com/blog/start-using-chatgpt-instantly 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Sortable Unique IDs With the NewId Library in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 06:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2024/01_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore why we might need sortable unique IDs in .NET and how to create them with the NewId NuGet Package. Let’s dive in! Why Might We Need Sortable Unique IDs in .NET We all know there are two main approaches when it comes to generating IDs for entities in our projects: […] The post Generate Sortable Unique IDs With the NewId Library in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Ways to Create a Generic List of Anonymous Types in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2024/31_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 06:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2024/31_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Knowing how to manipulate complex datatypes such as Lists is crucial when storing and manipulating data in C#. Sometimes, we may want to incorporate versatility by not having to define explicit classes and create generic lists of anonymous types in C#. In this article, we are going to learn some of the different ways we […] The post Different Ways to Create a Generic List of Anonymous Types in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fastest Way to Remove the Last Character of a String</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_03_2024/30_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 08:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_03_2024/30_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Creating and manipulating string objects can be useful when building applications. In the C# programming language, string objects contain text values stored as a sequential read-only collection of character objects. This means string objects are immutable and thus can’t be changed once created. Despite this, we often find ourselves needing to manipulate them. In this […] The post The Fastest Way to Remove the Last Character of a String appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Install Latest Version on macOS and Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 18:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Terraform from HashiCorp is provided as a command-line tool that must first be installed locally before excution. It’s easy to install, as the full tool is contained within a single executable. This makes it easy to put terraform in any folder on your machine for use. Although, to make it executable from anywhere on your […] The article Terraform: Install Latest Version on macOS and Linux appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (March 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 17:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.03.19 and 2024.03.25 releases as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout March. This month’s vcpkg release includes an arm64ec platform expression, more flexibility when mixing static and dynamic libraries,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-march-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bing on .NET 8: The Impact of Dynamic PGO</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bing Extensible Application Platform&#39;s upgrade to .NET 8 and how dynamic profile guided optimization continues to deliver performance gains
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/bing-on-dotnet-8-the-impact-of-dynamic-pgo 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide live agent assistance for your chatbot users with Amazon Lex and Talkdesk cloud contact center</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 14:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Lex provides advanced conversational artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities to enable self-service support for your organization’s contact center. With Amazon Lex, you can implement an omnichannel strategy where customers engage via phone, websites, and messaging platforms. The bots can answer FAQs, provide self-service experiences, or triage customer requests before transferring to a human agent. Amazon Lex integrates […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/provide-live-agent-assistance-for-your-chatbot-users-with-amazon-lex-and-talkdesk-cloud-contact-center/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I tell C&#43;&#43; that I want to discard a nodiscard value?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A variety of tricks, with different degrees of readability and legality.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240329-00/?p=109592 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #207</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 09:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #207 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks C# 12: Alias Any Type [www.thomasclaudiushuber.com] Aliasing types and namespaces has been around for the longest time. With C# that feature has been extended and now we can alias almost any type out […] The post Code Maze Weekly #207 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fastest Way to Check if a List is in Order in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 07:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll examine different techniques to check whether or not a list is in order in C#. We’ll begin by examining several techniques, including parallel processing. Finally, we’ll run a series of benchmarks to help us choose which option fits best in our use case. So, let’s begin! Initial Setup Before we start […] The post Fastest Way to Check if a List is in Order in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image manipulation experiments for Mobile Read Hero Images(MRHI) compatibility</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Consumer-packaged goods industry relies on multiple channels for selling the products and aims to provide a seamless buying experience for the consumer. With the advent of omni-channel retailing, CPGs (Consumer packaged goods) and retailers are striving towards providing the best possible experience to the customer alongside working on providing the most available information on the product they are selling on these touch points. On an e-commerce Channel which sells multiple products, the need for a compliant SKU image is key.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Challenges and Opportunities of Synthetic Voices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re sharing lessons from a small scale preview of Voice Engine, a model for creating custom voices.
Link to article: https://openai.com/blog/navigating-the-challenges-and-opportunities-of-synthetic-voices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Paths for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 20:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to highlight new learning content released focused on Semantic Kernel. APL-2005 Develop AI agents using Azure OpenAI and the Semantic Kernel SDK – Training | Microsoft Learn Student Hub Overview – Microsoft Learn Student Hub | Microsoft Learn .NET Conf Student Zone –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/learning-paths-for-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced RAG patterns on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 16:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, customers of all industries—whether it’s financial services, healthcare and life sciences, travel and hospitality, media and entertainment, telecommunications, software as a service (SaaS), and even proprietary model providers—are using large language models (LLMs) to build applications like question and answering (QnA) chatbots, search engines, and knowledge bases. These generative AI applications are not only […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advanced-rag-patterns-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient continual pre-training LLMs for financial domains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 16:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) are generally trained on large publicly available datasets that are domain agnostic. For example, Meta’s Llama models are trained on datasets such as CommonCrawl, C4, Wikipedia, and ArXiv. These datasets encompass a broad range of topics and domains. Although the resulting models yield amazingly good results for general tasks, such as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/efficient-continual-pre-training-llms-for-financial-domains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Video Analysis and Transcription Chatbot with the GenAI Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 14:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dive into a video transcription and chat project that leverages the GenAI Stack, along with seamless integration provided by Docker, to streamline video content processing and understanding.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-a-video-analysis-and-transcription-chatbot-with-the-genai-stack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I called Create­Environment­Block with a process’s token, but I didn’t get that process’s environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That&#39;s not what the Create­Environment­Block function does.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240328-00/?p=109590 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Native Authentication for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 12:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the public preview of Native Authentication for Microsoft Entra External ID, a feature that allows you to design and control the sign-in experience within your mobile apps. We compare browser-delegated authentication to native authentication which enables you to create customized, visually cohesive login screens that enhance user experience and maintain brand consistency.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/native-auth-for-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bot Powered Viva Connections extensibility supported for Teams Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 11:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bot powered Viva Connections extensibility is now supported in Microsoft Teams solutions. Market place support is coming within April 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/bot-powered-viva-connections-extensibility-supported-for-teams-solutions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 4 Weeks: Visual Studio LIVE! Chicago 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio LIVE! Chicago 2024 April 29 – May 3 | Swissôtel, Chicago Join us for Visual Studio LIVE! Chicago for a focused, deep dive into the latest .NET Microsoft Platform developments. You pick the package you want, 3, 4 or all 5 days!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-live-2024-chicago 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get the HTML Content of a Web Page as a String in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 07:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will look into a comprehensive guide on how to get the HTML content of a web page as a string and how to parse the content retrieved. First things first, we’ll learn how to retrieve HTML content as a string from the web using tools like HttpClient, HtmlAgilityPack, and AngleSharp. Then, […] The post How to Get the HTML Content of a Web Page as a String in .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.16 with simulated handling Teams Admin Center notifications for Microsoft Graph connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 07:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to share the launch of Dev Proxy v0.16, with new features for Microsoft Graph connectors and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-16-with-simulated-handling-teams-admin-center-notifications-for-microsoft-graph-connectors 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve DevOps maturity with BMC AMI zAdviser Enterprise and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post discusses how BMC Software added AWS Generative AI capabilities to its product BMC AMI zAdviser Enterprise. The zAdviser uses Amazon Bedrock to provide summarization, analysis, and recommendations for improvement based on the DORA metrics data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-devops-maturity-with-bmc-ami-zadviser-enterprise-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune your Amazon Titan Image Generator G1 model using Amazon Bedrock model customization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Titan lmage Generator G1 is a cutting-edge text-to-image model, available via Amazon Bedrock, that is able to understand prompts describing multiple objects in various contexts and captures these relevant details in the images it generates. It is available in US East (N. Virginia) and US West (Oregon) AWS Regions and can perform advanced image […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-your-amazon-titan-image-generator-g1-model-using-amazon-bedrock-model-customization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>containerd vs. Docker: Understanding Their Relationship and How They Work Together</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 13:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what containerd is, how Docker and containerd work together, and how their combined strengths can improve developer experience.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/containerd-vs-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Your Container Image Really Distroless?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 13:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out what makes an image distroless, tools that make the creation of distroless images practical, and security benefits of this approach.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/is-your-container-image-really-distroless/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Entity Framework Core Migrations in Production</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss the different approaches to migrating a production database when using Entity Framework (EF) Core code-first migrations. Let’s start. Entity Framework Core Project Setup Let’s start by creating a template Web API project and installing the necessary Entity Framework Core NuGet packages: Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore.SqlServer Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore.Design In this article, we use […] The post How to Use Entity Framework Core Migrations in Production appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Reverse a Number as an Integer and Not as a String in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will dive into various ways to reverse a number using integer reversal. We will begin by exploring the iterative approach, which breaks down numbers into individual digits and rebuilds them in reverse order. Next, we will discuss recursion as an alternative solution. We will also use a built-in function Math.Pow() for […] The post How to Reverse a Number as an Integer and Not as a String in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a receipt and invoice processing pipeline with Amazon Textract</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s business landscape, organizations are constantly seeking ways to optimize their financial processes, enhance efficiency, and drive cost savings. One area that holds significant potential for improvement is accounts payable. On a high level, the accounts payable process includes receiving and scanning invoices, extraction of the relevant data from scanned invoices, validation, approval, and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-receipt-and-invoice-processing-pipeline-with-amazon-textract/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing modern data governance for the era of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce a reimagined data governance experience within Microsoft Purview, available in preview April 8, 2024. This new software as a service (SaaS) experience offers sophisticated yet simple business-friendly interaction, integration across data sources, AI-enabled business efficiency, and actions and insights to help you put the ‘practice’ into your data governance practice. The post Introducing modern data governance for the era of AI appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Dijkstra&#39;s algorithm for finding the shortest path between two nodes using PriorityQueue in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe Dijkstra&#39;s algorithm for finding the shortest path between two nodes and how you can implement it with the PriorityQueue type in .NET 9
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/implementing-dijkstras-algorithm-for-finding-the-shortest-path-between-two-nodes-using-priorityqueue-in-dotnet-9/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Best Way to Count the Digits in a Number</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 06:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we examine how to count the digits in a number, using C#. Finding the number of digits of an integer is a common problem in informatics. For instance, it’s useful when we need to convert numbers from one numerical system to another, or when we want to understand the order of magnitude […] The post What’s the Best Way to Count the Digits in a Number appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Microsoft Intelligent Data Platform—Unleash your data and accelerate your transformation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Intelligent Data Platform is a suite of recommended AI, analytics, database, and security products and services. It includes our best offerings, delivering seamless data integration and real-time business intelligence required for powerful decision making, organizational performance, and innovation. The post The Microsoft Intelligent Data Platform—Unleash your data and accelerate your transformation appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/the-microsoft-intelligent-data-platform-unleash-your-data-and-accelerate-your-transformation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Tags: Important Organization Strategies and Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 18:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the Microsoft Azure cloud, the organization and management of resources are extremely important for operational efficiency and cost-effectiveness. Azure Tags serve as a fundamental tool in categorizing resources within the Azure environment, providing a versatile means to attach metadata to resources for various purposes, including administration, billing, and monitoring . These key-value pairs enable […] The article Azure Resource Tags: Important Organization Strategies and Tips appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for building secure applications with Amazon Transcribe</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 17:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Transcribe is an AWS service that allows customers to convert speech to text in either batch or streaming mode. It uses machine learning–powered automatic speech recognition (ASR), automatic language identification, and post-processing technologies. Amazon Transcribe can be used for transcription of customer care calls, multiparty conference calls, and voicemail messages, as well as subtitle […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-for-building-secure-applications-with-amazon-transcribe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Microsoft Azure Virtual Network Manager to enhance network security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By using Azure Virtual Network Manager, the governance team can create and update these network baselines at the network manager level, and apply them to multiple NSGs at once, ensuring that some critical security policies are enforced across the organization. The post Using Microsoft Azure Virtual Network Manager to enhance network security appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/using-microsoft-azure-virtual-network-manager-to-enhance-network-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert DateTime to user&#39;s time zone with Blazor in .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is an update of the original post Convert DateTime to user&#39;s time zone with server-side Blazor to take advantage of new .NET 8 features. It is inspired by the following pull request in dotnet/aspire When you display DateTime data to a user, you may want to convert the value to the user&#39;s time zone. With server-side Blazor, the code is executed on the server, so DateTime.Now corresponds to the…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sora: first impressions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have gained valuable feedback from the creative community, helping us to improve our model.
Link to article: https://openai.com/blog/sora-first-impressions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Logging With Serilog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 06:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll take a look at some best practices when it comes to logging in .NET with Serilog. Logging is essential to any application we build and Serilog is one of the major logging providers. For this reason, we’ve prepared some Serilog best practices to help you improve your logs. Through the article, […] The post Best Practices for Logging With Serilog appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
