<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 06:36:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-05-09</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 06:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/10/weekly-recap-20250509 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Anemic Models to Behavior-Driven Models: A Practical DDD Refactor in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A practical guide to transforming anemic domain models into behavior-rich aggregates in C# through incremental refactoring, enhancing code maintainability and business rule clarity.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/from-anemic-models-to-behavior-driven-models-a-practical-ddd-refactor-in-csharp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Office Is Modernizing Their App Suite’s UI using Windows App SDK and React Native</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An inside look at how Office has modernized their UI with WinAppSDK and React Native.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/react-native/2025-05-09-office-modernize 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAST vs DAST: Differences And When to Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anyone working in the software development field knows cybersecurity is a threat you cannot afford to downplay. A cyberattack on a product or service you’ve created carries a risk of serious financial and reputational damage, as well as regulatory penalties, depending on the industry and jurisdiction. Defending your software against cyberattacks means addressing security at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/05/sast-vs-dast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate marketing intelligence with Amazon Bedrock and LLMs for content creation, sentiment analysis, and campaign performance evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the media and entertainment industry, understanding and predicting the effectiveness of marketing campaigns is crucial for success. Marketing campaigns are the driving force behind successful businesses, playing a pivotal role in attracting new customers, retaining existing ones, and ultimately boosting revenue. However, launching a campaign isn’t enough; to maximize their impact and help achieve […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-marketing-intelligence-with-amazon-bedrock-and-llms-for-content-creation-sentiment-analysis-and-campaign-performance-evaluation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2025: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 15:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the May edition of our monthly newsletter, summarizing the latest news and developments in the exciting, ever-evolving world of Microsoft Entra.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-feb-25-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Compose Multiplatform for iOS is Stable (Plus AI, Web, and More!)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sit back, relax, and let the Kotlin vibes roll in. This roundup is overflowing with news: major moves in Kotlin Multiplatform (Compose Multiplatform for iOS is Stable 🎉), server-side upgrades, Kotlin for web, and smarter Kotlin development with JetBrains AI. Whether you’re building mobile apps, backend services, or playing with interactive notebooks, there’s something here […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/kodees-kotlin-roundup-compose-multiplatform-for-ios-is-stable/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRUD APIs are Poor Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m convinced that CRUD APIs and CRUD-driven systems—meaning systems built around Create, Read, Update, and Delete operations—are, in the long run, the hardest to change and evolve. This might sound unintuitive at first, especially since many of us have read blog posts, watched videos, or taken courses on building HTTP APIs under the guise of… Read More »CRUD APIs are Poor Design The post CRUD APIs are Poor Design appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I wait for Clipboard History to recognize a clipboard change before I change it again?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Listen for the change event.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250509-00/?p=111169 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2505.09 – Revamped UX, Improved Usability, and Many New Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 13:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX on Windows version 2505.09, which can be downloaded here. Since our preview announcement at GDC, we have been working hard to deliver the changes we promised and more. Today’s release includes many new improvements to PIX, including big overall changes and changes specific to GPU Captures and Timing Captures. Other improvements, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2505-09 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: From JavaScript to Cloud Privacy Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Brendan Eich may be best known as the creator of JavaScript, but his influence extends well beyond programming languages into the very core of internet privacy and emerging cloud ecosystems. Today, as CEO of Brave Software, Eich is a key figure pushing for decentralized, privacy-first approaches to cloud services and digital advertising. His vision challenges […] The article Big Thinkers: From JavaScript to Cloud Privacy Pioneer was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – May 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 22:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The May 2025 release includes updates in the Python Environments extension, a new color picker added by Pylance, branch coverage support, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-may-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 14 – Exploring extension members</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# 14 introduces extension members. See how the extension syntax offers flexibility for extension authors and continuity for developers using extensions
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/csharp-exploring-extension-members 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Developer’s Guide to Build 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Build 2025 is just around the corner (May 19-22), and we’re fired up about all the developer-focused content we’ve got lined up for you! Whether you’re a Visual Studio power user, a VS Code fan, all about Azure, looking for the newest in .NET, or just pumped about AI in development, this year’s Build is […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/a-developers-guide-to-build-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange Web Services code analyzer and usage report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are less than 18 months away from the retirement of Exchange Web Services. Start planning your migration from EWS to Microsoft Graph.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/exchange-web-services-code-analyzer-and-usage-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Present and Future of Kotlin for Web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: We remain committed to empowering Kotlin developers with robust and seamless support in Kotlin Multiplatform for web development. To achieve this, we are working on several key areas: Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) aims to help developers share code across different platforms, significantly reducing development time and effort. The web plays a crucial role in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/present-and-future-kotlin-for-web/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.2 – Bug Fixes Have Landed!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of bug fixes for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.2 comes with the following fixes: dotTrace Timeline viewer now correctly locates and lists functions when searching by type name. [DTRC-31451] For the full list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/08/resharper-rider-2025-1-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid T-SQL anti-patterns with the free T-SQL analysis tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 15:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            T-SQL Analyzer is a free, open-source, cross platform command line tool for identifying, and reporting the presence of anti-patterns and design issues in SQL Server T-SQL scripts. As a database developer, you can catch any potential bad practices and design problems very early in the project process – this ensures a frictionless path to deployment […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/sql-analysis-dotnet-tool 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabric Mirroring for Azure Cosmos DB: Public Preview Refresh Now Live with New Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the latest refresh of Fabric Mirroring for Azure Cosmos DB, now available with several powerful new features that enhance your data analytics infrastructure. This update significantly improves the experience, making it easier than ever to replicate your Azure Cosmos DB data into OneLake in Microsoft Fabric—giving you more control and flexibility […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/fabric-mirroring-for-azure-cosmos-db-public-preview-refresh-now-live-with-new-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn’t Clipboard History capture rapid changes to clipboard contents?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Clipboard history operates asynchronously, so you are changing it before it can respond to the changes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250508-00/?p=111162 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of Managed Identities as Federated Identity Credentials in your Entra apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 13:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the GA of Managed Identities as Federated Identity Credentials for Microsoft Entra. Enhance security by replacing app secrets with managed identities, simplify setup, and enable seamless cross-tenant access to Entra-protected resources like Azure and Microsoft Graph.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/access-cloud-resources-across-tenants-without-secrets-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: Docker – Container Revolution that Changed Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Between the constant chatter about “containers,” “microservices,” and “cloud-native,” Docker stands as a major player in the lexicon of contemporary software development. What started as a simple abstraction tool for Linux containers evolved into a cultural shift for software deployment practices, influencing how entire industries build and run their applications. Containers promise greater speed, portability, […] The article Software Innovation: Docker – Container Revolution that Changed Software Development was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taint Analysis: WebGoat Demo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 10:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is a text version of the demo provided during the Taint Analysis Livestream: Exploring Hidden Dangers In Your Team’s Code. Today, we’ll use WebGoat as our test application to demonstrate Qodana’s taint analysis functionality. This application is deliberately insecure. The first step is to open the application’s source code (the main branch) in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/taint-analysis-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.03.2 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 09:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re rolling out TeamCity On-Premises 2025.03.2, the second bug-fix update for the major TeamCity version released in back in March. This update addresses a few product issues, such as: Bug-fix updates also include performance improvements and security patches, so it’s always a good idea to install them as they come out. See TeamCity 2025.03.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/05/teamcity-2025-03-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration testing with Dapr and Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post discusses setting up a Pytest integration test framework for a system using Dapr and Testcontainers. This framework was initially setup for a customer to suit their needs and it has been extracted into a sample project to provide a starting point.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/external-data-handling-learnings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Single Sign On Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 06:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Configure SSO in Qodana Cloud with just a few clicks. If you have a Qodana license with at least 10 users, you can now configure custom single sign on (SSO) support for Qodana Cloud. Quick and easy sign-ons are just another way to make access easier and improve the login experience for your team. Watch […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/new-single-sign-on-is-here/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the May release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-may-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we built our startup in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tracebit built their B2B SaaS security product using C#.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/why-we-built-our-startup-in-csharp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.3-1 and 1.23.9-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 16:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-3-1-and-1-23-9-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Deutsche Bahn redefines forecasting using Chronos models – Now available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 15:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whereas traditional forecasting methods typically rely on statistical modeling, Chronos treats time series data as a language to be modeled and uses a pre-trained FM to generate forecasts — similar to how large language models (LLMs) generate texts. Chronos helps you achieve accurate predictions faster, significantly reducing development time compared to traditional methods. In this post, we share how Deutsche Bahn is redefining forecasting using Chronos models, and provide an example use case to demonstrate how you can get started using Chronos.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB with DiskANN Part 4: Stable Vector Search Recall with Streaming Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vector search with Azure Cosmos DB In Part 1 and Part 2 of this series, we explored vector search with Azure Cosmos DB and best practices for scaling it to 1 billion vector datasets while maintaining low query latency. In Part 3, we saw how we can create efficient sharded DiskANN indices for multi-tenant apps. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-with-diskann-part-4-stable-vector-search-recall-with-streaming-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 – v2025.1.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/intellij-idea-2025-1-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Availability for Data API in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Title: General Availability for Data API in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB We’re excited to announce the general availability of the Data API for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB! Overview The Data API is a RESTful HTTPS interface that enables developers to interact with their MongoDB data hosted in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/general-availability-for-data-api-in-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What were the MS-DOS programs that the moricons.dll icons were intended for?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tallying them up.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250507-00/?p=111157 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 11:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “C makes it easy to shoot yourself in the foot. C++ makes it harder, but when you do, it blows away your whole leg.” — Bjarne Stroustrup We can’t make С and C++ simpler, but we can make working with them a bit easier. CLion is now free for non-commercial use! Yes, finally. Whether you’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/clion-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The San Antonio Spurs use ChatGPT to scale impact on and off the court</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how the San Antonio Spurs are using custom GPTs to enhance fan engagement, streamline operations, and drive innovation across teams.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/san-antonio-spurs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowe’s puts project expertise into every hand</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Lowe’s partnered with OpenAI to build Mylow and Mylow Companion, AI-powered tools that bring expert help to both customers and store associates—making complex home improvement projects easier to plan, navigate, and complete.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/lowes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Enhancing .NET Logging with LoggingHelper in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enhance your .NET logging with LoggingHelper from Spargine! This powerful utility streamlines application and system logging while capturing and handling exceptions across assemblies, including domain-level errors. Check out the latest features and contribute to Spargine on GitHub or NuGet—your feedback helps shape its future!
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/05/07/boost-your-net-projects-enhancing-net-logging-with-logginghelper-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing OpenAI for Countries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new initiative to support countries around the world that want to build on democratic AI rails.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/openai-for-countries 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use custom metrics to evaluate your generative AI application with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 21:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Now with Amazon Bedrock, you can develop custom evaluation metrics for both model and RAG evaluations. This capability extends the LLM-as-a-judge framework that drives Amazon Bedrock Evaluations. In this post, we demonstrate how to use custom metrics in Amazon Bedrock Evaluations to measure and improve the performance of your generative AI applications according to your specific business requirements and evaluation criteria.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-custom-metrics-to-evaluate-your-generative-ai-application-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Model Context Protocol: Safer Agentic AI with Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 18:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Model Context Protocol (MCP) tools remain primarily in the hands of early adopters, but broader adoption is accelerating. Alongside this growth, MCP security concerns are becoming more urgent. By increasing agent autonomy, MCP tools introduce new risks related to misalignment between agent behavior and user expectations and uncontrolled execution. These systems also present a novel...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/whats-next-for-mcp-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nested App Authentication: Now generally available across Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 17:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started with Nested App Authentication, a modern protocol for simplifying authentication for Personal Tab Teams apps that run across Microsoft 365.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/nested-app-authentication-now-generally-available-across-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.8.0 Released: Compose Multiplatform for iOS Is Stable and Production-Ready</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 16:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today marks a major milestone in the Kotlin Multiplatform journey: the release of Compose Multiplatform 1.8.0, which brings Compose for iOS to Stable. With this update, Kotlin Multiplatform becomes a complete solution for mobile development, enabling flexible code sharing across both business logic and UI without compromising app quality or losing control over platform-specific capabilities. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/compose-multiplatform-1-8-0-released-compose-multiplatform-for-ios-is-stable-and-production-ready/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora Linux is now an official WSL distro</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re pleased to announce that one of the latest additions to the list of official WSL distros is Fedora Linux! The Fedora Project has taken advantage of WSL’s new tar-based architecture to produce WSL images beginning with Fedora 42. Try it out To install it, run wsl –-install FedoraLinux-42and then launch it with wsl –d […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/fedora-linux-is-now-an-official-wsl-distro 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently and Elegantly Modeling Embeddings in Azure SQL and SQL Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Storing and querying text embeddings in a database it might seem challenging, but with the right schema design, it’s not only possible, it’s powerful. Whether you’re building AI-powered search, semantic filtering, or recommendation features, embeddings, and thus vectors, are now a first-class data type. So how do you model them well inside a database like […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/efficiently-and-elegantly-modeling-embeddings-in-azure-sql-and-sql-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Language Updates in MSVC in Visual Studio 2022 17.14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In this update, we continue the tradition of bucketing bugs into helpful categories for you all to filter through along with even more notes from the compiler team as to what, exactly, was fixed. This blog is also complemented by the recent Pure Virtual C++ pre-conference talk by RanDair Porter; so please check out […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-language-updates-in-msvc-in-visual-studio-2022-17-14 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock seamless data management with Azure Storage Actions—now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the general availability of Azure Storage Actions, our fully managed platform that transforms how organizations automate data management tasks for Azure Blob and Data Lake Storage. The post Unlock seamless data management with Azure Storage Actions—now generally available appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/unlock-seamless-data-management-with-azure-storage-actions-now-generally-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What were the MS-DOS programs that Windows used the progman.exe stock icons for?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mostly generic-looking icons.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250506-00/?p=111149 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study in CDEs: Building CodeCanvas with CodeCanvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 13:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains CodeCanvas is a tool for orchestrating Cloud Development Environments (CDEs). These environments aim to solve some of the long-standing issues of local development setups: tedious onboarding, environment drift, resource-heavy builds, and more. When we started building CodeCanvas, we knew dogfooding would be essential. Our goal was to experience the product the same way users […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/05/building-with-codecanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AI stories: daily benefits shine a light on bigger opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sam Altman has written that we are entering the Intelligence Age, a time when AI will help people become dramatically more capable. The biggest problems of today—across science, medicine, education, national defense—will no longer seem intractable, but will in fact be solvable. New horizons of possibility and prosperity will open up.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/ai-stories-daily-benefits-bigger-opportunities 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the May edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This month, we have a special guest – Anton Arhipov. He joins us to share standout articles and other discoveries that recently caught his expert eye. Alongside his picks, you’ll find your regular dose of Java and tech news, AI updates, and industry events that are […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/java-annotated-monthly-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinventing Legacy App Modernization: Crowdbotics’ AI-Native Platform on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Author: Charath Ranganathan, CTO, Crowdbotics Modernizing legacy applications is one of the most daunting tasks facing enterprises today. These systems, often built decades ago using technologies like COBOL on mainframes, power critical business functions but are notoriously difficult, time-consuming, and expensive to update or replace. The process typically involves painstaking manual efforts to understand undocumented […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/reinventing-legacy-app-modernization-crowdbotics-ai-native-platform-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC1: Semantic Kernel for Java Agents API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release candidate of the Semantic Kernel for Java Agents API! This marks a major step forward in bringing the power of intelligent agents to Java developers, enabling them to build rich, contextual, and interactive AI experiences using the Semantic Kernel framework. What Are Agents in Semantic Kernel? Agents are intelligent, autonomous […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/preview-release-semantic-kernel-for-java-agents-api 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the new AI chat template</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I explore the new .NET AI Chat Web App template (currently in preview) and take a brief look at the implementation it provides
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-the-new-ai-chat-template/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? C# allows you to define custom operators for your own types by overloading built-in operators (like +, -, ==, etc.). This is not something most developers use often, and it can make your code behave like native types, which is a powerful but underutilized feature. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/06/dotinsights-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making WebStorm Faster: How We’re Improving Performance Behind the Scenes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At WebStorm, performance isn’t a side project – it’s a core part of what we do. Every millisecond counts when you’re deep in the flow, writing and navigating code. We’ve heard your feedback loud and clear: performance issues break that flow, and they’re frustrating. That’s why improving speed, responsiveness, and reliability is one of our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/05/improving-webstorm-performance-behind-the-scenes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common HttpClient tasks you&amp;#x27;re googling or asking ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:44:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using HttpClient has become my default choice when making HTTP requests from .NET. While there are many good alternatives out there (like Refit, Flurl, and RestSharp), having a built-in client that does most tasks in a pretty easy and straightforward way, makes this an obvious choice for many. While the
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/common-httpclient-tasks-youre-googling-or-asking-chatgpt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Power of Jitter: Enhancing Retry Patterns with a bit of randomness</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Operations may fail for transient reasons. How can you implement retry patterns? And how can a simple Jitter help you stabilize the system?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/retry-patterns-jitter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Deere transforms agriculture with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            John Deere’s Justin Rose talks about transforming agriculture with AI and shares how the company is scaling innovation to help farmers work smarter, more efficiently, and sustainably.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/john-deere-justin-rose 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the updated Teams AI Library and MCP support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the new and improved Teams AI Library, designed to help developers create even more powerful agents for Microsoft Teams.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-the-updated-teams-ai-library-and-mcp-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Docker MCP Catalog and Toolkit: The Simple and Secure Way to Power AI Agents with MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 15:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Model Context Protocols (MCPs) are quickly becoming the standard for connecting AI agents to external tools, but the developer experience hasn’t caught up. Discovery is fragmented, setup is clunky, and security is too often bolted on last. Fixing this experience isn’t a solo mission—it will take an industry-wide effort. A secure, scalable, and trusted MCP...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-docker-mcp-catalog-and-toolkit-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What were the intended uses of those icons in moricons.dll?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Icons for old MS-DOS apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250505-00/?p=111143 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine Meets AWS SNS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 13:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine 3.13 added a new message transport for Amazon SNS with a big pull request from Luis Villalaz. To get started, add this Nuget to your system: Assuming that you have set up a shared AWS configuration or credential files, you can connect to SNS from Wolverine with this: To set up message publishing with … Continue reading Wolverine Meets AWS SNS →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/05/05/wolverine-meets-aws-sns/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Azure Front Door, Traffic Manager, and Load Balancer: Choosing the Right Tool for Global Application Delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern cloud architectures demand flexible, resilient, and scalable traffic distribution strategies. As workloads increasingly span multiple regions and hybrid environments, choosing the right load balancing service in Microsoft Azure becomes a strategic architectural decision. Among Azure’s suite of traffic distribution tools, Azure Front Door, Azure Traffic Manager, and Azure Load Balancer are commonly evaluated — […] The article Comparing Azure Front Door, Traffic Manager, and Load Balancer: Choosing the Right Tool for Global Application Delivery was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StringComparison.InvariantCulture is not always invariant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CultureInfo.InvariantCulture is not invariant for all operations. It is a special culture that is used for formatting and parsing operations that do not depend on any specific culture. For instance, this is well-suited to format values in order to persist them. However, it is not invariant for string comparisons. Comparing strings using InvariantCulture can lead to different results depending on the…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/stringcomparison-invariantculture-is-not-always-invariant.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving OpenAI’s Structure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An update from the OpenAI board on transitioning its for-profit entity to a Public Benefit Corporation, reinforcing its mission-driven structure under nonprofit oversight while enabling greater impact and long-term alignment with the public good.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/evolving-our-structure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2025.2 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 08:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.2, which we plan to introduce in July. After reviewing your feedback and our strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following areas for development: 🚀 CLion Nova language engine improvements and bug fixes 🎛️ New features for embedded development 🤖 Support for Junie, JetBrains’ smart coding agent Read […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/2025-2-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Unleash the Power of Git with IntelliJ IDEA Version Control Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 08:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Justin Clareburt and discover all of the powerful version control tools available in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: May 15, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Discover all of the powerful UI tooling in IntelliJ IDEA that you never knew was there. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/new-livestream-new-livestream-unleash-the-power-of-git-with-intellij-idea-cersion-control-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowe’s powers home improvement retail with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A conversation with Chandhu Nair, Senior Vice President of Data, AI, and Innovation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/lowes-chandhu-nair 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify Dictionary Handling with AutoDefaultDictionary in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2025/04_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2025/04_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing AutoDefaultDictionary The AutoDefaultDictionary&amp;lt;TKey, TValue&amp;gt; class simplifies handling missing keys in dictionaries by automatically returning a default value or using a custom function to generate values dynamically. This feature is particularly useful in applications where missing data should be handled gracefully instead of throwing exceptions. This type was inspired by an insightful article by Simon … Continue reading Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify Dictionary Handling with AutoDefaultDictionary in Spargine →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Management Is Being Gatekept?! - Dev Leader Weekly 93</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/03/engineering-management-is-being-gatekept-dev-leader-weekly-93 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-05-02</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 06:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/03/weekly-recap-20250502 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event-Driven Architecture in .NET with RabbitMQ</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2025/03_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement flexible and resilient event-driven systems in .NET using RabbitMQ as a message broker with practical code examples for producers and consumers.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/event-driven-architecture-in-dotnet-with-rabbitmq 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
