<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 18:11:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing  Perpetual Licenses on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 18:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Marketplace provides various licensing models for paid plugins to suit different user preferences. Now, we are introducing a new option that may change how your users purchase your plugins – perpetual licensing. Licensing options on JetBrains Marketplace The current licensing schemes available on JetBrains Marketplace include: The licensing type (with or without fallback) and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/01/introducing-perpetual-licenses-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WinForms: Analyze This (Me in Visual Basic)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your WinForms code might have issues—maybe an Async call picked the wrong overload, or it’s leaking data into resource files. Time to call in a code-shrink! So, WinForms, Analyze This!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-winforms-analyzers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 17:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this release, you’ll find improvements to the UI, reworked internals for various components, and a binary-enabled textgen. MPS 2024.3 also brings enhanced support for icons, an applicability condition for quick-fixes, and numerous platform updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 What’s new Let’s check out the new features we’ve prepared for you in this release. Top-level folder […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/01/mps-2024-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a bulge on my bicycle tire when I inflate it?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get the order of operations right.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250121-01/?p=110790 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn’t the Windows blue screen of death prominently identify the company that created the driver that crashed?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Because the driver that crashed may not be the one at fault.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250121-00/?p=110788 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Code Security in JetBrains IDEs and Qodana With Mend.io</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has partnered with Mend.io, a trusted name in application security. This collaboration will help us continue providing the tools you need to develop secure applications with ease and confidence in our IDEs and Qodana. For the best user experience, make sure to use the latest stable version 2024.3.2. Why Mend? Trusted by industry giants […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/maximize-code-security-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana-with-mend-io/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking MediatR Validation: Moving from Pipeline to Domain Objects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore why traditional MediatR pipeline validation might be hurting your .NET application&#39;s architecture. Discover how to move validation to domain objects with value objects, following the &#39;Parse, Don&#39;t Validate&#39; principle.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/rethinking-mediatr-pipeline-validation-pattern/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing MSBuild properties and user configuration from source generators: Creating a source generator - Part 13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how to read MSBuild settings from inside a source generator, and how to use this to allow user configuration of your generator
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-source-generator-part-13-providing-and-accessing-msbuild-settings-in-source-generators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Complex Types in Entity Framework: A Complete Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 08:08:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core (EF Core) is a handy tool for database operations in .NET applications. It is also so powerful that you will find everything you can do conventionally in SQL queries with easy LINQ methods. Today, we will explore an essential feature of Efcore that may help you organize
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-complex-types-in-entity-framework-a-complete-guide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Database Connectivity with EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 06:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether during application startup, multi-step workflows, or monitoring an application’s overall health, verifying database connectivity is essential for smooth operation and graceful handling of potential failures. It improves reliability and the overall user experience. In modern containerized environments, often managed by orchestrators like Kubernetes (K8S), it’s equally important for services to report their health status. […] The post Testing Database Connectivity with EF Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: How to create Custom Attributes, and why they are useful</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applying custom attributes to C# classes and interfaces can be useful for several reasons. Let’s learn how to create Custom Attributes in C#, and let’s explore some practical usage!
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/create-custom-csharp-attributes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder: When a C&#43;&#43; object fails to construct, the destructor does not run</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you need to run after a failed construction, you have to put it in a base class or member variable.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250120-00/?p=110783 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending Regular Expressions (Regex) Support on Azure SQL Managed Instance (MI)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 13:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce the Private Preview of Regular Expressions (Regex) support on Azure SQL Managed Instance (MI). This new feature brings powerful text processing capabilities to your SQL queries, enabling you to perform complex pattern matching and data manipulation with ease. Regex support in Azure SQL The Regex feature in Azure SQL follows […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/extending-regular-expressions-regex-support-on-azure-sql-managed-instance-mi 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release of TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines. Some highlights of this release include: We recommend upgrading to apply the latest improvements and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/01/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Roslyn to analyze and rewrite code in a solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve written a lot about Roslyn in the context of Roslyn Analyzers and Source Generators. You can also use Roslyn as a library to analyze and generate code. For instance, you can create a console application that loads a solution, find patterns, and rewrite code. While Roslyn Analyzers are tied to a single project, you can use Roslyn as a library to analyze a whole solution. Let&#39;s create the console…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Unreal Engine Project Issues With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you saw our blog post about using Qodana in Unity and .NET projects, you know that we’ve been striving to explore Qodana’s potential for game development. What’s our next stop on this mission? Seeing our code quality platform in action with Unreal Engine, one of the most popular engines for different types of projects […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/01/unreal-engine-project-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user application access token management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article looks at management application access tokens in an ASP.NET Core web application. Any application with or without a user can use application access tokens as long as the application can persist the tokens in a safe way. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/token-mgmt-ui-application Blogs in this series Setup The ASP.NET Core web application authenticates using OpenID Connect […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/01/20/asp-net-core-user-application-access-token-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s FastSortedList</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a set of open-source .NET 8 packages created by the author since .NET 2, currently in production. It includes the EncryptionHelper class, which offers efficient methods for data encryption, key generation, and password verification.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/01/20/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-fastsortedlist/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Replacing Mid-Level Engineers - Dev Leader Weekly 79</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss recent claims about AI replacing mid-level engineers.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/01/18/ai-replacing-midlevel-engineers-dev-leader-weekly-79 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Monoliths: A Practical Guide for Growing Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A well-designed monolith can scale remarkably well, despite industry trends pushing toward microservices. From database sharding to message queues, learn practical strategies to grow your monolithic system effectively.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/scaling-monoliths-a-practical-guide-for-growing-systems 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Tools (Safely) with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_01_2025/18_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In previous posts in this series I&#39;ve shown how to call LLMs with C# using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI NuGet package. In this post I want to look at how you can enable the LLM to make calls into your own C# code by giving it &amp;quot;tools&amp;quot; it can use. And we&#39;ll also discuss some of the security implications as this can open up a number of concerning attack vectors. There are a number of reasons you might want to give an LLM the ability to call a tool.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.5-1 and 1.22.11-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds including security fixes is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-5-1-and-1-22-11-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Leap Forward with Modern AI using Microsoft 365 Agents SDK and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Leap Forward with Modern AI using Microsoft 365 Agents SDK and Semantic Kernel Today we’re featuring a guest author, Arafat Tehsin, who’s a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for AI. He’s written an article we’re sharing below, focused on how to Leap Forward with Modern AI using Microsoft 365 Agents SDK and Semantic Kernel. We’ll […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-leap-forward-with-modern-ai-using-microsoft-365-agents-sdk-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the crash when trying to erase an element from a std::set</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another kind of fiasco.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250117-00/?p=110777 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2025.1 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the launch of the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major release of ReSharper and the .NET Tools! This initial EAP build is now available for download and offers a preview of the upcoming features and enhancements. Your feedback is crucial in helping us refine these updates, so we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/resharper-2025-1-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 has just begun. This is your chance to preview the new features and enhancements we’ve been working on and share your feedback to help us shape the future of JetBrains Rider. There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: To see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/rider-2025-1-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Files View in Solution Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In modern development, repositories are much more than just .NET solutions. From TypeScript end-to-end tests and Docker compose files to global.json and Playwright configs – your codebase contains numerous essential files that live outside of your C# projects.While these files are fully supported in Rider, they can be hard to find when viewing your solution […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/new-files-view-in-solution-explorer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire小贴示 – 管理容器和数据生命周期</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 11:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自 James Montemagno 的 .NET Aspire Quick Tip – Managing Container &amp;amp; Data Lifetime .NET Aspire 凭借其强大的应用程序组合编排功能增强了本地开发流程。在 .NET Aspire 应用程序主机中，您可以在一个集中位置为应用程序指定所有项目、可执行文件、云资源和容器。当您运行应用程序主机项目时，.NET Aspire 将自动运行您的项目和可执行文件，根据需要配置云资源，并下载和运行应用程序依赖的容器。.NET Aspire 9 添加了新功能，让您可以更好地控制在本地计算机上管理容器生命周期的方式，从而在使用容器时加快开发速度。 .NET Aspire 容器 让我们看一个简单的 .NET Aspire 应用程序主机示例，该示例创建一个本地 Redis 容器资源，等待其可用后，为 Web 项目配置连接字符串： // Create a distributed application builder given the command line arguments. var builder = DistributedApplication.CreateBuilder(args); // Add a Redis server to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/net-aspire%e5%b0%8f%e8%b4%b4%e7%a4%ba-%e7%ae%a1%e7%90%86%e5%ae%b9%e5%99%a8%e5%92%8c%e6%95%b0%e6%8d%ae%e7%94%9f%e5%91%bd%e5%91%a8%e6%9c%9f 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re starting this year off with the opening of the RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program. In this blog post, you’ll find details about the new features and improvements we’ve been working on. What’s coming in RubyMine 2025.1? AI Assistant The 2024.3 release introduced enhanced cloud-based completion for Ruby code. The upcoming release will […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/01/the-rubymine-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event-Driven Architecture Issues &amp; Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 22:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Event-Driven architecture has a lot of benefits but comes at the cost of another set of problems. Some of the Event-Driven Architecture Issues are visibility in workflows and business processes, consistency, idempotency, and consumer lag. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in… Read More »Event-Driven Architecture Issues &amp;amp; Challenges The post Event-Driven Architecture Issues &amp;amp; Challenges appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for .env Files: Now Built into PhpStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 20:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .env files are widely used to configure applications by storing configuration settings, environment variables, and sensitive information. This eliminates the need to hardcode these values into the application code. Previously, developers using PhpStorm had to manually install the .env Files Support plugin, originally created by Adel Faizrakhmanov, to unlock dedicated features for working with these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/01/support-for-env-files/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Kyndryl integrated ServiceNow and Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Kyndryl integrated Amazon Q Business with ServiceNow in a few simple steps. You will learn how to configure Amazon Q Business and ServiceNow, how to create a generative AI plugin for your ServiceNow incidents, and how to test and interact with ServiceNow using the Amazon Q Business web experience. This post will help you enhance your ServiceNow experience with Amazon Q Business and enjoy the benefits of a generative AI–powered interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: Pushing the Boundaries of Multi-Agent AI Collaboration with ServiceNow and Microsoft Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Journey to Multi-Agent Innovation At ServiceNow, we embarked on an ambitious journey to redefine how AI systems collaborate in enterprise environments. Through our partnership with Microsoft, we set out to create something beyond traditional integration – a true multi-agent system across platform that could work effectively alongside human teams. While NowAssist and Microsoft Copilot […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-pushing-the-boundaries-of-multi-agent-ai-collaboration-with-servicenow-and-microsoft-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the .NET Team at NDC London 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Meet the .NET team at NDC London 2025 to explore the latest in .NET 9, Azure, and AI-powered development through keynotes, sessions, and 1:1 meetups.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/meet-the-dotnet-team-at-ndc-london-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Favorite NEW Visual Studio Features of 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last year, the Visual Studio team delivered many new developer-focused improvements and AI integrations, many of which came directly from your feedback on Developer Community. In this post, we highlight the team’s favorite features from 2024 that boost productivity, streamline workflows, and enhance your coding experience. Let’s dive in! Image Hover Preview: See your images […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/our-favorite-new-visual-studio-features-of-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate app compliance with ACAT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how you can define the compliance boundary for your Microsoft 365 application on Azure and AWS with the App Compliance Automation Tool (ACAT) for Microsoft 365.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/automate-app-compliance-with-acat 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In a C&#43;&#43; class template specialization, how can I call the unspecialized version of a method?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can&#39;t talk about things that might exist, so instead talk about things that do.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250116-00/?p=110773 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Named a Customers’ Choice Again for Integrated Development Environment Software</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is honored to be recognized as a Customers’ Choice in the 2024 Gartner® Peer Insights™ Voice of the Customer for Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Software – a distinction we are proud to receive for the second consecutive year. Read the Report A trusted vendor We believe JetBrains’ consistent innovation and developer-first approach have earned […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/01/16/gartner-peer-insights-customers-choice/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking new possibilities: Microsoft AI, database, and identity products receive authorization for Top Secret workloads</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft’s leading AI capabilities are being used across industries to enhance data analysis, bolster security, and support key business priorities. Our U.S. Government customers and authorized partners consistently share that they are ready and eager to apply these same tools to serve their critical missions, and Microsoft is committed to delivering the breadth of our […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/unlocking-new-possibilities 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Docker and Jenkins: Build Robust CI/CD Pipelines Efficiently</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use Docker and Jenkins together to build and maintain efficient pipelines.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-and-jenkins-build-robust-ci-cd-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting the Software Supply Chain: The Art of Continuous Improvement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Docker&#39;s tools enhance software supply chain security, empowering teams to innovate securely at every stage of development.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/software-supply-chain-art-of-continuous-improvement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GoLand 2025.1 Early Access Program Has Started!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for GoLand 2025.1 is now open! In this release cycle, we’re focusing on enhancing Go language support, improving code analysis, and boosting stability to provide a seamless development experience for all the gophers. The first EAP build can be downloaded via the Toolbox App, from our website, or as a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/01/16/the-goland-2025-1-early-access-program-has-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Machine Learning Using Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In recent years, many of our applications have been driven by the high volume of data that we are able to collect and process. Some may refer to us being in the age of data. One of the essential aspects of handling such a large amount of data is anomaly detection – processes that enable […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/anomaly-detection-in-machine-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Building Multi-Agent Systems with Multi-Models in Semantic Kernel – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today I want to welcome back Arafat Tehsin, who’s a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for AI. He’s written an article we’re sharing below, focused on Building Multi-Agent Systems with Multi-Models in Semantic Kernel. We’ll turn it over to Arafat to share more! Imagine running a restaurant. Each of your team member, from the chef […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-building-multi-agent-systems-with-multi-models-in-semantic-kernel-part-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the new year with the first Early Access Program (EAP) build for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1! This is your chance to get an exclusive first look at the upcoming features and improvements designed to make your coding workflow more efficient than ever. You can download this version from our website, update directly from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HCLTech’s AWS powered AutoWise Companion: A seamless experience for informed automotive buyer decisions with data-driven design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces HCLTech’s AutoWise Companion, a transformative generative AI solution designed to enhance customers’ vehicle purchasing journey. In this post, we analyze the current industry challenges and guide readers through the AutoWise Companion solution functional flow and architecture design using built-in AWS services and open source tools. Additionally, we discuss the design from security and responsible AI perspectives, demonstrating how you can apply this solution to a wider range of industry scenarios.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating risk: AWS backbone network traffic prediction using GraphStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can use our enterprise graph machine learning (GML) framework GraphStorm to solve prediction challenges on large-scale complex networks inspired by our practices of exploring GML to mitigate the AWS backbone network congestion risk.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mitigating-risk-aws-backbone-network-traffic-prediction-using-graphstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does Get­User­Default­Geo­Name choose between ISO 3166-1 and UN M.49 codes?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Clarifying the behavior.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250115-59/?p=110769 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips and Tricks for Adopting GitHub Copilot at Scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction​ Adopting GitHub Copilot at scale can be a game-changer for many development teams (especially large or distributed teams). This blog post provides best practices, actionable tips, and tricks to ensure a successful adoption of GitHub Copilot to ensure successful adoption at scale, foster engagement, and maximize the return on investment (ROI). 1. Raise Awareness […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/adopting-github-copilot-at-scale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for CLion 2025.1 has officially launched. The first EAP build, 251.14649.40, is here to provide an early look at some of the improvements coming in the next major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/01/2025-1-eap-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The Y2K bug, or “Millennium Bug,” was a programming issue caused by storing years with only two digits (e.g., “1999” as “99”) to save memory. As 2000 approached, systems risked interpreting “00” as 1900, leading to potential errors in calculations and data processing. Fears of disruptions in critical systems like banking and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/15/dotinsights-january-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify AI Development with the Model Context Protocol and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started using the Model Context Protocol to experiment with AI capabilities using Docker Desktop.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/simplify-ai-development-with-the-model-context-protocol-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user delegated access token management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article looks at managing user delegated access tokens for a downstream API in an ASP.NET Core web application. There are many ways of implementing this, all with advantages and disadvantages. The tokens are requested from an OpenID Connect server using the recommended standards. In this blog, the UI access token from the application authentication […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/01/15/asp-net-core-user-delegated-access-token-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI Explained: A Philosophical Framework for Understanding AI Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine an AI-powered world where assistance goes beyond tasks — where intelligent agents debate, learn and collaborate with the wisdom of history’s greatest minds. What if Socrates, Plato, and Aristotle could step into the digital age, engaging in vibrant discussions and offering their timeless perspectives. In this article, I’ll delve into how AI agents can […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/agentic-philosophers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Semantic Kernel AI Connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI Connectors in Semantic Kernel are components that facilitate communication between the Kernel’s core functionalities and various AI services. They abstract the intricate details of service-specific protocols, allowing developers to seamlessly interact with AI services for tasks like text generation, chat interactions, and more. Using AI Connectors in Semantic Kernel Developers utilize AI connectors […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/understanding-semantic-kernel-ai-connectors 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework January 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 21:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for January 2025. Let’s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what’s new in these releases: Security Improvements .NET updates .NET Framework updates Security improvements This month you will find several CVEs that have been fixed this month: […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/net-and-net-framework-january-2025-servicing-releases-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement RAG while meeting data residency requirements using AWS hybrid and edge services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 18:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to extend Amazon Bedrock Agents to hybrid and edge services such as AWS Outposts and AWS Local Zones to build distributed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) applications with on-premises data for improved model outcomes. With Outposts, we also cover a reference pattern for a fully local RAG application that requires both the foundation model (FM) and data sources to reside on premises.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking complex problem-solving with multi-agent collaboration on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The research team at AWS has worked extensively on building and evaluating the multi-agent collaboration (MAC) framework so customers can orchestrate multiple AI agents on Amazon Bedrock Agents. In this post, we explore the concept of multi-agent collaboration (MAC) and its benefits, as well as the key components of our MAC framework. We also go deeper into our evaluation methodology and present insights from our studies.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-complex-problem-solving-with-multi-agent-collaboration-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us at VS Live! 2025 Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join Your Favorite Speakers at VS Live! Las Vegas With the new year here, many developers are looking for the best ways to stay ahead in a rapidly evolving tech landscape. That’s why Visual Studio Live! Las Vegas, March 10-14, 2025, is a must-attend event! Stay ahead of the curve with the latest enhancements in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/vs-live-2025-las-vegas 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Storage—A look back and a look forward</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Storage has evolved to bolster the evolution of Microsoft AI and enterprise cloud onboarding with multiple innovations. The post Azure Storage—A look back and a look forward appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/azure-storage-a-look-back-and-a-look-forward/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Conversation: Call for Proposals for Azure Cosmos DB Conf 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you passionate about Azure Cosmos DB? Do you have insights, experiences, or innovations that the developer community would love to hear? Now is your chance to shine at the Azure Cosmos DB Conference 2025 – a free, virtual developer event co-organized by Microsoft and the vibrant Azure Cosmos DB community. Mark your calendar for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/join-the-conversation-call-for-proposals-for-azure-cosmos-db-conf-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: The walk-on topic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just walk on in with your topic.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250114-00/?p=110762 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Powerful Devs Conference &#43; Hack Together 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 14:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to invite you to participate in this year’s Powerful Devs Conference + Hackathon, commencing on February 12, 2025. The conference will be followed by a two-week Hack Together, ending on February 28, 2025. Join us to unleash your creativity and build innovation solutions!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-powerful-devs-conference-and-hack-together-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Factory Pattern: Solving JSON Deserialization Challenges in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement the Static Factory Pattern in .NET while handling JSON serialization challenges. Discover practical solutions using System.Text.Json with example implementations and best practices
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/static-factory-pattern-json-serialization-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading compilation options and the C# version in source generators: Creating a source generator - Part 12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to read details of a target project from a source generator, such as assembly name, the current configuration, or the c# version
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-source-generator-part-12-reading-compilation-options-and-csharp-version-in-source-generators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Records, Structs, and Classes in C#: When to Use What?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 07:48:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# provides a few ways to define types—records, structures, and classes. Each has its own qualities and limitations. In this blog post, I will discuss each construct and help you identify which one to use in your project.
What is a class in C#?
A class defines reference types,
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/comparing-records-structs-and-classes-in-c-when-to-use-what/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmos DB Embeddings Generator Sample</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever since our first preview announcement for vector indexing and support for DiskANN and then again when we announced the GA for these features, customers have been asking us to make it easier to generate Azure OpenAI embeddings on their data in Azure Cosmos DB. So we did just that and created the Azure Cosmos […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/embeddings-generator-sample 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Logging in ASP.NET: how to automatically log all incoming HTTP requests (and its downsides!)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aren’t you tired of adding manual logs to your HTTP APIs to log HTTP requests and responses? By using a built-in middleware in ASP.NET, you will be able to centralize logs management and have a clear view of all the incoming HTTP requests.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/httplogging-asp-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
