<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:48:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Articul8’s domain-specific model development with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Articul8 is redefining enterprise generative AI with domain-specific models that outperform general-purpose LLMs in real-world applications. In our latest blog post, we dive into how Amazon SageMaker HyperPod accelerated the development of Articul8’s industry-leading semiconductor model—achieving 2X higher accuracy that top open source models while slashing deployment time by 4X.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-articul8s-domain-specific-model-development-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How VideoAmp uses Amazon Bedrock to power their media analytics interface</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate how VideoAmp, a media measurement company, worked with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) team to develop a prototype of the VideoAmp Natural Language (NL) Analytics Chatbot to uncover meaningful insights at scale within media analytics data using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-videoamp-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-power-their-media-analytics-interface/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Your Productivity with New GitHub Copilot Features for .NET!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Visual Studio 17.14 GA release and recent C# Dev Kit releases for VS Code have introduced a whole new batch of GitHub Copilot features des
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/improve-productivity-with-github-copilot-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2025 (version 1.101)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code May 2025 Release (1.101) Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/may-2025-(version-1.101) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft recognized for second consecutive year as a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re proud to share that Microsoft has once again been named a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Data Science and Machine Learning (DSML) Platforms. The post Microsoft recognized for second consecutive year as a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/microsoft-recognized-for-second-consecutive-year-as-a-leader-in-the-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-data-science-and-machine-learning-platforms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You DON’T Need Microservices for Serverless!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I want to talk about something that might sound like a contradiction in terms: the serverless monolith. If you’re scratching your head right now, thinking, “Wait, that makes no sense, serverless is for microservices!” then stick with me. I’m going to clear up one of the biggest misconceptions out there and explain why a serverless… Read More »You DON’T Need Microservices for Serverless! The post You DON’T Need Microservices for Serverless!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build, Run, and Package AI Models Locally with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As a Senior DevOps Engineer and Docker Captain, I’ve helped build AI systems for everything from retail personalization to medical imaging. One truth stands out: AI capabilities are core to modern infrastructure. This guide will show you how to run and package local AI models with Docker Model Runner — a lightweight, developer-friendly tool...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-build-run-and-package-ai-models-locally-with-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Windows even have &lt;code&gt;Interlocked&lt;/code&gt; functions when we have &lt;code&gt;std::atomic&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows provides a family of functions for performing atomic operations. They have the word Interlocked in their name. But why do these functions even exist when we have std::atomic? This is similar to asking
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250612-00/?p=111265 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Building an MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, June 24, at 10 am EDT / 4 pm CEST (check other timezones) for our free livestream, Live Coding: Building an MCP Server. In this livestream, we’ll team up with Max Kless, a senior engineer at Nx, to build a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server from scratch and seamlessly integrate it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/06/livestream-building-an-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs Go: Which one to choose in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The programming landscape continues to evolve, bringing forward languages like Rust and Go that not only challenge traditional paradigms but also cater to the sophisticated needs of modern computing. Both have carved significant niches for themselves, celebrated for their efficient handling of system-level operations and concurrency. Recent findings from the State of Developer Ecosystem Report […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/06/12/rust-vs-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.3: Important Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A third set of updates for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.3 introduces support for SQL &amp;amp; NoSQL query languages You can now edit and format SQL and NoSQL queries […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/12/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-3-important-updates-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor your Quarkus native application on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 12:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Quarkus is a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/monitor-your-quarkus-native-application-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run HTTP Requests in Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 08:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that our HTTP Client plugin is now available in Android Studio! HTTP Client is a powerful tool for making HTTP, gRPC, GraphQL, and WebSocket requests. Its text-based interface offers seamless integration with the editor, along with extensive coding assistance including highlighting, code completion, refactorings, and inline documentation. While it was […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/06/12/run-http-requests-in-android-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from Cursor to IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 07:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re a developer working with Cursor, exploring alternatives for your growing project, and are curious to see what IntelliJ IDEA has to offer, this article is for you. While Cursor emphasizes a minimalistic setup approach, IntelliJ IDEA strikes a balance between out-of-the-box functionality and powerful customization, enabling developers to effortlessly scale from small projects […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/migrate-cursor-to-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dockerizing UV</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Containerizing your Python applications helps standardize environments and streamline deployment—but it also introduces unique challenges. In our team&#39;s exploration of modern dependency management tools, we discovered that while UV (Universal Virtualenv) delivers impressive speed and simplicity in local development, replicating its setup ins
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/dockerizing-uv 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing the Magic of AI to Mattel’s Iconic Brands</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Mattel are partnering to integrate AI into iconic brands such as Barbie and Hot Wheels, aiming to enhance creative development, streamline workflows, and create new ways for fans to engage.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/mattels-iconic-brands 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Complete MCP Experience: Full Specification Support in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VS Code now supports the complete Model Context Protocol specification, including authorization, prompts, resources, and sampling. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/the-complete-mcp-experience:-full-specification-support-in-vs-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security and Trust in Visual Studio Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 22:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s fast-paced digital world, keeping the Visual Studio Marketplace secure and trustworthy is extremely important. We know how crucial it is to protect your extensions, so we&#39;re always working on new ways to keep things safe. We&#39;d like to share an update on the existing safeguards and upcoming investments that ensure VS Marketplace r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//security-and-trust-in-visual-studio-marketplace 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Voice Intelligence with .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most interesting ways to enhance your existing applications with AI is to enable more ways for your users to interact with it. Today you probably handle text input, and perhaps some touch gestures for your power users. Now it&#39;s easier than ever to expand that to voice and vision, especially when your users&#39; primary input is via mobi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/multimodal-voice-intelligence-with-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe enhances developer productivity using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adobe partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and the Vector Engine for Amazon OpenSearch Serverless. This solution dramatically improved their developer support system, resulting in a 20% increase in retrieval accuracy. In this post, we discuss the details of this solution and how Adobe enhances their developer productivity.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/adobe-enhances-developer-productivity-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Nova Lite enables Bito to offer a free tier option for its AI-powered code reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bito is an innovative startup that creates AI agents for a broad range of software developers. In this post, we share how Bito is able to offer a free tier option for its AI-powered code reviews using Amazon Nova.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-nova-lite-enables-bito-to-offer-a-free-tier-option-for-its-ai-powered-code-reviews/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Gardenia Technologies helps customers create ESG disclosure reports 75% faster using agentic generative AI on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Gardenia Technologies, a data analytics company, partnered with the AWS Prototyping and Cloud Engineering (PACE) team to develop Report GenAI, a fully automated ESG reporting solution powered by the latest generative AI models on Amazon Bedrock. This post dives deep into the technology behind an agentic search solution using tooling with Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and text-to-SQL capabilities to help customers reduce ESG reporting time by up to 75%. We demonstrate how AWS serverless technology, combined with agents in Amazon Bedrock, are used to build scalable and highly flexible agent-based document assistant applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing the &lt;code&gt;MAX_PATH&lt;/code&gt; restriction on paths applies only to paths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was playing around with Windows long paths and found that even though they used the \?\ long path prefix, they still couldn&#39;t use a long path. The documentation on the maximum pat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250611-00/?p=111262 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing AI models to Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we first released Docker Model Runner, it came with built-in support for running AI models published and maintained by Docker on Docker Hub. This made it simple to pull a model like llama3.2 or gemma3 and start using it locally with familiar Docker-style commands. Model Runner now supports three new commands: tag, push, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/publish-ai-models-on-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Nemotron Super 49B and Nano 8B reasoning models now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Llama 3.3 Nemotron Super 49B V1 and Llama 3.1 Nemotron Nano 8B V1 are now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, you can now deploy NVIDIA’s newest reasoning models to build, experiment, and responsibly scale your generative AI ideas on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/nvidia-nemotron-super-49b-and-nano-8b-reasoning-models-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy JetBrains Mellum Your Way: Now Available via NVIDIA NIM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deploy Mellum as a production-grade LLM inside your own infrastructure – with NVIDIA. JetBrains Mellum – our open, focused LLM specialized on code completion – is now available to run as a containerized microservice on NVIDIA AI Factories. Using the new NVIDIA universal LLM NIM container, Mellum can be deployed in minutes on any NVIDIA-accelerated […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/06/deploy-jetbrains-mellum-your-way-now-available-via-nvidia-nim/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework June 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 20:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for June 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Security Update&amp;quot;] All developers using .NET 8.0 and .NET 9.0 should update immediately
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-june-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 19:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing patches that impact the latest version of our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can dow
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/june-patches-for-azure-devops-server-4 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 5 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the fifth preview release of .NET 10 with enhancements across the .NET Runtime, SDK, libraries, C#, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more. Check out the full release notes linked below and get started today. [cta-button align=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Download .NET 10 Preview 5&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;https:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.42: Native IPv6, Built-In MCP, and Better Model Packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.42 introduces powerful new capabilities that enhance network flexibility, improve security, and deepen AI toolchain integration, all while reducing setup friction. With native IPv6 support, a fully integrated MCP Toolkit, and major upgrades to Docker Model Runner and our AI agent Gordon, this release continues our commitment to helping developers move faster, ship...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-42-native-ipv6-built-in-mcp-and-better-model-packaging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate customer support with Amazon Bedrock, LangGraph, and Mistral models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock and LangGraph to build a personalized customer support experience for an ecommerce retailer. By integrating the Mistral Large 2 and Pixtral Large models, we guide you through automating key customer support workflows such as ticket categorization, order details extraction, damage assessment, and generating contextual responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-customer-support-with-amazon-bedrock-langgraph-and-mistral-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build responsible AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Bedrock Guardrails helps block harmful and undesirable multimodal content. Using a healthcare insurance call center scenario, we walk through the process of configuring and testing various guardrails.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-responsible-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective cost optimization strategies for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the increasing adoption of Amazon Bedrock, optimizing costs is a must to help keep the expenses associated with deploying and running generative AI applications manageable and aligned with your organization’s budget. In this post, you’ll learn about strategic cost optimization techniques while using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/effective-cost-optimization-strategies-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How E.ON saves £10 million annually with AI diagnostics for smart meters powered by Amazon Textract</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            E.ON’s story highlights how a creative application of Amazon Textract, combined with custom image analysis and pulse counting, can solve a real-world challenge at scale. By diagnosing smart meter errors through brief smartphone videos, E.ON aims to lower costs, improve customer satisfaction, and enhance overall energy service reliability. In this post, we dive into how this solution works and the impact it’s making.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-e-on-saves-10-million-annually-with-ai-diagnostics-for-smart-meters-powered-by-amazon-textract/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application compatibility for Windows 95 crashed a cash register</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I told the story of the time the development manager for Windows 95 bought one copy of every PC program in the Egghead Software store. I learned that in addition to stunning the store manager,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250610-00/?p=111260 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Python: Concurrency in async/await and threading</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have been coding with Python for a while, especially if you have been using frameworks and libraries such as Fast API and discord.py, then you have probably been using async/await or asyncio. You may have heard statements like “multithreading in Python isn’t real”, and you may also know about the famous (or infamous) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/06/concurrency-in-async-await-and-threading/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Blocks in Java: Perfect for Multiline Strings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve likely used String variables to store values that span multiple lines, such as LLM prompts, JSON, HTML, XML, code snippets, and other such values. Some of these, such as a JSON value, include double quotes as part of the data. Imagine the inconvenience of using backslashes () to escape those quotes, indenting lines using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/text-blocks-in-java-perfect-for-multiline-strings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin for Server-Side Development: Community Content Roundup #2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin community keeps delivering valuable content for server-side development. From gRPC best practices to hands-on Ktor tutorials and Spring integrations, here are the latest highlights. 📖 [Article] Kotlin Tips and Tricks You May Not Know: #6 — Inject Functions in Spring Boot – Elena van Engelen-Maslova shares how to inject functions in Spring Boot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/kotlin-for-server-side-development-community-content-roundup-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PhpStorm Helps Maintain PHP Open-Source Projects: Interviews and Real-World Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The PHP ecosystem is driven by passionate developers building tools that power everything from content management systems right the way through to testing libraries and database layers. Behind each project is a dedicated team working to modernize code, improve performance, and move the ecosystem forward. The fact that many of these teams choose PhpStorm to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/06/10/how-phpstorm-helps-maintain-php-open-source-projects-interviews-and-real-world-examples/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting a Microsoft XNA 3.1 game to MonoGame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how I took a Microsoft XNA 3.1 game from 15 years ago and converted it to use MonoGame on .NET 8 in just a few hours
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/converting-an-xna-game-to-monogame/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL and NoSQL Query langauge support come to ReSharper!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 08:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ReSharper’s query language support for SQL and NoSQL provides C# developers with a more convenient way to work with SQL and NoSQL code directly in Visual Studio with ReSharper, supporting multiple SQL dialects beyond just T-SQL. It includes syntax highlighting, code analysis, auto-completion, and quick fixes to boost efficiency and catch issues early. Based on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/10/sql-and-nosql-query-langauge-support-come-to-resharper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside Ruby Debuggers: TracePoint, Instruction Sequence, and CRuby API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 07:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Debugging is a key part of software development, but most developers use debuggers without knowing how they actually work. The RubyMine team has spent years developing debugging tools for Ruby, and we want to share some of the insights we’ve gained along the way. In this post, we’ll explore the main technologies […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/inside-ruby-debuggers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate JavaScript scanning with Retire.js in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 08:51:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every web developer uses a lot of JavaScript libraries. When installing packages from npm, it almost feels like you are downloading half of the libraries there. Like every other piece of code, JavaScript can include vulnerabilities that make hackers drool and eager to start exploiting your site. In this post,
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/automate-javascript-scanning-with-retire-js-in-azure-devops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental alternative flow for OAuth First-Party Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 04:11:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at an alternative way of implementing a native app authentication and authorization. At present, a web browser is used to implement authentication of native applications when using OAuth and OpenID Connect. The alternative approach implemented in the post is based on the OAuth 2.0 for First-Party Applications draft and adapted to be […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/06/10/experimental-alternative-flow-for-oauth-first-party-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: Handling exceptions with Task.WaitAll and Task.WhenAll</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Task.WhenAll and Task.WaitAll are common methods in C# that allow you to execute multiple Tasks. But… what happens when an exception is thrown?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/task-whenall-vs-task-waitall-error-handling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Rocks SQL Saturday in Louisiana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 16:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The dotNetDave No Rest for the Wicked World Tour will feature a session at SQL Saturday Baton Rouge on July 26, 2025. The speaker, a seasoned software engineer and educator, will share insights from 30 years of experience, focusing on career advancement, work-life balance, and effective learning strategies for tech professionals.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/09/dotnetdave-rocks-the-sql-saturday-in-louisiana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building intelligent AI voice agents with Pipecat and Amazon Bedrock – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this series of posts, you will learn how to build intelligent AI voice agents using Pipecat, an open-source framework for voice and multimodal conversational AI agents, with foundation models on Amazon Bedrock. It includes high-level reference architectures, best practices and code samples to guide your implementation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-intelligent-ai-voice-agents-with-pipecat-and-amazon-bedrock-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stream multi-channel audio to Amazon Transcribe using the Web Audio API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the implementation details of a web application that uses the browser’s Web Audio API and Amazon Transcribe streaming to enable real-time dual-channel transcription. By using the combination of AudioContext, ChannelMergerNode, and AudioWorklet, we were able to seamlessly process and encode the audio data from two microphones before sending it to Amazon Transcribe for transcription.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/stream-multi-channel-audio-to-amazon-transcribe-using-the-web-audio-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Kepler democratized AI access and enhanced client services with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Kepler, a global full-service digital marketing agency serving Fortune 500 brands, we understand the delicate balance between creative marketing strategies and data-driven precision. In this post, we share how implementing Amazon Q Business transformed our operations by democratizing AI access across our organization while maintaining stringent security standards, resulting in an average savings of 2.7 hours per week per employee in manual work and improved client service delivery.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next edit suggestions available in Visual Studio GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot code completions, or gray text, are specialized in autocompleting unfinished code or providing helpful template code. In reality, coding activities are more diverse than writing new code. What if Copilot could better assist your coding not only with code generation, but your code editing activities as well? We are excited to
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/next-edit-suggestions-available-in-visual-studio-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Penetration Testing? Types, Processes, Tools, And Why It’s All Worth It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 14:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Penetration testing (or “pen testing”) is an authorized, simulated cyberattack designed to test the security of a production system. Ethical hackers perform penetration tests, emulating the behavior of cybercriminals to evaluate your software’s security and identify any weaknesses. During a pen test, these cybersecurity specialists use a range of techniques to attack a system. Once […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/what-is-penetration-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: Tricking a program into running non-elevated</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Within the span of a week,¹ we received two security vulnerability reports that claimed that you could use the RunAsInvoker compatibility layer to run any program without requiring administrator privileges. I have pointed out in the past that RunAsInvoker is not a secret, even higher UAC setting, but rather
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250609-00/?p=111258 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Cloud: How to Seamlessly Migrate On-Prem File Shares to Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 11:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For many organizations, legacy file servers have long been the backbone of data sharing and collaboration. But as cloud adoption reaches critical mass, those old file shares start to look like an anchor holding you back. Whether it’s scalability, remote access, disaster recovery, or cost optimization, the writing’s on the wall: it’s time to migrate […] The article Unlocking the Cloud: How to Seamlessly Migrate On-Prem File Shares to Azure Storage was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling security with responsible disclosure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces its Outbound Coordinated Disclosure Policy to guide how it responsibly reports vulnerabilities in third-party software—emphasizing integrity, collaboration, and proactive security at scale.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/scaling-coordinated-vulnerability-disclosure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outbound coordinated vulnerability disclosure policy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Outbound coordinated vulnerability disclosure policy
Link to article: https://openai.com/policies/outbound-coordinated-disclosure-policy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Maximize Thread-Safe Performance in .NET with Spargine’s DistinctBlockingCollection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2025/08_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 16:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2025/08_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DistinctBlockingCollection enhances BlockingCollection by ensuring item uniqueness in high-performance .NET applications, especially in producer-consumer scenarios. It prevents duplicates, providing features like item addition with checks, collection clearing, and methods to maintain thread safety without compromising performance. It&#39;s ideal when duplicate processing could lead to errors or inefficiencies.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/08/boost-your-net-projects-maximize-thread-safe-performance-in-net-with-spargines-distinctblockingcollection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CollabTalk Podcast: Veteran Engineers Aren’t Done Yet – They’re Just Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2025/07_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 13:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2025/07_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this month&#39;s CollabTalk Podcast episode, David McCarter discusses how the tech industry&#39;s focus on youth harms code quality and mentorship, sidelining veteran engineers. He emphasizes the need for experienced voices in tech, encouraging all engineers to engage in discussions about long-term career strategies and to prepare for challenges ahead.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/07/collabtalk-podcast-veteran-engineers-arent-done-yet-theyre-just-getting-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Junior Developers in BIG TROUBLE With AI Usage?! - Dev Leader Weekly 97</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2025/07_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2025/07_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the usage of AI for junior developers just getting started.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/07/are-junior-developers-in-big-trouble-with-ai-usage-dev-leader-weekly-97 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-06-06</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2025/07_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 06:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2025/07_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/07/weekly-recap-20250606 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debunking the &#34;Filter Early, JOIN Later&#34; SQL Performance Myth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2025/07_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2025/07_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That viral SQL performance tip about filtering before joining? It is complete nonsense. Here is why query optimizers make it irrelevant.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/debunking-the-filter-early-join-later-sql-performance-myth 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.4-1 and 1.23.10-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 20:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-4-1-and-1-23-10-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless audio summarization solution with Amazon Bedrock and Whisper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 17:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use the Open AI Whisper foundation model (FM) Whisper Large V3 Turbo, available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace, which offers access to over 140 models through a dedicated offering, to produce near real-time transcription. These transcriptions are then processed by Amazon Bedrock for summarization and redaction of sensitive information.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-audio-summarization-solution-with-amazon-bedrock-and-whisper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement semantic video search using open source large vision models on Amazon SageMaker and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 17:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use large vision models (LVMs) for semantic video search using natural language and image queries. We introduce some use case-specific methods, such as temporal frame smoothing and clustering, to enhance the video search performance. Furthermore, we demonstrate the end-to-end functionality of this approach by using both asynchronous and real-time hosting options on Amazon SageMaker AI to perform video, image, and text processing using publicly available LVMs on the Hugging Face Model Hub.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-account support for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod task governance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how an enterprise with multiple accounts can access a shared Amazon SageMaker HyperPod cluster for running their heterogenous workloads. We use SageMaker HyperPod task governance to enable this feature.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multi-account-support-for-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-task-governance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Text-to-SQL solution for data consistency in generative AI using Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 16:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post evaluates the key options for querying data using generative AI, discusses their strengths and limitations, and demonstrates why Text-to-SQL is the best choice for deterministic, schema-specific tasks. We show how to effectively use Text-to-SQL using Amazon Nova, a foundation model (FM) available in Amazon Bedrock, to derive precise and reliable answers from your data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-text-to-sql-solution-for-data-consistency-in-generative-ai-using-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Modern Python API with Azure Cosmos DB: A 5-Part Video Series</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 15:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m excited to share our new video series where I walk through building a production-ready inventory management API using Python, FastAPI, and Azure Cosmos DB NoSQL. This project demonstrates modern async patterns, clean architecture, and enterprise-grade features like batch operations and optimistic concurrency control.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/building-a-modern-python-api-with-azure-cosmos-db-a-5-part-video-series 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 14:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi there, Java fans! It’s a new month, which means we’ve got a new batch of hot news, deep dives, and tasty tidbits from the Java world for you to enjoy. In this edition, Piotr Przybył joins us in the Featured Content section to share his cultivated list of content finds. We’re also testing a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/java-annotated-monthly-june-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does C&#43;&#43; think my class is copy-constructible when it can&#39;t be copy-constructed?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Consider the following scenario: template struct Base { // Default-constructible Base() = default; // Not copy-constructible Base(Base const &amp;amp;) = delete; }; template struct Derived : Base { Derived() = default; Derived(Derived const&amp;amp; d) :
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250606-00/?p=111254 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Extension Properties with State to Types, (Sort of) In Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author discusses the upcoming .NET 10 release and its new Extension Members feature, particularly focusing on extension properties. Despite direct support lacking, a workaround using ConditionalWeakTable enables tracking exception logging states via extension methods. The author integrates this approach into Spargine, encouraging others to try it for managing exceptions in their code.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/06/adding-extension-properties-to-types-sort-of-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenAI is the new Offshoring</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I originally posted this on LinkedIn / BlueSky but I&#39;ve found that it&#39;s nearly impossible to find (searching for &amp;quot;AI is the new offshoring…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/genai-is-the-new-offshoring/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) - June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 20:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shares the details of the latest changes to the Azure Developer CLI (azd) in releases 1.16.0, 1.16.1, and 1.17.0. We invite you to join our June release discussion on GitHub with questions and comments. This month&#39;s release has new features, bug fixes,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restricting PAT Creation in Azure DevOps Is Now in Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As organizations continue to strengthen their security posture, restricting usage of personal access tokens (PATs) has become a critical area of focus. With the latest public preview of the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/restricting-pat-creation-in-azure-devops-is-now-in-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and LangChain: Leading the Way in AI Security for Open Source on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 17:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For developers building in the field of AI, the industry moves so quickly that we often prioritise speed and execution over everything else. To keep up with the latest changes, many developers and enterpris
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//microsoft-and-langchain-leading-the-way-in-ai-security-for-open-source-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emit logs on-demand with log buffering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing logs in production environments involves tricky trade-offs. You want detailed logs when things go wrong, but you don&#39;t want to pay storage costs for logs that never get examined. While log sampling helps reduce log volume by emitting only a percentage of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/emit-logs-on-demand-with-log-buffering 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize and migrate on-premises fraud detection machine learning workflows to Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Radial is the largest 3PL fulfillment provider, also offering integrated payment, fraud detection, and omnichannel solutions to mid-market and enterprise brands. In this post, we share how Radial optimized the cost and performance of their fraud detection machine learning (ML) applications by modernizing their ML workflow using Amazon SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/modernize-and-migrate-on-premises-fraud-detection-machine-learning-workflows-to-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contextual retrieval in Anthropic using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Contextual retrieval enhances traditional RAG by adding chunk-specific explanatory context to each chunk before generating embeddings. This approach enriches the vector representation with relevant contextual information, enabling more accurate retrieval of semantically related content when responding to user queries. In this post, we demonstrate how to use contextual retrieval with Anthropic and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/contextual-retrieval-in-anthropic-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run small language models cost-efficiently with AWS Graviton and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy a small language model on SageMaker AI by extending our pre-built containers to be compatible with AWS Graviton instances. We first provide an overview of the solution, and then provide detailed implementation steps to help you get started. You can find the example notebook in the GitHub repo.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/run-small-language-models-cost-efficiently-with-aws-graviton-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Caching Done Right</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you need to scale your API, one of the first things developers often think about is, “Let’s just add a cache.” If API Caching were that simple. Adding caching introduces a whole new set of problems that you need to consider carefully to be successful with your caching strategy. In this article, I want… Read More »API Caching Done Right The post API Caching Done Right appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to filter C&#43;&#43; Build Insights by project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 15:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 version 17.14 comes with quality-of-life improvements to its C++ Build Insights integration that will make it easier for you to navigate large multi-project traces and handle long file names for your build inputs and artifacts.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-to-filter-c-build-insights-by-project 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Ceremony Railway Programming with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 15:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Railway Programming is an idea that came out of the F# community as a way to develop for “sad path” exception cases without having to resort to throwing .NET Exceptions as a way of doing flow control. Railway Programming works by chaining together functions with a standardized response in such a way that it’s relatively easy to abort … Continue reading Low Ceremony Railway Programming with Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do some Windows functions fail if I pass an unaligned Unicode string?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer found that if they passed Unicode strings (which in Windows means strings encoded as UTF-16LE using the two-byte data type wchar_t as code units) which are not on even addresses, then some—but not all—functions fail to accept those strings. Why isn&#39;t this documented? This is one of the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250605-00/?p=111250 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Plugin Metadata Management with SemanticPluginForge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of software development, flexibility and adaptability are key. Developers often face challenges when it comes to updating plugin metadata dynamically without disrupting services or requiring redeployment. This is where SemanticPluginForge, an open-source project, step
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/enhancing-plugin-metadata-management-with-semanticpluginforge 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarter SK Agents with Contextual Function Selection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 09:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Smarter SK Agents with Contextual Function Selection In today&#39;s fast-paced AI landscape, developers are constantly seeking ways to make AI interactions more efficient and relevant. The new Contextual Function Selection feature in the Semantic Kernel Agent Framework is here to address this need. By dynamically selecti
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/smarter-sk-agents-with-contextual-function-selection 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Waterfall Evaluation of Query Classification, Retrieval &amp; Generation in Multi-Agent LLM Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As organizations increasingly deploy multi-agent LLM systems to handle complex queries and workflows, the need for robust evaluation frameworks becomes crucial. Based on our recent work implementing hypothesis-driven experimentation for a large enterprise client, this post shares insights on building a hierarchical water
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/hierarchical-waterfall-evaluation-query-classification-rag-llm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.28 with LLM usage and costs tracking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 06:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the release of Dev Proxy v0.28. This version introduces a new ability to help you understand language models’ usage and costs in your applications, alongside many improvements to mocking, TypeSpec generation, and plugin flexibility. In this version: New OpenAITelemetryPlugin to track language mode
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-28-with-llm-usage-and-costs-tracking 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disrupting malicious uses of AI: June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our June 2025 update, we outline how we’re disrupting malicious uses of AI—through safety tools that detect and counter abuse, support democratic values, and promote responsible AI deployment for the benefit of all.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/disrupting-malicious-uses-of-ai-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing GenAI Coding Risk Like an Investment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI tools have greatly improved in their ability to generate large amounts of code, quickly, to support software development tasks…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/genai-coding-investment-risk-strategy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
