<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:37:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How BQA streamlines education quality reporting using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Education and Training Quality Authority (BQA) plays a critical role in improving the quality of education and training services in the Kingdom Bahrain. BQA reviews the performance of all education and training institutions, including schools, universities, and vocational institutes, thereby promoting the professional advancement of the nation’s human capital. In this post, we explore how BQA used the power of Amazon Bedrock, Amazon SageMaker JumpStart, and other AWS services to streamline the overall reporting workflow.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting team innovation, productivity, and knowledge sharing with Amazon Q Business – Web experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how MuleSoft introduced a generative AI-powered assistant using Amazon Q Business to enhance their internal Cloud Central dashboard. This individualized portal shows assets owned, costs and usage, and well-architected recommendations to over 100 engineers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boosting-team-innovation-productivity-and-knowledge-sharing-with-amazon-q-business-web-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simplified overview of ways to add or update elements in a std::map</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            And using it to find missing opportunities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250113-00/?p=110757 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Gordon: An AI Agent for Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We share our experiments creating a Docker AI Agent, named Gordon, which can help new users learn about our tools and products and help power users get things done faster.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/meet-gordon-an-ai-agent-for-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing CodeCanvas 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we enter 2025, we hope you had an amazing holiday season filled with joy, relaxation, and plenty of inspiration for the year ahead! CodeCanvas 2024.3, last year’s final release, went live just before the holidays. To avoid adding to the busy year-end rush, we delayed the announcement until now, ensuring it gets the attention […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/01/introducing-codecanvas-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Files vs. A Server with an SMB Share: Key Takeaways from MS Cloud IT Pro Podcast Episode 367</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MS Cloud IT Pro Podcast episode 367, hosted by Ben Segink and Scott Hoag, dives deep into a crucial IT topic: choosing between Azure Files and a traditional server with an SMB share for file storage in the cloud. This episode is essential for IT professionals navigating cloud migration strategies and balancing infrastructure needs. […] The article Azure Files vs. A Server with an SMB Share: Key Takeaways from MS Cloud IT Pro Podcast Episode 367 was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Change Signature in C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Change Signature allows you to modify a function’s parameters, including reordering, adding, removing, or altering them across various locations. Previously, the Change Signature feature in Visual Studio involved multiple clicks and nested pop-up windows. In Visual Studio 2022 version 17.12, we’ve reduced the number of clicks and eliminated these nested steps to streamline the process. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/enhanced-change-signature-in-c 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HSTS for HttpClient in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HTTP Strict Transport Security (HSTS) is a security feature that indicates a client to only connect to a website over HTTPS. Websites can set the Strict-Transport-Security header to inform the client to always use HTTPS. ASP.NET Core can easily set the header, but there is no built-in feature to enable HSTS for an HttpClient. In this post, I describe how to create an HttpClient that supports HSTS,…
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Perform Snapshot Testing With Verify in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to discuss how to perform snapshot testing on objects using the Verify library. Testing is an important part of our software development pipeline. As developers, we often rely on familiar testing approaches like unit testing, where we assert the behavior of individual components of an application, and integration testing, […] The post How to Perform Snapshot Testing With Verify in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop the Leaks: Properly Disposing Objects in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article highlights the persistent issue of failing to call Dispose() on disposable objects in .NET projects, which leads to memory leaks and system instability. The author recommends using IDisposableAnalyzers and memory profilers to detect these issues, alongside custom extension methods for easier disposal management, advocating for proactive solutions to maintain application performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/01/13/stop-the-leaks-properly-disposing-objects-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine 3.6: Modular Monolith and Vertical Slice Architecture Goodies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine 3.6 just went out tonight as a big release with bug fixes and quite a few significant features to improve Wolverine‘s usability for modular monolith architectures and to further improve Wolverine’s already outstanding usability for vertical slice architecture. Highlights: And of course, the full list of closed issues addressed by this release. As a little … Continue reading Wolverine 3.6: Modular Monolith and Vertical Slice Architecture Goodies →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How and Why To Learn In Public - Dev Leader Weekly 78</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to and why you should learn in public as a developer!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/01/11/how-and-why-to-learn-in-public-dev-leader-weekly-78 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Token Usage with Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing in my recent series of posts about calling LLMs with C# using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI NuGet package, in this post I want to discuss how to track the cost of your API calls to AI models. Each AI provider will have its own pricing structure for the various models it offers. For example, here are pricing pages for Azure OpenAI service, OpenAI&#39;s own API, Anthropic&#39;s API, Google Gemini API, DeepSeek API, Amazon Bedrock, and xAI Grok.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with LLMs in .NET using Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft.Extensions.AI provides a unified interface for integrating LLMs into .NET applications, allowing developers to switch between providers like Ollama, Azure, or OpenAI without changing application code. Through practical examples of chat completion, article summarization, and smart categorization, this article demonstrates how to leverage the library&#39;s features while running LLMs locally using Ollama.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/working-with-llms-in-dotnet-using-microsoft-extensions-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Azure Networking Outage in East US 2 Affecting VMs, App Service, and More! (Started January 8, 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On January 8, 2025, Microsoft Azure started experiencing a significant networking outage in the East US 2 region. This outage has impacted a broad range of Azure services (including Azure App Service, VMs, and more!) causing disruptions for businesses relying on these services for critical workloads. As of the time I’m writing this, the issue […] The article Major Azure Networking Outage in East US 2 Affecting VMs, App Service, and More!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Patterns for Building Resilient Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When the CrowdStrike incident happened, I was alarmed and notified of a degrading performance in parts of our system. That’s because we were indirectly impacted. I will provide some thoughts about how specific design patterns allow you to build resilient systems, allowing you to keep your system alive and online. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where… Read More »Design Patterns for Building Resilient Systems The post Design Patterns for Building Resilient Systems appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does inadvertently passing a std::string instead of a char const* to a variadic function crash on x86-32 but not x86-64?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking at the calling convention and the small string optimization.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250110-00/?p=110744 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Public Preview of Apple Identity Provider Support for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the public preview of &amp;quot;Sign in with Apple&amp;quot; support for Microsoft Entra External ID. This feature allows users to sign up and sign in to applications using their Apple ID. Apple joins Google and Facebook as pre-configured social identity providers, supporting Single Sign-On (SSO) through the OAuth framework.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/openid-connect-social-identity-provider-apple 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LLMOps in restricted networks and addressing continuous evaluation long run constraints</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we&#39;ll explore the challenges we faced in establishing LLMOps and continuous evaluation within a pipeline using Azure Machine Learning, particularly when dealing with long runs and a restricted Bring-Your-Own (BYO) network.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/llmops-in-restricted-networks-and-continuous-evaluation-long-run-constraints 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>通过 .NET Aspire 使用本地 AI 模型</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Aaron Powell的Using Local AI models with .NET Aspire 使用本地 AI 模型是在您自己的计算机上进行实验的一个很好的方法，它无需将资源部署到云中。在本文中，我们将了解如何使用.NET Aspire 和 Ollama 在本地运行 AI 模型，同时使用 Microsoft.Extensions.AI 抽象使其在部署时过渡到云托管模型。 在 .NET Aspire 中设置 Ollama 我们需要某种方法来从 .NET Aspire 应用程序中使用 Ollama，最简单的方法就是使用 .NET Aspire 社区工具包中的 Ollama 托管集成。您可以通过 Visual Studio 工具、VS Code 工具或 .NET CLI 从 NuGet 安装 Ollama 托管集成。让我们看一下如何通过命令行将 Ollama 托管集成安装到我们的应用程序主机项目中： dotnet add package CommunityToolkit.Aspire.Hosting.Ollama 安装 Ollama 托管集成后，您可以在 Program.cs […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e9%80%9a%e8%bf%87-net-aspire-%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8%e6%9c%ac%e5%9c%b0-ai-%e6%a8%a1%e5%9e%8b 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering AI Agents with Tools via OpenAPI: A Hands-On Guide with Microsoft Semantic Kernel Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 22:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today the Semantic Kernel team is happy to welcome back our guest author, Akshay Kokane. We will turn it over to him to dive into his recent Medium article on Semantic Kernel. As we advance towards an Agentic Approach in the AI world, I would like to share my insights on how Semantic Kernel can […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/empowering-ai-agents-with-tools-via-openapi-a-hands-on-guide-with-microsoft-semantic-kernel-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Essentials: Building Basics with Microsoft Copilot Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 22:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Exploring the Essentials: Building Basics with Microsoft Copilot Studio Don’t know how to start with building an agent in Microsoft Copilot Studio? We’ve got you covered! In our AI in Action: Building with Copilot Studio series on the Power Platform YouTube channel, we have several episodes that guide you through how to get started in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/exploring-the-essentials-building-basics-with-microsoft-copilot-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 21:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced the retirement of Azure CDN services from the azureedge.net domain by January 15, 2025, driven by Edgio’s (formerly Limelight Networks) business closure. This domain underpins Azure CDN services, .NET installations, and content delivery for various Azure and Microsoft services. The shift requires developers and DevOps teams to update configurations, pipelines, and deployment […] The article Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an Amazon Bedrock based digital lending solution on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 20:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we propose a solution using DigitalDhan, a generative AI-based solution to automate customer onboarding and digital lending. The proposed solution uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to automate services related to KYC verification, credit and risk assessment, and notification. Financial institutions can use this solution to help automate the customer onboarding, KYC verification, credit decisioning, credit underwriting, and notification processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-amazon-bedrock-based-digital-lending-solution-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI-powered malware analysis using Amazon Bedrock with Deep Instinct</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Deep Instinct’s generative AI-powered malware analysis tool, DIANNA, uses Amazon Bedrock to revolutionize cybersecurity by providing rapid, in-depth analysis of known and unknown threats, enhancing the capabilities of AWS System and Organization Controls (SOC) teams and addressing key challenges in the evolving threat landscape.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-ai-powered-malware-analysis-using-amazon-bedrock-with-deep-instinct/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email your conversations from Amazon Q</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As organizations navigate the complexities of the digital realm, generative AI has emerged as a transformative force, empowering enterprises to enhance productivity, streamline workflows, and drive innovation. To maximize the value of insights generated by generative AI, it is crucial to provide simple ways for users to preserve and share these insights using commonly used tools such as email. This post explores how you can integrate Amazon Q Business with Amazon SES to email conversations to specified email addresses.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code update – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 17:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the new year with exciting updates to Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code including a refreshed user interface for getting started and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/teams-toolkit-for-visual-studio-code-update-january-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MWA pattern: Strangler Fig</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 13:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Author’s Note: After announcing the Modern Web App (MWA) pattern (https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/introducing-the-modern-web-app-mwa-pattern-for-java), we now focus on one of its many pattens – the Strangler Fig pattern. This pattern incrementally modernizes a legacy Java application by “strangling” targeted areas and replacing them with new microservices or minimal web apps. We’ll explore an example showing how to integrate […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/mwa-pattern-strangler-fig 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incident Update: Docker Desktop for Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker has identified and provided a temporary workaround for an issue preventing Docker Desktop from starting on some macOS systems, with a permanent fix currently in development.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/incident-update-docker-desktop-for-mac/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock cost-effective AI inference using Amazon Bedrock serverless capabilities with an Amazon SageMaker trained model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 22:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies such as AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Mistral AI, Stability AI, and Amazon through a single API, along with a broad set of capabilities to build generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. In this post, I’ll show you how to use Amazon Bedrock—with its fully managed, on-demand API—with your Amazon SageMaker trained or fine-tuned model.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Dockerize a Django App: Step-by-Step Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We show how to create a Docker container for your Django application, which gives you a standardized environment and makes it easier to get up and running and be more productive.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-dockerize-django-app/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server Native Vector Search for .NET Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It seems that the majority of developers naturally believe this field of software development belongs to mathematics and Python developers, who originally started building the first solutions. However, .NET and C# provide a great foundation for building almost any kind of application on any platform in a highly professional way. In this post, we will […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/sql-server-native-vector-search-for-net-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a RAG-Based Smart Memory Application with Azure SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Project Mission The way people work and manage information is changing rapidly in our digital age. More and more people are struggling to keep track of all the online resources they use daily. They need a better way to save, organize, and retrieve important information from websites, articles, and other online sources. This is especially […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/building-a-rag-based-smart-memory-application-with-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term real-world data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/data-cleaning-in-data-science/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside STL: Waiting for a std::atomic&lt;std::shared_ptr&lt;T&gt;&gt; to change, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Waiting on a single pointer, but checking for two.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250108-00/?p=110732 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Efficiency with Docker for AI and Cloud-Native Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker helps you deliver secure, efficient applications by providing consistent environments and building on best practices that let you discover and resolve issues earlier in the software development life cycle (SDLC).
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/unlocking-efficiency-with-docker-for-ai-and-cloud-native-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Developer CLI: Accelerate App &amp; Infrastructure Deployment on Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers and organizations increasingly adopt cloud solutions, streamlining the deployment of applications and infrastructure becomes a critical part of achieving efficiency and scalability. Microsoft’s Azure Developer CLI (azd) addresses this by providing an integrated, open-source command-line tool that accelerates the journey from local development to Azure deployment. Whether you’re a solo developer or part […] The article Introduction to Azure Developer CLI: Accelerate App &amp;amp; Infrastructure Deployment on Microsoft Azure was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The start of the new year is the perfect time to share our plans for JetBrains Rider 2025.1. These plans are subject to change based on available resources, evolving development priorities, and shifts in the .NET landscape. Some features and improvements may be postponed to a later release date. With that in mind, let’s dive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/08/rider-2025-1-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Plan Support for GitHub Copilot Available on JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, developers! Welcome to our very first blog post dedicated to GitHub Copilot Plugin for JetBrains IDEs in 2025. We are excited to share that the new Free Plan for GitHub Copilot has been available for everyone on JetBrains IDEs! Whether you use IntelliJ IDEA (Ultimate, Community, Educational), PyCharm(Professional, Community, Educational), WebStorm, PhpStorm, Rider, or […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/free-plan-support-for-github-copilot-available-on-jetbrains-ides 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new year has arrived, and we’re kicking it off with another handpicked selection of must-read tutorials and the latest news you won’t want to miss. This issue starts with an amazing featured content section with Donald Raab. Settle in and scroll your way to some fresh knowledge! Featured Content Greetings, Java Annotated Monthly readers! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/java-annotated-monthly-january-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>azd CDN changing January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 22:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post makes customers aware of a critical Content Delivery Network (CDN) change for azd (the Azure Developer CLI) because the CDN provider is changing from Edgio to Azure Front Door.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azd-cdn-changing-january-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Update: blog migration to quantum.microsoft.com</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 21:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that the Q# blog will be migrating to a new home at Azure Quantum in Feb 2025. This move will allow us to provide you with a more integrated and enhanced experience, featuring the latest updates and resources in the world of quantum computing. Stay tuned for more details and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/qsharp/important-update-blog-migration-to-quantum-microsoft-com 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire Quick Tip – Managing Container &amp; Data Lifetime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Aspire 9 adds new control over the lifetime of containers on your local developer environment. Let&#39;s look at how to manage them with the new APIs!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-aspire-container-lifetime 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Align and monitor your Amazon Bedrock powered insurance assistance chatbot to responsible AI principles with AWS Audit Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI applications should be developed with adequate controls for steering the behavior of FMs. Responsible AI considerations such as privacy, security, safety, controllability, fairness, explainability, transparency and governance help ensure that AI systems are trustworthy. In this post, we demonstrate how to use the AWS generative AI best practices framework on AWS Audit Manager to evaluate this insurance claim agent from a responsible AI lens.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/align-and-monitor-your-amazon-bedrock-powered-insurance-assistance-chatbot-to-responsible-ai-principles-with-aws-audit-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Stock Exchange Group uses Amazon Q Business to enhance post-trade client services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore a client services agent assistant application developed by the London Stock Exchange Group (LSEG) using Amazon Q Business. We will discuss how Amazon Q Business saved time in generating answers, including summarizing documents, retrieving answers to complex Member enquiries, and combining information from different data sources (while providing in-text citations to the data sources used for each answer).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/london-stock-exchange-group-uses-amazon-q-business-to-enhance-post-trade-client-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate large language models for your machine translation tasks on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post with accompanying code presents a solution to experiment with real-time machine translation using foundation models (FMs) available in Amazon Bedrock. It can help collect more data on the value of LLMs for your content translation use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-large-language-models-for-your-machine-translation-tasks-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parameta accelerates client email resolution with Amazon Bedrock Flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Parameta used Amazon Bedrock Flows to transform their manual client email processing into an automated, intelligent workflow that reduced resolution times from weeks to days while maintaining high accuracy and operational control.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/parameta-accelerates-client-email-resolution-with-amazon-bedrock-flows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gesellschaft zur Stärkung der Verben: The German Society for the Irregularization of Verbs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stand strong and proud.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250107-01/?p=110724 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergency power resets on Lenovo, HP, Dell, and Acer laptops</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking for the magic button.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250107-00/?p=110719 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up a Kubernetes Cluster on Docker Desktop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We walk through the steps to start a Kubernetes cluster on Docker Desktop and provide troubleshooting tips to ensure a smooth experience.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-set-up-a-kubernetes-cluster-on-docker-desktop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking with Visual Studio Profiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Visual Studio 17.13 Preview we have released our updated BenchmarkDotNet diagnosers, allowing you to use more of the tools in the performance profiler to analyze benchmarks. With this change it is super quick to dig into CPU usage and allocations of benchmarks making the measure, change, measure cycle quick and efficient. Benchmarking a real […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/benchmarking-with-visual-studio-profiler 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a High-Performance Message Queue with Redis Streams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Beyond Pub/Sub: Implementing Reliable Work Distribution with Redis When developers reach for Redis as a messaging solution, they typically gravitate toward its Pub/Sub capabilities. While Pub/Sub excels at broadcasting messages to multiple subscribers, it falls short for reliable work distribution scenarios. Messages are transient - any offline
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/building-a-high-performance-message-queue-with-redis-streams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an interceptor with a source generator: Creating a source generator - Part 11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how interceptors work, and how you can implement an interceptor using a source generator and the GetInterceptableLocation API
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-source-generator-part-11-implementing-an-interceptor-with-a-source-generator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Code Java中的JavaC支持发布！</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家新年好！我们很高兴宣布，Visual Studio Code Java、JDT 和 JDT-LS 现已部分支持使用 Javac 作为底层编译器。这项支持是红帽和微软经过近一年合作的成果。 此更改旨在确保对最新 Java 特性的及时支持，并使 VS Code 上的 Java 语言支持与常见构建工具（如 Maven、Gradle）更加一致。许多用户希望获得更无缝的开箱即用开发体验，我们相信引入 Javac 是实现这一目标的重要第一步。 用户可以从基于 Javac 的工具中获得以下好处： 更符合 Java 规范的编译器正确性 在 VS Code 和 Eclipse 中更快地支持新 Java 版本 减少 JDT 和 JDT-LS 团队的维护负担 更轻松地测试预览功能和尚未发布的 Java 版本 请注意，基于 Javac 的 JDT 是 ECJ 编译器的另一选项，并非要完全替代 ECJ。目前，VS Code Java 中的基于 Javac 的支持默认处于关闭状态，可以通过以下方式启用： […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/visual-studio-code-java-javc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Neural Rendering in DirectX: Cooperative Vector Support Coming Soon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Neural Rendering: A New Paradigm in 3D Graphics Programming In the constantly advancing landscape of 3D graphics, neural rendering technology represents a significant evolution. Neural rendering broadly defines the suite of techniques that leverage AI/ML to dramatically transform traditional graphics pipelines. These new methods promise to push the boundaries of what’s possible in real-time graphics. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/enabling-neural-rendering-in-directx-cooperative-vector-support-coming-soon 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Courses for Java Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tired of the same predictable and monotonous Java tutorials? So was I. I used to think all Java courses were the same. Endless tutorials where someone talks about getters and setters in a monotonous, robotic voice while you put all of your effort into just trying to stay awake. After months of intensive research and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/best-courses-for-java-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness Functions in Software Architecture: measuring things to ensure prosperity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Non-functional requirements matter, but we often forget to validate them. You can measure them by setting up Fitness Functions.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/fitness-functions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing images to LLMs in C# with Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_01_2025/07_01_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I recently posted about how to get started calling LLMs with C# using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI NuGet package. The model we chose to use was gpt-4o-mini, which has the advantage of being &amp;quot;multimodal&amp;quot;, as it can accept not only text input, but images as well. In this post I&#39;ll show how you can pass an image to this model using Microsoft.Extensions.AI and ask it to describe the image. It&#39;s relatively straightforward, but as always seems to be the case with these things, there was a gotcha I ran into.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently build and tune custom log anomaly detection models with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through the process to build an automated mechanism using Amazon SageMaker to process your log data, run training iterations over it to obtain the best-performing anomaly detection model, and register it with the Amazon SageMaker Model Registry for your customers to use it.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/efficiently-build-and-tune-custom-log-anomaly-detection-models-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing personal access token (PAT) usage across Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the new year, we’ll be making moves towards strengthening Microsoft and our customers’ security posture in regards to the usage and creation of personal access tokens (PATs). If you’ve been following this blog, you may have noticed we’ve been distancing away from PATs as the recommended authentication method for Azure DevOps APIs by offering […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/reducing-pat-usage-across-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (December 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 18:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.12.16 registry release, 2024-12-09 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout December. This release includes a command line option to force vcpkg to use classic mode even if a manifest file is found along with bug fixes. Some […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-december-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) continues to permeate our daily lives, but the way we interact with these systems remains an evolving landscape. In a recent episode of the Hanselminutes podcast, host Scott Hanselman sat down with designer and technologist Maggie Appleton to explore a fascinating question: What is AI’s UI (User Interface)? Their conversation sheds light […] The article What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack Roadmap for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A belated Happy New Year’s to everybody! The “Critter Stack” had a huge 2024, and I listed off some of the highlights of the improvements we made in Critter Stack Year in Review for 2024. For 2025, we’ve reordered our priority order from what I was writing last summer. I think we might genuinely focus more … Continue reading Critter Stack Roadmap for 2025 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/01/06/critter-stack-roadmap-for-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I tell whether a change to a control was due to the user or due to my program?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You know when it was done by your program because you did it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250106-00/?p=110715 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking insights with Meter Histogram in the profiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you struggling with performance bottlenecks in your applications? Look no further! Visual Studio 2022 introduces the Meter Histogram feature in its performance profiling suite, providing you with the tools to analyze and visualize histogram data like never before. The Meter Histogram is a key enhancement to Visual Studio’s performance profiling suite. This feature enables […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/unlocking-insights-with-meter-histogram-in-the-profiler 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring CollectionsMarshal for Dictionary</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unlike ConcurrentDictionary, Dictionary does not have a GetOrAdd method. This method is useful when you want to add a key-value pair to the dictionary if the key does not exist, or return the value if the key already exists. The naive implementation of this method looks like this: public static TValue GetOrAdd&amp;lt;TKey, TValue&amp;gt;(this Dictionary&amp;lt;TKey, TValue&amp;gt; dict, TKey key, TValue value) where TKey : notnull {…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/exploring-collectionsmarshal-for-dictionary.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Parallel Processing of Collections in Microsoft .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses the performance of various parallelism techniques for iterating over collections in .NET, comparing parallel methods such as Parallel.For and AsParallel() with traditional approaches. It highlights that while parallel methods can enhance performance for large collections, traditional methods often outperform them, particularly with smaller collections. Recommendations and a new method, FastModifyCollection, are introduced for efficient processing.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/01/06/evaluating-the-parallel-processing-of-collections-in-microsoft-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persist Values With AsyncLocal in C# Async Flow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explain the AsyncLocal class and how to persist values across an async flow with the AsyncLocal class in C#. We’ll start by describing the challenge that AsyncLocal solves and continue with examples of how it does that. We’ll scratch the surface of the AsyncLocal inner workings and finish with the cases […] The post Persist Values With AsyncLocal in C# Async Flow appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
