<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>.NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 11:57:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>All KotlinConf Recordings Are Now Available. Enjoy!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 11:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now find all of the session recordings from KotlinConf’24 on the conference website! Sessions are also being added to the Kotlin YouTube channel: Photos and slides from some of the sessions are also available – click on a talk and select “Download slides” for the latter. Don’t miss these additional materials from the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/06/kotlinconf24-recordings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code 的 .NET MAUI 扩展现已正式发布</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 06:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Maddy Montaquila的The .NET MAUI Extension for Visual Studio Code is now Generally Available 今天，我们非常高兴地宣布 .NET MAUI VS Code 扩展插件结束了预览阶段，并将包含一些期待已久的新功能 – 包括 XAML IntelliSense 和 Hot Reload！ 什么是 .NET MAUI 扩展插件？ .NET MAUI 扩展插件为您提供了在轻量级 Visual Studio Code 中开发 .NET MAUI 应用所需的工具。它基于C# Dev Kit 和 C# 扩展构建，提供了解决方案资源管理器、C# Hot Reload、强大的 C# IntelliSense 等众多功能。.NET MAUI 扩展增加了针对移动设备和桌面设备的能力，此外，借助最新版本的扩展，增加了 XAML IntelliSense 和 XAML Hot Reload，同时让您的 VS Code 体验更加精简和简单。 全新的和改进的 XAML 编辑体验 .NET MAUI 扩展的预览版附带了基本的 XAML 语法高亮显示和自动补全功能，但它与我们想要交付的完整体验相距甚远。在过去的一年里，我们对 Visual Studio 中现有的 XAML 语言服务进行了现代化改造，将其打包，并带到 VS Code中以供您进行 .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 05:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to talk about a structural design pattern, the Proxy Pattern. We will discuss what problem this pattern solves and how to implement it in C#. If you want to read more about design patterns in C#, you can inspect our C# Design Patterns page. Let’s start. What is The Proxy Design […] The post Proxy Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Building AI Agents with LangChain and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LangChain is a tool for more easily creating AI agents that can autonomously perform tasks. These agents can streamline operations, enhance user experiences, and handle complex processes with minimal human intervention. Building these AI agents can be difficult and this is the reason for why LangChain exists. LangChain is a cutting-edge framework designed to simplify […] The article Introduction to Building AI Agents with LangChain and Python was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String Performance: Improving String Formatting Performance by a Factor of 1.5 or More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article demonstrates how to accelerate string formatting by more than 1.5 times using project resources or static text formats.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/23/string-performance-improving-string-formatting-performance-by-a-factor-of-1-5-or-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off Topic: 90’s Country Music Rewind</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 21:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m a huge fan of alt country or Americana music, definitely appreciate some classic country like Johnny Cash, Lefty Frizzell or Buck Owens, and I live in Austin so it’s mandatory to be into Willie Nelson, Robert Earl Keen, Hays Carll, and the late, great Billy Joe Shaver (maybe my favorite musician of all time). … Continue reading Off Topic: 90’s Country Music Rewind →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/06/22/off-topic-90s-country-music-rewind/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting AI Hallucinations using Semantic Entropy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 18:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) and the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) has transformed numerous fields, from healthcare to entertainment, by enabling machines to understand and generate human-like text. However, one significant challenge in deploying AI, especially LLMs, is the phenomenon of AI “hallucinations.” These are instances where the AI generates plausible-sounding but factually incorrect or […] The article Detecting AI Hallucinations using Semantic Entropy was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are AI Agents and Agentic AI?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 15:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI Agents are more advanced implementations of artificial intelligence (AI) built to more autonomously perform tasks, make decisions, and interact with users or other systems. These agents are designed to simulate human-like “cognitive” functions, enabling them to process information, learn from interactions, and adapt to new scenarios without direct human intervention. Where’s the AI intelligence […] The article What are AI Agents and Agentic AI? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actionable Code Review Culture Tips  – Dev Leader Weekly 49</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Actionable Code Review Culture Tips – Dev Leader Weekly 49 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss various actionable code review culture tips! The post Actionable Code Review Culture Tips – Dev Leader Weekly 49 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/06/22/actionable-code-review-culture-tips-dev-leader-weekly-49/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What You Need To Know About EF Core Bulk Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            EF Core 7 introduced two powerful new methods, ExecuteUpdate and ExecuteDelete. However, there&#39;s an important caveat: these bulk operations bypass the EF Core Change Tracker.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/what-you-need-to-know-about-ef-core-bulk-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Amazon SageMaker JumpStart foundation model access with private hubs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 19:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker JumpStart is a machine learning (ML) hub offering pre-trained models and pre-built solutions. It provides access to hundreds of foundation models (FMs). A private hub is a feature in SageMaker JumpStart that allows an organization to share their models and notebooks so as to centralize model artifacts, facilitate discoverability, and increase the reuse […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-foundation-model-access-with-private-hubs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eSentire delivers private and secure generative AI interactions to customers with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 14:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            eSentire is an industry-leading provider of Managed Detection &amp;amp; Response (MDR) services protecting users, data, and applications of over 2,000 organizations globally across more than 35 industries. These security services help their customers anticipate, withstand, and recover from sophisticated cyber threats, prevent disruption from malicious attacks, and improve their security posture. In 2023, eSentire was […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/esentire-delivers-private-and-secure-generative-ai-interactions-to-customers-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Windows Runtime winrt::hstring and the C&#43;&#43; std::wstring are inter-assignable</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just assign them over, no cermony necessary.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240621-00/?p=109925 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Building AI Agents with Microsoft Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 11:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Semantic Kernel is an innovative, open-source SDK designed to seamlessly integrate Large Language Models (LLMs) with conventional programming languages like C#, Python, and Java. By utilizing Semantic Kernel, developers can create powerful, AI-driven applications without needing to become AI experts. This introduction will guide you through the fundamental concepts, features, and benefits of using […] The article Introduction to Building AI Agents with Microsoft Semantic Kernel was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.4 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 10:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.4 has arrived with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates included in v2024.1.4: To find out more details about the issues […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/intellij-idea-2024-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.1.5 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 10:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WebStorm 2024.1.5, the fifth update for WebStorm 2024.1, is now available! It contains several improvements from the platform. You can update to v2024.1.5 by using the Toolbox App, installing it right from the IDE, or downloading it from our website. Notable improvements Here are some of the notable updates included in v2024.1.5: That’s all for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/06/webstorm-2024-1-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Collaboration with a Tech Savvy Customer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Empowering Collaboration with a Tech Savvy Customer
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/empowering-collaboration-with-tech-savvy-customer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 6: Streamlined Log Management, Enhanced Gradle Build Script Experience, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 06:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 6 is out! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 6 The latest build offers a streamlined user experience with Gradle build scripts, enhanced logging support for Java and Kotlin, and improvements to support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Semaphore Class in C# and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 21:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll introduce the semaphore class in C#. We’ll compare the semaphore and semaphoreSlim classes and discuss the best practices for using semaphores. Let’s start. What is a Semaphore Class in C#? The Semaphore class in C# is another mechanism to synchronize a thread’s access to shared resources. It’s more flexible than lock […] The post Working With Semaphore Class in C# and Best Practices appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Tenancy: Mixed Modes with Marten</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 19:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is continuing a series about multi-tenancy with Marten, Wolverine, and ASP.Net Core: In previous posts I’ve described first why multi-tenancy might be useful, how to do it with Marten’s “conjoined” tenancy model, and lastly how to do it with separate databases for each tenant. Marten is more flexible than that though, and it’s sometimes valid to … Continue reading Multi-Tenancy: Mixed Modes with Marten →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/06/20/multi-tenancy-mixed-modes-with-marten/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 18:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to announce the release of TypeScript 5.5! If you’re not familiar with TypeScript, it’s a language that builds on top of JavaScript by making it possible to declare and describe types. Writing types in our code allows us to explain intent and have other tools check our code to catch mistakes like typos,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperva optimizes SQL generation from natural language using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with Ori Nakar from Imperva. Imperva Cloud WAF protects hundreds of thousands of websites against cyber threats and blocks billions of security events every day. Counters and insights based on security events are calculated daily and used by users from multiple departments. Millions of counters are added daily, together […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/imperva-optimizes-sql-generation-from-natural-language-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create natural conversations with Amazon Lex QnAIntent and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customer service organizations today face an immense opportunity. As customer expectations grow, brands have a chance to creatively apply new innovations to transform the customer experience. Although meeting rising customer demands poses challenges, the latest breakthroughs in conversational artificial intelligence (AI) empowers companies to meet these expectations. Customers today expect timely responses to their questions […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-natural-conversations-with-amazon-lex-qnaintent-and-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Third Party API and Package Map Support for .NET Upgrade Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to extend the .NET Upgrade Assistant by providing mappings for your own libraries and packages.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-api-map-support-for-ua 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate the reliability of Retrieval Augmented Generation applications using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to evaluate the performance, trustworthiness, and potential biases of your RAG pipelines and applications on Amazon Bedrock. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Mistral AI, Stability AI, and Amazon through a single API, along with a broad set of capabilities to build generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Amazon services using AWS PrivateLink in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 16:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a solution for configuring SageMaker notebook instances to connect to Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services with the use of AWS PrivateLink and Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) security groups.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/connect-to-amazon-services-using-aws-privatelink-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI-Ready Infrastructure in Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 15:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is transforming the landscape of modern enterprises, driving innovation, enhancing operational efficiency, and unlocking new avenues for growth. As businesses strive to harness the full potential of AI, having an AI-ready infrastructure becomes paramount. Microsoft Azure stands out as a leader in this domain, offering a comprehensive suite of tools and services […] The article Build an AI-Ready Infrastructure in Microsoft Azure was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to convert between different types of counted-string string types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking for constructors that take a character count.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240620-00/?p=109922 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Beta Feature: Deep Dive into GitHub Actions Docker Builds with Docker Desktop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the new Docker Build Summary feature in GitHub Actions that helps provide a deeper understanding of your Docker builds.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/new-beta-feature-deep-dive-into-github-actions-docker-builds-with-docker-desktop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotCover Command Line Tools for Automation Testing Code Coverage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ultimate goal of creating a testing strategy is to be confident that you and your team have done their due diligence to deliver a quality product. Test harnesses typically include a mix of unit tests, integration testing, automation, and manual testing, each with advantages and disadvantages for your overall strategy. Determining the effectiveness of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/20/dotcover-command-line-tools-for-automation-testing-code-coverage/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy for Teams: How to Pitch It to Your Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 11:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a passionate coder using JetBrains Academy, you already know the incredible benefits of our project-based learning platform. Now imagine amplifying those benefits across your entire team. Here is why and how you should pitch JetBrains Academy for Teams to your employer. Why professional development is essential In the ever-evolving world of tech, keeping up […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/06/20/pitch-jetbrains-academy-to-your-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Fleet Plugins for Your Kotlin Codebase</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 09:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet is a code editor designed from scratch to be an extendable platform. Many pieces of Fleet’s functionality are implemented as plugins. While the Fleet team is working toward the Fleet Plugins Public Preview, we decided to share some ideas, details, and examples of why and how external developers are supposed to develop their own […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/06/custom-fleet-plugins-for-your-kotlin-codebase/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does the null! Statement Do?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 02:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to discuss the null! statement in C#. First, we will explore its construct, and function in our programs. Then, we will examine various situations where we can use this statement in our applications. Let’s dive in. A Little Bit of History – The Different Types of Objects in C# […] The post What Does the null! Statement Do? appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enums aren’t evil. Conditional statements everywhere are</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 22:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you seeing the same conditional statements (if/switch) against enums littered everywhere? There are different ways of handling that, but a lot of it comes down to your context. Conditionals around type checking, extension methods, Inheritance, and Polymorphism are all options. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts,… Read More »Enums aren’t evil. Conditional statements everywhere are The post Enums aren’t evil.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2024: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 19:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An overview of the latest updates in Microsoft Entra for Jun 2024. Discover how these new capabilities can be integrated into your projects for optimal performance and security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-jun-24 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7Rs of Cloud Migration: Guide to a Seamless Migration Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 18:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud computing has revolutionized how organizations manage and deploy their IT resources, offering unparalleled scalability, flexibility, and cost-efficiency. As businesses increasingly migrate their applications and data to the cloud, understanding the best migration strategies becomes crucial. This article introduces the 7 Rs of cloud migration, a comprehensive framework designed to guide organizations through the complexities […] The article The 7Rs of Cloud Migration: Guide to a Seamless Migration Strategy was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating cat qubits for fault-tolerant quantum computing using Azure Quantum Resource Estimator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 17:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This blog post highlights a recent collaboration between Microsoft and Alice &amp;amp; Bob, a French startup whose goal is to build a fault-tolerant quantum computer by leveraging a superconducting qubit called a cat qubit. In this collaboration, Alice &amp;amp; Bob uses the new extensibility mechanisms of Microsoft’s Resource Estimator to obtain resource estimates for their cat qubit architecture.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/qsharp/evaluating-cat-qubits-for-fault-tolerant-quantum-computing-using-azure-quantum-resource-estimator 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Visual Studio automatically updated and secure through Microsoft Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 17:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio is coming to Microsoft Update! We’re pleased to announce that starting in August 2024, developers who are not part of an organization managed by an IT administrator can choose to receive monthly Visual Studio security updates through the Microsoft Update (MU) system on “patch Tuesdays”.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/automatically-install-visual-studio-security-updates-through-microsoft-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Phi-3 &amp; C# with ONNX for text and vision samples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Harness the power of Phi-3 SLMs and ONNX for AI-driven .NET applications, showcasing C# integration for advanced tasks like image analysis and interactive Q&amp;amp;A.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-phi3-csharp-with-onnx-for-text-and-vision-samples-md 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retiring Lamar and the Ghost of IoC Containers Past</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 16:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re not familiar with it, Lamar is an IoC/DI container for .NET. It was originally built to be a faster, modernized, ASP.Net Core-compliant replacement for the much older StructureMap IoC library and also as a necessary subsystem of what is now Wolverine. First off, if you have a vested investment in continuing to use … Continue reading Retiring Lamar and the Ghost of IoC Containers Past →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.1.4 Is Out! Nova Now Available by Default for New Users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 16:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since November 2023, our team has been diligently working on the implementation of the ReSharper C++/Rider C++ language engine. This project was initiated with a clear focus on our users, aiming to address the long-standing performance and quality issues of CLion, which were caused by the usage of the slowly performing engine. The most notable […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/06/2024-1-4-update-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize your Amazon Translate architecture using strategic caching layers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 15:56:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how setting up a cache for frequently accessed translations can benefit organizations that need scalable, multi-language translation across large volumes of content. You’ll learn how to build a simple caching mechanism for Amazon Translate to accelerate turnaround times.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maximize-your-amazon-translate-architecture-using-strategic-caching-layers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2 EAP Digest #2: New TypeScript Engine, Ability to Run .ts Files, Git and Markdown Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re halfway through the Early Access Program for WebStorm 2024.2! It’s been a while since we walked you through the latest improvements and features in this release, so it’s about time for an update. Read on to learn about the key changes that made it into the EAP builds in the past few weeks. For […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/06/webstorm-2024-2-eap2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a Slack gateway for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced digital world, streamlining workflows and boosting productivity are paramount. That’s why we’re thrilled to share an exciting integration that will take your team’s collaboration to new heights. Get ready to unlock the power of generative artificial intelligence (AI) and bring it directly into your Slack workspace. Imagine the possibilities: Quick and efficient […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-a-slack-gateway-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the sadness of treating counted strings as null-terminated strings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You&#39;re throwing away perfectly good data, there.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240619-00/?p=109915 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Bring Science Into API Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 13:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced development environment, effective API documentation is not just a nice-to-have, but a necessity. This blog post explores how understanding pattern recognition and learning styles can revolutionize the way we create API documentation. By examining the different types of knowledge present in API references and recognizing diverse developer learning strategies, we can create […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/06/let-s-bring-science-into-api-documentation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Move From pandas to Polars</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 11:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Cheuk Ting Ho, a data scientist who contributes to multiple open-source libraries, such as pandas and Polars. You’ve probably heard about Polars – it is now firmly in the spotlight in the data science community. Are you still using pandas and would like to try out Polars? Are you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/06/how-to-move-from-pandas-to-polars/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>256 Seconds with dotNetDave: Documenting Code with Visual Studio and Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this episode of 256 Seconds with dotNetDave, learn to use Visual Studio and GitHub Copilot to swiftly create detailed XML comments for Microsoft .NET projects. Detailed commands for documenting classes are shared, along with a call to vote for displaying code examples in IntelliSense. Watch the demonstration here: https://player.vimeo.com/video/961522552?badge=0&amp;autopause=0&amp;player_id=0&amp;app_id=58479
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/19/256-seconds-with-dotnetdave-documenting-code-with-visual-studio-and-copilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use FakeLogger to Test Logging Code in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 06:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In software development, logging, and unit testing serve as foundational tools, each actively contributing to the reliability and functionality of our applications. While unit testing promptly alerts us to changes in our application’s business logic, logging actively monitors errors, performance metrics, and runtime execution flow. Despite their significance, many development workflows often overlook their incorporation. […] The post How to Use FakeLogger to Test Logging Code in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Step Forward for Gaming on Arm Devices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 02:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year at Microsoft Build 2024 we announced a new set of Windows devices, Copilot+ PCs. Copilot+ PCs are a new class of Windows 11 PCs, including Arm-powered devices that are powered by the Snapdragon® X Series. These new Arm devices have cutting-edge new processing power coming from the CPU,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/step-forward-for-gaming-on-arm-devices-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving air quality with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a solution that uses a generative artificial intelligence (AI) to standardize air quality data from low-cost sensors in Africa, specifically addressing the air quality data integration problem of low-cost sensors. The solution harnesses the capabilities of generative AI, specifically Large Language Models (LLMs), to address the challenges posed by diverse sensor data and automatically generate Python functions based on various data formats. The fundamental objective is to build a manufacturer-agnostic database, leveraging generative AI’s ability to standardize sensor outputs, synchronize data, and facilitate precise corrections.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use zero-shot large language models on Amazon Bedrock for custom named entity recognition</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Name entity recognition (NER) is the process of extracting information of interest, called entities, from structured or unstructured text. Manually identifying all mentions of specific types of information in documents is extremely time-consuming and labor-intensive. Some examples include extracting players and positions in an NFL game summary, products mentioned in an AWS keynote transcript, or […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-zero-shot-large-language-models-on-amazon-bedrock-for-custom-named-entity-recognition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguard a generative AI travel agent with prompt engineering and Guardrails for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a comprehensive solution for addressing the challenges of securing a virtual travel agent powered by generative AI. We provide an end-to-end example and its accompanying code to demonstrate how to implement prompt engineering techniques, content moderation, and various guardrails to make sure the assistant operates within predefined boundaries by relying on Guardrails for Amazon Bedrock. Additionally, we delve into monitoring strategies to track the activation of these safeguards, enabling proactive identification and mitigation of potential issues.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline financial workflows with generative AI for email automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explains a generative artificial intelligence (AI) technique to extract insights from business emails and attachments. It examines how AI can optimize financial workflow processes by automatically summarizing documents, extracting data, and categorizing information from email attachments. This enables companies to serve more clients, direct employees to higher-value tasks, speed up processes, lower expenses, enhance data accuracy, and increase efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-financial-workflows-with-generative-ai-for-email-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy and security improvements in .NET modernization tooling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the latest privacy and security-related updates to Azure Migrate application and code assessment and .NET Upgrade Assistant.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-modernization-privacy-security-improvements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily navigate code delegates while debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 15:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Delegates are everywhere in modern code; a delegate is a type that represents references to methods with a particular parameter list and return type. Developers use delegates to pass methods as arguments to other methods. One example you may be familiar with is with event handlers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/easily-navigate-code-delegates-while-debugging 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains to Integrate Google’s Gemini Models Into AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is planning to soon leverage Google Cloud’s Vertex AI by integrating Google’s Gemini models into its AI-powered coding tool, AI Assistant. This makes JetBrains AI Assistant the first of its kind to use multiple large language models (LLMs). JetBrains AI Assistant AI Assistant helps developers stay focused on creative challenges by handling routine tasks. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/06/jetbrains-to-integrate-google-s-gemini-models-into-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The time smart quotes prevented the entire Office division from committing code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Breaking your tools with your tools.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240618-00/?p=109910 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Style for Better Productivity – Tips and Tools from the Metalama Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 11:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While it may seem trivial, one of the first steps in creating a maintainable, team-friendly codebase is reaching a consensus on code style and ensuring its strict enforcement. This includes code formatting (spaces, blank lines, parentheses, and brackets), naming (casings, prefixes, suffixes, etc.), and usage of this, var and more. The ultimate goal? Make running […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/18/code-style-for-better-productivity-tips-and-tools-from-the-metalama-team/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand your C&#43;&#43; symbols using Copilot in Visual Studio’s Quick Info</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 09:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Navigating your codebase and forget what exactly that method does? Looking for quick, easy-to-digest information on your code at any point in your development journey? We are excited to announce that now when you hover over symbols in your codebase, you’ll be able to invoke Copilot conveniently within the Quick Info dialog to learn more about a given symbol and enhance existing or lacking code documentation.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/understand-your-c-symbols-using-copilot-in-visual-studios-quick-info 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the generated code: List&lt;T&gt; and fallback cases: Behind the scenes of collection expressions - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at the code generated when you use collection expressions with List or with types that can be used with collection initializers
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/behind-the-scenes-of-collection-expressions-part-2-exploring-the-generated-code-list-and-fallback-cases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently Handling Stored Procedures in EFCore: Practical Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 08:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover proven strategies and practical solutions for efficiently handling stored procedures in Entity Framework Core (EFCore) and optimize your database interactions.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/efficiently-handling-stored-procedures-efcore-practical-solutions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;Secret&amp;quot; elmah.io features #5 - Breadcrumbs leading up to errors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 09:36:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s time for a new post in the series about &amp;quot;secret&amp;quot; elmah.io features. This is the series where I highlight features that some of you may already know while others don&#39;t. For today&#39;s post, I want to highlight a feature that asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/secret-elmah-io-features-5-breadcrumbs-leading-up-to-errors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Ignore a Property in AutoMapper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 05:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore key techniques to ignore property in AutoMapper. We will use the Ignore() method, the Ignore attribute, and the DoNotValidate() method. We will also discuss when and how to use each of the methods mentioned. Without further ado, let’s start! When to Ignore a Property in AutoMapper Ignoring properties during […] The post How to Ignore a Property in AutoMapper appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Load testing with K6 on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Can your system withstand heavy loads? You can answer this question by running Load Tests. Maybe, using K6 as a free tool.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/k6-load-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Applied Skills Replacing Microsoft Certifications?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 22:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Learn Applied Skills credentials are not replacing Microsoft Certifications. Microsoft is expanding their credentialing portfolio to cater better to learners and customers, allowing validation of specific skill sets with this new offering. Microsoft Certifications are continuing to be role-based, and still assess a broad range of skills essential for success in key roles within […] The article Are Applied Skills Replacing Microsoft Certifications? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step by Step guide to develop AI Multi-Agent system using Microsoft Semantic Kernel and GPT-4o</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we want to highlight a recent Medium article published here: Step by Step guide to develop AI Multi-Agent system using Microsoft Semantic Kernel and GPT-4o | by Akshay Kokane | Jun, 2024 | Medium We’ve included a few excerpts below,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/step-by-step-guide-to-develop-ai-multi-agent-system-using-microsoft-semantic-kernel-and-gpt-4o 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Twilio used Amazon SageMaker MLOps pipelines with PrestoDB to enable frequent model retraining and optimized batch transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Shamik Ray, Srivyshnav K S, Jagmohan Dhiman and Soumya Kundu from Twilio. Today’s leading companies trust Twilio’s Customer Engagement Platform (CEP) to build direct, personalized relationships with their customers everywhere in the world. Twilio enables companies to use communications and data to add intelligence and security to every step of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-twilio-used-amazon-sagemaker-mlops-pipelines-with-prestodb-to-enable-frequent-model-retraining-and-optimized-batch-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactor your code with default lambda parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore opportunities to refactor your C# code with default lambda parameters, a new feature in C# 12.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/refactor-your-code-with-default-lambda-parameters 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Teams webinar integration with HubSpot marketing automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn why the integration of HubSpot with Microsoft Teams represents a significant new advancement for Teams webinar customers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-teams-webinar-integration-with-hubspot-marketing-automation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate deep learning training and simplify orchestration with AWS Trainium and AWS Batch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In large language model (LLM) training, effective orchestration and compute resource management poses a significant challenge. Automation of resource provisioning, scaling, and workflow management is vital for optimizing resource usage and streamlining complex workflows, thereby achieving efficient deep learning training processes. Simplified orchestration enables researchers and practitioners to focus more on model experimentation, hyperparameter tuning, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-deep-learning-training-and-simplify-orchestration-with-aws-trainium-and-aws-batch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosch widely adopts Visual Studio for their C&#43;&#43; remote Linux projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Bosch security camera team was seeking a unified development setup for their team and recently re-evaluated Visual Studio as a solution for their C++ projects and remote Linux development needs. Their experience with Visual Studio 2022 featured notable improvements relevant to their workflows such as seamless GDB integration and CMake/WSL integrations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/bosch-widely-adopts-visual-studio-for-their-c-remote-linux-projects 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 EAP 3: Improved GDB Performance and Enhancements for Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 15:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.2 EAP build (242.16677.29) is now out! It’s available from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 EAP Here are the highlights: The full release notes are available here. Find out more about our plans for this release in the CLion 2024.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/06/2024-2-eap-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I view the list of symbols available in a library?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A tool hiding inside another tool.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240617-00/?p=109905 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venerable Used Datalore to Reduce Eight-Hour Excel Analysis to Two Minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 09:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Caught in a spiderweb of spreadsheets Like many financial organizations, Venerable faced hurdles due to its dependence on Excel. Changes in a single spreadsheet often triggered a chain reaction of adjustments across countless others, leading to mistakes and a lot of manual work. This setup resulted in a time-consuming, error-prone process that was amplified when […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/06/17/venerable-used-datalore-to-reduce-eight-hour-excel-analysis-to-two-minutes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flattening Nested Collections in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 05:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore flattening nested collections in C#. We’ll examine different approaches for handling from simple to complex data structures, offering practical guidance to effectively flatten nested collections within our C# applications. Let’s get started. Importance of Flattening Nested Collections Nested collections can introduce unnecessary complexity, making it challenging to work with the […] The post Flattening Nested Collections in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
