<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devleader.ca on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devleader.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devleader.ca on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devleader.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MudBlazor with Blazor SSR – What You Need To Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post MudBlazor with Blazor SSR – What You Need To Know appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how to use MudBlazor with Blazor SSR! Blazor&#39;s Server Side Rendering can be used alongside this awesome control library for building your next Blazor app! The post MudBlazor with Blazor SSR – What You Need To Know appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/24/mudblazor-with-blazor-ssr-what-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try Catch in C#: The Basics You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Try Catch in C#: The Basics You Need to Know appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how exception handling works in C# with the basics of try catch. This article is perfect for junior software engineers aiming to understand dotnet and C#. The post Try Catch in C#: The Basics You Need to Know appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/23/try-catch-in-c-the-basics-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Convert a String to Byte Array in C#: Encoding and Decoding Simplified</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How to Convert a String to Byte Array in C#: Encoding and Decoding Simplified appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how to effectively convert a string to a byte array in C#! While it might seem straightforward on the surface, we have encodings to consider! The post How to Convert a String to Byte Array in C#: Encoding and Decoding Simplified appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating API Gateways in Zuplo – Dev Leader Weekly 40</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Creating API Gateways in Zuplo – Dev Leader Weekly 40 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue sponsored by Zuplo, I share how I&#39;m putting an API gateway in front of my ASCII art API! The post Creating API Gateways in Zuplo – Dev Leader Weekly 40 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/20/creating-api-gateways-in-zuplo-dev-leader-weekly-40/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Gateways in Zuplo – Creating an ASCII Art API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post API Gateways in Zuplo – Creating an ASCII Art API appeared first on Dev Leader.Just how easy is it to make an API gateway in Zuplo? Zuper eazy. Check out how I&#39;m making an ASCII art API with Zuplo as my API gateway! The post API Gateways in Zuplo – Creating an ASCII Art API appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/19/api-gateways-in-zuplo-creating-an-ascii-art-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Key Authentication Middleware In ASP NET Core – A How To Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post API Key Authentication Middleware In ASP NET Core – A How To Guide appeared first on Dev Leader.Want to add API key authentication middleware into your ASP.NET Core application? Check out this article for a simple code example that shows you how! The post API Key Authentication Middleware In ASP NET Core – A How To Guide appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/18/api-key-authentication-middleware-in-asp-net-core-a-how-to-guide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
