<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 17:27:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Tenancy: Marten’s “Conjoined” Model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 17:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is continuing a series about multi-tenancy with Marten, Wolverine, and ASP.Net Core: Let’s say that you definitely have the need for multi-tenanted storage in your system, but don’t expect enough data to justify splitting the tenant data over multiple databases, or maybe you just really don’t want to mess with all the extra overhead … Continue reading Multi-Tenancy: Marten’s “Conjoined” Model →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/20/multi-tenancy-martens-conjoined-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Tenancy: What is it and why do you care?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 21:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m always on the lookout for ideas about how to endlessly promote both Marten &amp;amp; Wolverine. Since I’ve been fielding a lot of questions, issues, and client requests around multi-tenancy support in both tools the past couple weeks, now seems to be a good time for a new series exploring the existing foundation in both … Continue reading Multi-Tenancy: What is it and why do you care? →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine’s Test Support Diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 18:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m working on fixing a reported bug with Wolverine today and its event forwarding from Marten feature. I can’t say that I yet know why this should-be-very-straightforward-and-looks-exactly-like-the-currently-passing-tests bug is happening, but it’s a good time to demonstrate Wolverine’s automated testing support and even how it can help you to understand test failures. First off, and … Continue reading Wolverine’s Test Support Diagnostics →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/16/wolverines-test-support-diagnostics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled Message Delivery with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 22:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine has the ability to schedule the delivery of messages for a later time. While Wolverine certainly isn’t trying to be Hangfire or Quartz.Net, the message scheduling in Wolverine today is valuable for “timeout” messages in sagas, or “retry this evening” type scenarios, or reminders of all sorts. If using the Azure Service Bus transport, … Continue reading Scheduled Message Delivery with Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/15/scheduled-message-delivery-with-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine’s HTTP Model Does More For You</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 21:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the things I’m wrestling with right now is frankly how to sell Wolverine as a server side toolset. Yes, it’s technically a message library like MassTransit or NServiceBus. It can also be used as “just” a mediator tool like MediatR. With Wolverine.HTTP, it’s even an alternative HTTP endpoint framework that’s technically an alternative … Continue reading Wolverine’s HTTP Model Does More For You →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/13/wolverines-http-model-does-more-for-you/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
