<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:17:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Messaging with Wolverine using Apache Pulsar</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of the Wolverine 3.0 release a couple weeks back, Wolverine gained a lightweight messaging transport option with Apache Pulsar. “Lightweight” just meaning “it doesn’t have a lot of features yet” To get started, first add this Nuget to your system: And just like that, you’re ready to start adding publishing rules and subscriptions … Continue reading Messaging with Wolverine using Apache Pulsar →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/11/05/messaging-with-wolverine-using-apache-pulsar/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Round Trips are Evil, So Batch Your Queries When You Can</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 18:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software frequently helps our customers wring better performance or scalability out of our customer’s systems. A somewhat frequent opportunity for improving the responsiveness and throughput of systems is merely identifying ways to batch up requests from middle tier, server side code to the backing database or databases. There’s a certain amount of overhead in … Continue reading Network Round Trips are Evil, So Batch Your Queries When You Can →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never mind, Lamar is going to continue</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 14:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A couple months ago I wrote Retiring Lamar and the Ghost of IoC Containers Past as we were closing in on decoupling Wolverine 3.0 from Lamar (since completed) and I was already getting sick of edge case bugs introduced by Microsoft from their inexplicably wacky approach for keyed services. Since releasing Wolverine 3.0 without its previous … Continue reading Never mind, Lamar is going to continue →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
