<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 20:40:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Marten’s 10th Birthday!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 20:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To the best of my recollection and internet sleuthing today, development on Marten started in October of 2015 after my then colleague Corey Kaylor had kicked around an idea the previous summer to utilize the new JSONB feature in PostgreSQL 9.4 as a way to replace our then problematic usage of a third party NoSQL … Continue reading Celebrating Marten’s 10th Birthday! →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/30/celebrating-martens-10th-birthday/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leader Election and Virtual Actors in Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A JasperFx Software client was asking recently about the features for software controlled load balancing and “sticky” agents I’m describing in this post. Since these features are both critical for Wolverine functionality and maybe not perfectly documented already, it’s a great topic for a new blog post! Both because it’s helpful to understand what’s going … Continue reading Leader Election and Virtual Actors in Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/29/leader-election-and-virtual-actors-in-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Sprint to Wolverine 5.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Little update since the last check in on Wolverine 5.0. I think right now that Wolverine 5.0 hits by next Monday (October 6th). To be honest, besides documentation updates, the biggest work is just pushing more on the CritterWatch backend this week to see if that forces any breaking changes in the Wolverine internals. What’s … Continue reading Last Sprint to Wolverine 5.0 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/28/last-sprint-to-wolverine-5-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Diary of How JasperFx Helps Our Clients</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For any shops using the “Critter Stack” (Marten and Wolverine), JasperFx Software offers support contracts and custom consulting engagements in support of these tools — or really anything you might be doing on the server side with .NET as well. Something we’ve had some success with, especially lately, is positioning these “support” contracts as essentially … Continue reading Little Diary of How JasperFx Helps Our Clients →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
