<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 18:04:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Note About JasperFx’s Plans for Marten &amp; Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 18:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So, yes, Wolverine overlaps quite a bit with both MediatR and MassTransit. If you’re a MediatR user, Wolverine just does a helluva lot more and we have an existing guide for converting from MediatR to Wolverine. For MassTransit (or NServiceBus) users, Wolverine covers a lot of the same asynchronous messaging framework use cases, but does … Continue reading A Quick Note About JasperFx’s Plans for Marten &amp;amp; Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack Work in Progress</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_03_2025/30_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 14:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_03_2025/30_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s just time for an update from my last post on Critter Stack Roadmap Update for February as the work has progressed in the past weeks and we have more clarity on what’s going to change. Work is heavily underway right now for a round of related releases in the Critter Stack (Marten, Wolverine, and other … Continue reading Critter Stack Work in Progress →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/03/30/critter-stack-work-in-progress/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projections, Consistency Models, and Zero Downtime Deployments with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 18:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This content will later be published as a tutorial somewhere on one of our documentation websites. This was originally “just” an article on doing blue/green deployments when using projections with Marten, so hence the two martens up above:) Event Sourcing may not seem that complicated to implement, and you might be tempted to forego any … Continue reading Projections, Consistency Models, and Zero Downtime Deployments with the Critter Stack →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
