<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:22:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Faster &amp; More Reliable Integration Testing Against Marten Projections or Subscriptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I just pulled the trigger on Marten 8.8 and Wolverine 4.10 earlier today. Neither is particularly large, but there’s some new toys and an important improvement for test automation support that are worth calling out. My goodness, that title is a mouthful. I’ve been helping a couple different JasperFx Software clients and community users on … Continue reading Faster &amp;amp; More Reliable Integration Testing Against Marten Projections or Subscriptions →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operations that Span Multiple Event Streams with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s just say that Marten incurs some serious benefits to being on top of PostgreSQL and its very strong support for transactional integrity as opposed to some of the high profile commercial Event Sourcing tools who are spending a lot of time and energy on their “Dynamic Consistency Boundary” concept because they lack the ACID … Continue reading Operations that Span Multiple Event Streams with the Critter Stack →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need Some Feedback on Near Term Wolverine Work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 19:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That’s supposed to be a play on a Wolverine as Winnie the Pooh in his “thinking spot” I’m wrestling a little bit with whether the new features and changes coming into Wolverine very soon are worthy of a 5.0 release even though 4.0 was just a couple months ago. I’d love any and all feedback … Continue reading Need Some Feedback on Near Term Wolverine Work →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
