<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:26:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine 4 is Bringing Multi-Tenancy to EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I think that even in a crowded field of existing “mediator” tools, ASP.Net Core endpoint frameworks, and asynchronous messaging frameworks in .NET that Wolverine has a great opportunity to grow its user base this year. There’s a lot of value that Wolverine brings to the table that I don’t believe other tools do, but it’s … Continue reading Wolverine 4 is Bringing Multi-Tenancy to EF Core →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of a JasperFx Support Contract</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 01:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software is the company I founded a little over two years ago to create an Open Core business model around the “Critter Stack” suite of open source tools (primarily Marten and Wolverine, with some smaller supporting tools). So far, our main sources of revenue (right now it’s myself with contributions from Babu Annamalai, but … Continue reading The Value of a JasperFx Support Contract →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/05/14/the-value-of-a-jasperfx-support-contract/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Auto Creation of Database or Message Broker Resources in the Critter Stack vNext</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2025/11_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 21:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2025/11_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’d prefer to start with more context, skip to the section named “Why is this important?”. To set up the problem I’m hoping to address in this post, there are several settings across both Marten and Wolverine that need to be configured for the most optimal possible functioning between development, testing, and deployment time … Continue reading Managing Auto Creation of Database or Message Broker Resources in the Critter Stack vNext →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
