<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeremydmiller.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 20:48:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/jeremydmiller.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multi Step Workflows with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 20:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m working with a JasperFx Software client who is in the beginning stages of building a pretty complex, multi-step file import process that is going to involve several different services. For the sake of example code in this post, let’s say that we have the (much simplified from my client’s actual logical workflow) workflow from … Continue reading Multi Step Workflows with the Critter Stack →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/10/01/multi-step-workflows-with-the-critter-stack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Event Projections and Subscriptions with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The feature set shown in this post was built earlier this year at the behest of a JasperFx Software client who has some unusually high data throughput and wanted to have some significant ability to scale up Marten and Wolverine‘s ability to handle a huge number of incoming events. We originally put this into what … Continue reading Scaling Event Projections and Subscriptions with the Critter Stack →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Recommendations for a Test Automation Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 01:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve been helping a JasperFx Software client with their test automation strategy on a new web application and surrounding suite of services. That makes this a perfectly good time to reevaluate how I think teams can succeed with automated testing as an update to what I thought a decade ago. I think you can justifiably … Continue reading My Recommendations for a Test Automation Strategy →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/29/my-recommendations-for-a-test-automation-strategy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
