<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 09:20:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discover Junie for PhpStorm: A Game-Changing AI Coding Agent for PHP Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 09:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, PhpStorm has entered the realm of agentic IDEs. Now, the PhpStorm IDE doesn’t just provide classical developer productivity tools and AI assistance features, but can also do massive amounts of work for PHP developers autonomously. Unlike other coding agent plugins, Junie is native to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/06/discover-junie-for-phpstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is an AI Coding Agent?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 15:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI has quickly become one of the most discussed subjects globally – and it now seems to be able to do just about everything for us. Students are asking it to help them with their homework, and lawyers are even using it for case research. AI agents have grown rapidly in popularity due to the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/junie/2025/06/what-is-an-ai-coding-agent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 3.2.0 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 15:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ktor 3.2.0 is here! This is the second minor release of the year, bringing exciting new features, performance improvements, and bug fixes. This release includes two new modules for dependency injection and HTMX, support for Gradle version catalogs, automatic configuration deserialization, Unix domain socket support for CIO, and much more. Check out the full changelog […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/ktor-3-2-0-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K2 Mode Takes Off: High Adoption, Fewer Bugs, and Major Improvements in 2025.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We want to share how things are going with K2 mode, which became the default in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1. In this post, we’ll give an overview of the current state of K2 mode, share its adoption metrics, highlight the improvements delivered in 2025.1, and preview what’s coming next. We recommend updating to the latest IntelliJ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/k2-mode-takes-off-high-adoption-fewer-bugs-and-major-improvements-in-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Your ML Models With Cadence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the rapidly evolving domains of machine learning (ML) and artificial intelligence (AI), the tools and technologies used by developers can significantly influence the speed, efficiency, and effectiveness of their projects. Recognizing this, we introduced Cadence in PyCharm 2025.1, a plugin that merges the ease of local development with advanced cloud computing capabilities. Why Cadence? […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/06/training-your-ml-models-with-cadence/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a Fresh Look for JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 10:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual context is always changing – and so should the look and feel of the tools you use every day. We know how much a familiar UI matters, and we’ve heard your feedback from past updates. That’s why we’re taking an iterative, careful approach this time: small, focused improvements, shared early, with your feedback guiding […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/06/testing-a-fresh-look-for-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.03.3 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 18:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The major TeamCity 2025.07 update is just around the corner! But first, we’re rolling out another bug-fix release for the current version: TeamCity On-Premises 2025.03.3. Here’re some of the bugs resolved in this update: Bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements, so we recommend installing them promptly. See TeamCity 2025.03.3 Release Notes for the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/teamcity-2025-03-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Developers on AI: Insights and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 12:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI tools continue to advance and become bigger parts of our lives, it is important to think critically about AI interactions. At JetBrains, the Developer Experience (DX) and Human-AI eXperience (HAX) study this, with a particular interest in enhancing these interactions in code-related tasks. In this post we will look at how our teams […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/06/software-developers-on-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is infrastructure As Code (IaC) Scanning?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 09:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Kumar Harsh, draft.dev. Infrastructure as code (IaC) is a popular practice in modern DevOps security and automation workflows. By treating infrastructure as code, teams can automate resource provisioning and deployments and significantly reduce efforts spent on manual configurations. However, just as with application code, IaC configurations can introduce […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/what-is-iac-scanning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2025 – Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 15:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plugin Developer Conf is back this November! We’re looking for speakers to share their insights with the JetBrains plugin development community. Submit your talk by July 10, 2025. What is JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf? Plugin Developer Conf is a free, live, online event hosted by JetBrains, created for and shaped by the plugin development community. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/06/jetbrains-plugin-developer-conf-2025-call-for-speakers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 EAP 5: Reimagined Monitoring tool window and New OpenTelemetry Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Rider 2025.2 EAP 5 build has just been released, and this one brings two major productivity enhancements for .NET developers. We’re excited to introduce the reimagined Monitoring tool window, which transforms how you identify and resolve performance issues, plus the new OpenTelemetry plugin, which brings runtime observability directly into your development environment. We can’t […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/16/rider-eap-5-new-monitoring-tool-opentelemetry-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenTelemetry Plugin for JetBrains Rider: Observability Inside Your IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding how your application behaves at runtime has always been a challenge. Traditional debugging and profiling tools can help you understand what’s happening at specific points in time – but getting a complete picture of system behavior, performance patterns, and architectural relationships often means jumping between external tools and dashboards. We’re building the OpenTelemetry plugin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/16/opentelemetry-plugin-for-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Java Enable Preview: Vector API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 10:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Daniel Hinojosa and explore the Vector API – a powerful tool for writing high-performance code in Java. Date: June 25, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this session, we will discuss the Vector API in a preview in Java. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/new-livestream-new-livestream-new-livestream-java-enable-preview-vector-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
