<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:15:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.34 is Out With AI Code Completion for Python and Kotlin, Smooth Caret Animation, Force Step Into, and Many More Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.34 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this latest version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights of this update. Download Fleet 1.34 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed a number […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/05/fleet-1-34-is-out-with-ai-code-completion-for-python-and-kotlin-smooth-caret-animation-em-force-step-into-em-and-many-more-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate 2024.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate offers an extensive set of features that go beyond the basics, providing access to AI-powered coding efficiency boosters, seamless integration with numerous frameworks and technologies, powerful database tools, and more. Download IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate 2024.1 In our latest release, version 2024.1, we’ve introduced a range of enhancements to elevate your coding experience. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/05/what-s-new-in-intellij-idea-ultimate-2024-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains .NET Days Online 2024 – Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On September 25 and 26, 2024, we’re hosting a free, live, virtual event where community speakers cover topics they are passionate about: JetBrains .NET Days Online! Talk topics could be C#, F#, .NET in general, performance, refactoring, open source projects, frameworks like MAUI and Blazor, and more. We are looking for speakers who are interested […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/02/jetbrains-dotnet-days-online-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the JetBrains Content Creators Program!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you passionate about creating engaging content for the tech community? Do you enjoy sharing your coding journey with others? If so, our new JetBrains Content Creators Program is just the thing for you! At JetBrains, not only do we work to provide an exceptional developer experience, but we also strive to inspire and support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/05/02/introducing-the-jetbrains-content-creators-program/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Roundup: K2 Compiler Updates, Ktor News, Kotlin for Data Analysis, and Other Ecosystem Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 11:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this roundup, let’s delve into the key recent developments in the Kotlin ecosystem. Did you know that the JetBrains team regularly publishes a newsletter featuring major Kotlin ecosystem news? Sign up to stay up to date with all things Kotlin.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/05/kotlin-roundup-april-24/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the April edition of PHP Annotated! We’ll recap the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, featuring handpicked news, articles, tools, and videos. Highlights PHP statement on glibc/iconv vulnerability The hype around CVE-2024-2961 in relation to PHP was extremely exaggerated. Many people were under the impression that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/04/php-annotated-april-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anything Session With the JetBrains Academy Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’d like to invite you to our very first free Ask Me Anything session on Discord with JetBrains Academy! Send us any questions you may have about JetBrains Academy courses, how to start a career in IT, teaching opportunities, our offline programs, or any other topic you’re interested in. We’ll kick off the chatting session […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/04/29/ask-me-anything-session-with-the-jetbrains-academy-team/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Dev Experience with Serverless Rust in RustRover</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 14:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Serverless computing and the Rust programming language together offer a promising path for developers to build efficient and scalable applications without the traditional barriers of infrastructure management. In our latest livestream session with James Eastham, a senior cloud architect at AWS, we explored the synergies between Rust and serverless architecture, particularly focusing on AWS Lambda. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/04/26/boosting-dev-experience-with-serverless-rust-in-rustrover/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.1.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WebStorm 2024.1.2, the second update for WebStorm 2024.1, is now available! It contains improvements for Angular and adds ESLint 9 support. You can update to v2024.1.2 by using the Toolbox App, installing it right from the IDE, or downloading it from our website. Angular improvements This update introduces new support for Angular 17.2 syntax output() […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/04/webstorm-2024-1-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2022.2.3 Is Ready for Download</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For MPS users still on version 2022.2, we’ve prepared another bug-fix release with several fixes and improvements. Check them out and see how they can make your life easier. DOWNLOAD MPS 2022.2.3 Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/04/mps-2022-2-2-has-been-released-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Spotlight on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Marketplace is a thriving ecosystem where developers can discover plugins that enhance their coding experience and implement and share their plugins with others. While many users find plugins through targeted searches, some may not be aware of tools and integrations that extend beyond programming to general productivity. To draw attention to this trove of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/04/plugin-spotlight-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.1.1 Bug-Fix Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.1.1 bug-fix update is here! The fixes included in this update are listed below. Download build 241.15989.121 from our website, through the Toolbox App, as a snap package for Ubuntu, or via a patch from inside the IDE. If you haven’t upgraded to v2024.1, now is a good time to do so. You […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/04/clion-2024-1-1-bug-fix-update/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K2 Compiler Performance Benchmarks and How to Measure Them on Your Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 15:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the Kotlin 2.0.0 release drawing ever closer, the K2 compiler is now available for you to try! In this blog post, we explore the performance of the K2 compiler in various projects and give you the tools to collect your own performance statistics. The road to the Stable version of the K2 compiler has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/04/k2-compiler-performance-benchmarks-and-how-to-measure-them-on-your-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
