<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 14:28:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cast Expressions, Primary Constructors, Collection Expressions, List Patterns – C# Language Support in 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 14:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our release for ReSharper and Rider 2024.2 is just around the corner, and we have lots of exciting features shipping for the new C# 13 and current C# and VB.NET! Since there are so many, we will split them into multiple blog posts. So make sure to check those posts out as well! In this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/09/cast-expressions-primary-constructors-collection-expressions-list-patterns-csharp-language-support-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Terminal (Beta): Updates for JetBrains IDEs v2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 12:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2024.1 versions of JetBrains IDEs introduced the new terminal as an opt-in feature, which can be enabled via Settings/Preferences | Tools | Terminal | Enable New Terminal. While we are actively gathering feedback and working on improvements, the new terminal remains in its Beta version. In the previous post, we covered the significant changes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/the-new-terminal-beta-updates-for-jetbrains-ides-v2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.6 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 09:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.6. We encourage IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.5 users to update to this version, as it brings an important hotfix. Update to IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.6 directly from your IDE. You can then choose to keep using this version or update to IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 to take advantage of the performance enhancements and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/intellij-idea-2024-1-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euro 2024: Scoring Goals With Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 09:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Now that the 2024 UEFA European Football Championship is over, and we’ve all experienced the thrilling moments of cheering for our favorite teams, let’s have some fun with Python and dive into the tournament’s data. Why not combine our love for football with some cool data analysis? In this blog post, we’ll demonstrate how Python […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/08/09/euro-2024-scoring-goals-with-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2024.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 15:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this release, you’ll find a new asynchronous implementation of the Logical View tool window, substantial improvements to Kotlin support for different platforms, and a noticeably faster test run time. You can also look forward to conditional forks in generator plans, deprecation of project paths in TestInfo, improvements to the new UI, and numerous platform […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/08/mps-2024-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equality Analysis, Ref Structs, Culture Previews, Using Directives – C# Language Support in 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 14:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our release for ReSharper and Rider 2024.2 is just around the corner, and we have lots of exciting features shipping for the new C# 13 and current C# and VB.NET! Since there are so many, we will be splitting things up into multiple blog posts. So make sure to come back for the others as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/08/equality-analysis-ref-structs-culture-previews-using-directives-csharp-language-support-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet Plugins Launched – Themes First</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet is engineered for ultimate extensibility, offering a dynamic and customizable experience. Virtually every feature of Fleet is already powered by plugins pre-packaged with the Fleet distribution. Now, we are happy to announce the rollout of the Fleet Plugins SDK to the broader developer community. As an exciting first step, we are enabling the creation […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/08/fleet-plugins-themes-first/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains is a Proud Sponsor of the International Olympiad in Informatics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 08:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’re committed to fostering education and nurturing young programming talents. Our support extends to various educational initiatives, such as scholarships for bachelor’s degrees in Germany and Cyprus, the Algorithm and Code Training School in Romania, and the International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC). This year, we’re excited to announce our sponsorship of the International […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/08/08/jetbrains-is-a-proud-sponsor-of-the-international-olympiad-in-informatics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Roundup: Ktor in Focus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 08:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this special edition of Kotlin Roundup, where we shine the spotlight on Ktor, our framework for building asynchronous servers and clients in connected systems! This issue is packed with the latest updates, insightful news, and exciting developments in the Ktor ecosystem, appealing to everyone from seasoned Ktor enthusiasts to those just getting started. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/08/kotlin-roundup-ktor-in-focus/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – August 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 07:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this month’s Java Annotated Monthly! As always, we bring you the latest Java news and updates on related technologies. This edition features a special section with Sebastian Daschner, who shares his favorite picks for July. You’ll also find helpful articles on Java 23, a snapshot of Java in today’s tech landscape, and much […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/java-annotated-monthly-august-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update August 2024 – Standalone Projects, Settings Tracing, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 07:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest release of Amper, version 0.4.0, is now available! In this release, we’re introducing a clear definition for the project root and providing a first look at settings tracing in Amper, alongside bug fixes and other improvements. To get support for Amper’s latest features, use Fleet 1.38 and IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 (or later versions). […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2024/08/amper-update-august-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and the .NET tools 2024.2 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get a preview of all the latest features and improvements set to be shipped with the next major ReSharper and .NET tools releases by downloading the Release Candidate builds that have just landed. Here are the major improvements in each of the new builds: The ReSharper 2024.2 Release Candidate The ReSharper C++ 2024.2 Release Candidate […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/07/resharper-2024-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2024.2 Release Candidate Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next big release for Rider is just around the corner! If you’re eager to get a sneak peek, you can download the Release Candidate version of Rider 2024.2 from our website right now. This build includes all the significant updates we introduced during the Early Access Program, as detailed in our earlier blog posts. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/07/rider-2024-2-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape Character, Extract Common Code, Params Modifier, Out Vars – C# Language Support in 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our release for ReSharper and Rider 2024.2 is just around the corner and we have lots of exciting features shipping for the new C# 13 and current C# and VB.NET! Since it’s really a lot, we will be splitting things up into multiple blog posts. So make sure to come back for the others as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/07/escape-character-extract-common-code-params-modifier-out-vars-csharp-language-support-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Financial Bubbles With Python and Datalore AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog post by Ryan O’Connell, CFA, FRM. Introduction In the late 1990s, the world witnessed an unprecedented surge in technology stocks, when investors couldn’t throw money at dot-com companies fast enough. Fast-forward to 2024, and we find ourselves in the midst of another technological revolution – the AI boom. As artificial […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/07/analyzing-financial-bubbles-with-python-and-datalore-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 08:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 has arrived, featuring a host of exciting upgrades to enhance your experience with the IDE. You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 This release enhances Spring Data JPA support, simplifies cron expression management, and upgrades the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/intellij-idea-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scala 3 The new release comes with lots of bug fixes and improvements to Scala 3 support. Here are some of them: Better code highlighting The new release includes several improvements to error and syntax highlighting. In addition, IntelliJ Scala Plugin is now more responsive when the user fixes errors, removing the red code right […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/08/07/intellij-scala-plugin-2024-1-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant 2024.2: Improved Code Completion, Smarter Chat, and More AI Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new and improved AI Assistant for the 2024.2 versions of JetBrains IDEs is now out, featuring smarter and faster AI code completion for Java, Kotlin, and Python; an enhanced UX when working with code in the editor; AI functionality for Git conflict resolution, in-terminal code generation, new customizable prompts, improved test generation, and more. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/08/jetbrains-ai-assistant-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.07.1 Bug Fix Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2024.07.1 bug fix for TeamCity On-Premises is now available for download! This bug fix update resolves over 30 issues, including failing Maven builds in containers, agent Windows services not locating the bundled JRE, new licensing mechanism problems, and more. In addition, version 2024.07.1 resolves multiple important security issues and performance problems, which is why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-2024-07-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in August</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            August is here already! We hope you haven’t forgotten to book a break so you can fully enjoy your last summer month. Unless you’re in the southern hemisphere, of course. But just because it isn’t summer where you are doesn’t mean you shouldn’t take a well-deserved break, too! One great way to get into vacation […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/08/06/jetbrains-academy-new-in-august/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.5 is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 05:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more details about the issues resolved, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/intellij-idea-2024-1-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #5: Smooth Parameter Replacement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 19:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            💡 TeamCity Pipelines by JetBrains is a new approach to CI/CD that offers blazing-fast pipelines to optimize your development flow. We release a new version every three weeks, and here’s what’s new in the latest edition. Imagine you could define parameters when configuring a pipeline and see their values right away, without all of the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue5-smooth-parameter-replacement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Renovated Kotlin Support – K2 Mode: What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we’ve gathered the essential information about K2 mode in IntelliJ IDEA. What does K2 mode do? K2 mode is a new implementation of the Kotlin support within IntelliJ IDEA that improves the stability of the IDE while also setting the foundation for supporting future Kotlin language features. What is the difference between […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/meet-the-renovated-kotlin-support-k2-mode/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
