<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:39:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Survey for JetBrains IDE Plugin Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you develop plugins for JetBrains IDEs, there is a good chance we have already met on the JetBrains Platform Slack, answered your questions in the plugin developer forum, or provided the IntelliJ Platform documentation you have read. Today, the IntelliJ Platform SDK team needs your help to gather feedback that will shape the future […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/03/a-survey-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 08:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 3 is ready for download! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, from inside the IDE, or by using snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 3 This is the final Beta build, with the release candidate just around the corner. It’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2025-1-beta-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch Laravel Foundation Meetup at the JetBrains Office</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 13:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this month, we had the pleasure of hosting a community meetup in our Amsterdam office in collaboration with our partner DLF (the Dutch Laravel Foundation). The event brought together Laravel and PHP developers for an evening of technical talks, networking, and knowledge sharing. The Dutch Laravel Foundation is a non-profit organization that works to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/03/dutch-laravel-foundation-meetup-at-the-jetbrains-office/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDE Workspaces Development: Challenges and Plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 11:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a while since we announced workspaces for IntelliJ IDEA – a feature that lets you manage multiple projects in a single IDE window – and we’ve received tons of feedback and made a lot of improvements since then. We see this feature as a tool to improve the developer experience by allowing you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/ide-workspaces-development-challenges-and-plans/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn JavaScript This Week: Start Your Web Applications Journey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JavaScript is the backbone of modern web development, powering dynamic websites and creating interactive user experiences. It’s an essential programming language, whether you’re just starting out or already an experienced developer. JetBrains Academy’s new free course, Introduction to JavaScript, provides a clear and structured approach to mastering JavaScript quickly and effectively. Why learn JavaScript? Why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/03/25/course-javascript/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: API Interaction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog posts (1,2), we created integration tests that interact with UI components and assert different properties of UI components. However, sometimes we need to check the internal state of our plugin or invoke some method to simplify or speed up the test and avoid too many UI interactions. Let’s explore exactly how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/03/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-api-interaction/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: New Releases, OpenAI vs. DeepSeek, and Compose Hot Reload</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, Kotlin fans! Kodee’s back with another roundup of the latest updates and stories from the Kotlin world. Grab your favorite drink, sit back, and enjoy! Kotlin YouTube spotlight Check out our latest YouTube videos and Shorts – sit back, relax, and enjoy!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/03/kodee-s-kotlin-roundup-new-releases-openai-vs-deepseek-and-compose-hot-reload/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose the Right LLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant is now multimodel! This is an exciting development, but what does it actually mean for you? It means AI Assistant is now more adaptable. It combines the strengths of different AI models, from the deep reasoning of large ones to the speed of compact ones, and even the privacy of local ones. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/how-to-choose-the-right-llm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is SAST? A Guide to Static Application Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is brought to you by Thinus Swart, draft.dev. Static application security testing (SAST) is a method for identifying vulnerabilities in application source code, binaries, or bytecode early in the software development lifecycle (SDLC). By analyzing code before it’s compiled or run, SAST allows developers to catch potential security flaws before they can be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/what-is-sast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Code Analysis in STEM: Protecting Work That Affects the World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 08:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Qodana, we champion code quality for businesses and enterprise development teams, but it has other crucial applications, and implications. Not only can good (and bad!) code be felt in the digital products we all know and use every day, but its impact also extends to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM). As STEM disciplines […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/03/code-analysis-in-stem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.47 Is Here With Folding Support for Multiline Comments, New AI Chat Functionality, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 13:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using our Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.47 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2025/03/fleet-1-47-is-here-with-folding-support-for-multiline-comments-new-ai-chat-functionality-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
