<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 13:36:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Learning Comes to the JetBrains Academy Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 13:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learning to code can be challenging – but struggling to understand a task or unfamiliar concept shouldn’t be one of those challenges. That’s why we’ve introduced two new AI-powered features in the JetBrains Academy plugin to help you stay focused, confident, and in the flow: Machine Translation and Theory Lookup. Unlike generic AI coding features, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/03/jetbrains-academy-plugin-2025-3-ai-features/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Team City’s New Design, Phase 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 11:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity is introducing a batch of UX/UI improvements and more in its upcoming release. With the December release of TeamCity 2024.12, we updated the main navigation and breadcrumb trail. Now, we’re excited to introduce the Settings view and updated page headers, making managing your projects and builds easier. By observing how people use TeamCity and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/introducing-teamcitys-new-design-phase-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | April 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 13:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? In C#, you can use a feature called “caller info attributes” to obtain information about the caller of a method. This can be incredibly useful for logging, debugging, or tracing. The attributes CallerMemberName, CallerFilePath, and CallerLineNumber provide information such as the name of the calling method, the path to the source file […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/02/dotinsights-april-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Miss IntelliJ IDEA Conf 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 08:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’re invited to IntelliJ IDEA Conf 2025, a celebration of the developer community and a chance to connect with professionals who strive for excellence in software development. Join us online on June 3–4 for a free conference filled with insightful talks, hands-on sessions, and opportunities to learn from industry leaders and experts. Conference Details and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/don-t-miss-intellij-idea-conf-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Features in CLion’s Bazel Plugin: Custom Toolchains and Windows Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 08:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion supports the Bazel build tool through a third-party plugin. We recently added two of its most requested features: custom toolchains and Windows support. As an active contributor to the plugin’s development, I’d like to show you how to get started using these features. In this blog post, I’ll explain how to configure your Windows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/04/new-features-in-bazel-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – March Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 14:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            April is always a busy month in tech. For example, in April 1986, IBM became the first to use a megabit chip. In 1991, Java development began in earnest. And, of course, there’s April Fools’ Day – perfect for programming jokes and clever pranks. This April is certainly no exception! Check out fresh courses, events, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/01/jetbrains-academy-march/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and Deploying Microservices With Spring Boot and TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 13:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial was brought to you by Rajkumar Venkatasamy, draft.dev. Microservice architecture has become a cornerstone for building scalable and maintainable applications. Microservices allow individual services to be developed, deployed, and scaled independently, resulting in faster delivery cycles and improved fault isolation. For example, an e-commerce platform can use independent services to handle product catalogs, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/building-and-deploying-microservices-spring-boot-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper’s Out-of-Process Journey: Major Progress and Next Steps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 09:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Good news, everyone! After years of work on one of our most challenging projects, we’re excited to share major progress on ReSharper’s out-of-process implementation. For those of you who’ve been following our journey, asking thoughtful questions, and patiently waiting for updates, we want to let you know how far we’ve come. Your continued support has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/01/resharper-out-of-process-update/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update April 2025 – IDE and CLI Feature Drop!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 08:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.6.0 is out, with improvements to both the IDE and CLI experience. Read on for all of the details, and see the release notes for the full list of changes and bug fixes. To get support for Amper’s latest features, use IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta (or newer). IDE improvements Improved template workflows Templates allow […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/04/amper-update-april-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening the MPS 2025.1 Early Access Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re starting the EAP for MPS 2025.1. The first EAP build is now ready for you to download and try! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.1 EAP Check out the major new features in this release: Project view performance As a result of fixing MPS-38299 and MPS-37938, navigation in the logical project view has been substantially improved. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/03/the-mps-2025-1-eap-has-started-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Survey for JetBrains IDE Plugin Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you develop plugins for JetBrains IDEs, there is a good chance we have already met on the JetBrains Platform Slack, answered your questions in the plugin developer forum, or provided the IntelliJ Platform documentation you have read. Today, the IntelliJ Platform SDK team needs your help to gather feedback that will shape the future […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/03/a-survey-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 08:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 3 is ready for download! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, from inside the IDE, or by using snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 3 This is the final Beta build, with the release candidate just around the corner. It’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2025-1-beta-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
