<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:31:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Performance Matters in Python Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Dido Grigorov, a deep learning engineer and Python programmer with 17 years of experience in the field. Python’s flexibility and ease of use make it a go-to language for developers, but its interpreted nature and global interpreter lock (GIL) can lead to performance bottlenecks, especially in large-scale or resource-intensive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/10/why-performance-matters-in-python-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Kotlin for Java Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This post opens The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how Kotlin adoption grows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/getting-started-with-kotlin-for-java-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Matter: The AI Development Companion for Product Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’ve spent 25 years building tools for developers. Over the past two years, we’ve seen that AI isn’t just changing how developers write code – it’s beginning to reshape the entire process of product development. Not only is AI making developers more productive, helping with everything from code completion to testing and deployment, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/matter/2025/10/introducing-matter-the-ai-development-companion-for-product-teams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Python to Kotlin: A Transition Worth Making</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was written by an external contributor. When it comes to writing short scripts or CRUDs, Python is a great choice. With its rich ecosystem and broad adoption, it can be easily used to scrape some data or to perform data analysis. However, maintaining a large codebase in Python can be very problematic. Python’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/from-python-to-kotlin-a-transition-worth-making/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to Rider 2025.3: ASP.NET and Database Issue Detection In The Monitoring Tool Window</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Rider 2025.3, the Monitoring tool window has become even more powerful with the addition of database and ASP.NET issue detection. These new capabilities let you track slow queries, inefficient request handling, and other performance bottlenecks in real time – right alongside CPU, memory, and GC activity. You can explore these new additions in the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/20/rider-2025-3-asp-dotnet-and-database-issue-monitoring/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science Learning Curve: Insights from 18k Learners Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 06:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The world of computer science (CS) education is changing rapidly. From AI-powered tools to new modes of online and blended learning, it has never been more dynamic – or more critical. Education research has looked into some aspects of how students learn computer science, but when we ask the big questions about who is learning […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/10/computer-science-learning-curve/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog 0.5.0 Is Out: Smarter Tools, Persistent Agents, and Simplified Strategy Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 07:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released Koog 0.5.0, introducing full Agent2Agent (A2A) protocol support, which makes it easier than ever to build systems of interconnected AI agents in Kotlin. But A2A is just the beginning. Koog 0.5.0 brings a host of improvements that make agents more persistent, tools smarter, and strategy design more intuitive. Let’s dive into the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/10/koog-0-5-0-is-out-smarter-tools-persistent-agents-and-simplified-strategy-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2025 Is Coming Up Soon!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey everyone! We’re excited to announce that JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf returns this November. Join us on Wednesday, November 5 for a full day of inspiring talks, live Q&amp;amp;A sessions, and deep dives into the latest in plugin development. Whether you’re just getting started or already publishing on JetBrains Marketplace, you’ll find new ideas, practical techniques, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/10/jetbrains-plugin-developer-conf-2025-is-coming-up-soon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “10x” Commandments of Highly Effective Go</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from John Arundel of Bitfield Consulting, a Go trainer and writer who runs a free newsletter for Go learners. His most recent book is The Deeper Love of Go. Ever wondered if there’s a software engineer, somewhere, who actually knows what they’re doing? Well, I finally found the one serene, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/10/16/the-10x-commandments-of-highly-effective-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Is Sunsetting CodeCanvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We started the development of CodeCanvas back in 2022, with the strong belief that cloud development environments (CDEs) would make development faster, smoother, and more efficient. With this goal in mind, we launched CodeCanvas publicly in 2024 and started accumulating users. We dove into the issues they faced in their development workflows and how we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/10/jetbrains-is-sunsetting-codecanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
