<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:51:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #4: Dependency Cache</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Everyone wants faster builds. Historically in TeamCity Pipelines, running Maven builds meant having to download all of your dependencies from scratch for every single build. Introducing Dependency Cache! Now, TeamCity Pipelines caches your Maven dependencies after the initial run and reuses them in future builds, saving you time and money. Dependency Cache is turned on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/07/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Tools for Java Developers in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 10:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just as an RPG player relies on a well-stocked bag of artifacts and tools to overcome obstacles and achieve goals, a Java developer also has a set of essential tools. Each tool performs a specific role in simplifying development and enhancing productivity. As Java has evolved, many tools have come and gone; what was popular […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/top-tools-for-java-developers-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The YouTrack App Now Supports Helpdesk Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 09:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The YouTrack Helpdesk functionality has arrived in the YouTrack app! This means you can manage your customer support services on the go. Your agents and other team members can now work with support requests from their phones and tablets, and your reporters can submit and review tickets and public Knowledge Base articles in the app […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/07/the-youtrack-app-now-supports-helpdesk-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2 EAP Digest #3: Bun Debugger, Language Server Updates for Vue and Astro, and Prettier Integration by Default</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 15:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s time for our last EAP digest of this release that will walk you through the new features and improvements in WebStorm 2024.2! For more information, check out our previous blog posts.The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the EAP builds and keep both your stable and EAP versions up to date. You […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/07/webstorm-2024-2-eap3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Shape the Future of Tech – Participate in the Developer Ecosystem Survey 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 11:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year’s Developer Ecosystem Survey is out now! This is your chance to contribute to a comprehensive, unbiased analysis of the software development landscape. Your insights and feedback are invaluable, and we can’t wait to hear from you. Offering you an opportunity to share your experiences as a developer, the survey will take around 30 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2024/07/15/help-shape-the-future-of-tech-participate-in-the-developer-ecosystem-survey-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Practical Debugging at Scale: Do You Really Know How to Debug Effectively?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Shai Almog, where we will delve into the capabilities of the debugger. Date: July 25, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Most of us didn’t learn debugging in university and just “picked it up on the job”. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Beta Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 22:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the Beta version of IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2. This milestone brings us closer to the big release date, and you still have time to try out the new features through the Early Access Program. The Beta build includes all of the new functionality detailed in our IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP blog posts. Here’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot Testing in .NET with Verify</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When writing tests, the ultimate goal should always be to deliver “value”. This value is not just about the number of tests written but about the quality and relevance of the tests. We aim to write, execute, and maintain valuable tests that instill confidence in our application’s ability to withstand the rigors of user production […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/11/snapshot-testing-in-net-with-verify/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Emerging Data Job Trends in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 09:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog post by Thu Vu. The long-term outlook for data jobs – like data scientists, statisticians, and market research analysts – predicts explosive growth, much faster than most other fields. But here’s the catch: Despite the promising stats, data professionals are struggling to find jobs. AI is also shaking things up […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/11/5-emerging-data-job-trends-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2024.1 Release Candidate Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 08:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Release Candidate for MPS 2024.1 is now available for download. Grab it and experience the new functionality before the final 2024.1 release. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.1 RC You can learn about the new features in more detail in this blog post. The full list of fixed issues can be found here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/07/the-mps-2023-3-release-candidate-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try Full Line Code Completion in JetBrains Rider 2024.1.4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released the 2024.1 version of all our IDE products, including the dotUltimate family of products: ReSharper, Rider, dotMemory, dotTrace, dotCover, and dotPeek. Full Line Code Completion (FLCC), a local and fast AI model fine-tuned for product-specific programming languages, is one feature you may have heard of in this release. FLCC was released with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/10/full-line-code-completion-in-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q2 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Flexible trial periods for paid plugins You can now customize trial periods for your paid plugins or simply disable them. Instead of the default 30-day trial, you can now set a shorter trial period or even none at all. Just select the preferred trial period while uploading your plugin to the Marketplace […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q2-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Column Selection DSL in Kotlin DataFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The Kotlin DataFrame library makes extracting values from structured data an easy task. As discussed in our documentation, there are four separate APIs that can be used for this purpose, with the optimal choice depending on your individual situation and requirements. To demonstrate, let’s read in a JSON document containing information about users: The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/07/enhanced-column-selection-dsl-in-kotlin-dataframe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip User Experience Survey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, DataGrip community! At JetBrains, delivering an excellent user experience is always a top priority. Today, we’re launching a survey to gather your feedback and explore how we can make DataGrip even better. Please take a few minutes to complete the DataGrip User Experience Survey. Your input will help us prioritize future improvements. As a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/07/09/datagrip-user-experience-survey/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in July</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This July, we’ve made some improvements to our courses to better serve your learning needs, added certificates for two more courses, and introduced new learning topics. Let’s take a closer look at these updates. Updated courses Our courses have been restructured to align with the latest job requirements. We’ve incorporated real interview questions and regularly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/09/jetbrains-academy-new-in-july/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
