<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 10:55:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Achieve Effortless GitHub Releases With a New Plugin for TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 10:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub releases are fantastic for distributing your open-source projects, as they let you turn any code revision into ready-to-go assets with a detailed version history. What makes them particularly popular, though, is that they give users a proper Download button (because not everyone dreams of compiling source code). In TeamCity, the traditional approach for publishing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/teamcity-github-releases-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains at the ICPC World Finals 2025 Baku</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ICPC World Finals 2025 in Baku was an unforgettable event, and we were honored to be part of it once again. It’s always a joy to see the brightest students from across the globe. The Finals reminds us why supporting the ICPC is such a vital mission – it’s about community, talent, and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/11/jetbrains-at-the-icpc-world-finals-2025-baku/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing AI Coding Agents With TeamCity and SWE-bench</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 08:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction AI coding agents are no longer research experiments. They are quickly becoming practical tools that can help developers solve real problems. But how do you know whether an agent is good enough for serious use? How do you measure progress when its answers are not always predictable and when there may be various correct […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/testing-ai-coding-agents-with-teamcity-and-swe-bench/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.07.2 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing our second bug-fix release for the 2025.07 major release —TeamCity On-Premises 2025.07.2. This update ships a considerable number of bug fixes, including the following: Apart from resolving regular bugs, all TeamCity bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements. For that reason, we recommend that you never ignore bug-fix releases and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/teamcity-2025-07-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.2.20 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 09:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.2.20 release is out, delivering important changes for web development. Kotlin/Wasm is now Beta, with improvements to exception handling in JavaScript interop, npm dependency management, built-in browser debugging support, and a new shared source set for js and wasmJs targets. Additionally, here are some main highlights: For the complete list of changes, see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/kotlin-2-2-20-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie Is Now Available in CLion: Supercharge Your C and C&#43;&#43; Development Today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 07:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with version 2025.2.1, CLion now supports Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, thanks to an integration that is currently in Beta. Developers working on embedded systems, projects written in C or C++, or performance-critical software can now experience the full benefit of Junie’s project insights and tooling, directly in CLion. With Junie, you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/09/junie-availability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MPS 2025.2 brings quality and stability improvements across the board, along with several notable upgrades. This release adds the ability to start MPS with OS-native launchers, introduces a modernized Show Node Info dialog, and improves how resolve-info is handled when references are copy-pasted. You can now provide icons using factory methods, and the platform has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/09/mps-2025-1-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating IntelliJ Platform UI Freezes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You have probably seen this picture occasionally and wondered what is happening with your IDE and why it freezes! This is a tricky question, and many types of bugs and performance issues may lead to UI freezes. JetBrains IDEs are built on top of a UI framework (the Java AWT) that uses a single thread, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/investigating-intellij-platform-ui-freezes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“GoLand Can Do That?” Ten Secret Superpowers You Might Not Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Note: This is a guest post from John Arundel, a Go writer and teacher who blogs at bitfieldconsulting.com. His most recent book is The Deeper Love of Go. How do you break it to someone that they’ve wasted most of their life? Well, I worked with a guy who didn’t know how to copy and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/09/08/goland-can-do-that-ten-secret-superpowers-you-might-not-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Mellum Now Available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace – For Free</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 12:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Production-grade code completion at your fingertips – deploy Mellum instantly with full control and zero extra model fees JetBrains Mellum – our focused large language model (LLM) for code completion – is now available on the Amazon Bedrock Marketplace. This means Mellum is easier than ever to use in real-world applications, with instant access via […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/jetbrains-mellum-now-available-on-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-for-free/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect MCP Servers to Junie in PhpStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open standard introduced by Anthropic. Think of it as a USB-C port for AI: a consistent way to plug the AI models your AI agent uses into specific tools and data sources. You can connect Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, to a wide variety of officially […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/09/connect-mcp-servers-to-junie-in-phpstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – September 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 08:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month’s Java Annotated Monthly comes with a fresh mix of Java, Kotlin, AI, and tech news, plus a look at some great events you won’t want to miss. We’ve also got a featured section by Marit van Dijk, covering the new Java 25 release, the latest IntelliJ IDEA updates, and a playful take on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/java-annotated-monthly-september-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
