<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:43:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a change in our licensing model that we believe will benefit the developer community – DataGrip is now free for non-commercial use! With this change, DataGrip joins JetBrains RustRover, CLion, Rider, WebStorm, and RubyMine, which are already free for non-commercial use. Read on to learn more about the change and why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/10/01/datagrip-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Recognized in the 2025 Magic Quadrant™ for AI Code Assistants</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, JetBrains’s AI (including both AI Assistant and Junie) was recognized in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for AI Code Assistants, an industry that we believe is innovating and changing faster than almost any other. Using AI is now a fundamental part of software development. Developers are increasingly able to automate mundane tasks like […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/30/jetbrains-recognized-in-the-2025-magic-quadrant-for-ai-code-assistants/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better AI Depends on Better Data: We Need Your Help</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Over the past few years, AI has made remarkable progress, but it doesn’t always deliver what professional developers need. One key reason is that most models are trained on public datasets that don’t reflect the complex, real-world scenarios faced by professional developers every day. Without such real-world data, our AI tools will fall short. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/30/detailed-data-sharing-for-better-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to TeamCity On-Premises Renewal Pricing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re committed to continuously improving TeamCity and providing high-quality support. To reflect that ongoing investment, we’re updating our renewal pricing and grace period policies, effective November 3, 2025. At the same time, we’re ensuring that all existing licenses purchased before November 3, 2025, will continue to benefit from the current renewal discounts. What’s changing? Next […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/updates-to-teamcity-on-premises-renewal-pricing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Claude Agent in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: The new Claude Agent is now seamlessly integrated into JetBrains IDEs via the AI chat and included in the JetBrains AI subscription. No extra plugins, no extra subscriptions – just advanced AI coding assistance built on Anthropic’s Agent SDK, which powers Claude Code, right inside your IDE. The new agent leverages Anthropic models, including […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/introducing-claude-agent-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I tried out JetBrains’ code analysis tool Qodana”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the English version of the Japanese article first published by Jan Maki on Qiita. This post was not commissioned by Qodana and was written independently. For more information please reach out to them in the comments or via their link tree. Qodana is JetBrains’ code analysis platform for quality and aspects of code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/09/i-tried-out-jetbrains-code-analysis-tool-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Java Open-Source Projects Use IntelliJ IDEA: Real-World Examples – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 07:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of this series, we introduced some of the Java community’s most recognized open-source projects. Now, we’re back with more standouts: projects that speed up builds, strengthen testing, and simplify working with modern web stacks. And as always, IntelliJ IDEA helps maintainers move faster, confidently, and with a focus on quality. 🌿 jsoup […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/26/how-java-open-source-projects-use-intellij-idea-real-world-examples-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuing Positive Impact: This Year’s AI4SE Interns in their New Roles at JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our last post, we introduced the talented intern cohort from our AI for Software Engineering (AI4SE) research partnership with Delft University of Technology (TU Delft). In this post, we’re excited to spotlight the next chapter in their journey: their evolution from interns to full-time members of our tech team. As interns, they didn’t just […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/ai4se-interns-employees-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider Roadmap: What to Expect From the Upcoming Updates and Releases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Rider 2025.2 already out in the wild and the 2025.3 release cycle underway, we want to take a step back and give you a broader picture of where Rider is headed. This roadmap covers our plans for Rider 2025.3 and what you can expect from the minor updates included in the 2025.2 release line. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/25/rider-rider-roadmap-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Python So Popular in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 11:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While other programming languages come and go, Python has stood the test of time and firmly established itself as a top choice for developers of all levels, from beginners to seasoned professionals. Whether you’re working on intelligent systems or data-driven workflows, Python has a pivotal role to play in how your software is built, scaled, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/09/why-is-python-so-popular/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kotlin AI Stack: Build AI Agents With Koog, Code Smarter With Junie, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 08:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is changing how we build software, and Kotlin is ready to meet that change by empowering developers to build AI-powered apps and by enhancing the developer experience through AI-based tools. This post explores both angles: the tools for developing AI-powered apps, both from JetBrains and from the community, and the ways Kotlin is evolving […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/the-kotlin-ai-stack-build-ai-agents-with-koog-code-smarter-with-junie-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
