<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 15:27:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trader Verification Requirement on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 15:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To comply with the Omnibus Directive 2019/2161, JetBrains Marketplace requires plugin vendors to declare whether they act as professional traders or not. This ensures that consumers are properly informed about the legal status of those offering plugins on the platform and their corresponding rights stemming from the EU consumer protection laws.The Digital Services Act (DSA) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/05/trader-verification-requirement-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources, Bytecode, Debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 12:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When debugging Java programs, developers are often under the impression that they’re interacting directly with the source code. This isn’t surprising – Java’s tooling does such an excellent job of hiding the complexity that it almost feels as if the source code exists at runtime. If you’re just starting with Java, you likely remember those […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/sources-bytecode-debugging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Can AI Do to Improve Diversity in the Tech Community?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 13:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It often feels like AI is ubiquitous these days. From helping with research to creating a joke, AI seems able to do everything for us. The public response and general opinions about AI are mixed. Some see the negative aspects of AI and frequently wonder, “Will AI take over my job?”, “Could AI steal my […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/05/what-can-ai-do-to-improve-diversity-in-the-tech-community/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Really Know Java?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 06:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From a humble passion project to a major language powering billions of devices worldwide, Java’s journey is anything but ordinary. Java has always been shaped by big ideas and the people behind them. It’s a language that grew not just through specs and syntax, but through community, creativity, and the occasional dancing triangle mascot. This […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/do-you-really-know-java/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next: The WebStorm 2025.2 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 15:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April of this year, we released WebStorm 2025.1, our first major update for 2025. Thank you to everyone who is already using it and providing feedback. With April now behind us, we’d like to announce what we’ve got planned for the next release of WebStorm, which is scheduled for July, with our usual disclaimer: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/05/what-s-next-the-webstorm-2025-2-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2025.2 EAP 2: First Public Build with Out-of-Process Mode Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 11:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that ReSharper 2025.2 EAP 2 is the first public build to introduce support for running ReSharper out-of-process (OOP) with Microsoft Visual Studio. This long-anticipated architectural change lays the foundation for better stability and performance in the future, as it decouples the ReSharper process from the Visual Studio one. More on that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/22/resharper-2025-2-eap-2-oop-mode/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse: Webhooks, Job-Level Parameters, And More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 09:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let your commits build faster with webhooks When you commit changes, you want your build to start as soon as you push code. Waiting for several minutes for a polling interval can be frustrating. That’s why we’re introducing webhooks, a simple way for your version control system to notify TeamCity as soon as new code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/05/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-webhooks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KotlinConf 2025 Unpacked: Upcoming Language Features, AI-Powered Development, and Kotlin Multiplatform Upgrades</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 08:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With 2.5 million developers worldwide using Kotlin, the language continues to thrive and evolve. From exciting language and ecosystem updates and robust AI tools that empower Kotlin development to major Kotlin Multiplatform milestones and a strategic partnership for the backend, KotlinConf 2025 brought a wave of news that set the tone for the year ahead. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/kotlinconf-2025-language-features-ai-powered-development-and-kotlin-multiplatform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening Kotlin for Backend Development: A Strategic Partnership With Spring</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we see Kotlin as a strong foundation for modern backend development, not just because of its technical strengths, but also because of how it helps developers build reliable, maintainable systems more efficiently. As part of our continued efforts to make Kotlin a top choice for professional server-side work, we’re excited to announce a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/strategic-partnership-with-spring/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Koog: Empowering Kotlin Developers to Build AI Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve got some exciting news for the Kotlin Community! At this year’s KotlinConf, we’re introducing Koog, an innovative, open-source agentic framework that empowers developers to build AI agents within the JVM ecosystem using a modern Kotlin DSL. We designed Koog to provide developers with the tools they need to create intelligent, autonomous agents with the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/05/meet-koog-empowering-kotlin-developers-to-build-ai-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Case Study: How JetBrains Kotlin QA Scaled Quality for Kotlin 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 15:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we prepared to release IntelliJ IDEA support for Kotlin 2.0, a major milestone for their compiler and ecosystem, their QA team faced a formidable challenge: how to ensure consistent, reliable quality across a complex and evolving codebase without slowing down development. With the Kotlin compiler, IDE plugin, and numerous inspections being refactored and rewritten, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/qodana-case-study-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update, May 2025 – A Standalone Build Tool for Kotlin, Server-Side and Multiplatform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.7.0 is here, expanding beyond multiplatform apps to include support for server-side development with Ktor and Spring, adding iOS to Amper’s list of supported Kotlin Multiplatform targets, and much more. The standalone version of Amper is now the primary focus of the project, and the Gradle-based variant is being phased out. Read on for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/05/amper-update-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Guidelines for Your AI Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 09:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As software developers, we invest significant time and effort learning various technologies, understanding design patterns, avoiding anti-patterns, and striving to write clean, maintainable code. Over the years, this knowledge becomes second nature, guiding our decisions as we design systems, write features, and review code. But the landscape is evolving fast. We’re now entering a new […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/coding-guidelines-for-your-ai-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving the MPS Forum to the New JetBrains Platform Community Space</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 05:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discussions help communities evolve and thrive. The MPS community has been relying on the MPS Slack channel and the Zendesk community forum for many years. While Slack has served its purpose as a place for instantly exchanging advice and ideas, the forum has gradually fallen out of use. This is for good reason – the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/05/mps-forum-moved/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s next for Junie: building a smart and controllable AI coding agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 16:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the last few months, our team has been on a thrilling journey, building the next generation of AI-assisted tools – Junie, the coding agent by JetBrains. After countless hours of experiments, collecting your feedback, and using Junie internally, we are convinced that coding agents bring a paradigm shift in how software is built. Today, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/junie/2025/05/what-s-next-for-junie-building-a-smart-and-controllable-ai-coding-agent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin and Azul: Collaboration for Enhanced Runtime Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Striving for high application performance For many years, JetBrains has aimed to help developers write high-performance applications by providing tools for development and diagnostics. On the Kotlin team, we pay close attention to performance, offering language features such as inline functions and classes, optimizations in the standard library, thoughtful bytecode generation, and the Kotlin coroutines […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/kotlin-and-azul-collaboration-for-enhanced-runtime-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana’s New Insights Dashboard Provides Cross-Project Code Analysis Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 19:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing code quality can be a challenge in itself, even without the complexity of multiple projects. Thanks to our new Insights dashboard you can now get a near-instant overview of the code quality and performance of all your projects whenever you need it, without having to constantly switch between projects. Get Qodana Who is it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/insights-dashboard-cross-project-code-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Multiplatform Tooling: Now in IntelliJ IDEA and Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 15:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently outlined our plans for the future of Kotlin Multiplatform tooling. Today, we’re putting those plans into action with the Beta release of the new KMP plugin for your favorite IDEs – IntelliJ IDEA and Android Studio. This plugin simplifies every part of the KMP experience, from project setup to cross-platform development and Compose […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/kotlin-multiplatform-tooling-now-in-intellij-idea-and-android-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re opening the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major PhpStorm 2025.2 release. About Early Access Program (EAP) If you’re not familiar with how our Early Access Program (EAP) works, here’s a quick overview:
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/05/phpstorm-2025-2-early-access-program-is-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant – Now in Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 11:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we design AI to empower developers and streamline their development process with AI-powered features integrated directly into their editor. From the beginning, AI Assistant was available only within JetBrains IDEs, and later in Android Studio, both of which are built on the IntelliJ Platform. While we’re incredibly proud of the deep integrations and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/05/jetbrains-ai-assistant-now-in-visual-studio-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper Comes to Microsoft Visual Studio Code: Public Preview Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 11:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the past 20 years, ReSharper has been the legendary .NET productivity tool that changed how millions of developers explore, write, and improve their code in Microsoft Visual Studio. Today, we’re bringing this transformative experience to a new environment. ReSharper is now available as an extension for Visual Studio Code. Whether VS Code is your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/19/resharper-comes-to-microsoft-visual-studio-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Your Tribe – JUGs Unveiled</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever catch yourself venting to your AI assistant at 2 am about more than just code? We get it. Debugging can very quickly turn into a therapy session. But when it comes to real talk, real career advice, and real connections, nothing beats an actual community. Java User Groups (JUGs) are spaces where Java devs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/finding-your-tribe-jugs-unveiled/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
