<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:21:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Bug-Fix Releases Are Available for MPS – 2025.2.1, 2025.1.1, 2024.3.4, and 2024.1.5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released updates for multiple major MPS versions that fix several additional issues. The two most notable improvements that these releases bring are: MPS-38681 – Invisible references can now be excluded from usage highlighting. MPS-36481 – The task in Ant now recognizes two additional project properties to configure the location of the log files: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/10/new_bugfix_releases_mps-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper Is Now on the Open VSX Registry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ReSharper for Visual Studio Code has been available on the Microsoft Visual Studio Marketplace for some time now. However, ReSharper didn’t appear in many VS Code-compatible editors because these editors aren’t able to connect directly to the Visual Studio Code Marketplace. For this reason, users of such editors who wanted to install ReSharper had to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/14/resharper-open-vsx/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Kotlin Multiplatform Project and Win a Trip to KotlinConf 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year’s Kotlin Multiplatform Contest for students and recent graduates is open. Build a project using KMP, and it could take you to KotlinConf 2026 in Munich, Germany! Whether you are already exploring Kotlin Multiplatform or just curious about how far you can take shared Kotlin code, seize the chance to challenge yourself, stand out, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/kotlin-multiplatform-contest-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana’s Public API Is Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Qodana Public API is now live, complete with full documentation, examples, and OpenAPI specifications. This release gives all Qodana Cloud users the ability to integrate Qodana directly into their own systems, automate key workflows, and access core functionality programmatically. View Documentation What’s new? Until now, a few API endpoints were available only to selected […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/10/qodana-public-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.07.3 Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re releasing one of the final bug-fix updates before the next major version —TeamCity On-Premises 2025.07.3. This minor update addresses several issues, including: In addition to regular bug fixes, all TeamCity bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements. For that reason, we recommend that you never ignore bug-fix releases and update your On-Premises […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/10/teamcity-2025-07-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting Your KotlinConf Proposal: Expert Tips to  Help You Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thinking about sharing your Kotlin expertise on the big stage? KotlinConf is the premier event for all things Kotlin, and getting a talk accepted for inclusion in the conference is a fantastic way to contribute to the community and elevate your profile. However, submitting a talk proposal, especially for the first time, can feel daunting. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/crafting-your-kotlinconf-proposal-expert-tips/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling All Non-Commercial JetBrains Rider Users: Tell Us Your Stories!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, everyone! It’s been almost a year since we made Rider free for non-commercial use. To celebrate this milestone, we want to spotlight the amazing projects it helped create. We’re looking to interview a handful of users who’ve taken advantage of the free non-commercial use license, whether it was to build a side project, contribute […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/08/calling-all-non-commercial-rider-users/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet JetBrains at Azure Dev Summit 2025 (Lisbon, Oct 13–16)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains will be at Azure Dev Summit 2025 in Lisbon, and we’d love to connect with attendees interested in learning more about our products and services. My name is Max Solovyev, and I’m the Head of Growth at .NET and GameDev Tools – I’ll be on site and available throughout the event for brief, no-pressure […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/07/meet-jetbrains-at-azure-dev-summit-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Now Supports DAP Debuggers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest EAP build of CLion 2025.3, released yesterday, includes support for the Debug Adapter Protocol (DAP), which allows CLion to communicate with a variety of additional debuggers. Besides the bundled LLDB and GDB, you can now work with third-party implementations that support DAP. This feature brings CLion closer to becoming an IDE that is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/10/dap-debuggers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
