<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:07:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Datalore 2024.4: Limit 500 Toggle, Easier Folder Import, Polars DataFrames Support, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2024.4 introduces quality-of-life improvements for SQL cells, a revamped folder import workflow, support for Polars DataFrames, and more. Datalore Cloud customers have already received the new update automatically, and Datalore On-Premises customers can upgrade by following these instructions. Limit 500 toggle for SQL cells To help you prototype SQL queries faster, we’ve introduced a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/22/what-s-new-in-datalore-2024-4-limit-500-toggle-easier-folder-import-polars-dataframes-support-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper Tips &amp; Tricks with Matt Ellis – Livestream</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 13:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on September 12, 2024, at 2:00 PM UTC for another JetBrains livestream event. You can register for the event using the link below or subscribe to our YouTube channel, JetBrainsTV, to get a notification closer to the event. With over 20 years of ReSharper setting the standard for the .NET development experience, it’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/21/resharper-tips-tricks-with-matt-ellis-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Chatbots With LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 10:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Dido Grigorov, a deep learning engineer and Python programmer with 17 years of experience in the field. Chatbots have evolved far beyond simple question-and-answer tools. With the power of large language models (LLMs), they can understand the context of conversations and generate human-like responses, making them invaluable for customer […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/how-to-build-chatbots-with-langchain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.39 Is Out With Smart Mode for Single Files, the Ability to Compare Files, the Structure Tool Window, Automatic Language Detection for Untitled Files, and Other Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 14:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.39 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.39 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/08/fleet-1-39-is-out-with-smart-mode-for-single-files-the-ability-to-compare-files-the-structure-tool-window-automatic-language-detection-for-untitled-files-and-other-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Datalore Cloud Plans – What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 13:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Datalore has evolved over the years, we’ve added more and more pricing tiers to cater to different users in the cloud. The variety of tiers sometimes made choosing a plan complicated. Now, we’ve decided to revamp our subscription plans to simplify the process of finding the option that best fits your needs. You no […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/20/new-datalore-cloud-plans-what-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Learned From the Perforce 2024 State of Game Technology Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 11:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The gaming industry has long been a hotbed of innovation, with developers consistently pushing the boundaries of what’s possible. But as we progress into 2024, it’s clear that game technology’s sphere of influence is expanding far beyond the realm of gaming. Technological advancements coming out of the game industry are quickly adopted by various other […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/perforce-2024-game-tech-report/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Code Arena: How Well Can AI Models Understand Your Entire Project?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the last couple of years, AI has found its way into virtually all aspects of software development. We know that AI models are getting smarter, and we can clearly see how they have become better at seemingly everything, but why is this happening? One factor that is changing is context size, which is how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/08/long-code-arena-how-well-can-ai-models-understand-your-entire-project/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the PyCharm Databricks Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 08:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re introducing the Databricks integration with PyCharm Professional to make it easier for you to process, store, and analyze your data! The integration allows you to build your data and AI apps on the Databricks Data Intelligence Platform directly within PyCharm Professional, enhancing the data analytics platform with the powerful Python IDE by JetBrains. It […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/introducing-the-pycharm-databricks-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking a JVM Application With IntelliJ IDEA’s Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 09:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in the day, computer games were different. Not only have their graphics and mechanics evolved, but they also had one characteristic that doesn’t seem very common in games today: cheat codes. Cheat codes were sequences of keys that would give you something extraordinary, such as infinite ammo or the ability to walk through walls. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/hacking-a-jvm-application-with-intellij-idea-s-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2024.2 Versions of JetBrains IDEs Are Here With Enhanced FLCC and Remote Development, the New UI as the Default, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 09:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains IDEs, .NET tools, and AI Assistant are ready to be updated to the 2024.2 versions, which introduce a plethora of new features and improvements. We’ve seen high adoption rates for the new UI, and in the 2024.2 versions of JetBrains IDEs, the new UI is now the default for all users. The classic UI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/08/15/the-2024-2-versions-of-jetbrains-ides-are-here-with-enhanced-flcc-and-remote-development-the-new-ui-as-the-default-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotCover, dotMemory, dotPeek, and dotTrace 2024.2 Have Been Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dotCover 2024.2, dotMemory 2024.2, dotPeek 2024.2, and dotTrace 2024.2 have been released and are ready for download! Let’s take a look at what’s new with these .NET tools. dotMemory 2024.2 dotTrace 2024.2 dotCover 2024.2 dotPeek 2024.2 General enhancements Handling of external sources Build configuration detection If you’re also interested in learning more about ReSharper 2024.1 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/15/dotnet-tools-242-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2024.2: Deepened C#12 and Initial C#13 Support, New AI Capabilities, Localization, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, ReSharper 2024.2 and the latest versions of other JetBrains .NET tools have just been released. This release brings support for the .NET 9 Preview SDK, new C# and C++ features, localization updates, AI Assistant enhancements, and much more. In this article, we’ll cover the highlights of this major update for ReSharper and touch […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/15/resharper-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2: Full Line Code Completion, Reader Mode, Major Enhancements to Debugging, and More.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, We’re happy to announce the release of Rider 2024.2, which comes packed with a range of exciting features and improvements designed to elevate your .NET and game development experience. From enhanced language support to advanced AI capabilities, this update has something for everyone. Now, let’s dive into the details! Key features and enhancements […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/15/rider-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
