<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:06:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains with its CLion IDE Is Now an Official ST Authorized Partner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re pleased to announce that JetBrains has joined the ST Partner Program. Through this collaboration, we aim to improve the experience of embedded developers working with ST microcontroller solutions in CLion. Here’s what developers get from this partnership: About ST ST (STMicroelectronics) is a European company that specializes in designing, developing, and manufacturing semiconductor technologies. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/st-authorized-partner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KotlinX RPC 0.9.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 13:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release of kotlinx.rpc introduces significant improvements aimed at the long-term stability, maintenance, and evolution of the library. We’ve focused on decoupling dependencies and simplifying the API to create a more robust and user-friendly experience. Ready to get started? Build your next project with the interactive generator at start.ktor.io, or check out our samples on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kotlinx-rpc-0-9-1-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Integrate Qodana Into TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are many compelling reasons to use TeamCity as your CI server. Thanks to its out-of-the-box features, smart test management capabilities, and great scalability for enterprises, TeamCity offers a robust and reliable CI solution. But if you’re really looking to increase compliance and improve code quality and security, you can couple it with Qodana. Integrating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/08/how-to-integrate-qodana-into-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Assistant, Junie and Kineto Now Support GPT-5 by OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we are committed to delivering the best technologies to professional developers. We support multiple LLM providers across our AI products to ensure you have access to the right tools for your needs and the freedom to choose the ones you prefer. Today, we’re excited to announce that the latest model from OpenAI, GPT-5, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/08/07/gpt-5-support-in-ai-assistant-junie-kineto/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Drift: The Pitfall of Local Machines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve seen it before. Someone says, “It works on my machine,” and suddenly you’re deep in a rabbit hole trying to understand why a project that works perfectly on one machine fails to build or test on another. That’s configuration drift – when a developer’s actual environment starts to deviate from the project’s intended configuration. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/08/configuration-drift-the-pitfall-of-local-machines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 11:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this month’s Java Annotated Monthly – your pit stop for all things related to Java, Kotlin, frameworks, and the ever-shifting tech scene. From helpful reads to red-hot takes, we’ve lined up a range of articles for curious devs and ambitious teams. But wait, there’s more! As always, our AI corner is here, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/java-annotated-monthly-august-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Fixed in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the first-ever standalone What’s Fixed overview of an IntelliJ IDEA release! We are always working hard to make the IDE even more stable, reliable, and enjoyable to use. In previous releases, information about this work was blended into the What’s New content, making it very long and sometimes hard to grasp. To address […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/whats-fixed-intellij-idea-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Notebook Meets IntelliJ Platform: Advancing IDE Plugin Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The value of extensibility The ability to extend and customize software, from game mods to browser extensions, gives users a sense of freedom and the chance to bring their ideas to life. JetBrains IDEs already provide this sense of freedom through their support for plugins. For some time now, creating plugins for JetBrains IDEs has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/08/kotlin-notebook-meets-intellij-platform-advancing-ide-plugin-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RustRover 2025.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 15:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This version introduces major debugger enhancements, including remote and on-chip support, a new color scheme, improved borrow checker assistance, additional Rust learning resources, and more. RustRover goes AI Junie, the in-IDE coding agent, is now 30% faster, connects to external sources via MCP, and supports remote development. AI Assistant adds even smarter code completion for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/08/05/rustrover-2025-2-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin DSL: What’s New?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 13:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the last few TeamCity releases, we made some improvements to the Kotlin DSL. This is a summary of these enhancements. Custom path for Kotlin DSL files TeamCity has always had strict requirements regarding the directory location for Kotlin DSL files. It insisted on saving the files under the .teamcity directory, which had some drawbacks. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/08/kotlin-dsl-what-s-new/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 13:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Along with making Laravel Idea free for PhpStorm users, this release brings improvements to the remote development experience, JetBrains AI tools, and more. Download PhpStorm 2025.2 Junie coding agent MCP support Support for the Model Context Protocol (MCP) allows you to connect Junie to external sources like databases, file systems, and APIs. You can now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/08/phpstorm-2025-2-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2025.2 Is Now Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 12:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2025.2 introduces updates for working with HTTP servers, smarter inspections powered by data flow analysis (DFA), and a new non-blocking Welcome screen. This release also brings significant quality improvements to golangci-lint support, including version 2, making the integration more robust for real-time code analysis. Let’s take a closer look at all the new additions […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/08/05/goland-2025-2-is-now-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Your Ideas Clickable With Kineto by JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 12:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While developing a website or an app, you’ll encounter loads of technical challenges that need to be solved – from how to code the functionality to how to host it. Delivering even a simple to-do app requires a hefty technology stack, a team of professionals, and hours of testing and maintenance. This is the reason […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kineto/2025/08/make-your-ideas-clickable-with-kineto-by-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.2 Is Here: Better CLion Nova, Smarter Embedded Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion 2025.2 is now available. This latest version of the JetBrains IDE for C and C++ includes the following key updates: You can download CLion 2025.2 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu, or via a patch update from version 2025.1. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.2 CLion Nova […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/clion-2025-2-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2025.2: AI Toolkit for AI Engineers and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2025.2 introduces the AI Toolkit: everything AI engineers need – now natively supported in your IDE. This release’s other highlights include the last supported version of PyCharm Community, improvements to AI Assistant, Junie, and notebooks, as well as a persistent UI for updating .lock files and other enhancements. Download the latest version from our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/08/pycharm-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains is a Platinum Sponsor of the Godot Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 10:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we believe deeply in the value of diverse developer tools and open-source ecosystems, and so we’re thrilled to announce that we’ve just become a Platinum Sponsor of the Godot Foundation! Godot is a fantastic game engine, with a very different approach to other game engines. It’s open source, not for profit and driven […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/05/jetbrains-is-a-platinum-sponsor-of-the-godot-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
