<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:28:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and the .NET tools 2024.2 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get a preview of all the latest features and improvements set to be shipped with the next major ReSharper and .NET tools releases by downloading the Release Candidate builds that have just landed. Here are the major improvements in each of the new builds: The ReSharper 2024.2 Release Candidate The ReSharper C++ 2024.2 Release Candidate […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/07/resharper-2024-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2024.2 Release Candidate Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next big release for Rider is just around the corner! If you’re eager to get a sneak peek, you can download the Release Candidate version of Rider 2024.2 from our website right now. This build includes all the significant updates we introduced during the Early Access Program, as detailed in our earlier blog posts. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/07/rider-2024-2-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape Character, Extract Common Code, Params Modifier, Out Vars – C# Language Support in 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our release for ReSharper and Rider 2024.2 is just around the corner and we have lots of exciting features shipping for the new C# 13 and current C# and VB.NET! Since it’s really a lot, we will be splitting things up into multiple blog posts. So make sure to come back for the others as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/07/escape-character-extract-common-code-params-modifier-out-vars-csharp-language-support-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Financial Bubbles With Python and Datalore AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog post by Ryan O’Connell, CFA, FRM. Introduction In the late 1990s, the world witnessed an unprecedented surge in technology stocks, when investors couldn’t throw money at dot-com companies fast enough. Fast-forward to 2024, and we find ourselves in the midst of another technological revolution – the AI boom. As artificial […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/07/analyzing-financial-bubbles-with-python-and-datalore-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 08:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 has arrived, featuring a host of exciting upgrades to enhance your experience with the IDE. You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 This release enhances Spring Data JPA support, simplifies cron expression management, and upgrades the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/intellij-idea-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scala 3 The new release comes with lots of bug fixes and improvements to Scala 3 support. Here are some of them: Better code highlighting The new release includes several improvements to error and syntax highlighting. In addition, IntelliJ Scala Plugin is now more responsive when the user fixes errors, removing the red code right […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/08/07/intellij-scala-plugin-2024-1-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant 2024.2: Improved Code Completion, Smarter Chat, and More AI Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new and improved AI Assistant for the 2024.2 versions of JetBrains IDEs is now out, featuring smarter and faster AI code completion for Java, Kotlin, and Python; an enhanced UX when working with code in the editor; AI functionality for Git conflict resolution, in-terminal code generation, new customizable prompts, improved test generation, and more. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/08/jetbrains-ai-assistant-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.07.1 Bug Fix Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2024.07.1 bug fix for TeamCity On-Premises is now available for download! This bug fix update resolves over 30 issues, including failing Maven builds in containers, agent Windows services not locating the bundled JRE, new licensing mechanism problems, and more. In addition, version 2024.07.1 resolves multiple important security issues and performance problems, which is why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-2024-07-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in August</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            August is here already! We hope you haven’t forgotten to book a break so you can fully enjoy your last summer month. Unless you’re in the southern hemisphere, of course. But just because it isn’t summer where you are doesn’t mean you shouldn’t take a well-deserved break, too! One great way to get into vacation […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/08/06/jetbrains-academy-new-in-august/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.5 is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 05:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more details about the issues resolved, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/intellij-idea-2024-1-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #5: Smooth Parameter Replacement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 19:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            💡 TeamCity Pipelines by JetBrains is a new approach to CI/CD that offers blazing-fast pipelines to optimize your development flow. We release a new version every three weeks, and here’s what’s new in the latest edition. Imagine you could define parameters when configuring a pipeline and see their values right away, without all of the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue5-smooth-parameter-replacement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Renovated Kotlin Support – K2 Mode: What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we’ve gathered the essential information about K2 mode in IntelliJ IDEA. What does K2 mode do? K2 mode is a new implementation of the Kotlin support within IntelliJ IDEA that improves the stability of the IDE while also setting the foundation for supporting future Kotlin language features. What is the difference between […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/meet-the-renovated-kotlin-support-k2-mode/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | August 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? In 1936, Russian engineer Vladimir Lukyanov built a mechanical computer known as a Water Integrator that carefully manipulated water in a room full of interconnected pipes and pumps. The water level in various chambers represented stored numbers, and the computer could solve complex mathematical equations. I’m sure the last thing Vladimir wanted […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/01/dotinsights-august-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 Release Candidate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next major CLion release is around the corner, and the v2024.2 RC is already available! To install CLion 2024.2 RC (build 242.20224.214), download it from our website, update via the Toolbox App, or use this snap package (for Ubuntu). You need an active subscription or a trial license to use the CLion 2024.2 RC. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/08/2024-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – July Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 16:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Summer’s almost gone! Don’t delay upgrading your tech skills. Our July digest has it all: a new Git starter kit, fresh courses, top projects you can work on, career tips, events, and free educational licenses. Dive in and level up!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/31/jetbrains-academy-july-digest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Quality: Leadership Strategies for Finding and Supporting Quality-Focused Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 13:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why is prioritizing code quality so important? Building successful software products starts with getting the right team on board, but as any technical recruiter or team lead will tell you, this is often easier said than done. One of the greatest challenges leaders face is balancing culture, competency, and potential in order to grow teams […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/07/leadership-code-quality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KotlinConf 2025 Tickets Are Now on Sale!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The countdown to KotlinConf 2025 has officially begun, and we’re excited to announce that tickets are now on sale for this premier event, which will take place from May 21–23, 2025, in Copenhagen, Denmark! Organized by JetBrains, this is the largest Kotlin event in the world. Starting today, you can secure your spot at KotlinConf […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/07/kotlinconf-2025-tickets-on-sale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
