<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:55:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update, October 2025 – Compose Hot Reload and UX Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.8.0 is out, with Compose Hot Reload, a customizable Kotlin compiler version, new JavaScript and Wasm platforms, and many other improvements to both the IDE and CLI experience. Read on for all of the details, and see the release notes for the full list of changes and bug fixes. To get support for Amper’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/10/amper-update-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 – v2025.2.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/10/intellij-idea-2025-2-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog × A2A: Building Connected AI Agents in Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever tried building a system of multiple AI agents, you’ve probably run into the problem. It starts simple enough: You’ve got one agent writing blog posts, another proofreading them, and maybe a third suggesting or generating images. Individually, they’re effective. But getting them to work together? That’s where things might start falling apart. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/10/koog-a2a-building-connected-ai-agents-in-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Visual Studio 2026: Day-One Compatibility, Migration Steps, and Performance Gains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here, and the next major VS update is on the horizon. As with any new Visual Studio version, one of the first questions developers ask is: “Will my extensions work after updating – especially ReSharper?”. The short answer is a resounding “yes”. But there’s more to the story, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/02/resharper-and-visual-studio-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving PHP open source forward</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we want the PHP community to shine. First and foremost, we do this by building PhpStorm, the best IDE for PHP development; but we also support and help drive the PHP Foundation; have just organised PHPverse, accessible for everyone worldwide; and recently we made the Laravel Idea plugin free for all. On top […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/10/moving-php-open-source-forward/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a change in our licensing model that we believe will benefit the developer community – DataGrip is now free for non-commercial use! With this change, DataGrip joins JetBrains RustRover, CLion, Rider, WebStorm, and RubyMine, which are already free for non-commercial use. Read on to learn more about the change and why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/10/01/datagrip-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Recognized in the 2025 Magic Quadrant™ for AI Code Assistants</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, JetBrains’s AI (including both AI Assistant and Junie) was recognized in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for AI Code Assistants, an industry that we believe is innovating and changing faster than almost any other. Using AI is now a fundamental part of software development. Developers are increasingly able to automate mundane tasks like […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/30/jetbrains-recognized-in-the-2025-magic-quadrant-for-ai-code-assistants/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better AI Depends on Better Data: We Need Your Help</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Over the past few years, AI has made remarkable progress, but it doesn’t always deliver what professional developers need. One key reason is that most models are trained on public datasets that don’t reflect the complex, real-world scenarios faced by professional developers every day. Without such real-world data, our AI tools will fall short. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/30/detailed-data-sharing-for-better-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to TeamCity On-Premises Renewal Pricing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re committed to continuously improving TeamCity and providing high-quality support. To reflect that ongoing investment, we’re updating our renewal pricing and grace period policies, effective November 3, 2025. At the same time, we’re ensuring that all existing licenses purchased before November 3, 2025, will continue to benefit from the current renewal discounts. What’s changing? Next […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/updates-to-teamcity-on-premises-renewal-pricing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Claude Agent in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: The new Claude Agent is now seamlessly integrated into JetBrains IDEs via the AI chat and included in the JetBrains AI subscription. No extra plugins, no extra subscriptions – just advanced AI coding assistance built on Anthropic’s Agent SDK, which powers Claude Code, right inside your IDE. The new agent leverages Anthropic models, including […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/introducing-claude-agent-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I tried out JetBrains’ code analysis tool Qodana”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the English version of the Japanese article first published by Jan Maki on Qiita. This post was not commissioned by Qodana and was written independently. For more information please reach out to them in the comments or via their link tree. Qodana is JetBrains’ code analysis platform for quality and aspects of code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/09/i-tried-out-jetbrains-code-analysis-tool-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Java Open-Source Projects Use IntelliJ IDEA: Real-World Examples – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 07:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of this series, we introduced some of the Java community’s most recognized open-source projects. Now, we’re back with more standouts: projects that speed up builds, strengthen testing, and simplify working with modern web stacks. And as always, IntelliJ IDEA helps maintainers move faster, confidently, and with a focus on quality. 🌿 jsoup […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/26/how-java-open-source-projects-use-intellij-idea-real-world-examples-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
