<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 16:14:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s next for Junie: building a smart and controllable AI coding agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 16:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the last few months, our team has been on a thrilling journey, building the next generation of AI-assisted tools – Junie, the coding agent by JetBrains. After countless hours of experiments, collecting your feedback, and using Junie internally, we are convinced that coding agents bring a paradigm shift in how software is built. Today, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/junie/2025/05/what-s-next-for-junie-building-a-smart-and-controllable-ai-coding-agent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin and Azul: Collaboration for Enhanced Runtime Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Striving for high application performance For many years, JetBrains has aimed to help developers write high-performance applications by providing tools for development and diagnostics. On the Kotlin team, we pay close attention to performance, offering language features such as inline functions and classes, optimizations in the standard library, thoughtful bytecode generation, and the Kotlin coroutines […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/kotlin-and-azul-collaboration-for-enhanced-runtime-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana’s New Insights Dashboard Provides Cross-Project Code Analysis Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 19:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing code quality can be a challenge in itself, even without the complexity of multiple projects. Thanks to our new Insights dashboard you can now get a near-instant overview of the code quality and performance of all your projects whenever you need it, without having to constantly switch between projects. Get Qodana Who is it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/insights-dashboard-cross-project-code-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Multiplatform Tooling: Now in IntelliJ IDEA and Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 15:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently outlined our plans for the future of Kotlin Multiplatform tooling. Today, we’re putting those plans into action with the Beta release of the new KMP plugin for your favorite IDEs – IntelliJ IDEA and Android Studio. This plugin simplifies every part of the KMP experience, from project setup to cross-platform development and Compose […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/kotlin-multiplatform-tooling-now-in-intellij-idea-and-android-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re opening the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major PhpStorm 2025.2 release. About Early Access Program (EAP) If you’re not familiar with how our Early Access Program (EAP) works, here’s a quick overview:
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/05/phpstorm-2025-2-early-access-program-is-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant – Now in Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 11:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we design AI to empower developers and streamline their development process with AI-powered features integrated directly into their editor. From the beginning, AI Assistant was available only within JetBrains IDEs, and later in Android Studio, both of which are built on the IntelliJ Platform. While we’re incredibly proud of the deep integrations and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/05/jetbrains-ai-assistant-now-in-visual-studio-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper Comes to Microsoft Visual Studio Code: Public Preview Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 11:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the past 20 years, ReSharper has been the legendary .NET productivity tool that changed how millions of developers explore, write, and improve their code in Microsoft Visual Studio. Today, we’re bringing this transformative experience to a new environment. ReSharper is now available as an extension for Visual Studio Code. Whether VS Code is your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/19/resharper-comes-to-microsoft-visual-studio-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Your Tribe – JUGs Unveiled</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever catch yourself venting to your AI assistant at 2 am about more than just code? We get it. Debugging can very quickly turn into a therapy session. But when it comes to real talk, real career advice, and real connections, nothing beats an actual community. Java User Groups (JUGs) are spaces where Java devs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/finding-your-tribe-jugs-unveiled/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join JetBrains PHPverse to Celebrate 30 Years of PHP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PHP turns 30 this June, and we’re looking forward to celebrating this notable milestone together with you! On June 17, 2025, we’re hosting JetBrains PHPverse 2025, where prominent people from the PHP community will come together and share their thoughts about the state and the future of the modern PHP language and ecosystem. This is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/05/join-jetbrains-phpverse-to-celebrate-30-years-of-php/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Live!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for Rider 2025.2 has just begun, and the first preview build for the upcoming major release is already out. There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: A reminder of what the EAP is all about The Early Access Program is a long-standing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/16/rider-2025-2-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.2 Has Begun!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that the Early Access Program (EAP) for ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.2 is now underway! The first build is available for download, giving you a sneak peek into the features and improvements coming in the next major release. As always, your feedback is key to shaping the final version – we’d […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/16/resharper-2025-2-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re launching our two-month Early Access Program (EAP) for CLion 2025.2. The EAP allows you to try new CLion features and improvements at no cost before the stable release. You can download the first EAP build, 252.13776.55, from the link below or via Toolbox App. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.1 EAP For the first EAP release, we’ve […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/2025-2-eap-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 14:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 has now officially begun! We’d like to share a glimpse of what we’re working on for the upcoming release and invite you to join us on this exciting journey over the coming weeks. There will also be a small change in the way we’ll deliver our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/the-intellij-idea-2025-2-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 11:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MPS 2025.1 allows the build language to serve as a target for code generation. This version also introduces visual and performance enhancements to the Project tool window’s Logical view, several useful improvements to the UI, and numerous platform updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.1 What’s new Let’s check out all the new features waiting for you in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/05/mps-2025-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion and the Open-Source Community: Growing Together</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From the beginning, CLion has been shaped by the needs of C and C++ developers around the world. Our cross-platform IDE was built to simplify development, boost productivity, and make working with C++ more enjoyable. We’re excited to take the next step in our ongoing collaboration with the community: CLion is now free for non-commercial […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/05/14/clion-and-the-open-source-community-growing-together/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try Declarative Gradle EAP3 in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 08:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Declarative Gradle project, aimed at making Gradle build scripts easier to read and use, is at full steam. Last month, EAP3 landed, bringing testing support and more DCL language features, like lists and files. Read the Gradle blog post to learn more about what the EAP, and Declarative Gradle in general, brings you. Like […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/try-declarative-gradle-eap3-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip and Database Tools UX Survey #2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to launch the second edition of our User Experience Survey for DataGrip and the Database Tools &amp;amp; SQL Plugin! Your feedback from the previous survey helped us better understand your needs and prioritize the features and improvements that matter most to you. Thanks to your input, we’ve already delivered a first set of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/05/13/datagrip-and-database-tools-ux-survey-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Rust the Future of Programming?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 12:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rust is rewriting the rules of modern software development as the fastest-growing programming language. Its unmatched performance, memory safety without garbage collection, and concurrency capabilities are capturing developers’ attention worldwide. According to our data, with 2,267,000 developers using Rust in the last 12 months and 709,000 identifying it as a primary language, Rust’s footprint in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/05/13/is-rust-the-future-of-programming/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Cloud-Ready Apps Locally: Spring Boot, AWS, and LocalStack in Action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developing an application with AWS services can introduce significant local‑development hurdles. Often, developers don’t receive timely AWS access, or a sysadmin inadvertently grants credentials for the wrong account – only to fix the error a week later. Then, when engineers discover they still lack permissions for certain resources, they must endure yet another week-long wait […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/building-cloud-ready-apps-locally-spring-boot-aws-and-localstack-in-action/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Plugin Verifier and API Compatibility Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maintaining plugin compatibility across JetBrains IDEs can be tricky — but the Plugin Verifier is here to help. On Wednesday, May 21, at 2:00 PM UTC, join us for a live session with IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Róbert Novotný and Yann Cébron, focused on the Plugin Verifier and API compatibility maintenance. During the webinar, you’ll discover how: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/05/livestream-plugin-verifier-and-api-compatibility-maintenance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CodeCanvas 2025.1 With Free Tier and Toolbox Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 09:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April, we released CodeCanvas 2025.1 with many important changes. The release brings improved infrastructure flexibility for easier multi-region setups, a new AWS CloudFormation installation option, enhanced environment logs, and more. Today, we want to highlight two major updates: See the full What’s New for the full details. Use CodeCanvas for free With the 2025.1 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/05/codecanvas-2025-1-with-free-tier-and-toolbox-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
