<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:24:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ask Us Anything During JetBrains AMA Week</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains will be hosting a series of open Ask Me Anything (AMA) sessions on Reddit December 9–12. On scheduled days, our product teams will join r/jetbrains to talk directly with developers who use our tools every day. We’ll be there for honest conversations about what’s working, what’s not, and where your priorities lie. Your feedback […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/03/ask-us-anything-during-jetbrains-ama-week/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Stories Of Developers Using JetBrains Rider to Create, Collaborate, and Have Fun</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago, we introduced a free non-commercial use license option for JetBrains Rider, hoping to remove barriers for developers who code with no financial objective in mind for their projects. Recently, we put out a call for your stories – curious to learn how you’ve been using Rider throughout this year. What came back […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/03/5-stories-of-developers-using-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grok Models Come to the AI Chat in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re expanding our AI offering with xAI’s Grok family of LLMs: Grok 4, Grok 4.1 Fast, Grok 4.1 Fast (Non-Reasoning), and Grok Code Fast 1. With the addition of these models in the AI chat across all JetBrains IDEs, you now have even more flexibility to choose the model that best fits your workflow. How […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/grok-models-come-to-the-ai-chat-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip 2025.3: Migration From Consoles to Query Files, Connection to Cloud Providers, Introspection Levels for Amazon Redshift, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2025.3, the final major update of the year, is here! Let’s take a look at what it has to offer. Download DataGrip 2025.3 Migration from query consoles to query files Previously, when referring to the SQL files that are attached to a data source by default, we used the term query console, and their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/02/datagrip-2025-3-migration-from-consoles-to-query-files-connection-to-cloud-providers-introspection-levels-for-amazon-redshift-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? Calling GC.Collect() explicitly forces the garbage collector to run and reclaim memory from unreachable objects. However, it’s generally discouraged to use this method in most applications because the garbage collector is highly optimized to run automatically. Forcing it can lead to performance issues by interrupting the normal optimization process. Welcome to dotInsights […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/02/dotinsights-december-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Achieve Significant Build Performance Gains With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is brought to you by Mdu Sibisi, draft.dev. Long build times interfere with developer momentum, disrupt flow states, and negatively impact productivity. While seemingly minor gaps in work rate may appear negligible in the moment, they quickly accumulate into significant increases in release cycle times and infrastructure costs. (There’s a reason high-performance development […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/build-performance-gains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Engineers Talk About Spring Boot 4, Life, and Other Stuff</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us as we welcome the Spring team and Evgeny Borisov for a new IntelliJ IDEA livestream, where we’ll discuss what’s new in Spring Boot 4 and how all the new updates work in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: December 11, 2025 Time: 4:00–5:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this livestream, we’ll explore […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/new-livestream-engineers-talk-about-spring-boot-4-life-and-other-stuff/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Through the Noise: Smarter Context Management for LLM-Powered Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you’re working on a project and jotting down every single idea, experiment, and failure. After a while, your notes pile up so high that finding what’s useful takes more time and energy than the work itself. A similar problem faces users of software engineering (SE) agents: the agents “take notes” on every generated output, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/12/efficient-context-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2025: A Kotlin Playground</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us live for five days of Advent of Code puzzles and five Kotlin livestreams on December 1–5. Solve the puzzles in Kotlin with help from Kotlin team experts and fun community guests, climb the leaderboard, learn new tricks, and have a chance to win some prizes along the way! Here’s what we have planned […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/advent-of-code-in-kotlin-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Advent of Code in Rust, With Just Enough AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago, I wrote a blog post about solving Advent of Code puzzles using Rust as the implementation language. I believe it’s still relevant if you plan to use Rust this year. In one section, I advised limiting the use of AI and demonstrated how to disable the relevant functionality in RustRover, either partially […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/11/28/solving-advent-of-code-in-rust-with-just-enough-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Release Candidate Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Release Candidate for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 is now available, and we’re closing the Early Access Program for this development cycle. Thank you to everyone who evaluated the EAP builds, shared feedback, and reported issues. Your input has been invaluable in shaping the upcoming release. When we opened the IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 EAP, we outlined […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-2025-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Went to BazelCon 2025 – Here’s Everything You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, BazelCon was held at the Omni Atlanta Hotel at Centennial Park for a very special occasion: the tenth anniversary of Bazel 🎉 For me, visiting from Europe, Atlanta made quite the first impression. The city felt bigger than anything I’ve seen back home, and with KubeCon happening right next door, the streets were […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/11/bazelcon-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in TeamCity 2025.11: AI Assistant, New Pipeline Features, Enhanced Server Encryption Settings, and More.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity 2025.11 introduces new build steps for pipelines, enhanced encryption settings, and a refreshed experience that makes powerful CI/CD workflows easier to create and manage. Here’s what’s new in this release. Introducing AI Assistant (Early Access) TeamCity is a true powerhouse, but mastering every one of its features can be challenging. To help you get […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/11/teamcity-202511/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.3.0.3: A Fresh Set of Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another set of updates for the 2025.3 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.3.0.3 The most notable fix of this build is that extension methods from source-only NuGet packages are now recognized correctly in the editor and by InspectCode. [RSRP-502165]. You can find the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/27/resharper-and-rider-2025-3-0-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Could Simply Add Nullability Check Support… Without Even Noticing It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            (The Growing Pains of a Good Idea: What Happens After JSpecify Adoption Begins) The good news: JSpecify is finally here JSpecify adoption is accelerating. You don’t even need to “install” it – nullability support now arrives automatically with your dependencies. If you somehow missed the long history behind the JSpecify effort and want a quick […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/one-could-simply-add-nullability-check-support-without-even-noticing-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Spring Data AOT in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring’s AOT engine has been around since the Spring Native days, but Spring Data never really benefited from it – until now. Repository infrastructure is one of the most dynamic parts of the framework, and for years it relied heavily on proxies, reflection, and queries generated at runtime. That flexibility has a price: it slows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/spring-data-aot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Too Much News to Keep Quiet About</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve gathered the latest Kotlin highlights for you – from the Kotlin Reddit AMA and documentation updates to learning programs and Google Summer of Code 2025 projects. Whether you’re here to stay up to date or just looking for something interesting to explore, there’s plenty to dive into. Where You Can Learn More YouTube Highlights
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/kodees-kotlin-roundup-november-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 2: A Deeper Dive Into Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous article, we saw how to build a basic coding agent with list, read, write, and edit capabilities. Today, we’ll dive into how to extend the agents’ capabilities by creating additional tools within the Koog framework. As an example, we’ll be building an ExecuteShellCommandTool, teaching our agent to run code and close the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-2-a-deeper-dive-into-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
