<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 17:59:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Data Analysis with Kotlin DataFrame Tables in Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce a new UI component in Kotlin DataFrame 0.13.1, which enhances your data exploration experience inside the Kotlin Notebook plugin. The existing component is helpful, but can only show a certain number of rows, limiting your navigation through the data. When used extensively, it can also impact performance negatively. The new UI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/05/streamline-data-analysis-with-kotlin-dataframe-tables-in-notebooks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RustRover Is Released and Includes a Free Non-Commercial Option</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 16:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since the announcement of the RustRover Public Preview eight months ago, we’ve been hard at work shaping our vision for this feature-rich Rust IDE. Today, we’re excited to announce the general availability of this brand-new IDE, which joins our existing family of JetBrains IDEs. We’d like to thank all the early adopters for their trust, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/05/21/rustrover-is-released-and-includes-a-free-non-commercial-option/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant for JavaScript Developers – WebStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 11:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There is no doubt that the advent of AI is changing the way many of us work. Whether you choose to accept this with optimism… or skepticism… is a topic for another day. We choose optimism, as AI has incredible potential to improve how we work. In this blog post, we’ll look at how you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/05/ai-assistant-for-javascript-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying to Multiple Targets With Ease</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 10:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever been faced with a situation where you needed to deploy your system to many different environments? For many of us, this is probably just staging or production. When using TeamCity to do this, we just create a build chain as follows: But what if the number of deployment targets is higher, like […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/05/deploying-to-multiple-targets/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 14:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new season of our Early Access Program has officially started! The first EAP build for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 is now available for download, offering a sneak peek at some of the exciting updates in the pipeline. You can download the new version from our website, update directly from inside the IDE or via the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/05/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 13:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re glad to announce the opening of the RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program. In this blog post, we’ll share what you can expect in this release cycle. What’s coming in RubyMine 2024.2? In this update, our goal is to enhance your RubyMine experience by incorporating new AI features, improving remote work capabilities, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/05/rubymine-2024-2-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oren Eini – Building a Database Engine in C# and .NET – June 18th Livestream</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 05:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on June 18th, 2024, at 2:00 PM UTC on JetBrains TV for our latest livestream with our special guest, the prolific Oren Eini, when they give their presentation, “Building a Database Engine in C# and .NET”. Join Oren Eini, CEO of RavenDB, as he delves into the intricate process of constructing a database […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/16/oren-eini-building-a-database-engine-in-csharp-and-dotnet-june-18th-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
