<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:12:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 3 Pro Is Now Available in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest AI model from Google, Gemini 3 Pro, is now live in JetBrains IDEs. From day one, it powers AI Chat and soon will be available in Junie, our coding agent, giving you smarter reasoning, stronger instruction following, and seamless integration into your workflow. What’s new Gemini 3 Pro shows clear improvements that matter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/gemini-3-pro-is-now-available-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Release of MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting today, you can download the second EAP release for MPS 2025.3 and try all the latest updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 EAP 2 This release includes several noteworthy improvements: JavaDoc language overhaul The JavaDoc language has been completely migrated to use the jetbrains.mps.lang.text language for text representation and editing. This change should have minimal impact […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/11/the-mps-2025-3-eap2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping Decision‑Makers Say Yes to Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the fourth post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/helping-decision-makers-say-yes-to-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: Projects We’re Proud to Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference — the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and to contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/11/18/open-source-in-focus-projects-we-re-proud-to-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Features in Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider provides robust support for working with databases directly within the IDE – powered by DataGrip! Rider and DataGrip smooth development workflows by allowing you to manage and interact with a variety of database systems. This integration enhances productivity for developers who frequently work with data. Database projects and connectivity There has long been support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/17/database-features-in-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Prepare for the Future of Programming</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Start a start-up? Scratch that. Call your mom. Go back to school? Don’t go back to school. Learn to code? Don’t learn to code. Forget coding. Only prompt engineering matters now. Actually, I heard it’s overrated. You think we’re gonna be prompting in 5 years? 2 years? Nonsense. All this hype is being blown so […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/11/17/how-to-prepare-for-the-future-of-programming/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Your Calendars! Qodana Events in November</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As 2025 starts racing to a close, the JetBrains Qodana team is ending the year with a series of events dedicated to what matters most in modern software development: secure workflows, high-quality code, and practical tooling that empowers developers to ship with confidence. Whether you’re working in security engineering, backend development, DevOps, or AI-powered applications, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/11/mark-your-calendars-qodana-events-in-november/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Diffusion Models Could Change Developer Workflows in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers spend much of their time editing, refactoring, and debugging rather than producing entirely new code. Code creation tends to involve non-sequential back-and-forth refinement rather than typing out a complete function in one uninterrupted sequence. You might sketch a part, adjust parameters, skip ahead, then revisit earlier sections to refine them. Diffusion models, and in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/why-diffusion-models-could-change-developer-workflows-in-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Is Heading to VSLive! Orlando</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Next week we’ll be in Orlando, Florida for Visual Studio Live!, and if you work with .NET, we’d like to meet you. You’ll find the JetBrains booth (#118) in the conference expo area throughout the week. Stop by to: We’ll also have special offers available for those who visit the booth.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/15/jetbrains-is-heading-to-vslive-orlando/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 💚 Spring 7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Major Spring Framework releases don’t come around often – and when they do, they tend to reshape how we build applications for years to come. Spring Framework 7 is one of those releases. It simplifies many aspects of development, cleans up some long-standing pain points, and introduces features that previously required custom annotations or boilerplate-heavy […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-2025-3-spring-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code 2025: What Our Contributors Built</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Congrats to all GSoC 2025 contributors and mentors! This year’s projects have made a real impact on the Kotlin ecosystem and the contributions are already being integrated, used, and appreciated. Thank you all for your hard work! Let’s take a closer look at this year’s projects: IntelliJ Platform Gradle Plugin – Gradle Reporting and Parallel […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/google-summer-of-code-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Developers Really Mean by “Bad Code”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The phrase “bad code” gets thrown around in reviews and online forums all the time. But what does it actually mean? It’s a good example of the vague terms that occasionally make the rounds in developer circles without much to qualify them. We’ve collected opinions on the subject, metrics, and code risks that you can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/11/what-is-bad-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
