<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.2 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper and .NET tools 2025.2 Release Candidates are ready for you to try. This release introduces the public preview of ReSharper’s Out-of-Process mode, adds support for the latest C# 14 and C++26 features, and brings a range of improvements for performance, refactorings, and inspections. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/24/resharper-dot-net-tools-2025-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2025.2 Release Candidate Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2025.2 is shaping up to be a big release – especially if you’re a game developer. This update introduces powerful new debugging features for Unity, Unreal Engine, and Godot, including source-level shader debugging, mixed-mode debugging for native and managed code, and stepping time improvements. Beyond game dev, Rider 2025.2 delivers a range of enhancements […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/24/the-rider-2025-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in TeamCity 2025.07: Public Recipes, Pipelines, Dependency Control, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 11:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the launch of TeamCity 2025.07! This release brings a range of improvements across the UI, Perforce integration, recipes, and more. It is also the first version to include pipelines: a reimagined TeamCity experience that focuses on a healthy balance of functionality and an intuitive design-first workflow. Read on to learn what’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/07/teamcity-202507/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.4 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released another update for v2025.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This version brings the following refinements: To see the full list of issues addressed in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/intellij-idea-2025-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 Beta: EAP Closure and Our New Approach to Release Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 13:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 is now available, marking the end of our Early Access Program for this release cycle. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 Beta Thank you to everyone who used the EAP builds, shared feedback, and helped shape this release. As we mentioned in the EAP opening post, we have moved away […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/intellij-idea-2025-2-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reworked Terminal Becomes the Default in 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 12:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting from 2025.2, the default terminal implementation is now the reworked terminal. To create this new implementation, the classic terminal was rewritten almost from scratch to provide the technical foundation for new terminal features like visual separation of executed commands, AI integration, and the ability to work seamlessly in remote development scenarios. Functionally, it is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/07/the-reworked-terminal-becomes-the-default-in-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 3.2.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Ktor 3.2.2 patch release brings a critical fix for Android D8 compatibility, along with some minor enhancements and bug fixes. 🚀 Get started Ready to explore Ktor 3.2.2? Start building your next project today with our interactive project generator at start.ktor.io. Your feedback and contributions are always welcome! 🔗 Get Started With Ktor | […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/ktor-3-2-0-is-now-available-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking to Build: Fuzzing the Kotlin Compiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we care about Kotlin compiler quality. One powerful way to test it? Fuzzing, an approach that feeds programs unexpected, often random, inputs to uncover bugs that traditional tests may miss. It may sound chaotic, but it works, especially for complex software like compilers. In a previous post, our colleagues introduced kotlinx.fuzz, a powerful […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/07/fuzzing-the-kotlin-compiler/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Cloud vs. Self-Hosted Lite: Which Is Best for Your Team?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Onboarding development teams with new tools can be difficult. People disagree about what’s best, and different organizations have different pains, needs, and regulations. Which option is the best for you? How do you find consensus in your team? How much control do you need over your data? There are many considerations, and it can feel […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/07/cloud-vs-self-hosted-lite/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA Moves to the Unified Distribution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the next step for IntelliJ IDEA: we are moving to a single, unified distribution. And yes, before you ask, our commitment to open source remains as strong as ever. There will be just one IntelliJ IDEA installer, replacing the separate downloads for Community Edition and Ultimate Edition. In this new […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/intellij-idea-unified-distribution-plan/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
