<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 08:32:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.4: Another Set of Bug-fixes Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 08:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A fourth set of updates for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.4 comes with the following fixes For the full list of resolved issues, please refer to our issue tracker. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/30/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 EAP 7: Low-Level Exception Suppression and Other Updates for Debugging Games</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 09:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2025.2 is shaping up to be an exciting release for game developers, no matter which engine you work with. Over the last few EAP builds, we’ve been rolling out targeted improvements to make debugging smoother, faster, and more reliable, whether you’re building with Unreal Engine, Unity, Godot, or custom C++ frameworks. In the latest […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/26/rider-2025-2-eap-7-low-level-exception-suppression/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Live</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 19:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the MPS 2025.2 Early Access Program (EAP). You can download the first 2025.2 EAP build and try it out now! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.2 EAP The release brings numerous bug fixes and improvements, such as: Resolve info is now correctly updated when copying references into the clipboard. The Show Node Info dialog has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/06/the-mps-2025-2-eap-has-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Spring Boot With Spring Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 07:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Boot is a marvel of developer productivity. It hides the plumbing and gets you up and running fast. Components are “miraculously” autowired, properties are “magically” resolved, and database connections materialize seemingly without explicit configuration. But when something goes wrong, the magic becomes a mystery, and debugging becomes a deep dive into the framework’s internal […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/demystifying-spring-boot-with-spring-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern CI/CD for a Post-VMware World: Embrace KubeVirt With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 11:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In November 2023, Broadcom acquired VMware for a whopping USD 69 billion. The strategic goal behind the acquisition was to enable customers to create and modernize their cloud environments, both private and hybrid. Following the acquisition, VMware perpetual license holders started receiving cease-and-desist letters from Broadcom. Users can continue using the software, but can no […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/kubevirt-with-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Your Code in Check With Qodana On-Prem Lite, Our Newest, Easy-to-Deploy Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 11:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve probably heard of Qodana Self-Hosted, but now we’re bringing you a different kind of Self-Hosted Qodana that’s on-premises, Qodana On-Prem Lite, making powerful code quality analysis more accessible than ever. Designed for teams seeking a streamlined, resource-efficient solution, this new offering brings the benefits of Qodana to a more on-premises environment with a focus […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/06/qodana-on-prem-lite/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.3 is out with a number of useful fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. The latest update brings the following improvements: For a comprehensive overview of the fixes, see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/intellij-idea-2025-1-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.2.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.2.0 release is out! This version includes both new and stable language features, tooling updates, performance improvements for different platforms, and important fixes. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.2.0 or the release notes on GitHub. Join the Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/kotlin-2-2-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover Junie for PhpStorm: A Game-Changing AI Coding Agent for PHP Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 09:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, PhpStorm has entered the realm of agentic IDEs. Now, the PhpStorm IDE doesn’t just provide classical developer productivity tools and AI assistance features, but can also do massive amounts of work for PHP developers autonomously. Unlike other coding agent plugins, Junie is native to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/06/discover-junie-for-phpstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
