<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:43:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your Writing with Grazie, Now Included in the AI Pro Subscription</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This week, we announced the general availability of Grazie, our AI writing companion for people in tech. We’re also excited to share that Grazie is now part of the AI Pro subscription at no extra cost. Grazie streamlines your non-coding tasks by integrating generative AI into your JetBrains IDEs, browsers, and other tools. Grazie’s main […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/06/enhance-your-writing-with-grazie-now-included-in-the-ai-pro-subscription/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – June Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stay updated with the latest news in the JetBrains Academy Newsletter. Discover the newest version of the JetBrains Academy plugin, celebrate our students’ international achievements, and learn how to become a JetBrains ambassador. All this and more await you in this month’s newsletter
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/06/28/jetbrains-academy-june-digest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Plugins to Enhance Your IntelliJ IDEA Experience in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 07:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2024/28_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Even though IntelliJ IDEA is powerful and self-sufficient, we love to customize it a bit with plugins. Why? Because they’re fun! In this blog post, we’ll share a list of cool plugins that will help you liven things up in your IDE. Let’s go! JetBrains AI Assistant AI has touched every industry over the past […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/10-plugins-to-enhance-your-intellij-idea-experience-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.03.3 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 17:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2024.03.3 bug fix for TeamCity On-Premises is now available for download! This release includes a few performance and security fixes. Among others, we addressed the following issues: For the full list of the issues fixed in this version, please refer to our release notes. As with other minor updates, TeamCity 2024.03.3 shares the same […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/06/teamcity-2024-03-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Where Conditions Work in Entity Framework Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core is a popular data access library in the .NET space that makes it easier to write, execute, and process SQL statements and the resulting data. If you’re new to the .NET space, this blog post will help you understand how to create filtered result sets using the Where operator and how to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/26/how-where-conditions-work-in-entity-framework-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Grazie – The AI Writing Companion for People in Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Grazie, a new AI writing companion for people working in tech, is now generally available. With Grazie, you can streamline your non-coding tasks by integrating generative AI into your JetBrains IDEs, browsers, and other tools. Grazie helps transform your thoughts into clear, well-articulated text through features like instant proofreading, inline text completion, summarization, translation, rephrasing, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2024/06/introducing-grazie-the-ai-writing-companion-for-people-in-tech/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #3: YAML Configuration Settings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With this TeamCity Pipelines release, we’re introducing the option to store and load pipeline definitions in YAML format from your repositories. The search panel for the YAML editor now looks better than ever. Bugs were squashed, improvements made, and our users are happier than ever. Read on to learn what’s new! Storing and loading configuration […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/06/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.1.4: What’s New!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.1.4 is here! View and navigate to URLs directly from the Editor tab, get context-based model suggestions for Hugging Face, and enjoy smart code assistance for TypedDict (PEP 692). You can download the latest version from our download page, or update your current version through our free Toolbox App. [banner] Key Features Gutter actions […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/06/pycharm-2024-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 EAP 4: Inline Rendering of Doc Comments and Tasks View</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another week, another Rider 2024.2 Early Access Program build! This EAP build is packed with highly anticipated features such as the Tasks view and inline rendering of documentation comments. Let’s have a look! Inline rendering of documentation comments Instead of a wall of text mixed with tags, inline rendering changes these comments into a more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/25/rider-2024-2-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Datalore 2024.3: Quality Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following a feature-rich 2024.2 release, we’ve focused on enhancing the quality and reliability of Datalore in our 2024.3 update. Datalore Community, Professional, and Team customers have already received the new update automatically, and Datalore Enterprise customers can upgrade by following these instructions. Enhanced file handling for scheduled runs We’ve added an option that lets you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/06/25/what-s-new-in-datalore-2024-3-quality-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bug Fixes for ReSharper 2024.1.4 and Rider 2024.1.4 Are Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 20:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new bug fixes for the 2024.1 release are available to download. ReSharper ReSharper 2024.1.4 fixes a couple of notable issues: You can find the full list of fixed issues here. Rider In addition to fixed issues from ReSharper, Rider 2024.1.4 delivers several important fixes of its own: For the full list of fixed issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/24/resharper-rider-2024-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All KotlinConf Recordings Are Now Available. Enjoy!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 11:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now find all of the session recordings from KotlinConf’24 on the conference website! Sessions are also being added to the Kotlin YouTube channel: Photos and slides from some of the sessions are also available – click on a talk and select “Download slides” for the latter. Don’t miss these additional materials from the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/06/kotlinconf24-recordings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.4 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 10:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.4 has arrived with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates included in v2024.1.4: To find out more details about the issues […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/intellij-idea-2024-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.1.5 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 10:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WebStorm 2024.1.5, the fifth update for WebStorm 2024.1, is now available! It contains several improvements from the platform. You can update to v2024.1.5 by using the Toolbox App, installing it right from the IDE, or downloading it from our website. Notable improvements Here are some of the notable updates included in v2024.1.5: That’s all for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/06/webstorm-2024-1-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 6: Streamlined Log Management, Enhanced Gradle Build Script Experience, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 06:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 6 is out! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 6 The latest build offers a streamlined user experience with Gradle build scripts, enhanced logging support for Java and Kotlin, and improvements to support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
