<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:39:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extending Qodana: Adding Custom Code Inspections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Qodana is a static code analysis tool that brings code inspections and quick-fixes from JetBrains IDEs to the realm of continuous integration. It can be run in the cloud, executed from a Docker container, integrated into CI/CD pipelines, or invoked through a JetBrains IDE. Qodana already offers an impressive suite of inspections, but it is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/02/extending-qodana-adding-custom-code-inspections/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – February 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            February is a strange little month. Short, quiet, and typically uneventful. There are fewer distractions and fewer launches, which makes it the ideal time to slow down and take a look at what is actually driving the tech world at the moment. This issue leans into that calm, with Trisha Gee joining us as our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/02/java-annotated-monthly-february-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced AI Management and Analytics for Organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re introducing the JetBrains Console, which provides enhanced AI management and analytics for organizations, including new capabilities to manage, observe, and control AI usage and costs across teams. AI is no longer an experiment for most development teams. It’s becoming part of the core toolchain. As usage increases, so does the need for clarity. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/02/enhanced-ai-management-and-analytics-for-organizations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wayland By Default in 2026.1 EAP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting from version 2026.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will run natively on Wayland in supported desktop configurations. This follows Wayland’s ascendance to the position of primary display server across contemporary Linux distributions. By making this change in our EAP releases first, we hope to be able to give more Linux users the opportunity to try the native […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/02/wayland-by-default-in-2026-1-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pick Your KotlinConf Workshop by What You Want to Learn</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi! Already coming to KotlinConf in Munich? Kick off the conference with a full day of hands-on workshops on May 20. Not going yet? Then this is a good moment to get your KotlinConf ticket and start with a workshop that matches what you want to learn. Asynchronous programming with Kotlin coroutines Learn how to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/02/pick-your-kotlinconf-workshop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
