<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 14:26:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – June Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 14:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month, we’ve gathered fun plugins and a course to help you build your own, as well as AI updates, exciting news for C++ learners and professional developers. Dive in!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/06/13/jetbrains-academy-june/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains GameDev Days 2025 – Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 09:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains GameDev Day is back! Join us online on October 21, 2025, for a day dedicated to all things game development. We’re looking for speakers who are eager to share their knowledge, experience, tools, or creative approaches across the gamedev community. What is GameDev Day? GameDev Day is a free, live, online event hosted by […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/13/jetbrains-gamedev-days-2025-call-for-speakers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Building an MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, June 24, at 10 am EDT / 4 pm CEST (check other timezones) for our free livestream, Live Coding: Building an MCP Server. In this livestream, we’ll team up with Max Kless, a senior engineer at Nx, to build a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server from scratch and seamlessly integrate it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/06/livestream-building-an-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs Go: Which one to choose in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The programming landscape continues to evolve, bringing forward languages like Rust and Go that not only challenge traditional paradigms but also cater to the sophisticated needs of modern computing. Both have carved significant niches for themselves, celebrated for their efficient handling of system-level operations and concurrency. Recent findings from the State of Developer Ecosystem Report […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/06/12/rust-vs-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.3: Important Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A third set of updates for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.3 introduces support for SQL &amp;amp; NoSQL query languages You can now edit and format SQL and NoSQL queries […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/12/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-3-important-updates-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run HTTP Requests in Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 08:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that our HTTP Client plugin is now available in Android Studio! HTTP Client is a powerful tool for making HTTP, gRPC, GraphQL, and WebSocket requests. Its text-based interface offers seamless integration with the editor, along with extensive coding assistance including highlighting, code completion, refactorings, and inline documentation. While it was […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/06/12/run-http-requests-in-android-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from Cursor to IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 07:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re a developer working with Cursor, exploring alternatives for your growing project, and are curious to see what IntelliJ IDEA has to offer, this article is for you. While Cursor emphasizes a minimalistic setup approach, IntelliJ IDEA strikes a balance between out-of-the-box functionality and powerful customization, enabling developers to effortlessly scale from small projects […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/migrate-cursor-to-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy JetBrains Mellum Your Way: Now Available via NVIDIA NIM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deploy Mellum as a production-grade LLM inside your own infrastructure – with NVIDIA. JetBrains Mellum – our open, focused LLM specialized on code completion – is now available to run as a containerized microservice on NVIDIA AI Factories. Using the new NVIDIA universal LLM NIM container, Mellum can be deployed in minutes on any NVIDIA-accelerated […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/06/deploy-jetbrains-mellum-your-way-now-available-via-nvidia-nim/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Python: Concurrency in async/await and threading</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have been coding with Python for a while, especially if you have been using frameworks and libraries such as Fast API and discord.py, then you have probably been using async/await or asyncio. You may have heard statements like “multithreading in Python isn’t real”, and you may also know about the famous (or infamous) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/06/concurrency-in-async-await-and-threading/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Blocks in Java: Perfect for Multiline Strings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve likely used String variables to store values that span multiple lines, such as LLM prompts, JSON, HTML, XML, code snippets, and other such values. Some of these, such as a JSON value, include double quotes as part of the data. Imagine the inconvenience of using backslashes () to escape those quotes, indenting lines using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/text-blocks-in-java-perfect-for-multiline-strings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin for Server-Side Development: Community Content Roundup #2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin community keeps delivering valuable content for server-side development. From gRPC best practices to hands-on Ktor tutorials and Spring integrations, here are the latest highlights. 📖 [Article] Kotlin Tips and Tricks You May Not Know: #6 — Inject Functions in Spring Boot – Elena van Engelen-Maslova shares how to inject functions in Spring Boot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/kotlin-for-server-side-development-community-content-roundup-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PhpStorm Helps Maintain PHP Open-Source Projects: Interviews and Real-World Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The PHP ecosystem is driven by passionate developers building tools that power everything from content management systems right the way through to testing libraries and database layers. Behind each project is a dedicated team working to modernize code, improve performance, and move the ecosystem forward. The fact that many of these teams choose PhpStorm to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/06/10/how-phpstorm-helps-maintain-php-open-source-projects-interviews-and-real-world-examples/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL and NoSQL Query langauge support come to ReSharper!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 08:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ReSharper’s query language support for SQL and NoSQL provides C# developers with a more convenient way to work with SQL and NoSQL code directly in Visual Studio with ReSharper, supporting multiple SQL dialects beyond just T-SQL. It includes syntax highlighting, code analysis, auto-completion, and quick fixes to boost efficiency and catch issues early. Based on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/10/sql-and-nosql-query-langauge-support-come-to-resharper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside Ruby Debuggers: TracePoint, Instruction Sequence, and CRuby API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 07:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Debugging is a key part of software development, but most developers use debuggers without knowing how they actually work. The RubyMine team has spent years developing debugging tools for Ruby, and we want to share some of the insights we’ve gained along the way. In this post, we’ll explore the main technologies […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/inside-ruby-debuggers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Penetration Testing? Types, Processes, Tools, And Why It’s All Worth It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 14:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Penetration testing (or “pen testing”) is an authorized, simulated cyberattack designed to test the security of a production system. Ethical hackers perform penetration tests, emulating the behavior of cybercriminals to evaluate your software’s security and identify any weaknesses. During a pen test, these cybersecurity specialists use a range of techniques to attack a system. Once […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/what-is-penetration-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 14:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi there, Java fans! It’s a new month, which means we’ve got a new batch of hot news, deep dives, and tasty tidbits from the Java world for you to enjoy. In this edition, Piotr Przybył joins us in the Featured Content section to share his cultivated list of content finds. We’re also testing a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/java-annotated-monthly-june-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
