<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:06:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Global Project Configuration: One Place to Manage All Your Qodana Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Global Project Configuration is a new feature that helps Qodana users manage linter settings across an entire organization or team – all from one location. Until now, maintaining consistent code quality rules meant updating configuration profiles in every individual repository. Whether you were approving new licenses, adjusting rule severity, or defining custom patterns for hardcoded […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2026/01/introducing-global-project-configuration-one-place-to-manage-all-your-qodana-rules/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights Into China’s Developer Landscape: Key Trends From the JetBrains Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every year, thousands of developers take part in the JetBrains Developer Ecosystem Survey, helping us map the evolving landscape of software development worldwide. Published in eight languages with data from 20 geographical regions, the survey includes China – a fast-evolving market that shares many global characteristics while retaining distinct traits of its own. For example, Java […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2026/01/insights-into-china-s-developer-landscape-key-trends/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.10.0: Unified @Preview, Navigation 3, and Stable Compose Hot Reload</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Multiplatform 1.10.0 has been released! We’re continually developing our multiplatform APIs and expanding support for Jetpack libraries commonly used on Android. Here are the highlights of this release: Get Started with Compose Multiplatform For a complete overview of the changes, check out What’s new in Compose Multiplatform 1.10.0 or the release notes on GitHub. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/compose-multiplatform-1-10-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to Compose Hot Reload 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Hot Reload has just been promoted to stable with our 1.0.0 release. We worked hard to build a technology that is easy to use and well-integrated into existing tools while also requiring zero configuration from users. The tool is bundled with Compose Multiplatform, starting from version 1.10 (see our dedicated release blog post). While […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/the-journey-to-compose-hot-reload-1-0-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2026.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re now working on our next major release, which we plan to deliver in March. In our latest stable version (v2025.3), we introduced many features and enhancements, so for the next release, we’ve decided to focus on maintenance and bug fixes rather than introducing new functionality. With that in mind, we’ve prioritized the following areas […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2026/01/2026-1-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 4: Delegation and Sub-Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 08:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously in this series: In the previous installment, we saw how to set up tracing, which brings us to two new questions: What should we experiment with based on the information this tool provides? And what parts of our agent could we improve using its observations? The first idea we had was to experiment with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/01/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-4-delegation-and-sub-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2025 in Kotlin: Puzzles, Prizes, and Community</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you to everyone who participated in Advent of Code 2025 in Kotlin! Once again, it was a joy to see so many of you sharing solutions, cheering each other on in Slack, and keeping the holiday coding spirit alive. This year, we kicked things off with five days of livestreams on December 1–5, with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/advent-of-code-2025-in-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Troubleshoot Builds With TeamCity Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Damaso Sanoja, draft.dev. If you’re spending your mornings debugging Jenkins pipeline failures, waiting for builds that should take minutes but stretch into hours, or scrambling to identify which plugin update broke your deployment process, you’re not alone. These daily troubleshooting battles with legacy CI/CD systems drain engineering time […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/how-to-troubleshoot-teamcity-builds-using-dashboards/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing Backwards With Go</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from John Arundel, a Go writer and teacher who runs a free email course for Go learners. His book The Power of Go: Tests is a love letter to test-driven development in Go. Have you ever tried programming backwards? If not, you’re in for a treat! You won’t even need […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2026/01/12/dancing-backwards-with-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Real Users Into a Product Team Gathering – A JetBrains Research Story</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In product development, assumptions about how people will use a tool don’t always align with the practical reality. Last spring, during a gathering of our Junie team, we set out to bridge that gap by trying something new. We ran two hands-on user workshops – one online and another in our Belgrade office. For the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2026/01/bringing-real-users-into-a-product-team-gathering-a-jetbrains-research-story/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
