<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 12:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sunsetting Writerside IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 12:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In October 2023, we launched the Early Access Program for Writerside – a tool for authoring, testing, and publishing documentation. Built on the IntelliJ Platform, Writerside was available in two versions: a standalone tool and a plugin for JetBrains IDEs. Our goal was to serve two key audiences – developers who document their work and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2025/03/sunsetting-writerside-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Essential Tools for JetBrains IDE Plugin Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for an insightful session on the top tools every plugin developer should know. IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Yann Cébron and Jakub Chrzanowski will walk you through essential utilities that streamline plugin development for JetBrains IDEs. During the webinar, you will discover how: No matter your level of experience, this webinar will equip you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/03/livestream-essential-tools-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-developmentlivestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Assistant Comes to Kotlin Developers in Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin developers can now enhance their workflows in Android Studio with the new JetBrains AI Assistant plugin, which is now available in Beta. This plugin offers AI-powered coding assistance, including code suggestions, AI-driven explanations, refactorings, commit message generation, and more – all within Android Studio. Backed by large language models (LLMs) from both JetBrains and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/ai-assistant-comes-to-kotlin-developers-in-android-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA’s Blog Feedback 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 10:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the years, the IntelliJ IDEA blog has become your go-to hub for expert insights, handy tips, and tech inspiration. But we want more – we’re heading to perfection, and we need your ideas to get there. Fill out this survey to let us know what rocks and what could be even better. It only […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-s-blog-feedback-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar – OSS Power-Ups: EntityFramework.Exceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 14:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Tuesday, March 18, 2025, 14:00 – 15:30 UTC (check other timezones) for our free live webinar, OSS PowerUps – EntityFramework.Exceptions, with Giorgi Dalakishvili. This is the fourtheenth episode of our series of OSS Power-Ups, where we put a spotlight on open-source .NET projects. Register now and get a reminder, or join on YouTube […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/03/07/webinar-oss-power-ups-entityframework-exceptions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.3 Bug Fix Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 09:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.3 bug-fix update is out and ready to be installed on your servers! This update resolves over 10 issues and, as always, includes essential security and performance fixes. We highly recommend upgrading to keep your system secure and optimized. The list of resolved issues includes: See TeamCity 2024.12.3 Upgrade Notes for the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/teamcity-2024-12-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are OWASP Top 10 Checks and How Can Your Team Benchmark Security?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 09:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_03_2025/07_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Businesses of different sizes have various motives for prioritizing code security. For an enterprise client, it might have to do with compliance. For a business that handles user data, there could be very imminent risk to customers and staff alike. Any development team could fall prey to the rise of cybercrime and attacks as detailed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/03/owasp-top-10/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Angular Language Server: Understanding IDE Integration Approaches</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 18:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Language Server Protocol (LSP) has been a fundamental part of the code editor landscape for years, providing a consistent development experience across different editors. The Angular Language Server leverages this protocol to provide Angular-specific features to compatible editors. However, not all IDEs take the same approach to delivering these capabilities. Let’s look at the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/03/the-angular-language-server-understanding-ide-integration-approaches/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 12:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this month’s Java Annotated Monthly! As always, we bring you the most interesting tutorials on Java, Kotlin, and other technologies, along with the latest news you don’t want to miss. We’re also excited to introduce a brand-new AI section, which we reserve for the most fascinating content on the topic. And this month, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/java-annotated-monthly-march-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try The New Toolbox App 2.6 EAP With Remote Development Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 10:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the latest update, the Toolbox App now supports remote development, allowing you to manage your JetBrains tools and projects both locally and on remote servers. This allows you to connect to cross-platform hosts, including Windows, macOS, and Linux, and use integrated OpenSSH for secure and customizable SSH connections. You can download the latest Toolbox […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/toolbox-app/2025/03/try-the-new-toolbox-app-2-6-eap-with-remote-development-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 17:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta is now available! This means we’re in the final stretch before the major release, and you can try out all the new features and improvements right now. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 13:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The [InternalsVisibleTo] attribute in .NET is a powerful feature that allows an assembly to expose its internal members (normally only accessible within the same assembly) to another specified assembly. This is typically used in scenarios like unit testing or multi-assembly projects where tight integration between assemblies is needed. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/03/05/dotinsights-march-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
