<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:51:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>C# Language Support in ReSharper and Rider 2025.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our release for ReSharper and Rider 2025.1 is just around the corner, and we have lots of exciting features shipping for the current and next version of C#! This will be a really long post (blame our awesome devs!), so make sure to use the table of contents on the right. Oh, and of course… […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/10/csharp-language-support-in-resharper-and-rider-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 – Help Shape the Future of Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since 2017, we’ve been checking in with developers around the world to better understand how the industry is evolving and how we can build better tools to support you. Now, the Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 is live, and we’d love for you to be part of it. This annual survey is a community milestone that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2025/04/10/developer-ecosystem-survey-2025-help-shape-the-future-of-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Context Parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Context parameters are an upcoming feature in Kotlin, with a variety of use cases including more powerful extension methods and better tools for DSL development. Kotlin 2.2.0 will feature context parameters in Beta, and dedicated IntelliJ IDEA support will be available from 2025.1. Context parameters replace another experimental feature in the language, namely context receivers. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/update-on-context-parameters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bug-Fix Releases Are Available – MPS 2024.3.2 and MPS 2024.1.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 11:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released updates for MPS 2024.1 and MPS 2024.3 that fix several additional issues. Check them out and see what you think. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3.2 Download MPS 2024.3.2 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Download MPS 2024.1.3 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/04/mps-2024-3-2-has-been-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown in Java Docs? Shut Up and Take My Comments!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 07:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you’re building a cutting-edge Java library, optimizing every method, and writing the most efficient algorithms. At some point, you’ll need to document your code because well-documented code increases adoption (a fact backed by various surveys). Including documentation comments within a Java class ensures that the documentation evolves with the code, keeping it relevant. Using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/markdown-in-java-docs-shut-up-and-take-my-comments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate is ready for you to try! The upcoming stable release delivers initial support for .NET 10 and C# 14 Preview features. It also brings the new Files view for repository-wide visibility, a Roslyn syntax tree visualizer, and numerous enhancements for debugging both .NET and C++ solutions. If you’re ready to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/rider-2025-1-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.1 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper and .NET tools 2025.1 RCs are now available. This ReSharper update delivers initial support for .NET 10 Preview and C# 14 features, along with expanded inspections, smarter refactorings, and noticeable performance improvements. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the next release, you can download the RC build from our website […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/resharper-2025-1-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 18:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Release Candidate is available for download, so we’re one step away from the major release! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. To use this build, an active subscription to IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate is required. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 RC […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/intellij-idea-2025-1-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Tools for JetBrains IDE Plugin Development: Livestream Recording and Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The recording of our livestream is available on JetBrains TV! In the recent session, IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Yann Cébron and Jakub Chrzanowski explored some of the most helpful tools for developing plugins for JetBrains IDEs. From plugin creation to UI debugging, the session covered practical tips and tricks to enhance your workflow. Let’s take […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/essential-tools-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-development-livestream-recording-and-key-takeaways/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Terminal: A New Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 13:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce our reworked terminal architecture, which is available in Beta starting with the 2025.1 versions of JetBrains IDEs. It now runs on a stable, standards-compliant core and uses the IDE’s editor for UI rendering. This change lets us introduce new features while preserving compatibility and performance across various platforms, whether local or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/jetbrains-terminal-a-new-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Golang Still Growing? Go Language Popularity Trends in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 15:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a fast-growing language with a wide range of applications, Go has become increasingly relevant to both new and existing developers. In this blog post, we will share our overview of the current state of Go, its position in the programming landscape, and the strategies for the future of Go. Following an analysis of its […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/04/is-golang-still-growing-go-language-popularity-trends-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Code Smarter, Not Harder: AI-Powered Dev Hacks for All</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 07:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_04_2025/07_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Dan Vega, where we’ll explore the Stream Gatherer API in JDK 24 and how to use it effectively in your applications. Date: April 17, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In today’s fast-paced software development landscape, AI has become a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/new-livestream-code-smarter-not-harder-ai-powered-dev-hacks-for-all/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Fuzz Testing to Kotlin with kotlinx.fuzz</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 13:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Identifying edge cases for testing can be a challenging task, often leaving hidden bugs and vulnerabilities undetected. Fuzz testing (fuzzing) addresses this challenge by automatically generating tests with random or invalid inputs, enabling developers to uncover unexpected exceptions and failure scenarios. Thanks to its effectiveness in detecting critical software flaws, fuzzing has gained widespread use […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/04/kotlinxfuzz-kotlin-fuzzing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – April 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 07:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the April edition of Java Annotated Monthly! Java 24 has landed, and we’ve got plenty to say about it. From fresh language features to smart tricks and must-try tutorials, there’s something for every curious developer. The cherry on top? Mala Gupta joins us as this month’s featured guest – don’t miss her insights! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/java-annotated-monthly-april-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Learning Comes to the JetBrains Academy Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 13:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learning to code can be challenging – but struggling to understand a task or unfamiliar concept shouldn’t be one of those challenges. That’s why we’ve introduced two new AI-powered features in the JetBrains Academy plugin to help you stay focused, confident, and in the flow: Machine Translation and Theory Lookup. Unlike generic AI coding features, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/03/jetbrains-academy-plugin-2025-3-ai-features/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Team City’s New Design, Phase 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 11:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity is introducing a batch of UX/UI improvements and more in its upcoming release. With the December release of TeamCity 2024.12, we updated the main navigation and breadcrumb trail. Now, we’re excited to introduce the Settings view and updated page headers, making managing your projects and builds easier. By observing how people use TeamCity and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/introducing-teamcitys-new-design-phase-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
