<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:02:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Better Way to Explore kotlinx-benchmark Results with Kotlin Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Benchmarking is an important part of writing efficient Kotlin code. The kotlinx-benchmark library helps you measure and compare performance across different implementations or hardware configurations. However, raw text results only take you so far. Sometimes you need to visualize your data, not just read it. That’s where Kotlin notebooks come in. Kotlin notebooks combine the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/a-better-way-to-explore-kotlinx-benchmark-results-with-kotlin-notebooks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy Plugin 2025.11 is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the holidays just around the corner and the year coming to a cheerful close, we’re ringing in the final JetBrains Academy plugin update of 2025, version 2025.11! This release focuses on the introduction of the standalone Hyperskill plugin, expands achievement-sharing to IDE-based courses, and brings a number of improvements and fixes to make your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/11/jetbrains-academy-plugin-2025-11-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider and ReSharper 2025.3.0.4: Important Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another set of updates for the 2025.3 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. Rider 2025.3.0.4 Multi-agent experience in the AI Chat window: Junie and Claude Agent Claude Agent has become the first third-party AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/11/rider-and-resharper-2025-3-0-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Laravel Support: A New Era for PhpStorm Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For years, PhpStorm has been the go-to IDE for PHP developers – powerful and deeply integrated with the language. But there was one thing many kept asking for: Laravel support out of the box. It should come with built-in — Amdadul Haq (@amdad121) July 30, 2025 Starting with PhpStorm 2025.3, Laravel support is now built […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/12/built-in-laravel-support-a-new-era-for-phpstorm-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue Center, All Reports Tab, Improved Report Sharing, the Ability to Change User Roles, and More in Datalore 2025.6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The final Datalore release of the year is here, and it brings multiple improvements designed to make your day-to-day work smoother. Whether you’re trying to keep reports error-free, managing user roles, or setting up environments, Datalore 2025.6 adds new tools that will help you stay organized and productive. Issue center The issue center is available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/12/10/datalore-2025-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Backups in Git Repositories, the Ability to Share Reports With Preselected Values, Mobile Layout for Reports, and More in Datalore 2025.5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.5 is out with multiple new features and improvements, including a new Git integration for workspace backups, the ability to share reports with preselected values in dropdowns, date pickers, and other inputs, and support for new LLMs in AI Assistant. These updates are already available for Datalore Cloud users, and Datalore On-Premises users can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/12/10/datalore-2025-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Architectural Update: Introducing the New Search Everywhere API (Built for Remote Development)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Search Everywhere dialog is one of the most important entry points in the IntelliJ Platform. To future-proof this core feature and ensure its optimal performance in remote development, we have completely rewritten the underlying architecture, and we’re introducing a brand-new API for plugin developers. This is a critical update for anyone contributing custom results […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/12/major-architectural-update-introducing-the-new-search-everywhere-api-built-for-remote-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the TeamCity Operator for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running TeamCity in Kubernetes has always been possible, but it often required knowing your way around both systems pretty well. TeamCity is flexible and easy to tune, and Kubernetes provides excellent tools for running applications at scale. However, bringing the two together smoothly wasn’t always straightforward. The new TeamCity Operator is designed to change that. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/teamcity-kubernetes-operator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sky’s the Limit: The Cloud9 × JetBrains Global Hackathon Is Live</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month, we announced that JetBrains is now the Official AI-Powered Coding Partner of Cloud9. The response from the community has been incredible, and today, we’re taking the next step in that journey. We’re excited to launch Sky’s the Limit, a global hackathon designed for developers, esports fans, analysts, and creators who want to push […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/09/sky-s-the-limit-the-cloud9-jetbrains-global-hackathon-is-live/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Joins the Agentic Artificial Intelligence Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is joining the new Agentic Artificial Intelligence Foundation (AAIF) hosted by the Linux Foundation. The AAIF brings together leading organizations contributing to the next generation of open agentic technologies. The foundation launches with several key open-source projects – including MCP, goose, and AGENTS.md – which already form an emerging ecosystem for shared standards and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/09/jetbrains-joins-the-agentic-artificial-intelligence-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Resource Leaks in Go: How GoLand Helps You Write Safer Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every Go application uses resources, such as files, network connections, HTTP responses, and database query results. But when a resource is left unclosed, it can cause a leak, which drains memory, exhausts system limits, introduces subtle bugs, and eventually brings even the most robust service to failure. Recently, we’ve introduced resource leak analysis in GoLand […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/12/09/preventing-resource-leaks-in-go-how-goland-helps-you-write-safer-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Your CI/CD Tool Helping or Hindering Performance?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every engineering leader would love to work with a team of elite performers who deploy 182x more frequently, recover from failures 2,293x faster, and achieve 127x faster lead times than low performers. (Yes, that’s the actual difference in performance of real teams from the 2024 DORA research report). But how do you improve your team’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/is-your-ci-cd-tool-helping-or-hindering-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperskill Gets Its Own Plugin Inside JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hyperskill is introducing its own free dedicated plugin inside JetBrains IDEs. This new plugin is built specifically for the Hyperskill learning experience and replaces the previous integration inside the JetBrains Academy plugin. Starting December 11, Hyperskill courses will be available exclusively through the new Hyperskill Academy plugin. The new Hyperskill Academy plugin provides a more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/09/hyperskill-gets-its-own-plugin-inside-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2025.3: Visualization Cells, Multi-Agent Support, Jupyter Improvements.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the 2025.3 release, DataSpell continues its mission to make data analysts more productive with the help of AI. In addition to improving DataSpell’s own AI agent, this release expands your options by introducing direct access to Claude Agent from the IDE – with more agents coming soon. DataSpell 2025.3 also includes major visualization workflow […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/12/dataspell-2025-3-visualization-cells-multi-agent-support-jupyter-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the RubyMine Team on Reddit AMA Session</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The RubyMine team will be stopping by r/jetbrains on December 11 from 1–5 pm CET and doing an Ask Me Anything (AMA) thread. You’re invited to join us! This isn’t a product launch or a marketing campaign – it’s a chance to have an open conversation about RubyMine and the challenges you face as a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/12/join-the-rubymine-team-on-reddit-ama-session/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2025.3 – Unified IDE, Jupyter notebooks in remote development, uv as default, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that PyCharm 2025.3 is here! This release continues our mission to make PyCharm the most powerful Python IDE for web, data, and AI/ML development. It marks the migration of Community users to the unified PyCharm and brings full support for Jupyter notebooks in remote development, uv as the default environment manager, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/12/pycharm-2025-3-unified-ide-jupyter-notebooks-in-remote-development-uv-as-default-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Fleet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Fleet started as our attempt to explore a new generation of JetBrains IDEs, developed in parallel with those based on the IntelliJ Platform. Over time, we learned that having two general-purpose IDE families created confusion and diluted our focus. Rebuilding the full capabilities of IntelliJ-based IDEs inside Fleet did not create enough value, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2025/12/the-future-of-fleet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.3 Is Now Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to PhpStorm 2025.3! This release brings native Claude Agent integration, out-of-the-box Laravel support, support for PHP 8.5, improvements in generics, a new Islands theme, and more. Download PhpStorm 2025.3 PHP PHP 8.5 support PhpStorm 2025.3 supports all of the changes introduced in the recently released PHP 8.5. As usual, you can try new features by setting […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/12/phpstorm-2025-3-is-now-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Made Simple: A Guide for JVM Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was written by an external contributor. Kubernetes is a container orchestration system for deploying, scaling, and managing containerized applications. If you build services on the Java virtual machine (JVM), you likely know that most microservices run on Kubernetes. Kubernetes has become the de facto standard for running containerized microservices at scale. However, Kubernetes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/kubernetes-made-simple-a-guide-for-jvm-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie Now Integrated Into the AI Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’re always listening closely to our users, ensuring that the products we ship provide a consistent and intuitive user experience. One area for improvement that we both noticed is the presence of two separate UIs – one for Junie, the coding agent by JetBrains, and one for the JetBrains AI chat. We’ve now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/junie-now-integrated-into-the-ai-chat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2025.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2025.3 brings a set of powerful upgrades designed to help you write cleaner and more efficient code. This release introduces on-the-fly resource leak detection, bundled Terraform support, smoother single-file editing, updates to golangci-lint integration, and performance boosts everywhere in the IDE. Early resource leak detection GoLand now helps you catch resource leaks – situations […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/12/08/goland-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.3 Is Here, and It’s Epic: Faster Language Engine, Unique Constexpr Debugger, DAP Support, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is one of our largest updates ever, featuring advanced capabilities and refinements to deliver a smoother workflow. CLion 2025.3 represents one of our most ambitious releases yet. Beyond the extensive feature additions and workflow improvements, this version marks a fundamental shift in how we approach C and C++ language support – prioritizing speed and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/12/2025-3-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2025.3: Multi-Agent AI Chat, Rails-Aware MCP Server, Faster Multi-Module Projects Startup, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2025.3 is out! This blog post briefly goes over the highlights of the latest release. For a detailed description, check out our What’s New page. You can get the new build from our website or via the free Toolbox App. AI Assistant Multi-agent experience: Junie and Claude Agent With the addition of Claude Agent, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/12/rubymine-2025-3-multi-agent-ai-chat-rails-aware-mcp-server-faster-multi-module-projects-startup-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Is Out Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 has arrived! This version brings significant updates designed to streamline your productivity and help you confidently adopt the latest innovations across the Java ecosystem. You can download this latest release from our website or update to it directly from inside the IDE, via the free Toolbox App, or using snap packages for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2025.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scala 3 Support Scala 3.8 introduces several significant changes, including a new into modifier, the standard library now being compiled with Scala 3, and the minimum required JDK version being updated to 17. Given that the next Scala version, 3.9 LTS, will focus on stabilization, it was important for us to support these new changes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2025/12/08/scala-plugin-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unified IntelliJ IDEA: More Free Features, a Better Experience, Smoother Flow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA is now a unified product! As we announced back in July, starting from this release (2025.3), there is one IntelliJ IDEA, replacing the separate IntelliJ IDEA Community Edition and IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate to keep things simple and convenient. All the functionality of the Community Edition remains free for non-commercial and commercial use. We’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-unified-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Islands Theme – The New Default Look for JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_24/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Islands theme is now the default look across JetBrains IDEs starting with version 2025.3.This update is more than a visual refresh. It’s our commitment to creating a soft, balanced environment designed to support focus and comfort throughout your workflow. We began introducing the new theme earlier this year, gathering feedback, conducting research, and testing it hands-on with developers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/12/meet-the-islands-theme-the-new-default-look-for-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring your own AI agent to JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey! Here at JetBrains, we’re always happy to bring our users the best and most popular tools available on the market. This has been true for decades with conventional dev tooling: compilers, debuggers, build tools, etc; in the past several years, we’ve shipped all the newest LLMs in the same manner, and we want the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/bring-your-own-ai-agent-to-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.3 Release Candidate Is Ready!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the last step on our way toward the final release, the Release Candidate for MPS 2025.3 is now available for you to download! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 RC 1 To find out what features to expect in this release, check out the earlier updates from the EAP 1 and EAP 2 builds. The full list […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/12/the-mps-2025-3-rc1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Manage Configuration Drift in Your Jenkins Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Rajkumar Venkatasamy, draft.dev. Jenkins is still one of the most popular tools for continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD). People love it for its flexibility, vast plugin ecosystem, and the fact that it’s open source. It can automate just about any build, test, or deployment you throw at it, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/jenkins-configuration-drift/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month brings significant developments throughout the Java ecosystem. Java has begun announcing JEPs targeted for the upcoming release, while Spring has unveiled major updates with Spring Framework 7 and Spring Boot 4. As always, we’ve curated the most interesting articles, videos, and podcasts covering Java, Kotlin, Spring, AI, and other relevant topics in technology […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/java-annotated-monthly-december-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
