<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 08:40:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Troubleshooting Spring Boot Applications with the Spring Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 08:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Marco Belher and explore how to uncover and fix Spring Boot bugs using the Spring Debugger in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: July 17, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Spring Boot hides a lot of complexity to help you build applications […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/new-livestream-troubleshooting-spring-boot-applications-with-the-spring-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 10:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the July edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This issue is packed with fresh articles, helpful tips, and ideas to keep you inspired and motivated in your work. We’re excited to feature Aicha Laafia, a Java engineer passionate about writing clean, green code and empowering women in tech. She’ll share how sustainable coding practices […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/java-annotated-monthly-july-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: A Carefully Curated June Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 13:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s time for another edition of Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup! If June flew by while you were deep in development, don’t worry – I’ve gathered all the ecosystem highlights for you in one handy digest. Here’s what you might have missed. Kotlin YouTube highlights That’s all for June! While you’re rewatching conference talks or experimenting with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/kodees-kotlin-roundup-june-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Why Kakao Pay Chose Kotlin for Backend Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 05:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is a JetBrains translation of the original post by katfun.joy, a backend developer at Kakao Pay. Kakao Pay leverages Kotlin with Spring for backend development across various services, including its insurance offerings. Check out Kakao Pay’s story to see how Kotlin helps it address the complex requirements of the insurance industry and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/case-study-why-kakao-pay-chose-kotlin-for-backend-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module Import Declarations: No More Import Hell</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you are proud of yourself for creating an amazing Java application, framework, or a library. You open one of its source files to make some changes and this is what you see: While looking at this long list of imports, are you wondering why you need to know the name of every single class […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/module-import-declarations-no-more-import-hell/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Remote Development Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 09:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The concept of remote development is deceptively simple: spin up your development environment somewhere that’s not your local machine. The perks range from freeing up local resources to not panicking when your laptop gets stolen. Yet, there are plenty of pitfalls, including flaky setups, poor visibility, and lousy monitoring. Let’s look at some best practices […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/07/10-remote-development-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
