<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 14:22:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #6: Introducing Self- Hosted Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 14:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want total control over your CI/CD pipeline? We’re introducing self-hosted agents in TeamCity Pipelines! Define your own build environments, manage your resources, and scale effortlessly. No more waiting in line for shared agents. You can now choose whether to run jobs on JetBrains-hosted agents or your own. You can also add various requirements for the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue6-self-hosted-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Introduction to Workspaces in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 06:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode, where we will explore how to take advantage of the new workspace functionality in your IntelliJ IDEA projects with Andrey Belyaev. Date: September 12, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract This session will provide a comprehensive overview of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains JavaScript Day 2024 Registration Is Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 15:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey everyone! JetBrains JavaScript Day is back for year four, and this edition promises to be our best one yet! Let’s face it, keeping up with the rapid changes in the JavaScript ecosystem is no easy task – it can be hard for us, too. That’s exactly why we created JetBrains JavaScript Day! This year, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/08/jetbrains-javascript-day-2024-registration-is-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track and Analyze GitHub Star Growth With  Kandy and Kotlin DataFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin DataFrame and Kandy are two powerful tools for data analysis in Kotlin. Kotlin DataFrame simplifies data manipulation and processing, while Kandy allows you to create visualizations directly within your Kotlin projects. In this post, we’ll show you how these tools can be used together within Kotlin Notebook to analyze the star history of GitHub […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/08/track-and-analyze-github-star-growth-with-kandy-and-kotlin-dataframe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Guide to Credit Risk Analysis With Python and Datalore AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog post by Ryan O’Connell, CFA, FRM. Understanding the relationships between various economic indicators is crucial for navigating the financial landscape. These relationships significantly impact the overall state of the economy, affecting businesses, investors, and individuals alike. We’ll analyze data spanning over two decades of financial history, leveraging the power of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/26/a-complete-guide-to-credit-risk-analysis-with-python-and-datalore-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspaces in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 09:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Better late than never! This idiom is probably the best way to describe the functionality we’ll introduce in this article, specifically, support for workspaces in IntelliJ IDEA. Intro In a nutshell, a workspace is a meta-project that allows you to manage multiple projects simultaneously. This feature is useful for various reasons, from coordinating complex development […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/workspaces-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fail-Fast Strategy: What Is It and How Does TeamCity Support It?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 09:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Cameron Pavey, draft.dev. Software development teams are always looking for ways to move faster and deliver more value in less time. However, one common pitfall for many teams is spending far too much time and effort building something, only to encounter major issues late in the project’s lifecycle. The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/fail-fast-strategy-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.0.20 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.0.20 release is out! This version includes performance improvements and bug fixes for Kotlin 2.0.0, where we announced the Kotlin K2 compiler as Stable. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.0.20 or the release notes on GitHub. How to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/08/kotlin-2-0-20-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Datalore 2024.4: Limit 500 Toggle, Easier Folder Import, Polars DataFrames Support, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2024/22_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2024.4 introduces quality-of-life improvements for SQL cells, a revamped folder import workflow, support for Polars DataFrames, and more. Datalore Cloud customers have already received the new update automatically, and Datalore On-Premises customers can upgrade by following these instructions. Limit 500 toggle for SQL cells To help you prototype SQL queries faster, we’ve introduced a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/22/what-s-new-in-datalore-2024-4-limit-500-toggle-easier-folder-import-polars-dataframes-support-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper Tips &amp; Tricks with Matt Ellis – Livestream</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 13:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on September 12, 2024, at 2:00 PM UTC for another JetBrains livestream event. You can register for the event using the link below or subscribe to our YouTube channel, JetBrainsTV, to get a notification closer to the event. With over 20 years of ReSharper setting the standard for the .NET development experience, it’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/21/resharper-tips-tricks-with-matt-ellis-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Chatbots With LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 10:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2024/21_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Dido Grigorov, a deep learning engineer and Python programmer with 17 years of experience in the field. Chatbots have evolved far beyond simple question-and-answer tools. With the power of large language models (LLMs), they can understand the context of conversations and generate human-like responses, making them invaluable for customer […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/how-to-build-chatbots-with-langchain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.39 Is Out With Smart Mode for Single Files, the Ability to Compare Files, the Structure Tool Window, Automatic Language Detection for Untitled Files, and Other Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 14:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.39 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.39 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/08/fleet-1-39-is-out-with-smart-mode-for-single-files-the-ability-to-compare-files-the-structure-tool-window-automatic-language-detection-for-untitled-files-and-other-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Datalore Cloud Plans – What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 13:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Datalore has evolved over the years, we’ve added more and more pricing tiers to cater to different users in the cloud. The variety of tiers sometimes made choosing a plan complicated. Now, we’ve decided to revamp our subscription plans to simplify the process of finding the option that best fits your needs. You no […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/08/20/new-datalore-cloud-plans-what-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Learned From the Perforce 2024 State of Game Technology Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 11:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The gaming industry has long been a hotbed of innovation, with developers consistently pushing the boundaries of what’s possible. But as we progress into 2024, it’s clear that game technology’s sphere of influence is expanding far beyond the realm of gaming. Technological advancements coming out of the game industry are quickly adopted by various other […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/perforce-2024-game-tech-report/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
