<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:06:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meet JetBrains at Azure Dev Summit 2025 (Lisbon, Oct 13–16)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains will be at Azure Dev Summit 2025 in Lisbon, and we’d love to connect with attendees interested in learning more about our products and services. My name is Max Solovyev, and I’m the Head of Growth at .NET and GameDev Tools – I’ll be on site and available throughout the event for brief, no-pressure […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/07/meet-jetbrains-at-azure-dev-summit-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Now Supports DAP Debuggers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest EAP build of CLion 2025.3, released yesterday, includes support for the Debug Adapter Protocol (DAP), which allows CLion to communicate with a variety of additional debuggers. Besides the bundled LLDB and GDB, you can now work with third-party implementations that support DAP. This feature brings CLion closer to becoming an IDE that is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/10/dap-debuggers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Nova Will Become the Default Engine for All Users in v2025.3 – Here’s What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion Nova became the default language engine for new users starting with v2024.2. Since then, we’ve delivered the features users wanted most and addressed key bugs. We’ve also received very positive feedback from people and organizations who have tried the new engine and compared it with the legacy one, CLion Classic. All of this has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/10/nova-default-for-all/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains × Zed: Open Interoperability for AI Coding Agents in Your IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, our mission is simple: help developers achieve engineering excellence without distractions or vendor lock-in. Today, we’re excited to share that we’re collaborating with Zed on the Agent Client Protocol (ACP) – an open protocol that lets AI coding agents work inside editors, including JetBrains IDEs, if both are ACP-compatible. Why this collaboration matters […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/10/jetbrains-zed-open-interoperability-for-ai-coding-agents-in-your-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 ReSharper Features Every .NET Developer Should Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Around 15 years ago, I got my first assistant job at a university department. Frankly, I only used ReSharper for its solution-wide analysis, which would alert me whenever I broke the spaghetti code I got served. I did not know about all the refactorings yet. It was only at my second job that my awesome […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/06/9-resharper-features-every-dotnet-developer-should-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of CI/CD in 2025: Key Insights from the Latest JetBrains Survey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The CI/CD tools market has become increasingly complex over the past few years. DevOps engineers now have to manage a wide range of tools, all with their own complex setups and features. JetBrains’ TeamCity and Research departments came together to produce a joint survey looking into the CI/CD tool market in 2025. To gain […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/10/the-state-of-cicd/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The yield return keyword allows you to pause and resume execution of a method, enabling lazy evaluation without generating intermediate collections. This makes writing custom iterators simple and efficient. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 📆 Just two more days […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/06/dotinsights-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.2.3: The Third Set of Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A third set of updates for the 2025.2 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.2.3 comes with the following fixes: For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/06/resharper-and-rider-2025-2-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to Java Annotated Monthly! Wow, September really flew by! We’ve gathered all the top Java news and insights to help you catch up on anything you missed. First up, we’re diving headfirst into a big splash around Java 25 and all the updates it brings along. Then, as always, you’ll find plenty of tech […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/10/java-annotated-monthly-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update, October 2025 – Compose Hot Reload and UX Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.8.0 is out, with Compose Hot Reload, a customizable Kotlin compiler version, new JavaScript and Wasm platforms, and many other improvements to both the IDE and CLI experience. Read on for all of the details, and see the release notes for the full list of changes and bug fixes. To get support for Amper’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/10/amper-update-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 – v2025.2.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/10/intellij-idea-2025-2-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog × A2A: Building Connected AI Agents in Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever tried building a system of multiple AI agents, you’ve probably run into the problem. It starts simple enough: You’ve got one agent writing blog posts, another proofreading them, and maybe a third suggesting or generating images. Individually, they’re effective. But getting them to work together? That’s where things might start falling apart. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/10/koog-a2a-building-connected-ai-agents-in-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Visual Studio 2026: Day-One Compatibility, Migration Steps, and Performance Gains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here, and the next major VS update is on the horizon. As with any new Visual Studio version, one of the first questions developers ask is: “Will my extensions work after updating – especially ReSharper?”. The short answer is a resounding “yes”. But there’s more to the story, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/02/resharper-and-visual-studio-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving PHP open source forward</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we want the PHP community to shine. First and foremost, we do this by building PhpStorm, the best IDE for PHP development; but we also support and help drive the PHP Foundation; have just organised PHPverse, accessible for everyone worldwide; and recently we made the Laravel Idea plugin free for all. On top […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/10/moving-php-open-source-forward/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a change in our licensing model that we believe will benefit the developer community – DataGrip is now free for non-commercial use! With this change, DataGrip joins JetBrains RustRover, CLion, Rider, WebStorm, and RubyMine, which are already free for non-commercial use. Read on to learn more about the change and why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/10/01/datagrip-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
