<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:59:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Fleet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Fleet started as our attempt to explore a new generation of JetBrains IDEs, developed in parallel with those based on the IntelliJ Platform. Over time, we learned that having two general-purpose IDE families created confusion and diluted our focus. Rebuilding the full capabilities of IntelliJ-based IDEs inside Fleet did not create enough value, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2025/12/the-future-of-fleet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.3 Is Now Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to PhpStorm 2025.3! This release brings native Claude Agent integration, out-of-the-box Laravel support, support for PHP 8.5, improvements in generics, a new Islands theme, and more. Download PhpStorm 2025.3 PHP PHP 8.5 support PhpStorm 2025.3 supports all of the changes introduced in the recently released PHP 8.5. As usual, you can try new features by setting […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/12/phpstorm-2025-3-is-now-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Made Simple: A Guide for JVM Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was written by an external contributor. Kubernetes is a container orchestration system for deploying, scaling, and managing containerized applications. If you build services on the Java virtual machine (JVM), you likely know that most microservices run on Kubernetes. Kubernetes has become the de facto standard for running containerized microservices at scale. However, Kubernetes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/kubernetes-made-simple-a-guide-for-jvm-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie Now Integrated Into the AI Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’re always listening closely to our users, ensuring that the products we ship provide a consistent and intuitive user experience. One area for improvement that we both noticed is the presence of two separate UIs – one for Junie, the coding agent by JetBrains, and one for the JetBrains AI chat. We’ve now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/junie-now-integrated-into-the-ai-chat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2025.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2025.3 brings a set of powerful upgrades designed to help you write cleaner and more efficient code. This release introduces on-the-fly resource leak detection, bundled Terraform support, smoother single-file editing, updates to golangci-lint integration, and performance boosts everywhere in the IDE. Early resource leak detection GoLand now helps you catch resource leaks – situations […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/12/08/goland-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.3 Is Here, and It’s Epic: Faster Language Engine, Unique Constexpr Debugger, DAP Support, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is one of our largest updates ever, featuring advanced capabilities and refinements to deliver a smoother workflow. CLion 2025.3 represents one of our most ambitious releases yet. Beyond the extensive feature additions and workflow improvements, this version marks a fundamental shift in how we approach C and C++ language support – prioritizing speed and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/12/2025-3-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2025.3: Multi-Agent AI Chat, Rails-Aware MCP Server, Faster Multi-Module Projects Startup, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2025.3 is out! This blog post briefly goes over the highlights of the latest release. For a detailed description, check out our What’s New page. You can get the new build from our website or via the free Toolbox App. AI Assistant Multi-agent experience: Junie and Claude Agent With the addition of Claude Agent, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/12/rubymine-2025-3-multi-agent-ai-chat-rails-aware-mcp-server-faster-multi-module-projects-startup-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Is Out Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 has arrived! This version brings significant updates designed to streamline your productivity and help you confidently adopt the latest innovations across the Java ecosystem. You can download this latest release from our website or update to it directly from inside the IDE, via the free Toolbox App, or using snap packages for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2025.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scala 3 Support Scala 3.8 introduces several significant changes, including a new into modifier, the standard library now being compiled with Scala 3, and the minimum required JDK version being updated to 17. Given that the next Scala version, 3.9 LTS, will focus on stabilization, it was important for us to support these new changes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2025/12/08/scala-plugin-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unified IntelliJ IDEA: More Free Features, a Better Experience, Smoother Flow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA is now a unified product! As we announced back in July, starting from this release (2025.3), there is one IntelliJ IDEA, replacing the separate IntelliJ IDEA Community Edition and IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate to keep things simple and convenient. All the functionality of the Community Edition remains free for non-commercial and commercial use. We’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-unified-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Islands Theme – The New Default Look for JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Islands theme is now the default look across JetBrains IDEs starting with version 2025.3.This update is more than a visual refresh. It’s our commitment to creating a soft, balanced environment designed to support focus and comfort throughout your workflow. We began introducing the new theme earlier this year, gathering feedback, conducting research, and testing it hands-on with developers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/12/meet-the-islands-theme-the-new-default-look-for-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Fixed in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the overview of fixes and improvements in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3. In this release, we have resolved over 800 bug reports and usability issues throughout the IDE, with the highlights including improvements to the developer experience, Spring support, build tools, version control, the terminal, and more. Below are the most impactful changes that will […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/what-s-fixed-in-intellij-idea-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring your own AI agent to JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey! Here at JetBrains, we’re always happy to bring our users the best and most popular tools available on the market. This has been true for decades with conventional dev tooling: compilers, debuggers, build tools, etc; in the past several years, we’ve shipped all the newest LLMs in the same manner, and we want the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/bring-your-own-ai-agent-to-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.3 Release Candidate Is Ready!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the last step on our way toward the final release, the Release Candidate for MPS 2025.3 is now available for you to download! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 RC 1 To find out what features to expect in this release, check out the earlier updates from the EAP 1 and EAP 2 builds. The full list […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/12/the-mps-2025-3-rc1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Manage Configuration Drift in Your Jenkins Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Rajkumar Venkatasamy, draft.dev. Jenkins is still one of the most popular tools for continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD). People love it for its flexibility, vast plugin ecosystem, and the fact that it’s open source. It can automate just about any build, test, or deployment you throw at it, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/jenkins-configuration-drift/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month brings significant developments throughout the Java ecosystem. Java has begun announcing JEPs targeted for the upcoming release, while Spring has unveiled major updates with Spring Framework 7 and Spring Boot 4. As always, we’ve curated the most interesting articles, videos, and podcasts covering Java, Kotlin, Spring, AI, and other relevant topics in technology […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/java-annotated-monthly-december-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Deprecation of K1 Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the next step in the evolution of K2 mode, with the IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 release we are officially deprecating its predecessor, K1 mode. In this post, we’ll give some background about K2 mode and discuss its current state, including adoption numbers, performance test results, and feature parity and stability. As always, we recommend updating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/the-deprecation-of-k1-mode/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Us Anything During JetBrains AMA Week</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains will be hosting a series of open Ask Me Anything (AMA) sessions on Reddit December 9–12. On scheduled days, our product teams will join r/jetbrains to talk directly with developers who use our tools every day. We’ll be there for honest conversations about what’s working, what’s not, and where your priorities lie. Your feedback […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/03/ask-us-anything-during-jetbrains-ama-week/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Stories Of Developers Using JetBrains Rider to Create, Collaborate, and Have Fun</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago, we introduced a free non-commercial use license option for JetBrains Rider, hoping to remove barriers for developers who code with no financial objective in mind for their projects. Recently, we put out a call for your stories – curious to learn how you’ve been using Rider throughout this year. What came back […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/03/5-stories-of-developers-using-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grok Models Come to the AI Chat in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re expanding our AI offering with xAI’s Grok family of LLMs: Grok 4, Grok 4.1 Fast, Grok 4.1 Fast (Non-Reasoning), and Grok Code Fast 1. With the addition of these models in the AI chat across all JetBrains IDEs, you now have even more flexibility to choose the model that best fits your workflow. How […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/grok-models-come-to-the-ai-chat-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip 2025.3: Migration From Consoles to Query Files, Connection to Cloud Providers, Introspection Levels for Amazon Redshift, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2025.3, the final major update of the year, is here! Let’s take a look at what it has to offer. Download DataGrip 2025.3 Migration from query consoles to query files Previously, when referring to the SQL files that are attached to a data source by default, we used the term query console, and their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/02/datagrip-2025-3-migration-from-consoles-to-query-files-connection-to-cloud-providers-introspection-levels-for-amazon-redshift-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? Calling GC.Collect() explicitly forces the garbage collector to run and reclaim memory from unreachable objects. However, it’s generally discouraged to use this method in most applications because the garbage collector is highly optimized to run automatically. Forcing it can lead to performance issues by interrupting the normal optimization process. Welcome to dotInsights […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/02/dotinsights-december-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Achieve Significant Build Performance Gains With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is brought to you by Mdu Sibisi, draft.dev. Long build times interfere with developer momentum, disrupt flow states, and negatively impact productivity. While seemingly minor gaps in work rate may appear negligible in the moment, they quickly accumulate into significant increases in release cycle times and infrastructure costs. (There’s a reason high-performance development […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/build-performance-gains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Engineers Talk About Spring Boot 4, Life, and Other Stuff</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us as we welcome the Spring team and Evgeny Borisov for a new IntelliJ IDEA livestream, where we’ll discuss what’s new in Spring Boot 4 and how all the new updates work in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: December 11, 2025 Time: 4:00–5:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this livestream, we’ll explore […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/new-livestream-engineers-talk-about-spring-boot-4-life-and-other-stuff/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Through the Noise: Smarter Context Management for LLM-Powered Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you’re working on a project and jotting down every single idea, experiment, and failure. After a while, your notes pile up so high that finding what’s useful takes more time and energy than the work itself. A similar problem faces users of software engineering (SE) agents: the agents “take notes” on every generated output, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/12/efficient-context-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
