<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 17:05:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The First Set of Bug Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2024.1 Are Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 17:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, The ReSharper and Rider 2024.1.1 bug-fix updates have just been released! If you haven’t upgraded to the 2024.1 versions of our products, we highly recommend that you check out these two blog posts: And now, let’s go over the most important fixes in 2024.1.1. ReSharper 2024.1.1 The first bug-fix update fixes the issue […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/04/17/the-first-set-of-bug-fixes-for-resharper-and-rider-2024-1-are-here/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.1.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:49:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WebStorm 2024.1.1, the first update for WebStorm 2024.1, is now available! It contains fixes for two major issues that unfortunately made it into the latest release. We are sincerely sorry for this and have tried our best to rectify the situation quickly. These issues have highlighted problems in our own internal communication and QA process […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/04/webstorm-2024-1-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Code Quality in JavaScript Projects With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 13:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s no doubt that code quality plays an important role in any team’s output. Whether you’re weeding out critical issues, improving your skills, or simply establishing standards as a team, it’s paramount to be on the same page when it comes to defining and executing high-quality projects. Having the right tools along the way can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/04/improving-code-quality-in-javascript-projects-with-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Hacks: How to Handle Exceptions in Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 11:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously, we explored how to throw exceptions in Java to signal error conditions in our code. But throwing exceptions is only half the story. To build robust and reliable applications, we also need to know how to handle them effectively. In this post, we’ll explore how you can handle exceptions in Java, and we’ll also […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/04/easy-hacks-how-to-handle-exceptions-in-java/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: 10 Strategies for Launching Students Into the Software Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 07:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Academy has started a series of livestreams crafted especially for teachers and educators. Join us on Tuesday, April 23, at 4:00 pm UTC for the first livestream of the series with our Developer Advocate, Garth Gilmour. He’ll discuss how to ensure students are well-equipped for success in the real world of the tech industry. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/04/17/10-strategies-for-launching-students-into-the-software-industry/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Collections &amp; DataTables</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 12:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Rider 2024.1, we’re shipping a highly requested feature: collection visualizers. Our very own Evgeny Terekhin has taken on the task of integrating DataGrip’s infrastructure to visualize data in the debugger. This makes it easier for .NET developers to inspect collections like List and Dictionary&amp;lt;TKey, TValue, as well as data-oriented objects such as DataSet, DataTable, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/04/15/exploring-collections-and-datatables/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Java 22 and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 07:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2024/15_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Mala Gupta to explore how IntelliJ IDEA accelerates the adoption of Java 22 features. Date: April 24, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Get ready to use the new and updated features in Java 22 with IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1. Knowing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/04/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
