<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 13:41:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD and Serverless Computing: Best Practices for Microservices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 13:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Mdu Sibisi, freelance writer, draft.dev. Cloud technology has reshaped how developers manage and deliver software. For example, “serverless computing” allows a provider to dynamically manage the allocation and provisioning of servers for you, which makes it ideal for running microservices. When paired with CI/CD practices, serverless computing can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/ci-cd-and-serverless-computing-best-practices-for-microservices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Better Developer Experience: A Collaboration Between Gradle, Google, and JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The original blog post was published here. Developers are at the heart of everything we do. You are the ones who create all of those new things to make the world better. To do that effectively, you need tools to rely on that are powerful yet easy to use. That’s why Kotlin was created. But […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/building-a-better-developer-experience-a-collaboration-between-gradle-google-and-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 24: Build Games, Prototypes, Utilities, and More—With Less Boilerplate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At ten, I sat in my school’s computer lab, in awe of a line drawing on the screen—my own code had brought it to life. “Yay! I coded that! I can code anything!”, I thought. My teacher, surprised, asked, “Wow! You did that?” It felt like magic, but it was more than that—I realized I […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/java-24-build-games-prototypes-utilities-and-more-with-less-boilerplate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines: SSH Authentication Option, Custom Git URL Support, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 11:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve been busy improving TeamCity Pipelines to make your CI/CD workflows even smoother. Here’s a quick update on what’s new! SSH authentication option Exciting news – we’re expanding the list of authentication options in TeamCity Pipelines! Now, you can easily authenticate using SSH. Once you set up SSH keys, you can push and pull without […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/teamcity-pipelines-ssh-authentication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 EAP 5: Roslyn Syntax Tree Visualizer, Unity Profiler Integration, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 17:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Rider 2025.1 EAP 5 has just been released! You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Here’s what you can expect from this update: Roslyn support enhancements Roslyn syntax tree visualizer Working with Roslyn […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/24/rider-2025-1-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science and AI BSc Open Day in Cyprus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 13:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos is opening its doors! Join us for our Open Day, where you will have the opportunity to meet the program’s professors and students and visit the campus. The JetBrains Foundation supports this bachelor’s program and offers 15 fully funded scholarships for the most […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/02/24/computer-science-and-ai-bsc-open-day-in-cyprus/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 6: Interactive Scratch Files in K2 Mode, Enhanced Dependency Resolution in Kotlin Script Files, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 07:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 6 is here! As we continue shaping the first major release of the year, you can get an early look at what’s coming by trying out the latest EAP build. You can download it from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: Intro, Dependencies, and First Integration Test</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 15:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following the enthusiastic response to our Plugin Testing: Performance, UI, and Functional Testing session at JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024, we’re launching a series of blog posts diving deeper into plugin testing strategies. This first post will guide you through setting up your testing environment and creating your first integration test, with detailed step-by-step instructions. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/02/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-intro-dependencies-and-first-integration-test/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doc-Powered AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 14:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with the 2024.3 version of JetBrains IDEs, AI Assistant can not only access the context from your project but also the IDE’s own documentation. Whenever you have a question about how to accomplish a task in a JetBrains IDE, such as WebStorm, IntelliJ IDEA, or PyCharm, AI Assistant is here to help. How do […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/doc-powered-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
