<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 15:09:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Python Developer Advocate – Will Vincent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 15:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, I’m a new Python Developer Advocate, focusing especially on web development. If you have any questions or want to share ideas around JetBrains products, most notably PyCharm, say hi at william.vincent@jetbrains.com. Background I’m a former Django Board Member and the author of three books on Django. Since 2019, I’ve co-hosted the Django Chat podcast […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/python-developer-advocate-will-vincent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3: Kotlin K2 Mode Updates, Enhanced Logical Code Structure View, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Early Access Program is in full swing, and build #3 is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3 We’re covering all of the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains and LinkedIn Partner to Launch a Professional Certificate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 17:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has partnered with LinkedIn to offer the Java Foundations Professional Certificate, exclusively available on LinkedIn Learning. With over 1 billion members on the platform and 7 people hired every minute, LinkedIn provides unmatched access to professional growth opportunities. Together, with our expertise in software development and education, we’re combining the best of both worlds: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2025/01/29/jetbrains-and-linkedin-partner-to-launch-a-professional-certificate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 Tips for Productive Java Development With Databases in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 15:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll share nine time-saving ways IntelliJ IDEA can boost your productivity when developing Java applications with databases – whether you’re starting a new project or diving into an ongoing one. Get IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate Create data sources automatically from properties IntelliJ IDEA makes it easy to create a data source for your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/tips-for-productive-java-development-with-databases-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack 2025 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our commitment to you We remain fully committed, as we have been all these years, to developing YouTrack as a platform that evolves with your needs. Our promise to you is to ensure that YouTrack continues to be available in both Server and Cloud versions, giving you the freedom to choose the hosting option that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/01/youtrack-2025-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JITWatch4i: Analyzing IntelliJ IDEA’s Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 11:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction A typical Java or Kotlin programmer spends most of their productive time either creating application code in an editor or searching for bugs in a debugger. Occasionally, they might dive into a profiler when looking for places where the application spends too much time. However, they almost never venture into the Java C1 or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/01/jitwatch4i-analyzing-intellij-idea-s-startup/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 11:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the January edition of PHP Annotated! This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise, we’ve done it for you. Highlights PHP 8.4 PHP 8.4 was officially released on November 21, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/01/php-annotated-january-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Django Views</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 10:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Views are central to Django’s architecture pattern, and having a solid grasp of how to work with them is essential for any developer working with the framework. If you’re new to developing web apps with Django or just need a refresher on views, we’ve got you covered. Gaining a better understanding of views will help […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/django-views/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curious About The State of Software Quality?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 13:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first edition of the JetBrains Qodana Software Quality Report which looks at key findings from 2024. We decided to conduct this research to gain a deeper understanding of best practices for delivering quality software today, and how companies of different sizes and maturity levels determine when their product is production-ready. To […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/01/state-of-software-quality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.3.2: uv Package Management Support and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 10:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.3.2 is here with uv package management support, flame graph visualization, and other improvements! Get the latest version from our download page or update through our free Toolbox App. Read this blog post to learn more about new features. Support for uv package management Take your environment management to the next level with uv […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/pycharm-2024-3-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin for Server-Side Content Creators</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2025/27_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 15:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2025/27_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            More and more developers are using Kotlin for server-side development, building reliable and efficient backend systems. Many of them also share their experiences through articles, videos, and sample projects. If you’re one of these creators, we want to recognize your work! Sharing your knowledge helps others solve real problems, improve their skills, and discover better […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/01/kotlin-for-server-side-content-creators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream alret: Programming Prep Guide for the CSAI Entrance Test</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2025/27_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 14:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2025/27_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want to study computer science in Europe? Enroll in the Computer Science and AI bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos. Exclusive JetBrains scholarships are up for grabs! Join us on February 11, at 4:00 pm UTC, for a special preparation session to help you ace the entrance test for this program. You’ll get first-hand tips […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/01/27/livestream-alret-programming-prep-guide-for-the-csai-entrance-test/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.45 Is Here With Auto-Import for Gradle, Improved Preview for Markdown, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2025/27_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 11:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2025/27_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using our Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.45 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2025/01/fleet-1-45-is-here-with-auto-import-for-gradle-improved-preview-for-markdown-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: Top Courses and Projects of 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 08:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2025/24_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This International Day of Education, we’re celebrating that in 2024 over 340,000 new coders joined JetBrains Academy, making our community almost 1.5 million members strong. To mark this impressive milestone, we’re looking back at the most popular JetBrains Academy offerings of 2024 – including JetBrains IDE courses (designed exclusively for IDEs) and Hyperskill projects (available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/01/24/jetbrains-academy-top-courses-and-projects-of-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Is Now Available on AWS Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 22:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity is officially listed on AWS Marketplace! This milestone makes it even easier for teams to integrate the power of TeamCity into their CI/CD pipelines while leveraging the scalability and flexibility of Amazon Web Services (AWS). TeamCity interface Whether you’re already an AWS user or exploring AWS for your next project, TeamCity on AWS Marketplace […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/01/teamcity-is-now-available-on-aws-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Junie, Your Coding Agent by JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 13:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we aim to enable and scale the next generation of technologies to make software development a more productive and enjoyable experience. To empower and support developers, we build a variety of products for professional development, including powerful AI tools and features that have already enhanced productivity and opened new horizons for creativity. But […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/junie/2025/01/meet-junie-your-coding-agent-by-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and Rider 2024.3.4 Bug-Fix Updates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download. ReSharper 2024.3.4 For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our issue tracker. Rider 2024.3.4 We’ve also fixed several issues affecting .NET MAUI development: For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/23/resharper-and-rider-2024-3-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
