<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:39:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extending Qodana: Adding Custom Code Inspections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Qodana is a static code analysis tool that brings code inspections and quick-fixes from JetBrains IDEs to the realm of continuous integration. It can be run in the cloud, executed from a Docker container, integrated into CI/CD pipelines, or invoked through a JetBrains IDE. Qodana already offers an impressive suite of inspections, but it is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/02/extending-qodana-adding-custom-code-inspections/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – February 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            February is a strange little month. Short, quiet, and typically uneventful. There are fewer distractions and fewer launches, which makes it the ideal time to slow down and take a look at what is actually driving the tech world at the moment. This issue leans into that calm, with Trisha Gee joining us as our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/02/java-annotated-monthly-february-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced AI Management and Analytics for Organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re introducing the JetBrains Console, which provides enhanced AI management and analytics for organizations, including new capabilities to manage, observe, and control AI usage and costs across teams. AI is no longer an experiment for most development teams. It’s becoming part of the core toolchain. As usage increases, so does the need for clarity. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/02/enhanced-ai-management-and-analytics-for-organizations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wayland By Default in 2026.1 EAP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting from version 2026.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will run natively on Wayland in supported desktop configurations. This follows Wayland’s ascendance to the position of primary display server across contemporary Linux distributions. By making this change in our EAP releases first, we hope to be able to give more Linux users the opportunity to try the native […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/02/wayland-by-default-in-2026-1-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pick Your KotlinConf Workshop by What You Want to Learn</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi! Already coming to KotlinConf in Munich? Kick off the conference with a full day of hands-on workshops on May 20. Not going yet? Then this is a good moment to get your KotlinConf ticket and start with a workshop that matches what you want to learn. Asynchronous programming with Kotlin coroutines Learn how to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/02/pick-your-kotlinconf-workshop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Kotlin Ecosystem Mentorship Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: The Kotlin Foundation is launching a mentorship program that pairs experienced open-source maintainers with new Kotlin contributors to help them make their first meaningful contributions, with branded swag and a chance to win a trip to KotlinConf. I still remember my first contribution to an open-source library. It was Typhoon, a widely popular dependency […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/02/kotlin-ecosystem-mentorship/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog x ACP: Connect an Agent to Your IDE and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We hope you’re staying up to date with our latest posts and have checked out our tutorials on how to create coding agents in Koog and connect ACP-compliant agents to your JetBrains IDE. As useful as these guides are, one important piece was hitherto missing from the puzzle: How do you make your Koog agent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/02/koog-x-acp-connect-an-agent-to-your-ide-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana for Android: Increasing Code Quality for Kotlin-First Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When people think about tooling for Android development, the conversation often gravitates towards platform-specific concerns: UI performance, layout validation, device compatibility, or resource management. Yet for many Android teams, the most persistent challenges don’t sit at the platform level – they’re in the team’s Kotlin codebase itself. As Android projects scale, Kotlin brings strong language […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2026/01/qodana-for-android-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q4 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your quarterly dose of plugin dev news, tools, and tips from JetBrains. 🧩 Marketplace Updates Integration Tests Now Part of Automated Moderation Integration test results are now displayed directly on the plugin page, alongside Plugin Verifier results on the Versions tab. These tests help ensure that a plugin version works smoothly in the IDE and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/01/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q4-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.3.2 Updates Out Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released another update for ReSharper, Rider and the .NET tools version 2025.3. You can update to this version from inside those tools, using the Toolbox app or our website. Let’s take a look at the latest updates. Rider 2025.3.2 Agent Client Protocol (ACP) agent registry support You can now browse and install ACP-compatible […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/29/resharper-and-rider-2025-3-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Dev in 2025: Excerpts From the State of Game Development Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we approach the midpoint of the decade, game developers face an evolving landscape shaped by shifting job security, technology choices, platform strategies, and practical AI adoption. Our State of Game Development 2025 report reveals critical insights that provide a clearer picture of where the industry is heading. Layoffs and job security concerns The game […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/29/game-dev-in-2025-excerpts-from-the-state-of-game-development-report/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
