<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 12:11:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.38 Is Here With Support for Virtual Environments Created by Anaconda, Auto-Refresh for Log Files, Improved Proxy Setting Detection, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 12:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.38 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.38 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/07/fleet-1-38-is-here-with-support-for-virtual-environments-created-by-anaconda-auto-refresh-for-log-files-improved-proxy-setting-detection-and-much-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Numbers to Clarity: Using Math to Simplify Data-Heavy Product Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 09:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s world, data platforms are crucial for any organization. These platforms make data storage assets available and provide the necessary tools to work with data effectively. In this blog post, we’ll explore the inner workings of JetBrains’ data kitchen and the role that documentation plays in it. What is the Product Analytics Platform at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/07/from-numbers-to-clarity-using-math-to-simplify-data-heavy-product-documentation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 20 years!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains celebrated 24 years this February! Now, the company comprises 2,200 employees, 40 products, 3M total customers, and 11.4M users who regularly use and trust our tools. But how did it all start? IntelliJ IDEA was the first flagship product we launched, but right after that came ReSharper, which is celebrating 20 years on the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/23/resharper-20-years/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream – Jodie Burchell, Matt Ellis, Khalid Abuhakmeh, and Maarten Balliauw – AI in Game Development With JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Wednesday, August 7, 2024, at 2:00 pm UTC (check other timezones) for a free livestream entitled AI in Game Development With JetBrains AI Assistant, with JetBrains Developer Advocates Jodie Burchell, Matt Ellis, Khalid Abuhakmeh, and Maarten Balliauw. REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Game development has entered a new era with the rise of AI-powered […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/23/livestream-jodie-burchell-matt-ellis-khalid-abuhakmeh-and-maarten-balliauw-ai-in-game-development-with-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Laravel Tutorials and Resources for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 11:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Laravel is one of the most popular PHP frameworks, known for its elegant syntax and powerful features. According to the JetBrains Development Ecosystem Report 2023, over 60% of PHP developers use Laravel, and nowadays, many opt for this framework for their professional development. Whether you’re a beginner just starting with web development or an experienced […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/07/the-best-laravel-tutorials-and-resources-for-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dev Containers in JetBrains IDEs – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2024/22_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2024/22_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As cloud technologies and containerization evolve, we enter a new era of software development where flexibility, scalability, and efficiency become key requirements for any project. Dev Containers, or development containers, represent an approach to creating developer workspaces that allows you to focus on the code while worrying less about dependencies and surrounding infrastructure. This tool […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/using-dev-containers-in-jetbrains-ides-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn JavaScript: Your Step-by-Step Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 13:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learning is a never-ending journey, or at least it should be. It can be frustrating starting learning to program, and becoming really good at it is even more challenging. However, learning a skill that others may not have the patience to acquire is what makes coders so inherently unique. In this blog post, we’ll look […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/07/how-to-learn-javascript/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Books Every Beginner Programmer Should Read</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting to code can feel like a daunting task, but pairing courses with the right books can provide both hands-on skills and in-depth knowledge. To help you on this journey, we’ve curated a list of five must-read books that cover everything from clean code practices to mastering design patterns. Let’s turn the page! Code Complete: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/19/5-books-every-beginner-programmer-should-read/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.07 Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity 2024.07 is out! With this release, we’re introducing a number of important features, such as a new licensing mechanism that simplifies the management of TeamCity server and agent licenses. There’s also the new GitHub Checks webhook trigger that allows you to queue builds instantly after pushing a commit to GitHub and receive updates in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/07/teamcity-202407/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 Goes Beta With Remote Development and Code With Me Support for CLion Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 13:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of CLion 2024.2 is now available with the key improvements and changes expected in the upcoming release. Download build 242.20224.66 from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package (for Ubuntu). DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 BETA The full release notes can be found here, and below you’ll find the highlights. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/07/clion-2024-2-goes-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Beta 2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 13:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Beta 2! This build incorporates all of the latest enhancements rolled out during the Early Access Program. You can download it from our website, the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Beta 2 The Beta 2 build marks an important milestone towards delivering […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-beta-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
