<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:15:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Declarative Gradle in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last year Gradle announced a new experimental project called Declarative Gradle that aims to make Gradle build scripts easier to read and use. Instead of writing detailed instructions for how to build your project, Declarative Gradle allows you to describe what your software needs (like libraries, applications, or tests) in a clear and simple way. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/declarative-gradle-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code in Rust for the Rest of Us</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 07:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m not a competitive programmer – far from it. I never received formal education in advanced algorithms and data structures. In fact, I can’t even implement Dijkstra’s algorithm without referring to Wikipedia. Yet, I still participate in Advent of Code competitions. I’ve never made it onto an official leaderboard; I’m too slow for that. Completing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/11/29/advent-of-code-in-rust-for-the-rest-of-us/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve Advent of Code 2024 Puzzles in Rust and Win Prizes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 07:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2024/29_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the fourth year in a row, JetBrains is a proud sponsor of the Advent of Code, and this year, alongside the Kotlin challenge, we invite all Rust developers to join. Test your skills at a comfortable pace or join the leaderboards for a chance to win a USD 100 Amazon Gift Card! What is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/11/29/solve-advent-of-code-2024-puzzles-in-rust-and-win-prizes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Code Analysis in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 13:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This series of blog posts covers several ways that code analysis in IntelliJ IDEA can help you find and fix problems in your code. In the previous posts, we first looked at how the IDE can help you prevent problems while working with code in the editor before moving on to how to resolve problems […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/advanced-code-analysis-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify ML Workflows With Hugging Face and PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 12:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2024/28_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ready to boost your workflows with pre-trained ML models? PyCharm‘s integration with Hugging Face is designed to bring a new level of productivity to your machine learning and development workflows. This integration helps you seamlessly find and use the best-fit model from the Hugging Face library, access model documentation, and manage models – all in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/11/hugging-face-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recordings from JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024 Are Now Live</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 19:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 7, 2024, we hosted our first-ever JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf, an exciting online event dedicated to plugin development for JetBrains products. We’d like to extend a huge thank you to everyone who joined us and made this event such a success! For those who couldn’t be there or who want to revisit their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/11/recordings-from-jetbrains-plugin-developer-conf-2024-are-now-live/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.43 Is Here With Improved Branches Menu, Context Retrieval and Slash Commands in AI Chat, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.43 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/11/fleet-1-43-is-here-with-improved-branches-menu-context-retrieval-and-slash-commands-in-ai-chat-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.1.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.1.0 release is out! This version introduces new language features, tooling updates, performance improvements, and important fixes. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.1.0 or the release notes on GitHub. Join the Kotlin 2.1.0 Livestream Do you want to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/kotlin-2-1-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.5 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 13:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 – 2024.2.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/intellij-idea-2024-2-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discontinuation of the SpaceCode Private Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 09:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dear customers, Today we are announcing the discontinuation of the SpaceCode Private Preview, which we launched in May 2024. On May 27, 2024, we announced that we had decided to discontinue Space and pivot it to a new product: SpaceCode. The plan was for SpaceCode to focus primarily on Git hosting and code reviews. For […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/space/2024/11/27/discontinuation-of-the-spacecode-private-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Roundup: Kodee’s Top Picks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone! Time flies, doesn’t it? It’s already my second edition of Kotlin Roundup, and I can’t wait to share the latest from the Kotlin ecosystem. Did you know that the JetBrains team regularly publishes a newsletter featuring major Kotlin ecosystem news? Sign up to stay up to date with all things Kotlin.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/kotlin-roundup-kodee-s-top-picks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve Advent of Code 2024 Puzzles in Kotlin and Win Prizes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DRAdvent of Code is the perfect opportunity to level up your Kotlin skills, whether you are a beginner or looking to finally tackle that advanced Kotlin feature you’ve been curious about. Here’s what’s in store: So join in, solve some Advent of Code puzzles, and enjoy the holiday coding spirit with Kotlin! About Advent of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/advent-of-code-2024-in-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant Integrates Google Gemini and Local LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve now added Gemini 1.5 Pro and Gemini 1.5 Flash to the lineup of LLMs used by JetBrains AI Assistant. These LLMs join forces with OpenAI models and local models. What’s special about Google models? Gemini 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash on Google Cloud’s Vertex AI will deliver advanced reasoning and impressive performance, unlocking several […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/11/jetbrains-ai-assistant-integrates-google-gemini-and-local-llms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
