<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:55:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: New Releases, OpenAI vs. DeepSeek, and Compose Hot Reload</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, Kotlin fans! Kodee’s back with another roundup of the latest updates and stories from the Kotlin world. Grab your favorite drink, sit back, and enjoy! Kotlin YouTube Spotlight Check out our latest YouTube videos and Shorts – sit back, relax, and enjoy!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/03/kodee-s-kotlin-roundup-new-releases-openai-vs-deepseek-and-compose-hot-reload/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose the Right LLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant is now multimodel! This is an exciting development, but what does it actually mean for you? It means AI Assistant is now more adaptable. It combines the strengths of different AI models, from the deep reasoning of large ones to the speed of compact ones, and even the privacy of local ones. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/how-to-choose-the-right-llm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is SAST? A Guide to Static Application Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is brought to you by Thinus Swart, draft.dev. Static application security testing (SAST) is a method for identifying vulnerabilities in application source code, binaries, or bytecode early in the software development lifecycle (SDLC). By analyzing code before it’s compiled or run, SAST allows developers to catch potential security flaws before they can be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/what-is-sast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Code Analysis in STEM: Protecting Work That Affects the World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 08:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_03_2025/22_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Qodana, we champion code quality for businesses and enterprise development teams, but it has other crucial applications, and implications. Not only can good (and bad!) code be felt in the digital products we all know and use every day, but its impact also extends to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM). As STEM disciplines […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/03/code-analysis-in-stem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.47 Is Here With Folding Support for Multiline Comments, New AI Chat Functionality, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 13:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using our Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.47 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2025/03/fleet-1-47-is-here-with-folding-support-for-multiline-comments-new-ai-chat-functionality-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in TeamCity 2025.03: Recipes, Improved Docker and Podman Integration, UI Updates, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity’s first major release of the year, version 2025.03, is now available. It’s packed with new features, including massive UI updates, a new Run in Docker build feature, and JetBrains-crafted recipes available in our Marketplace. UI updates In line with our commitment to make TeamCity easier and more intuitive to use, this release introduces significant […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/teamcity-2025-03-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.1.20 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 11:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.1.20 release is out! This version includes performance improvements and bug fixes for Kotlin 2.1.0. Here are some highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.1.20 or the release notes on GitHub. How to install Kotlin 2.1.20 Starting from IntelliJ IDEA 2023.3 and Android […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/03/kotlin-2-1-20-released 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Roadmap 2025: Updating the UI, TeamCity Recipes, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, the TeamCity team is working on a number of new initiatives, including updating the UI, TeamCity recipes, Jenkins migration tools, and many others. Read on to learn what our focus is for 2025. Modernizing the TeamCity Enterprise interface In 2025, we’re taking a major step forward in enhancing the TeamCity experience. The modern […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/teamcity-roadmap-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AI Agents for Notebook Debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 12:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debugging computational notebooks can be quite frustrating for a variety of reasons, including issues like out-of-order cell execution, missing data files, and library conflicts. Traditional AI tools often struggle with these problems due to the interactive nature of notebooks, but at JetBrains, we are exploring new solutions. Our research team has developed a prototype of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/using-ai-agents-for-notebook-debugging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shout-Out to Kotlin for Server-Side Content Creators!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re using Kotlin for server-side development and sharing your experiences – whether through blog posts, videos, or sample projects – know that we see you, and we want to highlight your work! Recent picks from the community 📖 [Article] From Java to Kotlin — a practical example of how to convert code – Paul […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/03/shout-out-to-kotlin-for-server-side-content-creators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Code Completion: Less Is More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 10:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve been following our journey, you might’ve read our recent blog post on the Complete the Un-Completable: The State of AI Completion in JetBrains IDEs. From that post, you might remember this cool chart on code completions. In April, something exciting happened: our acceptance rate went up while the explicit cancel rate dropped. In […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/ai-code-completion-less-is-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 10:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released another update for v2024.3! You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This new version that brings the following valuable improvements: To see the full list of issues addressed in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2024-3-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 24 and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 08:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA has supported Java 24 since an earlier release, with more enhancements being added in the later releases! I’m often asked, “What’s the best feature of Java 24?” My answer? Why pick just one? 🙂 Java 24 continues to enhance the language with improvements like Simple source files and instance main methods, Primitive Types […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/java-24-and-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the IntelliJ Infrastructure Team Cuts Build Execution Time by 30% With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction JetBrains is known for developing some of the world’s most popular IDEs, including IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, and WebStorm. Supporting this development is a dedicated infrastructure team that ensures hundreds of developers can efficiently build, test, and release these products. At the core of their workflow is TeamCity, JetBrains’ own CI/CD solution, which powers build […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/how-intellij-uses-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.1 Goes Beta With Enhanced CLion Nova, Debugger, and Embedded Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 08:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of CLion 2025.1 is now available with key improvements and changes announced for the upcoming release. You can download build 251.23774.112 for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.1 BETA Read the full release notes on YouTrack. Below […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/03/clion-2025-1-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
