<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 09:44:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Year of Creator Wins: Highlights from the JetBrains Content Creators Program 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2026/27_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 09:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2026/27_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With more than 200 new members joining the JetBrains Content Creator community, we were bound to hear some exciting new things from them in 2025. Our members were steadily increasing in number, honing their YouTube videos, tirelessly keeping up with the posting schedule, and providing JetBrains perks directly to their audiences. But the real results […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2026/01/27/content-creators-wins/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jenkins Migration Planning Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Cameron Pavey, draft.dev. Jenkins has served the development community well for over a decade, but it was designed for a different era of software development. Developers who are tired of fighting with plugin compatibility issues, slow builds, and brittle configurations are exploring alternatives. But is your organization ready […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/jenkins-migration-planning-kit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 5: Teaching Agents to Forget</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously in this series: Agents eventually run out of context. When they do, they crash, and you lose everything mid-task. We’ve been running GPT-5 Codex since Part 1. It scores 0.58 on SWE-bench Verified. We tried Claude Sonnet 4.5 next, which scored 0.6 and ran faster on most tasks. But complex problems hit Claude’s 200K […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/01/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-5-teaching-agents-to-forget/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Made Variable Inspections 87 Times Faster for Unreal Engine in Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever expanded a complex Unreal Engine variable in Rider’s debugger and had time to contemplate your life choices, this post is for you. We’ve rewritten our expression evaluator, and the results are dramatic: Variable inspection is up to 87 times faster on warm runs and 16 times faster on cold ones. The debugger […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/26/how-we-made-variable-inspections-87-times-faster-for-unreal-engine-in-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the First Speakers Heading to KotlinConf 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With each KotlinConf, developers from around the world come together to learn from leading experts, explore the latest industry insights, and engage with the Kotlin community. KotlinConf’25 alone welcomed attendees from over 50 countries. KotlinConf’26 is just a few months away, and we’re excited to introduce the first round of speakers who will be joining […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/meet-the-first-speakers-heading-to-kotlinconf-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – From Detection to Remediation: Wiz in Your JetBrains IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join our upcoming IntelliJ IDEA livestream with Daniel Velikanski from Wiz to see how cloud security insights can be brought directly into your JetBrains IDE, helping you detect and address real risks as you code. Date: February 5, 2026 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Developers move fast in the cloud, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/new-livestream-engineers-talk-about-spring-boot-4-life-and-other-stuff/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot Debugging – Now Remote</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We released Spring Debugger in May 2025 to bring more clarity to the “magic” behind Spring Boot – helping you see what’s really happening inside your running application. By the end of 2025, the plugin had reached more than 300,000 unique downloads and became a trusted tool within the developer community. We’ve received a lot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/spring-boot-debugging-now-remote/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 3.4.0 Is Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ktor 3.4.0 improves stability and addresses outstanding issues. Highlights include OpenAPI generation, Ztsd support for the compression plugin, duplex streaming for OkHttp, Structured concurrency integrations for the HTTP request lifecycle, and much more. For a detailed list of all the changes, check out the What’s new page. Stability and performance With its focus on stability […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/ktor-3-4-0-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposed 1.0 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the first major release of Exposed – a huge milestone for both the project and the Exposed team! This release brings many new exciting features, the most requested being R2DBC support, as well as performance enhancements and bug fixes. Exposed 1.0 also introduces a stable API that guarantees no breaking changes until the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/exposed-1-0-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codex Is Now Integrated Into JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI Codex is now natively integrated into the JetBrains AI chat, giving you another powerful option for tackling real development tasks right inside your IDE. You can use Codex with a JetBrains AI subscription, your ChatGPT account, or an OpenAI API key – all within the same AI сhat interface.See Codex in action in a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/01/codex-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released another update for v2025.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This version brings the following valuable refinements: To see the full list of issues addressed in this version, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/intellij-idea-2025-3-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2026.1 Early Access Program Has Begun</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper 2026.1 Early Access Program is now open, and the first EAP build brings a mix of C# productivity improvements, new inspections, performance work, and expanded C++ language support. As always, EAP builds are an opportunity to try upcoming features early and help us refine them before the final release. Here’s what’s new in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/22/resharper-2026-1-early-access-program/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2026.1 Early Access Program Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for Rider 2026.1 has just begun, and the first preview build for the upcoming major release is already out. There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: A reminder of what the EAP is all about The Early Access Program is a long-standing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/22/rider-2026-1-early-access-program-start/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ROI of Developer Experience: How a Better CI/CD Tool Pays for Itself</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Cameron Pavey, draft.dev. Developer experience (DevEx) directly correlates with engineering performance, which in turn drives competitive advantage. And yet many software engineering teams continue to operate on legacy CI/CD platforms that create unnecessary friction, burn developer hours, and ultimately limit business growth. While some teams remain trapped by […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/the-roi-of-dev-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA Conf 2026: Learn From the People Building the JVM Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’re invited to IntelliJ IDEA Conf 2026 – a free online conference for developers working across the JVM ecosystem. Join us for two days of in-depth technical talks, practical insights, and conversations with experts who build and shape modern Java and Kotlin development. The conference will take place online on March 26–27, 2026, with sessions […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/intellij-idea-conf-2026-learn-from-the-people-building-the-jvm-ecosystem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid Common Pitfalls With JPA and Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was written together with Thorben Janssen, who has more than 20 years of experience with JPA and Hibernate and is the author of “Hibernate Tips: More than 70 Solutions to Common Hibernate Problems” and the JPA newsletter. Kotlin and Jakarta Persistence (also known as JPA) are a popular combination for server-side development. Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/how-to-avoid-common-pitfalls-with-jpa-and-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
