<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 05:50:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Why Kakao Pay Chose Kotlin for Backend Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 05:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is a JetBrains translation of the original post by katfun.joy, a backend developer at Kakao Pay. Kakao Pay leverages Kotlin with Spring for backend development across various services, including its insurance offerings. Check out Kakao Pay’s story to see how Kotlin helps it address the complex requirements of the insurance industry and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/case-study-why-kakao-pay-chose-kotlin-for-backend-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module Import Declarations: No More Import Hell</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you are proud of yourself for creating an amazing Java application, framework, or a library. You open one of its source files to make some changes and this is what you see: While looking at this long list of imports, are you wondering why you need to know the name of every single class […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/module-import-declarations-no-more-import-hell/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Remote Development Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 09:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The concept of remote development is deceptively simple: spin up your development environment somewhere that’s not your local machine. The perks range from freeing up local resources to not panicking when your laptop gets stolen. Yet, there are plenty of pitfalls, including flaky setups, poor visibility, and lousy monitoring. Let’s look at some best practices […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/07/10-remote-development-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Leadership Series</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Progress Or Perfection? Staying Quality-Focused as a Team Under Pressure Everyone from growth-mindset gurus to Agile die-hards talk about ways in which we can iterate as developers. Release an MVP, build as you go, “minimize waste, maximize value” to stay lean, and do it all while prioritizing user feedback. But as much merit as these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/06/qodana-leadership-series-minaev/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New YouTrack Prices Starting from October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re introducing a few changes to YouTrack prices, which will take effect on October 1, 2025. What’s not changing What will be changing Read on to learn about the reasons for this change, how to prepare, and what it means for YouTrack Cloud and Server customers. Why are we making this change? Our current pricing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/06/new-youtrack-prices-starting-from-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.4: Another Set of Bug-fixes Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 08:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A fourth set of updates for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.4 comes with the following fixes For the full list of resolved issues, please refer to our issue tracker. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/30/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 EAP 7: Low-Level Exception Suppression and Other Updates for Debugging Games</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 09:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2025.2 is shaping up to be an exciting release for game developers, no matter which engine you work with. Over the last few EAP builds, we’ve been rolling out targeted improvements to make debugging smoother, faster, and more reliable, whether you’re building with Unreal Engine, Unity, Godot, or custom C++ frameworks. In the latest […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/26/rider-2025-2-eap-7-low-level-exception-suppression/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
