<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:14:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spring Debugger: ApplicationContext at Your Fingertips</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA has great support for debugging Java and Kotlin applications. But if you are building Spring Boot applications, you may want to access Spring components along with their metadata. That’s where the Spring Debugger plugin comes in. It makes life easier by letting you explore and use the entire Spring ApplicationContext right from your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/spring-debugger-applicationcontext-at-your-fingertips/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.3 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to kick off the Early Access Program (EAP) for Rider 2025.3! With the first preview build now available, you can try out the new features we’ve been working on and let us know what you think. Your feedback plays a vital role in shaping the final release. If you haven’t joined an EAP […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/17/the-early-access-program-for-rider-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.3 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that the Early Access Program (EAP) has started for both ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.3. The first preview build is now available, giving you an early opportunity to explore what’s coming in the next major release. Your feedback is essential in helping us polish these updates, so we’d love to hear […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/17/the-early-access-program-for-resharper-and-net-tools-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Farewell to Consoles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting from the 2025.3 release, DataGrip and other JetBrains IDEs with database support will stop using the term query console. From now on, we’ll use query file – because consoles were essentially files all along, and it’s time the UI reflected that. We’ve made the workflow simpler, more discoverable, and more consistent. A bit of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/09/16/a-farewell-to-consoles/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ: New AI Quotas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We hear you. And you’re right – the new quotas are a reduction from what you experienced. When we launched, we had little usage data for agentic experiences and no top‑up feature existed, so we set quotas much higher than the real cost of AI usage (tokens from providers) as a temporary measure. That felt […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/faq-new-ai-quota/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the next development cycle and inviting you to join it. The Early Access Program (EAP) for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 is now open, offering an early look at the new features and improvements we’re working on. By evaluating new features and sharing constructive feedback, you help us provide you with powerful, reliable tooling […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/intellij-idea-2025-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 25 LTS and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Java release cadence means we get a new Java version every six months. Java 25 was released on September 16, 2025. At JetBrains, we are committed to supporting new technologies in IntelliJ IDEA and adding useful enhancements for both stable and preview features. In this blog post, we will give you an overview of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/java-25-lts-and-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Constexpr Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 07:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “Not a constant expression.” You’ve seen the diagnostics and the note trail, but never the actual state. Until now. Modern C++ pushes more logic into constexpr/consteval: parsers, tables, DSLs, hashing – real code with real branches. When code fails at compile time, you can either try to guess the reason from the compiler’s notes or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/09/introducing-constexpr-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Voice Belongs Here: Creating Compelling KotlinConf Proposals [Livestream]</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you given a talk before – maybe at a meetup, online event, or a smaller conference – and wondered if you’re ready for a bigger stage like KotlinConf? This supportive and practical webinar is designed for people from underrepresented groups in tech who already have some speaking experience and are ready to level up. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/creating-kotlinconf-proposals/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve Effortless GitHub Releases With a New Plugin for TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 10:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub releases are fantastic for distributing your open-source projects, as they let you turn any code revision into ready-to-go assets with a detailed version history. What makes them particularly popular, though, is that they give users a proper Download button (because not everyone dreams of compiling source code). In TeamCity, the traditional approach for publishing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/teamcity-github-releases-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains at the ICPC World Finals 2025 Baku</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ICPC World Finals 2025 in Baku was an unforgettable event, and we were honored to be part of it once again. It’s always a joy to see the brightest students from across the globe. The Finals reminds us why supporting the ICPC is such a vital mission – it’s about community, talent, and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/11/jetbrains-at-the-icpc-world-finals-2025-baku/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing AI Coding Agents With TeamCity and SWE-bench</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 08:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction AI coding agents are no longer research experiments. They are quickly becoming practical tools that can help developers solve real problems. But how do you know whether an agent is good enough for serious use? How do you measure progress when its answers are not always predictable and when there may be various correct […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/testing-ai-coding-agents-with-teamcity-and-swe-bench/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.07.2 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing our second bug-fix release for the 2025.07 major release —TeamCity On-Premises 2025.07.2. This update ships a considerable number of bug fixes, including the following: Apart from resolving regular bugs, all TeamCity bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements. For that reason, we recommend that you never ignore bug-fix releases and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/teamcity-2025-07-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.2.20 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 09:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.2.20 release is out, delivering important changes for web development. Kotlin/Wasm is now Beta, with improvements to exception handling in JavaScript interop, npm dependency management, built-in browser debugging support, and a new shared source set for js and wasmJs targets. Additionally, here are some main highlights: For the complete list of changes, see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/kotlin-2-2-20-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie Is Now Available in CLion: Supercharge Your C and C&#43;&#43; Development Today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 07:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with version 2025.2.1, CLion now supports Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, thanks to an integration that is currently in Beta. Developers working on embedded systems, projects written in C or C++, or performance-critical software can now experience the full benefit of Junie’s project insights and tooling, directly in CLion. With Junie, you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/09/junie-availability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
