<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:37:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Livestream recording] Maximizing TeamCity: New Features in Action and a Look Ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our latest livestream, TeamCity Solutions Engineers Ricardo Leite and Daniel Gallo hosted a livestream packed with exciting updates about TeamCity – from brand-new features already making life easier for CI/CD engineers, to a sneak peek at what’s next for 2026. If you missed it or just want a quick refresher, here are the key […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/10/livestream-recording-maximizing-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grazie’s Next Step: Built-In Language Intelligence for Your IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the last few years, Grazie has grown from a simple proofreading tool into a comprehensive writing assistant for developers, offering intelligent support across different contexts like code comments, documentation, and README files. Starting with the upcoming 2025.3 IDE versions, Grazie will become a native part of IntelliJ-based IDEs through the Natural Languages plugin, bringing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2025/10/grazie-s-next-step-built-in-language-intelligence-for-your-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Becomes Cloud9’s Official AI-Powered Coding Partner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers love coding – it’s a passion we all share. But staying productive means taking time to recharge, and for many of us, that means playing video games. That’s why we’re excited to team up with the legendary Cloud9 Esports as their official AI-Powered Coding Partner. With this partnership, we’re bringing AI-powered coding to the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/10/29/jetbrains-becomes-cloud9s-official-ai-powered-coding-partner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Distributed Systems: Jason Taylor Shows How .NET Aspire Makes the Complex Feel Effortless</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025, Jason Taylor, Microsoft MVP and Solutions Architect at Particular Software, delivered an engaging presentation that transforms how we think about building distributed systems. Through live coding and interactive polls with the audience, Taylor demonstrated how .NET Aspire can turn what’s traditionally been a complex, friction-filled process into something surprisingly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/29/simplifying-distributed-systems-dotnet-aspire-jason-taylor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program Has Started</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re starting the MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program (EAP) today. You can download the first 2025.3 EAP release and try it out now! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 EAP Besides numerous bug fixes, this release brings three major improvements: Light and dark TextIcon options TextIcon’s layers can now be configured to apply to the light, dark, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/10/the-mps-2025-3-eap-has-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Order in the Mayhem: A Novel Concurrency Testing Tool that Improved the Kotlin Compiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever tried to track down a bug in concurrent programs, you know how chaotic and frustrating it can be: everything seems to work fine, then suddenly crashes, and you can’t quite pin down why – all while the bugs slip through. To bring order to this chaos, at JetBrains Research we built LitmusKt […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/10/litmuskt-concurrency-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Launch of Developer Productivity AI Arena: An Open Platform for Benchmarking AI Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For 25 years, JetBrains has shaped the software development landscape across multiple programming languages, advancing how developers and organizations build software. Our focus has always been on improving productivity and the overall developer experience. With the rise of AI, a key challenge now is understanding how to measure the real-world productivity gains provided by AI-assisted […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/10/28/the-launch-of-developer-productivity-ai-arena-an-open-platform-for-benchmarking-ai-coding-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Developer Productivity AI Arena: An Open Platform for AI Coding Agents Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s software development landscape, AI coding agents are evolving rapidly from prototypes into indispensable tools. Yet the industry still lacks an open, neutral, standards-based way to measure the real-world effectiveness of these agents across languages, frameworks, and environments. With over two decades of experience building developer tools that are trusted by millions worldwide, we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/10/28/introducing-developer-productivity-ai-arena-an-open-platform-for-ai-coding-agents-benchmarks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces a Remote MCP Server and New Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The YouTrack 2025.3 release introduces remote MCP (Model Context Protocol) support, which expands the possibilities for those who build integrations with YouTrack. This enables you to securely connect AI-powered tools to YouTrack, allowing your teams to manage their work directly from an LLM, IDE, or agent platform. In addition, many new apps are now available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/10/youtrack-introduces-a-remote-mcp-server-and-new-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Kotlin in Real Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the second post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/evaluating-kotlin-in-real-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.2.4: Another Set of Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A fourth set of updates for the 2025.2 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.2.4 TeamCity extension is back After listening to feedback from teams who rely on it for their CI workflows, we’ve restored […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/28/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-4-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Modern Enterprise Toolkit for Secure, High-Quality Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 19, 2025, join JetBrains Qodana for a live session exploring how enterprises can embed quality, security, and compliance directly into their development workflows. Hosted by Product Specialist, Kai Schmithuesen, this session will walk you through the latest Qodana capabilities and real-world applications for modern software development and DevOps teams. Mark your calendars and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/10/the-modern-enterprise-toolkit-for-secure-high-quality-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Finally Back with News</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a while since you last heard from me – I know, I’ve been a busy bee! Between releases and launches, time just flew by. But I’ve got plenty of updates to share with you. Let’s start with some of the biggest highlights from September and October, and if you’re curious, scroll down for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/kodees-kotlin-roundup-october-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Django 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the highlights and key takeaways from the recently released Django Developers Survey. Now in its fourth year, this annual collaboration between the Django Software Foundation and PyCharm tabulates responses from over 4,600 Django developers worldwide. If you work with Python and the web more broadly, there’s a lot to learn from what’s happening […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/10/the-state-of-django-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use a Spec-Driven Approach for Coding with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s see how this works with Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains. What you’ll get from this guide Developing complex software features can be daunting. Such tasks often feel overwhelming due to the sheer size of the codebase, the uncertainty of dependencies, and the difficulty of keeping all requirements in mind. With the advent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/junie/2025/10/how-to-use-a-spec-driven-approach-for-coding-with-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
