<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:42:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Dev Containers in JetBrains IDEs – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2024/22_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2024/22_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As cloud technologies and containerization evolve, we enter a new era of software development where flexibility, scalability, and efficiency become key requirements for any project. Dev Containers, or development containers, represent an approach to creating developer workspaces that allows you to focus on the code while worrying less about dependencies and surrounding infrastructure. This tool […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/using-dev-containers-in-jetbrains-ides-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn JavaScript: Your Step-by-Step Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 13:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learning is a never-ending journey, or at least it should be. It can be frustrating starting learning to program, and becoming really good at it is even more challenging. However, learning a skill that others may not have the patience to acquire is what makes coders so inherently unique. In this blog post, we’ll look […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/07/how-to-learn-javascript/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Books Every Beginner Programmer Should Read</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting to code can feel like a daunting task, but pairing courses with the right books can provide both hands-on skills and in-depth knowledge. To help you on this journey, we’ve curated a list of five must-read books that cover everything from clean code practices to mastering design patterns. Let’s turn the page! Code Complete: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/19/5-books-every-beginner-programmer-should-read/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.07 Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity 2024.07 is out! With this release, we’re introducing a number of important features, such as a new licensing mechanism that simplifies the management of TeamCity server and agent licenses. There’s also the new GitHub Checks webhook trigger that allows you to queue builds instantly after pushing a commit to GitHub and receive updates in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/07/teamcity-202407/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 Goes Beta With Remote Development and Code With Me Support for CLion Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 13:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of CLion 2024.2 is now available with the key improvements and changes expected in the upcoming release. Download build 242.20224.66 from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package (for Ubuntu). DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 BETA The full release notes can be found here, and below you’ll find the highlights. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/07/clion-2024-2-goes-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Beta 2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 13:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Beta 2! This build incorporates all of the latest enhancements rolled out during the Early Access Program. You can download it from our website, the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Beta 2 The Beta 2 build marks an important milestone towards delivering […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-beta-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect With Our Developer Advocate: WebStorm Open Hours</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 13:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone!My name is Jan-Niklas. Some of you may already know me from WebStorm, as I am the Developer Advocate for JavaScript and TypeScript at JetBrains. I’m excited to share some news with you today—I’m trying something new and opening up my calendar to you! Whether you’re a long-time user of JetBrains tools or just […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/07/connect-with-our-developer-advocate-webstorm-open-hours/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Company Financial Data with Python and Datalore AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 11:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog post by Ryan O’Connell, CFA, FRM. Introduction In the twilight of 2022 and the dawn of 2023, the tech industry was rocked by a seismic shift. Giants like Meta, Amazon, Microsoft, Google, and Salesforce – names that once seemed impervious to economic tremors – announced wave after wave of substantial […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/17/analyzing-company-financial-data-with-python-and-datalore-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2022.3.2 Has Been Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 10:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re releasing an update for MPS 2022.3 with numerous fixes. DOWNLOAD MPS 2022.3.2 See the full list of issues fixed in 2022.3.2 here. One improvement that’s worth a separate mention is: Filter commented out nodes from scopes action. Filter commented out nodes from scopes When relying on default scope calculation, commented out potential target nodes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/07/mps-2022-3-2-has-been-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #4: Dependency Cache</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Everyone wants faster builds. Historically in TeamCity Pipelines, running Maven builds meant having to download all of your dependencies from scratch for every single build. Introducing Dependency Cache! Now, TeamCity Pipelines caches your Maven dependencies after the initial run and reuses them in future builds, saving you time and money. Dependency Cache is turned on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/07/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Tools for Java Developers in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 10:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just as an RPG player relies on a well-stocked bag of artifacts and tools to overcome obstacles and achieve goals, a Java developer also has a set of essential tools. Each tool performs a specific role in simplifying development and enhancing productivity. As Java has evolved, many tools have come and gone; what was popular […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/top-tools-for-java-developers-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The YouTrack App Now Supports Helpdesk Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 09:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The YouTrack Helpdesk functionality has arrived in the YouTrack app! This means you can manage your customer support services on the go. Your agents and other team members can now work with support requests from their phones and tablets, and your reporters can submit and review tickets and public Knowledge Base articles in the app […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/07/the-youtrack-app-now-supports-helpdesk-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2 EAP Digest #3: Bun Debugger, Language Server Updates for Vue and Astro, and Prettier Integration by Default</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 15:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s time for our last EAP digest of this release that will walk you through the new features and improvements in WebStorm 2024.2! For more information, check out our previous blog posts.The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the EAP builds and keep both your stable and EAP versions up to date. You […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/07/webstorm-2024-2-eap3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Shape the Future of Tech – Participate in the Developer Ecosystem Survey 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 11:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year’s Developer Ecosystem Survey is out now! This is your chance to contribute to a comprehensive, unbiased analysis of the software development landscape. Your insights and feedback are invaluable, and we can’t wait to hear from you. Offering you an opportunity to share your experiences as a developer, the survey will take around 30 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2024/07/15/help-shape-the-future-of-tech-participate-in-the-developer-ecosystem-survey-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Practical Debugging at Scale: Do You Really Know How to Debug Effectively?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Shai Almog, where we will delve into the capabilities of the debugger. Date: July 25, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Most of us didn’t learn debugging in university and just “picked it up on the job”. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
