<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:49:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New! Security Analysis Plugin for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Application security is a critical requirement in modern software development. The latest release of IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 – along with the optional new Security Analysis by Qodana plugin – elevates your security efforts with advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for code written in Java and Kotlin. Trained on popular OWASP security benchmark projects, this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/security-analysis-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 – 2024.3.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. v2024.3.1 introduces advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for Java and Kotlin. This allows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/intellij-idea-2024-3-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream alert: Ace the CSAI Math Entrance Test</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want to study computer science in Europe? Join the Computer Science and AI bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos – with exclusive JetBrains scholarships up for grabs! On December 18, 2024, at 5:00 pm UTC, we’re hosting a special preparation session to help you ace the entrance test for this BSc. You’ll get tips from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/06/livestream-alert-ace-the-csai-math-entrance-test/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Ruby Debugging: From puts to Professional Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Debugging is an essential skill in software development, and in this post, we’ll be looking at how to investigate the behavior of Ruby code. As the RubyMine team, we’ve accumulated considerable expertise in creating tools for Ruby developers, and we’re excited to share our experience and knowledge with you. Recently, at the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/12/mastering_ruby_debugging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code, Learn, Repeat: Get Ready for KotlinConf 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            KotlinConf has always been about more than just code – it’s where ideas spark, skills develop, and the Kotlin community comes together to share knowledge, connect, and celebrate. While we’re still crafting the 2025 program (stay tuned for the big reveal in February), here are the recordings of last year’s top talks to give you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/code-learn-repeat-get-ready-for-kotlinconf-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – November Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year draws to a close, the JetBrains Academy team has some exciting updates for you! In this newsletter, you’ll discover new courses, plugins to enhance your learning, tech career tips, and updates for computer science educators.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/05/jetbrains-academy-november-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3.20 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just published a maintenance update to IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3. This minor release includes several bug fixes and improvements to existing features introduced in the main release. Lambda breakpoints in the debugger We’ve made improvements to how lambda expressions are handled in the debugger. Previously, setting a breakpoint on a line with a lambda […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/12/05/intellij-scala-plugin-2024-3-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – December 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As 2024 wraps up, this December edition of Java Annotated Monthly brings you the latest on JEPs targeted for Java 24, helpful tutorials on Java, Kotlin, and AI, and more. This time, we’ve included thought-provoking non-tech articles perfect for year-end reflection. Plus, we’re thrilled to welcome Josh Long as our featured author, who will be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/java-annotated-monthly-december-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12: UI Updates, Experimental Kubernetes Executor Mode, Conditional Dependencies in Build Chains, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity 2024.12 introduces a redesigned UI, conditional build chains, simplified OAuth token management, and enhanced AWS and Perforce integrations. New features also include support for custom Kotlin DSL libraries, centralized refreshable token management, and single-action build chain approvals, among others. Conditional dependencies in build chains In TeamCity, you can break down complex build processes into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/teamcity-202412/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Do Sentiment Analysis With Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sentiment analysis is a powerful tool for understanding emotions in text. While there are many ways to approach sentiment analysis, including more traditional lexicon-based and machine learning approaches, today we’ll be focusing on one of the most cutting-edge ways of working with text – large language models (LLMs). We’ll explain how you can use these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/how-to-do-sentiment-analysis-with-large-language-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GreenJinn Took the Strain Off Their Core Tech Team and Achieved a 200% ROI With Datalore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 10:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trapped in the insights loop As GreenJinn scaled, its tech and engineering team became overwhelmed with data extraction requests from non-technical teams, including operations, insights, sales, and marketing. These teams relied on the tech department for all their data needs, creating a bottleneck that slowed down operations and disrupted product development. The insights loop was a repetitive cycle. The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/12/04/greenjinn-achieved-a-200-roi-with-datalore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring in C&#43;&#43;: Top Techniques and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 13:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re a seasoned C++ developer or just starting out, refactoring is a key way you can make your code cleaner, more efficient, and easier to maintain. In this article, we’ll review common refactoring techniques in C++ and explore their benefits, from improving code readability to reducing technical debt. We’ll also look at the main […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/12/refactoring-in-cpp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowering Prices for TeamCity Pipelines | TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Great news – we’re cutting the cost of TeamCity Pipelines! Now, the prices start from USD 15/month. Check out all the pricing options on our website. Why the change? Because we’re committed to making modern, reliable CI/CD solutions affordable for teams of all sizes. Building and shipping great software shouldn’t break the bank. New UI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/lowering-prices-for-teamcity-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Data Science 2024: 6 Key Data Science Trends</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI and LLMs have been hot topics this year, but are they affecting trends in data science and machine learning? What new trends in data science are worth following? Every year, JetBrains collaborates with the Python Software Foundation to carry out the Python Developer Survey, which can offer some useful insight into these questions. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/the-state-of-data-science/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: From Code to Clarity With the Redesigned Structure Tool Window</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Siva Reddy to explore the IDE’s redesigned Structure tool window, featuring insights for seamless code exploration and context-relevant actions. Date: December 12, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract As developers, we often find ourselves navigating through existing code far more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/new-livestream-from-code-to-clarity-with-the-redesigned-structure-tool-window/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
