<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 13:31:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 13:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The Original Name of .NET Was “Next Generation Windows Services (NGWS)“. Before Microsoft officially named it “.NET,” the platform was internally referred to as NGWS: Next Generation Windows Services. The name “.NET” was adopted in the late 1990s to emphasize the platform’s focus on web-based development and interoperability, as opposed to being […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/03/dotinsights-june-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: How Junie Uses TeamCity to Evaluate Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Junie is an intelligent coding agent developed by JetBrains. It automates the full development loop: reading project files, editing code, running tests, and applying fixes, going far beyond simple code generation. Similar to how developers use tools like ChatGPT to solve coding problems, Junie takes it a step further by automating the entire process. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/how-junie-uses-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! The RubyMine 2025.2 Early Access Program is already available! In this blog post, we’ll share the upcoming features and updates planned for this release cycle. What’s coming in RubyMine 2025.2? Debugger improvements We’re introducing a number of changes aimed at enhancing the debugger installation experience. The entire process will now take less time, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/what-s-next-for-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie and RubyMine: Your Winning Combo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Junie, a powerful AI coding agent from JetBrains, is available in RubyMine! Install the plugin and try it out now! Why Junie is a game-changer Unlike other AI coding agents, Junie leverages the robust power of JetBrains IDEs and reliable large language models (LLMs) to deliver exceptional results with high precision. According to SWE-bench Verified, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/junie-and-rubymine-your-winning-combo/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context Collection Competition by JetBrains and Mistral AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Build smarter code completions and compete for a share of USD 12,000! In AI-enabled IDEs, code completion quality heavily depends on how well the IDE understands the surrounding code – the context. That context is everything, and we want your help to find the best way to collect it. Join JetBrains and Mistral AI at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/06/context-collection-competition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Predict the Future of AI in Software Development!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 11:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever wanted to share your ideas about AI and have a chance at winning prizes at the same time? As a company dedicated to creating the best possible solutions for software development, we at JetBrains want to know what you think about AI in software development. In this post, we tell you more about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/06/predict-the-future-of-ai-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Learning, Part 2: Get Unstuck With AI Hints in Python and Kotlin Tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 08:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous post, we introduced AI-powered machine translation and inline theory definitions to help make learning smoother and more accessible. Today, we’re excited to share the next big step in bringing intelligent assistance to your programming journey: AI hints. This feature is designed especially for beginners who may get stuck while solving coding tasks […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/06/02/ai-hints-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Answers to Your KMP Questions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            During the Closing Panel at KotlinConf 2025, we received many questions about Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP), but unfortunately didn’t have time to address them all live. So we’ve decided to answer the most popular ones in a follow-up blog post. Will IntelliJ IDEA and Android Studio support full Swift navigation, completion, etc., for iOS code, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/get-answers-to-your-kmp-questions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 15:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the May edition of PHP Annotated! It’s been a minute since the last edition. Turns out time flies when you’re deep in foundation work, and the occasional existential debugging session. But we are back. Here’s everything you might’ve missed in the PHP world, we dug through the noise so you can just enjoy […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/05/php-annotated-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Verifier and API Compatibility Maintenance: Livestream Recording &amp; Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 13:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a recent session, IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocate Róbert Novotný walked through the Plugin Verifier—one of the most important tools for maintaining plugin compatibility across JetBrains IDEs. The session focused on spotting breaking API changes, avoiding internal APIs, and verifying plugin behavior across IDE versions. If you couldn’t join us live, the full recording is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/05/plugin-verifier-and-api-compatibility-maintenance-livestream-recording-amp-key-takeaways/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Live Watches in CLion’s Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest CLion 2025.2 EAP build, 252.18003.25, includes one of the most requested features for embedded development: live watches. It allows you to monitor global variables in real time without stopping the debugger or the program’s execution. This feature is particularly useful for embedded developers working with time-sensitive protocols, such as Bluetooth, or with physical […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/introducing-live-watches/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
