<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:04:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KotlinConf 2025 Tickets Are Now on Sale!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The countdown to KotlinConf 2025 has officially begun, and we’re excited to announce that tickets are now on sale for this premier event, which will take place from May 21–23, 2025, in Copenhagen, Denmark! Organized by JetBrains, this is the largest Kotlin event in the world. Starting today, you can secure your spot at KotlinConf […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/07/kotlinconf-2025-tickets-on-sale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Platform Gradle Plugin 2.0 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 17:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Version 2.0 of the IntelliJ Platform Gradle Plugin is now available! Previously called the Gradle IntelliJ Plugin, this updated plugin for the Gradle build system simplifies the configuration of environments for building, testing, verifying, and publishing plugins for IntelliJ-based IDEs. Redesigned and rewritten, it addresses community-reported issues and feature requests from previous versions. The path […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/intellij-platform-gradle-plugin-2-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Teachers, Involved Students: Active Learning with the Capture the Flag Game</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 14:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, August 13, at 3:00 pm UTC for the livestream in the JetBrains Academy series for educators, Lazy Teachers, Involved Students: Active Learning with the Capture the Flag Game The relevance of traditional education and the necessity of an academic degree have long been debated in the tech industry. The rapid pace […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/30/lazy-teachers-involved-students-active-learning-with-the-capture-the-flag-game/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2024.2 Release Candidate is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 12:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2024.2 Release Candidate is available now! You can get this build via the Toolbox App or download it from our website. You can also download the build from inside GoLand by going to Settings | Appearance &amp;amp; Behavior | System Settings | Updates and selecting Check IDE updates for: Early Access Program. Download GoLand […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/07/30/goland-2024-2-release-candidate-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 18:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Release Candidate is now available for download! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. To use this build, you need an active IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate subscription. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 RC With the major release just around the corner, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Resources for pytest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 08:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we’ll look at how PyCharm helps you when you’re working with pytest, and we will signpost you to a bunch of resources for learning pytest. While some of these resources were created by us here at JetBrains, others were crafted by the storytellers in the pytest community. Using pytest in PyCharm […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/07/learning-resources-for-pytest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Java Still Relevant Nowadays?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 13:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the biggest challenges for technologies nowadays is keeping up to date with the latest developments, remaining relevant to the demands of modern business, and continuing to provide added value for users. The world is changing faster than ever before, and the pace of this change shows no signs of slowing. As a major […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/is-java-still-relevant-nowadays/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make it Happen – With Easter Eggs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 12:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever since the dawn of humanity, we’ve had a fascination with discovery. For Neanderthals, it was fire, for people of the Renaissance it was electricity, and now it’s funny cat gifs and Easter eggs hidden deep within videos. Despite clocking in at just 1 minute and 18 seconds, the “Make it happen. With code. | […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/07/26/make-it-happen-with-easter-eggs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Microsoft Edge? Try Grazie!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 09:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to share that Grazie, our AI writing companion for people in tech, is now available for Microsoft Edge users. This is one more step towards streamlining your non-coding tasks wherever you work. How to get started: Grazie is currently available as a plugin for JetBrains IDEs and as an extension for Microsoft […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2024/07/use-microsoft-edge-try-grazie/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Stimulus in your Rails apps with RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! The RubyMine team is constantly striving to provide support for new technologies for Ruby and Rails. One of the most exciting recent additions to Rails is undoubtedly Hotwire, so we’ve prepared an overview of this suite of frameworks and a tutorial on how to use the most important Turbo and Stimulus features in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/07/how-to-use-stimulus-in-your-rails-apps-with-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.38 Is Here With Support for Virtual Environments Created by Anaconda, Auto-Refresh for Log Files, Improved Proxy Setting Detection, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 12:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.38 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.38 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/07/fleet-1-38-is-here-with-support-for-virtual-environments-created-by-anaconda-auto-refresh-for-log-files-improved-proxy-setting-detection-and-much-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Numbers to Clarity: Using Math to Simplify Data-Heavy Product Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 09:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s world, data platforms are crucial for any organization. These platforms make data storage assets available and provide the necessary tools to work with data effectively. In this blog post, we’ll explore the inner workings of JetBrains’ data kitchen and the role that documentation plays in it. What is the Product Analytics Platform at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/07/from-numbers-to-clarity-using-math-to-simplify-data-heavy-product-documentation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
