<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:06:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Default Bundled Plugins in Fleet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recently, we announced the public rollout of the Fleet Plugins SDK – a step that finally allows plugins to be created and shared among the Fleet community at large. Believe it or not, this did not mark the very beginning of extensibility in Fleet. Fleet has always featured a variety of bundled plugins (currently upwards […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/11/default-bundled-plugins-in-fleet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Release Candidate is here! You can download the latest build from our website, from the free Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. To use this build, you need to have an active IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate subscription. With the big release day approaching fast, our team is putting the finishing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/intellij-idea-2024-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next big release for Rider is just around the corner! If you’re eager to get a sneak peek, you can download the Release Candidate version of Rider 2024.3 from our website right now. Here are the feature highlights of the Rider 2024.3 RC build: If you encounter any issues when using the Rider 2024.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/07/the-rider-2024-3-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2024.3 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get a preview of all the latest features and improvements set to be shipped with the next major ReSharper and .NET tools releases by downloading the Release Candidate builds that have just landed. Here are the lists of major improvements in each of the new builds: The ReSharper 2024.3 Release Candidate The ReSharper C++ 2024.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/07/rsrp-net-tools-2024-3-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 Goes Beta With Enhanced CLion Nova, Debug Servers, and OpenCV Image Viewer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of CLion 2024.3 is now available with key improvements and changes announced for the upcoming release. You can download build 243.21565.87 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 BETA Read the full release notes on YouTrack. Below is a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/11/clion-2024-3-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on Unreal Engine Support in TeamCity: UGS Integration and Open-Sourcing the Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve got a few exciting updates about the Unreal Engine plugin announced in the previous blog post. TL;DR – we’re adding Unreal Game Sync (UGS) integration and open-sourcing the plugin. These updates are all about making the CI/CD experience smoother for Unreal Engine devs and getting the community more involved. UGS Before diving in, let’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/11/unreal-engine-plugin-ugs-integration-and-open-sourcing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in November</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 18:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month, we’ve introduced new projects and topics to help you reach your coding goals in Kotlin, backend development, Git, or AI. Kotlin 🆕 Project: My first project with Kotlin. Easy Imagine that you’re the owner of a new small corner shop. You are doing well and want to determine how much you earned in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/11/05/jetbrains-academy-new-in-november/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update November 2024 – Project File Tooling, Compose Resources, KSP2, and Android Release Builds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 13:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.5.0 is now available! With this release, we’ve improved the IDE experience when working with multiple modules and project.yaml files, made nested completion in Amper configuration files more powerful, introduced support for Compose Resources and KSP2, improved Android release builds, and more! For the full list of changes and bug fixes in Amper 0.5.0, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2024/11/amper-update-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 11:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Java Annotated Monthly is here! Check out the latest news across Java, Spring, AI, and emerging technologies. We offer practical tutorials to enhance your skills, a curated list of November’s top tech events, both online and offline, and an exclusive feature by industry expert Mala Gupta. Stay informed, and stay ahead! Featured Content In this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/java-annotated-monthly-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wow! It’s easy to take the rapid pace of technological advancement for granted, especially given how many of us have been tech-natives for most of our lives. For Mac lovers, Infinite Mac takes a trip across the decades of the 1980s to 2000s through the lens of releases. Experience history all in your browser. Draw […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/04/dotinsights-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dobar Dan! Algorithm and Code Training School Heads to Serbia This Winter!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the beginning of 2025, the Algorithm and Code Training School (ACTS) camp is moving to an exciting new location – Serbia! While our summer camp in Romania was a great success, we’re taking things to the next level with an even more intensive competition format. This camp is perfect for young coders aiming to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/11/04/dobar-dan-algorithm-and-code-training-school-heads-to-serbia-this-winter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Full-Stack App With Go and React</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a language that emerged over 14 years ago, Go has many use cases. From web development, APIs, and CLIs to Wasm, cloud technologies, and even AI-powered tools, its applications are broad. The same goes for demo projects, which have countless variations and purposes! Now, wouldn’t it be great if there was a full-stack, API-oriented, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/11/04/create-a-full-stack-app-with-go-and-react/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Build GraphQL Services With Spring Boot Like Netflix</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Netflix Staff Engineer, Paul Bakker, to discover how Netflix implements GraphQL services with Spring Boot and the DGS framework. Date: November 14, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Netflix uses GraphQL and the DGS framework (recently fully integrated with Spring […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Memory of Stiver</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 13:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On October 20, the original author of the Fernflower Java decompiler, Stiver, passed away after a long fight against glioblastoma. Stiver was a German programmer of Russian origin, primarily developing software for medical equipment. Twenty years ago, he developed a deep professional interest in Java virtual machine internals. You may remember his research blog posts, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/in-memory-of-stiver/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Blogs for Experienced Programmers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following up on our previous article in which we shared some great multi-author blogs to follow, today we have a curated selection of personal blogs from top Java experts. These experts aren’t just the best at what they do – they’re also great at sharing their knowledge in ways that are easy to understand and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/top-java-blogs-for-experienced-programmers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
