<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 05:41:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.5 is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 05:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more details about the issues resolved, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/intellij-idea-2024-1-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #5: Smooth Parameter Replacement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 19:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            💡 TeamCity Pipelines by JetBrains is a new approach to CI/CD that offers blazing-fast pipelines to optimize your development flow. We release a new version every three weeks, and here’s what’s new in the latest edition. Imagine you could define parameters when configuring a pipeline and see their values right away, without all of the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue5-smooth-parameter-replacement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Renovated Kotlin Support – K2 Mode: What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we’ve gathered the essential information about K2 mode in IntelliJ IDEA. What does K2 mode do? K2 mode is a new implementation of the Kotlin support within IntelliJ IDEA that improves the stability of the IDE while also setting the foundation for supporting future Kotlin language features. What is the difference between […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/meet-the-renovated-kotlin-support-k2-mode/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | August 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? In 1936, Russian engineer Vladimir Lukyanov built a mechanical computer known as a Water Integrator that carefully manipulated water in a room full of interconnected pipes and pumps. The water level in various chambers represented stored numbers, and the computer could solve complex mathematical equations. I’m sure the last thing Vladimir wanted […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/01/dotinsights-august-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 Release Candidate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next major CLion release is around the corner, and the v2024.2 RC is already available! To install CLion 2024.2 RC (build 242.20224.214), download it from our website, update via the Toolbox App, or use this snap package (for Ubuntu). You need an active subscription or a trial license to use the CLion 2024.2 RC. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/08/2024-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – July Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 16:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Summer’s almost gone! Don’t delay upgrading your tech skills. Our July digest has it all: a new Git starter kit, fresh courses, top projects you can work on, career tips, events, and free educational licenses. Dive in and level up!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/31/jetbrains-academy-july-digest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Quality: Leadership Strategies for Finding and Supporting Quality-Focused Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 13:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why is prioritizing code quality so important? Building successful software products starts with getting the right team on board, but as any technical recruiter or team lead will tell you, this is often easier said than done. One of the greatest challenges leaders face is balancing culture, competency, and potential in order to grow teams […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/07/leadership-code-quality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KotlinConf 2025 Tickets Are Now on Sale!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The countdown to KotlinConf 2025 has officially begun, and we’re excited to announce that tickets are now on sale for this premier event, which will take place from May 21–23, 2025, in Copenhagen, Denmark! Organized by JetBrains, this is the largest Kotlin event in the world. Starting today, you can secure your spot at KotlinConf […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/07/kotlinconf-2025-tickets-on-sale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Platform Gradle Plugin 2.0 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 17:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Version 2.0 of the IntelliJ Platform Gradle Plugin is now available! Previously called the Gradle IntelliJ Plugin, this updated plugin for the Gradle build system simplifies the configuration of environments for building, testing, verifying, and publishing plugins for IntelliJ-based IDEs. Redesigned and rewritten, it addresses community-reported issues and feature requests from previous versions. The path […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/intellij-platform-gradle-plugin-2-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Teachers, Involved Students: Active Learning with the Capture the Flag Game</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 14:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, August 13, at 3:00 pm UTC for the livestream in the JetBrains Academy series for educators, Lazy Teachers, Involved Students: Active Learning with the Capture the Flag Game The relevance of traditional education and the necessity of an academic degree have long been debated in the tech industry. The rapid pace […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/30/lazy-teachers-involved-students-active-learning-with-the-capture-the-flag-game/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2024.2 Release Candidate is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 12:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2024.2 Release Candidate is available now! You can get this build via the Toolbox App or download it from our website. You can also download the build from inside GoLand by going to Settings | Appearance &amp;amp; Behavior | System Settings | Updates and selecting Check IDE updates for: Early Access Program. Download GoLand […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/07/30/goland-2024-2-release-candidate-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
