<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:15:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming Education: Tailoring Tools and Techniques for Rust</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disclaimer: This article was created using JetBrains Grazie, an AI-based writing and communication companion. With its help, the core topics of this rich and nuanced livestream were conveniently distilled into a compact blog post format. In the world of programming languages, the ability to learn and understand a language is a critical factor for developers. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/06/12/programming-education-tailoring-tools-and-techniques-for-rust/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2024.2 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 12:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post marks the start of the Early Access Program for DataSpell 2024.2. The DataSpell 2024.2 EAP 1build is now accessible for download, providing an early glimpse into the exciting updates on the horizon.You can download the new version from our website, update directly from inside the IDE or via the free Toolbox App, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2024/06/2024-2-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.36 Is Here, With Improved Syntax Highlighting for PHP, C/C&#43;&#43;, and Svelte, Better Remote Development With SSH, and Other Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.36 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this latest version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at this update’s highlights. Download Fleet 1.36 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/06/fleet-1-36-is-here-with-improved-syntax-highlighting-for-php-c-c-and-svelte-better-remote-development-with-ssh-and-other-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape The Future Of Embedded Development with CLion!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we believe in constantly evolving to meet the needs of our users. Embedded development is no exception, and we are looking for your feedback. Your experience and insights are essential to the continuous improvement of CLion, a JetBrains IDE. That’s why we’d like to invite you to participate in our survey, designed to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/06/shape-the-future-of-embedded-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream – An Authentic Voice in Young Professionals: Why and How Educators Should Foster It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 12:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, June 18, at 3:00 pm UTC for the third livestream in the JetBrains Academy series for educators, An Authentic Voice in Young Professionals: Why and How Educators Should Foster It with Andrew Paul. Andrew has extensive teaching experience at various academic levels. He started his journey in education with Kainos, Queen’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/06/06/an-authentic-voice-in-young-professionals-why-and-how-educators-should-foster-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 10:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? A commonly used sorting algorithm known as Bogosort is also referred to as the ‘slow sort’. Because the algorithm works by generating all permutations of its input until it finds one that is sorted, makes it significantly inefficient and impractical for large data sets. Despite its impracticality, it’s often mentioned in computer […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/06/dotinsights-june-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Trial Periods Now Available for Plugins on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 10:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Selling your plugins on JetBrains Marketplace comes with numerous benefits. The platform handles licensing and billing, eliminating the need for a custom solution and simplifying the checkout process by taking care of payment processing and sales-related communications. JetBrains Marketplace allows you to fine-tune your offering, including volume and community discounts, as well as coupons with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/06/flexible-trial-periods-now-available-for-plugins-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Code Analysis for Spring: Run Analysis, Fix Critical Errors, Hit the Beach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fun fact: 72% of our JVM users use Spring in their applications, especially in industries like manufacturing and finance. Why? Spring makes programming with Java and Kotlin quicker, easier, and safer for everybody – but it also comes with unique challenges. Why is it so tricky to manage code quality in Spring? Spring has a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/06/static-code-analysis-for-spring-run-analysis-fix-critical-errors-hit-the-beach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writerside’s First AI EAP Release is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 14:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The first Writerside build with AI-powered features is now available as part of its Early Access Program. Read on the full story, or jump straight to the new features. No longer a threat, AI is a writer’s friend Just one year ago, tech writers felt threatened by the AI breakthrough and were worried their jobs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/06/writerside-s-first-ai-eap-release-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the first Rider 2024.2 Early Access Program (EAP) build just around the corner, we thought we’d give you an idea of what we’re working on for the next major update. The following is a list of our priorities for the next release. Note that these are the features we’re working on, however some might […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/05/rider-2024-2-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 08:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly is here! This month, we’re thrilled to welcome Tom Cools to share some of the interesting things he’s found of late in our Featured Content section. As always, we bring you the latest Java news, highlighting the key JEPs set to be available in Java 23. You’ll also […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/java-annotated-monthly-june-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
