<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 10:08:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Transactions? Let Spring Debugger Do the Heavy Lifting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 10:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Framework’s declarative transaction management is incredibly powerful, allowing developers to simply add the @Transactional annotation to a method and let Spring handle the transaction details. However, misconfigurations or misunderstandings of how transactions work can lead to frustrating database transaction handling issues. Debugging these problems often means sifting through a lot of AOP proxy code, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/debugging-transactions-let-spring-debugger-do-the-heavy-lifting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: 2.2.20-Beta2, Shipaton 2025, and a New Face on the Foundation Board</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kodee here – your ever-cheerful tour guide through the ever-bustling streets of Kotlin-land. Summer may be the season for vacations, but we’re not slowing down! Let’s take a stroll through the latest news. What else to read YouTube highlights Check out some of the most popular videos on our Kotlin YouTube channel: And these are […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kodee-kotlin-roundup-july-25-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell Is Now an AI-First Tool for Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From the 2025.2 version onward, every paid DataSpell subscription includes JetBrains AI Pro for free, reflecting our commitment to bringing AI into our data products. Please note that the bundled AI Pro plan is limited to use inside DataSpell. Download DataSpell 2025.2 AI Pro included at no extra cost! You now get JetBrains AI Pro […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/08/dataspell-is-now-an-ai-first-tool-for-data-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? A feature of C# is null-coalescing operators. The ?? operator (null-coalescing operator) returns the left-hand operand if it is not null; otherwise, it evaluates and returns the right-hand operand. The ??= operator (null-coalescing assignment operator) assigns the right-hand operand’s value to the left-hand operand only if the left-hand operand is null. Welcome to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/12/dotinsights-august-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free JetBrains Student Pack – Your Toolkit for a Future in Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For a successful career in tech, having the right tools from day one makes all the difference. That’s why we created the JetBrains Student Pack – all-in-one development kit designed to help you learn to code, build real-world projects, and kickstart your future career, using the same tools trusted by developers at Google, NASA, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/08/12/jetbrains-student-pack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains with its CLion IDE Is Now an Official ST Authorized Partner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re pleased to announce that JetBrains has joined the ST Partner Program. Through this collaboration, we aim to improve the experience of embedded developers working with ST microcontroller solutions in CLion. Here’s what developers get from this partnership: About ST ST (STMicroelectronics) is a European company that specializes in designing, developing, and manufacturing semiconductor technologies. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/st-authorized-partner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KotlinX RPC 0.9.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 13:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release of kotlinx.rpc introduces significant improvements aimed at the long-term stability, maintenance, and evolution of the library. We’ve focused on decoupling dependencies and simplifying the API to create a more robust and user-friendly experience. Ready to get started? Build your next project with the interactive generator at start.ktor.io, or check out our samples on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kotlinx-rpc-0-9-1-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Integrate Qodana Into TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are many compelling reasons to use TeamCity as your CI server. Thanks to its out-of-the-box features, smart test management capabilities, and great scalability for enterprises, TeamCity offers a robust and reliable CI solution. But if you’re really looking to increase compliance and improve code quality and security, you can couple it with Qodana. Integrating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/08/how-to-integrate-qodana-into-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Assistant, Junie and Kineto Now Support GPT-5 by OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we are committed to delivering the best technologies to professional developers. We support multiple LLM providers across our AI products to ensure you have access to the right tools for your needs and the freedom to choose the ones you prefer. Today, we’re excited to announce that the latest model from OpenAI, GPT-5, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/08/07/gpt-5-support-in-ai-assistant-junie-kineto/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Drift: The Pitfall of Local Machines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve seen it before. Someone says, “It works on my machine,” and suddenly you’re deep in a rabbit hole trying to understand why a project that works perfectly on one machine fails to build or test on another. That’s configuration drift – when a developer’s actual environment starts to deviate from the project’s intended configuration. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/08/configuration-drift-the-pitfall-of-local-machines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 11:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this month’s Java Annotated Monthly – your pit stop for all things related to Java, Kotlin, frameworks, and the ever-shifting tech scene. From helpful reads to red-hot takes, we’ve lined up a range of articles for curious devs and ambitious teams. But wait, there’s more! As always, our AI corner is here, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/java-annotated-monthly-august-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Fixed in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the first-ever standalone What’s Fixed overview of an IntelliJ IDEA release! We are always working hard to make the IDE even more stable, reliable, and enjoyable to use. In previous releases, information about this work was blended into the What’s New content, making it very long and sometimes hard to grasp. To address […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/whats-fixed-intellij-idea-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Notebook Meets IntelliJ Platform: Advancing IDE Plugin Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The value of extensibility The ability to extend and customize software, from game mods to browser extensions, gives users a sense of freedom and the chance to bring their ideas to life. JetBrains IDEs already provide this sense of freedom through their support for plugins. For some time now, creating plugins for JetBrains IDEs has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/08/kotlin-notebook-meets-intellij-platform-advancing-ide-plugin-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
