<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:25:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 EAP 3: OpenCV Image Viewer and the Ability to Attach the Debugger to an Unstarted Process</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The third CLion 2024.3 EAP build, 243.18137.40, is out. You can download it for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 EAP This build introduces an OpenCV image viewer for you to use while debugging. It also gives you the option […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/10/2024-3-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of the Kotlin Language and How You Can Contribute</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 10:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin’s evolution is significantly influenced by its active community. From early ideas to the final features, it’s shaped by feedback, discussions, and real-world use cases. We call this process KEEP – the Kotlin Evolution and Enhancement Process. To keep you informed about what’s coming next, we’ve created the new Kotlin Language Features and Proposals page. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/the-evolution-of-the-kotlin-language-and-how-emyou-em-can-contribute/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: How to !create a Plugin for JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 07:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode, where we discuss whether you always need to create a new plugin with Jakub Chrzanowski. Date: October 17, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract We all aim to deliver – be it through writing new code, fixing bugs, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete the Un-Completable: The State of AI Completion in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code completion has always been a standout feature in JetBrains IDEs, helping developers code faster, smarter, and with fewer mistakes. But what if it could do even more? What if it could predict not just the next element but entire lines of code – or even complete blocks? That’s exactly what we’ve been working on. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/10/complete-the-un-completable-the-state-of-ai-completion-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for SLNX Solution Files</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 12:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For nearly twenty years, the .NET community has enjoyed working with solution files (*.sln). Due to their tooling-centered format, manually changing these files has always been challenging. Merge conflicts in solution files—much like merging CSPROJ files—were commonplace and often resulted in corrupted files or lost changes. The structure of SLN files is overly verbose—an empty […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/10/04/support-for-slnx-solution-files/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – October 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 11:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, Java fans! Get ready for a treat – it’s time for our October 2024 Java Annotated Monthly! We’re buzzing with excitement about Java 23, and we’ve got a bunch of ace articles and videos to keep you updated about the newest features. We’re also exploring some tech stuff beyond Java, and IntelliJ IDEA is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/java-annotated-monthly-october-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 4: Updated Run Widget, Support for Maven’s Split Local Repositories, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 4 is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 4 If you missed our previous overviews of the newly added features, visit the IntelliJ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt AI Directly in the Editor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 06:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With PyCharm, you now have the support of AI Assistant at your fingertips. You can interact with it right where you do most of your work – in the editor. Stuck with an error in your code? Need to add documentation or tests? Just start typing your request on a new line in the editor, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/prompt-ai-directly-in-the-editor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 3.13 and the Latest Trends: A Developer’s Guide to 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 19:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We invite you to join us in just two days time, on October 3 at 5:00 pm CEST (11:00 am EDT), for a livestream shining a spotlight on Python 3.13 and the trends shaping its development. Our speakers: They will discuss the most notable features of Python 3.13 and examine the industry trends likely to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/python-3-13-and-the-latest-trends-a-developer-s-guide-to-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Blogs to Follow in 2024 – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 15:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a world full of endless articles and tutorials, it’s easy to become overwhelmed by unreliable or irrelevant information. With so much out there, how do you separate the good from the great? This is where we come in! We’ve prepared two articles in which we’ve handpicked the coolest Java blogs that cut through the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/top-java-blogs-to-follow-in-2024-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm’s Interactive Tables for Data Science</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data cleaning, exploration, and visualization are some of the most time-consuming tasks for data scientists. Nearly 50% of data specialists dedicate 30% or more of their time to data preparation. The pandas and Polars libraries are widely used for these purposes, each offering unique advantages. PyCharm supports both libraries, enabling users to efficiently explore, clean, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/interactive-tables-for-data-science/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing TeamCity AWS Agents’ Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the key components of TeamCity’s ecosystem is the bundled Amazon Cloud Agents plugin, which allows our customers to leverage cloud agents to scale the performance of their build farms on demand. Given its widespread use and importance, ensuring its optimal performance is essential. As our user base and workload have grown, we’ve noticed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/enhancing-teamcity-aws-agents-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown-Powered Slides in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we have a JetBrains Community Contributor (JBCC) program aimed at helping community content creators get the most out of their JetBrains tools when creating articles, social media posts, videos, and public presentations. It’s a fantastic program where we try to provide help and feedback and learn from each other. One innovative idea we’ve […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/10/01/markdown-powered-slides-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.07.3 Bug Fix Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 10:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The TeamCity On-Premises 2024.07.3 bug fix is now available for installation! This update tackles around 20 issues, including problems with failing SSH agents on Windows, incorrect counts of pending changes and available agents, unexpected build cancellations, and more. Each bug fix not only improves performance, but also patches security vulnerabilities, making it highly recommended to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/teamcity-2024-07-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – September Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “Wake me up when September ends,” goes the famous song, and here we are! The JetBrains Academy team is back with updates: fresh courses, IT clubs for school students, and ways to boost your portfolio with real-world projects and certificates. Wake up and dive into the tech world with our latest digest!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/09/30/jetbrains-academy-july-digest-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 IntelliJ IDEA Shortcuts for Efficient Data Querying With the Database Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thanks to the dedicated SQL query console inside IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate’s Database Tools, you can easily modify and extract data from any database connected to your Java application without ever leaving the IDE. The query console comes with an SQL statement-specific code snippets library, code completion, on-the-fly error detection, and useful shortcuts – all to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/top-10-shortcuts-for-efficient-data-querying/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Big Deal About Endpoints for Python Web Development?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Python has almost 30 years of history doing Python web development. Can you believe it? But 3-tier web projects have gotten really complicated and stressful. You’re busy, everything is all over the place – it’s hard! But PyCharm is here to help: bring your work together with the Endpoints tool window. I just made a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/python-web-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
