<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 07:09:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.4 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 07:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor version for IntelliJ IDEA – 2024.2.4. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, please […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-2-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Interview: Nana Janashia on Her Journey to DevOps and First Impressions of TeamCity Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 16:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to bring you an exclusive interview with Nana Janashia, the mastermind behind the largest DevOps YouTube channel – TechWorld with Nana. Nana has built an incredible career, sharing valuable insights about automation, cloud-native technologies, and everything DevOps with her global audience. But did you know that her journey started in marketing? In this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/exclusive-interview-nana-janashia-teamcity-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth Challenge Returns in November!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Prepare yourselves for the second season of the JetBrains Academy Youth Challenge, the competition for young coders and mathematicians. If you missed out last time or are ready to prove yourself again, this is your chance to win special prizes and compete with students worldwide. Choose your track The challenge continues with two tracks: math […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/10/22/youth-challenge-returns-in-november/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Mellum: JetBrains’ New LLM Built for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has taken a major step forward in advancing AI-driven development tools with the launch of Mellum, a proprietary large language model (LLM) specifically designed to assist software developers. Currently available only with JetBrains AI Assistant, Mellum provides faster, smarter, and more contextually aware code completion. There are hundreds of LLMs. Why Mellum? Unlike typical […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/22/introducing-mellum-jetbrains-new-llm-built-for-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip User Experience Survey Results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Recently, we conducted our first DataGrip UX Survey to better understand and prioritize the pain points that have the greatest impact on your experience. The data and feedback we gathered have helped us refine our plans to focus on what matters most to you. In this post, we’ll highlight the key findings from the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/10/22/datagrip-user-experience-survey-results/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Godot Game Builds With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Godot, an open-source game engine known for its versatility and simplicity, is gaining popularity among both indie developers and the broader game development community. While Godot comes with its own scripting language, GDScript, it also supports the widely-used C# language, familiar to Unity and Unreal Engine developers. In this tutorial, we will use “Dodge the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/automating-godot-game-builds-with-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 EAP 5: Support for the Call Hierarchy in CLion Nova and the New Project Status Widget</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new CLion 2024.3 EAP build, 243.20847.43, is out. You can download it for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 EAP This build introduces two major features: support for function call hierarchy in CLion Nova and a new project status […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/10/clion-2024-3-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Gap Between the Classic and New UIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 15:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Any significant update to the UI and UX of a professional tool is likely to pose challenges for its users. We recognize that the new UI of JetBrains IDEs represents a major change and understand how unsettling it can be when the software you rely on for productivity is significantly reworked. However, in order for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/bridging-the-gap-between-the-classic-and-new-uis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 6: Updated Structure Tool Window, Streamlined GraalVM Native Image Debugging, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP build is here, bringing new features and improvements for you to explore! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 6 In this update, we’ve […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains at the ICPC World Finals 2024 Astana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 18:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year’s ICPC World Finals Astana was remarkable, and we were thrilled to be a part of it. The event brought together the world’s brightest young minds in competitive programming. Engaging with students, coaches, and the community was a valuable experience that reinforced our commitment to supporting emerging talent. The Opening Ceremony held at the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/17/jetbrains-icpc-world-finals-2024-astana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Exciting News &#43; Special Announcement!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 12:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, it’s Kodee here, your favorite Kotlin mascot. I thought, who would be better to bring you all the exciting news from the Kotlin ecosystem than the cutest member of the team – me. So, without further ado, let’s jump right in!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/kodee-s-kotlin-roundup-exciting-news-special-announcement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.7 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 09:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released a minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1 – 2024.1.7. You can update to this version from inside the IDE or via the Toolbox App. This version brings the following fix: For details, refer to the release notes. If you encounter any issues or would like to make a suggestion or a feature […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-1-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
