<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 09:17:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is It Still Worth Learning to Code in an AI World?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 09:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released some new AI features for the JetBrains Academy plugin. Learners will now be able to use machine translation of course content, theory lookup, and AI hints for Kotlin courses. At first glance, these might seem fairly tame. There are no big LLM integrations, JetBrains AI Assistant is not being marketed toward beginners, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/23/is-it-still-worth-learning-to-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Testing Spring Controllers With MockMvcTester</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Framework 6.2 introduced MockMvcTester to support writing AssertJ style assertions using AssertJ under the hood. If you’re using Spring Boot, the spring-boot-starter-test dependency transitively adds the most commonly used testing libraries such as mockito, assertj, json-path, jsonassert, etc. So, if you’re using Spring Boot 3.4.0 (which uses Spring framework 6.2) or any later version, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/a-practical-guide-to-testing-spring-controllers-with-mockmvctester/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD Security Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 12:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Software development moves fast – really fast. It can also involve multiple teams working from different locations around the world. However, while speed and collaboration can be great for developers and businesses, they can also create security challenges. With more entry points and less time to catch potential threats, each commit, build, and deployment is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/ci-cd-security-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aqua Sunset</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 12:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aqua was originally developed as a dedicated IDE for QA engineers working in automated testing. After carefully evaluating adoption rates, market trends, and user feedback, we have made the difficult decision to discontinue the product. While this was not an easy choice, Aqua did not reach the level of adoption we had anticipated. We believe […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qa/2025/04/aqua-sunset/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana For Code Quality in STEM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your code drives discovery. Keep it precise. In STEM fields, software isn’t just a product, it underpins innovation, research, and life-critical infrastructure. Qodana brings advanced static code analysis to STEM software projects, helping ensure code quality, security, and compliance where it matters most. Qodana for STEM Why code quality matters in STEM Software in science, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/qodana-for-code-quality-in-stem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discord for WebStorm: Less Noise, More Signal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TLDR: We’ve revamped the JetBrains Community Discord with dedicated WebStorm channels for announcements, discussions, help, and Q&amp;amp;As to create a more valuable community resource. We’ll have live office hours on April 23rd to connect directly with our team. Not part of our Discord community yet? Join the JetBrains Community Discord here to start connecting with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/04/discord-for-webstorm-less-noise-more-signal/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taint Analysis: Exploring Hidden Dangers in Your Team’s Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 20:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for an engaging roundtable discussion where our panel of developers will share their firsthand insights on the latest Taint Analysis from JetBrains. Discover how critical checks can improve codebase security and be easily implemented in your code review process. Session abstract Whether you’re new to JetBrains or looking to deepen your understanding of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/taint-analysis-exploring-hidden-dangers-in-your-team-s-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 15:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that the Release Candidate for MPS 2025.1 is now available! Download it today and be among the first to try out the latest features and improvements. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.1 RC Curious about what’s new? Check out this blog post for a deep dive into all the updates. The full list of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/04/the-mps-2025-1-rc-ready/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore 2025.2 Is Out With Report Tabs, Extended DuckDB Support, and Snowflake Key Pair Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 13:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.2 introduces several new features, including report tabs, DuckDB as a data source for SQL cells, Snowflake key pair authentication, and the possibility to use a custom JDBC driver for the Datalore server, which is particularly relevant for the On-Premises version. Datalore Cloud users have already received the new updates automatically, and Datalore On-Premises […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/04/17/datalore-2025-2-is-out-with-report-tabs-extended-duckdb-support-and-snowflake-key-pair-authentication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Gemini 2.5 Pro arrives in JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 12:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant now supports Google’s latest and most intelligent AI model, Gemini 2.5 Pro. This integration makes your JetBrains IDE even smarter, providing enhanced accuracy and deep reasoning capabilities to streamline your coding experience. At JetBrains, we aim to equip developers with AI tools that simplify complex tasks and make everyday coding more productive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/04/google-gemini-2-5-pro-arrives-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarter Kotlin Development With JetBrains AI: Junie and AI Assistant in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 12:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI is now a lot more useful for Kotlin developers. With the public release of Junie and a major update to AI Assistant, two powerful AI tools are now deeply integrated with JetBrains IDEs – and ready to help you move faster with less overhead. Whether you’re starting a new feature or cleaning up […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/smarter-kotlin-development-with-jetbrains-ai-junie-and-ai-assistant-in-your-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse: Enhanced Notification Options</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 10:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this TeamCity Pipelines release, we’re focusing on improving the user experience with more flexible notification options. You can now choose which specific email notifications you want to receive from the system. You can select between default or custom notification options or unsubscribe from everything. The following options are available for custom notifications: To change […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-enhanced-notification-options/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big News! JetBrains Qodana’s Code Quality Plugin Is Now Available for Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s no secret that Qodana is a team tool that JetBrains designed to integrate seamlessly with its suite of IDEs, but every team and tech stack is different. One common question remains: “What about other members of our team who still use VS Code or Visual Studio?” To help with this problem, we decided to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/visual-studio-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.03.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The first bug-fix update for version 2025.03, TeamCity On-Premises 2025.03.1, is out and ready to be installed on your servers! This update ships around 30 bug fixes, performance enhancements, and security patches. We highly recommend upgrading to keep your system secure and optimized. The list of resolved issues includes: See TeamCity 2025.03.1 Upgrade Notes for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/teamcity-2025-03-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2025.1: Unified PyCharm, Free AI Tier, Junie Release, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2025.1 brings major updates to improve your development experience. PyCharm is now a unified product, combining PyCharm Professional and Community Edition. Version 2025.1 also brings a free AI tier, the public release of Junie, the launch of Cadence, significant Jupyter enhancements, support for Hatch, Data Wrangler, and many other improvements. Get the latest version […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/04/pycharm-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2025.1: JetBrains Data Wrangler AI Agent, No-Code Data Preparation Flow, AI Quick Charts, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to introduce DataSpell 2025.1, the first major release of 2025. This update focuses on making data cleaning and preparation more intuitive and efficient than ever before. Download DataSpell 2025.1 JetBrains Data Wrangler AI agent With Data Wrangler, you can choose between a no-code flow or full AI automation. Easily toggle between: No-code flow […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/04/dataspell-2025-1-jetbrains-data-wrangler-ai-agent-no-code-data-preparation-flow-ai-quick-charts-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release is a major update that includes improvements in PHPStan annotations, Xdebug, and WordPress support, an AI Free tier and new subscription system for JetBrains AI, and more. Download PhpStorm 2025.1 PHP Code completion for @phpstan-type and @phpstan-import-type This release improves PhpStorm’s PHPStan annotation support, introducing code completion for array shape aliases in @phpstan-type […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/04/phpstorm-2025-1-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Support for new features in Scala 3 Context Bounds and Givens Scala 3.6 introduced a new syntax for context bounds and givens. You can read more about it in SIP-64. In short, before Scala 3.6, it was impossible to name the context bound in the same place where it was defined. The way to do […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2025/04/16/intellij-scala-plugin-2025-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.1 Arrives With Support for Out-of-Project Files in CLion Nova, Qt Renderers, the ST-LINK Debug Server, and West Build Options</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion 2025.1 is now available. This latest version of the JetBrains IDE for C and C++ includes the following key features: You can download CLion 2025.1 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu, or via a patch update from version 2024.3. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.1 CLion Nova […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/04/clion-2025-1-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2025.1 comes with several exciting updates to help you write better Go code and work more efficiently. This release introduces support for golangci-lint, improvements to the Rename refactoring and static analysis, smarter handling of the toolchain directive, and full support for Go 1.24. We’re also bringing major updates for JetBrains AI. Let’s take a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/04/16/goland-2025-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip 2025.1: Schema Context for AI-based Error Explanations, Introspection by Levels for MySQL and MariaDB, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2025.1 is here! This is the first major update of 2025. Let’s take a look at what it has to offer. For a detailed description of this update, visit our What’s New page. AI Assistant Connectivity Working with data Coding assistance
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/04/16/datagrip-2025-1-schema-context-for-ai-based-error-explanations-introspection-by-levels-for-mysql-and-mariadb-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2025.1: Major Improvements to JetBrains AI, Enhanced Angular Support, and Better Monorepo Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our first major release of 2025 is here! This version includes major improvements to JetBrains AI, enhanced Angular support, better monorepo support, a range of user experience improvements, and a whole lot more. DOWNLOAD WEBSTORM 2025.1 To dive deeper into what you can expect in the release, just carry on reading! The new features and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/04/webstorm-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 release has landed! It delivers numerous refinements across the IDE to enhance your productivity, the quality of your code, and your overall comfort. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/intellij-idea-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2025.1: Major AI Assistant Upgrade, Cloud-Based Code Completion for RBS, More Ruby 3.4 Support, Kamal Schema Updates, Enhanced RemDev, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2025.1 introduces a massively upgraded AI Assistant (code completion for RBS, offline mode, more models available, and other features), support for the latest Kamal version, debugging for multi-module projects, and significantly improved remote development. Below is a brief overview of the most notable features. For a detailed description of this update, please visit our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/04/rubymine-2025-1-major-ai-assistant-upgrade/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
