<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 10:54:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apply for an IDE Research Integration Grant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 10:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is devoted to bringing the latest ideas and technologies to developers worldwide. Many innovations are born in academia, and researchers are often looking for practical applications for their projects. We are introducing the IDE Research Integration Grant Program, aimed at computer science researchers who have already completed research projects they would like to deploy […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/05/09/apply-for-an-ide-research-integration-grant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the JetBrains Team at Microsoft Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 14:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On May 21–23, 2024, the Microsoft Build conference is bringing together a diverse community of coders and engineers, and JetBrains is happy to be a part of it. You can attend the event either online or in person in Seattle, WA, USA. To engage with us online, check out our partner page, and don’t forget […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/08/meet-jetbrains-at-microsoft-build-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Modeling in Python With Datalore and AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 13:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Risk is an inherent part of the financial landscape, and as investors, we’re constantly seeking ways to quantify and mitigate it. By modeling risks, we can assess potential losses and make informed decisions. By quantifying risk, we can develop strategies to minimize risk exposure and optimize returns. Python, with its rich ecosystem of libraries and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/05/08/risk-modeling-in-python-with-datalore-and-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next: The WebStorm 2024.2 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 10:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April this year, we released WebStorm 2024.1, our first major update for 2024. Thank you to everyone who is already using it and providing us with feedback. With April now behind us, we’d like to announce what we’ve got planned for the next release of WebStorm, which is scheduled for the end of July, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/05/2024-2-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Ecosystem Survey Insights: A Comparative Look at Students and Professionals</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 09:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our series exploring how market and user research is done at JetBrains continues. Want to learn more about research insights and take part in future JetBrains studies? Join our JetBrains Tech Insights Lab! The world of IT is a rapidly growing industry, attracting more and more people with a passion for creative and challenging tasks. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2024/05/developer-ecosystem-survey-insights-a-comparative-look-at-students-and-professionals/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.34 is Out With AI Code Completion for Python and Kotlin, Smooth Caret Animation, Force Step Into, and Many More Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.34 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this latest version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights of this update. Download Fleet 1.34 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed a number […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/05/fleet-1-34-is-out-with-ai-code-completion-for-python-and-kotlin-smooth-caret-animation-em-force-step-into-em-and-many-more-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate 2024.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate offers an extensive set of features that go beyond the basics, providing access to AI-powered coding efficiency boosters, seamless integration with numerous frameworks and technologies, powerful database tools, and more. Download IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate 2024.1 In our latest release, version 2024.1, we’ve introduced a range of enhancements to elevate your coding experience. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/05/what-s-new-in-intellij-idea-ultimate-2024-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains .NET Days Online 2024 – Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On September 25 and 26, 2024, we’re hosting a free, live, virtual event where community speakers cover topics they are passionate about: JetBrains .NET Days Online! Talk topics could be C#, F#, .NET in general, performance, refactoring, open source projects, frameworks like MAUI and Blazor, and more. We are looking for speakers who are interested […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/02/jetbrains-dotnet-days-online-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the JetBrains Content Creators Program!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you passionate about creating engaging content for the tech community? Do you enjoy sharing your coding journey with others? If so, our new JetBrains Content Creators Program is just the thing for you! At JetBrains, not only do we work to provide an exceptional developer experience, but we also strive to inspire and support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/05/02/introducing-the-jetbrains-content-creators-program/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Roundup: K2 Compiler Updates, Ktor News, Kotlin for Data Analysis, and Other Ecosystem Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 11:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this roundup, let’s delve into the key recent developments in the Kotlin ecosystem. Did you know that the JetBrains team regularly publishes a newsletter featuring major Kotlin ecosystem news? Sign up to stay up to date with all things Kotlin.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/05/kotlin-roundup-april-24/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
