<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:44:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How the IntelliJ Infrastructure Team Cuts Build Execution Time by 30% With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction JetBrains is known for developing some of the world’s most popular IDEs, including IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, and WebStorm. Supporting this development is a dedicated infrastructure team that ensures hundreds of developers can efficiently build, test, and release these products. At the core of their workflow is TeamCity, JetBrains’ own CI/CD solution, which powers build […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/03/how-intellij-uses-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.1 Goes Beta With Enhanced CLion Nova, Debugger, and Embedded Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 08:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of CLion 2025.1 is now available with key improvements and changes announced for the upcoming release. You can download build 251.23774.112 for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.1 BETA Read the full release notes on YouTrack. Below […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/03/clion-2025-1-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for Game Consoles in JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 16:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Big news for console game developers! As part of the 2024.3 release, JetBrains Rider added support for PlayStation®5 and Xbox consoles, allowing you to build, deploy, and debug your Unreal Engine and custom game engines directly on your preferred game consoles. Rider has excellent built-in support for working with C++, with lots of great functionality […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/03/14/support-for-game-consoles-in-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2025.1 Beta Is Here With AI Enhancements, Framework Improvements, and a Better User Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 11:18:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The EAP cycle for WebStorm 2025.1 is over, and we’re excited to share what’s included in the Beta builds. The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the Beta builds and keep both them and your stable versions up to date. You can also manually download the Beta builds from our website. DOWNLOAD WEBSTORM […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/03/webstorm-2025-1-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the JetBrains Team at GDC 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From March 17–21, 2025, the Game Developers Conference (GDC) will bring together professionals from across the game industry at the Moscone Center in San Francisco. JetBrains is excited to once again be part of this event, and we invite you to visit our booth to explore how our tools can enhance your game development workflow. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/03/14/jetbrains-meets-gdc-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Xdebug Helper Browser Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 09:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For years, PHP developers have relied on the popular Xdebug Helper Chrome extension to simplify their debugging experience with Xdebug. Unfortunately, this extension may soon no longer be supported, potentially disrupting developers’ workflows. To ensure that PHP developers can continue debugging without interruptions, we’re collaborating with Fraser Chapman on the official Xdebug Helper extension for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/03/jetbrains-xdebug-helper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 2 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 07:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_03_2025/14_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 2 is now available, bringing us one step closer to the major release! This build provides access to all the features we’ve rolled out in the Early Access Program, and there’s still plenty of time for you to explore and test them before the official release. You can download this version […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2025-1-beta-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunsetting Writerside IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 12:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_03_2025/11_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In October 2023, we launched the Early Access Program for Writerside – a tool for authoring, testing, and publishing documentation. Built on the IntelliJ Platform, Writerside was available in two versions: a standalone tool and a plugin for JetBrains IDEs. Our goal was to serve two key audiences – developers who document their work and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2025/03/sunsetting-writerside-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Essential Tools for JetBrains IDE Plugin Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for an insightful session on the top tools every plugin developer should know. IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Yann Cébron and Jakub Chrzanowski will walk you through essential utilities that streamline plugin development for JetBrains IDEs. During the webinar, you will discover how: No matter your level of experience, this webinar will equip you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/03/livestream-essential-tools-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-developmentlivestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Assistant Comes to Kotlin Developers in Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin developers can now enhance their workflows in Android Studio with the new JetBrains AI Assistant plugin, which is now available in Beta. This plugin offers AI-powered coding assistance, including code suggestions, AI-driven explanations, refactorings, commit message generation, and more – all within Android Studio. Backed by large language models (LLMs) from both JetBrains and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/03/ai-assistant-comes-to-kotlin-developers-in-android-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA’s Blog Feedback 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 10:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_03_2025/10_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the years, the IntelliJ IDEA blog has become your go-to hub for expert insights, handy tips, and tech inspiration. But we want more – we’re heading to perfection, and we need your ideas to get there. Fill out this survey to let us know what rocks and what could be even better. It only […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-s-blog-feedback-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
