<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 17:16:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 17:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta is now available! This means we’re in the final stretch before the major release, and you can try out all the new features and improvements right now. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 13:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The [InternalsVisibleTo] attribute in .NET is a powerful feature that allows an assembly to expose its internal members (normally only accessible within the same assembly) to another specified assembly. This is typically used in scenarios like unit testing or multi-assembly projects where tight integration between assemblies is needed. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/03/05/dotinsights-march-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Horizon: Top Three Updates Coming Soon From Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 14:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we head deeper into Q1 of 2025, some exciting new developments are underway. From expanding Qodana’s integrations with new IDEs to consolidating organizational data, many more promising new projects are in the works to help increase code quality in your team. Let’s take a look at the top three! An organization-wide dashboard Insights into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/03/qodana-roadmap-2025-q1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2024.1.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 07:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released an update to MPS 2024.1, which corrects several problems, mainly in the UI, indexing, and migrations. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.1.2 See the full list of fixed issues here. Download this latest version here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/03/mps-2024-1-2-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Gatherers: The API Your Stream Was Missing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 08:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with José Paumard, where we’ll explore the Stream Gatherer API in JDK 24 and how to use it effectively in your applications. Date: March 13, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract JDK 24 is bringing a new enhancement to the Stream […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/new-livestream-gatherers-the-api-your-stream-was-missing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Admission for the Computer Science and AI BSc Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 08:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Admission to the Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos is open! The JetBrains Foundation supports this bachelor’s program and offers 15 fully funded scholarships for the most talented applicants. The scholarships cover tuition, accommodation, medical insurance, visa fees, and spending money (€300 per month). Many students who graduate from bachelor’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/03/03/admission-for-the-computer-science-and-ai-bsc-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New MPS 2024.3.1 Bugfix Release Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released an update for MPS 2024.3 that brings numerous fixes. Check them out and see what you think. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3.1 See the full list of fixed issues here. Download MPS 2024.3.1 here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/03/mps-2024-3-1-has-been-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – February Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 20:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Here’s a roundup of all the good stuff from February – AI skills to develop, scholarship opportunities, the latest programming and AI trends, and, as a little extra treat, a discount on a Hyperskill Premium subscription!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/02/28/jetbrains-academy-december-february/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: UI Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog post, we created a basic integration test that: Now, let’s explore how to interact with UI elements in our tests. UI hierarchy IntelliJ-based IDEs primarily use Swing and AWT for their user interface, while JCEF is used in specific cases like Markdown rendering. This UI framework organizes elements in a parent-child […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/02/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-ui-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for Google Summer of Code 2025 and Contribute to the Kotlin Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 13:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin Foundation is once again participating in Google Summer of Code (GSoC), offering contributors an opportunity to work on open-source projects that shape the Kotlin ecosystem. This year, the program is expanding to include even more projects from Kotlin Foundation member companies like JetBrains, Google, Uber, and Gradle, providing contributors with mentorship from some […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/02/google-summer-of-code-2025-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Set of Bug-Fix Updates for ReSharper and Rider 2024.3 Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 10:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download. ReSharper 2024.3.6 This build contains a fix for an issue where xUnit v3 tests resulted in Inconclusive: Test has not run when executed in under .NET Framework. [RSRP-499789] Rider 2024.3.6 Notable fixes For the full list of changes, please see our issue tracker.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/28/resharper-rider-2024-3-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.4 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 07:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released another update for v2024.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This version brings the following refinements: To see the full list of issues addressed in this version, please […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2024-3-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 7: Maven 4 Support And Improved Support For Multi-Release JARs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 21:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 is here! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 7 The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Early Access Program is nearing its end, but there’s still time to explore […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD and Serverless Computing: Best Practices for Microservices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 13:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Mdu Sibisi, freelance writer, draft.dev. Cloud technology has reshaped how developers manage and deliver software. For example, “serverless computing” allows a provider to dynamically manage the allocation and provisioning of servers for you, which makes it ideal for running microservices. When paired with CI/CD practices, serverless computing can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/ci-cd-and-serverless-computing-best-practices-for-microservices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Better Developer Experience: A Collaboration Between Gradle, Google, and JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The original blog post was published here. Developers are at the heart of everything we do. You are the ones who create all of those new things to make the world better. To do that effectively, you need tools to rely on that are powerful yet easy to use. That’s why Kotlin was created. But […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/building-a-better-developer-experience-a-collaboration-between-gradle-google-and-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
