<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:00:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learn AI-Assisted Programming With JetBrains Academy and Nebius</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learning to code with AI isn’t cheating – it’s the next skill every developer needs. AI tools are changing the way we write, test, and maintain code but using them effectively isn’t always straightforward. That’s why we’ve partnered with Nebius, an AI cloud platform known for its expertise in high-performance and AI-first workloads, to bring […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/15/learn-ai-assisted-programming-with-jetbrains-academy-and-nebius/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: GitHub Actions and Setting Up Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog posts, we created integration tests that interact with UI components, assert different properties of UI components, and interact with APIs. Now, it’s time to look at how to set up continuous integration to ensure that we don’t break them in the next commit. We will be creating continuous integration using GitHub […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-github-actions-and-setting-up-continuous-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbox App 2.6 Is Here With Remote Development Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Toolbox App 2.6 introduces support for remote development, allowing you to manage JetBrains tools and projects both locally and on remote servers. You can connect to different host platforms, including Windows, macOS, and Linux, and use the integrated OpenSSH for secure and customizable SSH connections. The Toolbox App supports connections to remote SSH hosts, as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/toolbox-app/2025/04/toolbox-app-2-6-is-here-with-remote-development-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q1 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Option to Cancel Continuity Discounts JetBrains Marketplace now allows plugin authors to cancel continuity discounts for paid plugins. This can be done easily from the Sales tab, with the option to set a specific end date. Customers with active subscriptions for existing plugins will still benefit from the discount, while for new […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q1-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind K2 Mode and How It Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m Yan Zhulanow, and I lead the Kotlin Analysis API team. Last year, we made a series of announcements about Kotlin K2 mode in IntelliJ IDEA. Now, as K2 mode is about to become the default, I am thrilled to tell you more about everything we had to go through to make this release happen. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/the-story-behind-k2-mode-and-how-it-works/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Increase Code Quality in GitHub With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 17:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago we shared a post on how to integrate Qodana with Github Actions on the .NET Community – but a lot has changed since then. Qodana self-hosted has been released, with analysis that can make your code more secure by detecting hardcoded passwords and running taint analysis for JVM. The new Android Linter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/code-quality-in-github/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Language Support in ReSharper and Rider 2025.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our release for ReSharper and Rider 2025.1 is just around the corner, and we have lots of exciting features shipping for the current and next version of C#! This will be a really long post (blame our awesome devs!), so make sure to use the table of contents on the right. Oh, and of course… […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/10/csharp-language-support-in-resharper-and-rider-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 – Help Shape the Future of Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since 2017, we’ve been checking in with developers around the world to better understand how the industry is evolving and how we can build better tools to support you. Now, the Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 is live, and we’d love for you to be part of it. This annual survey is a community milestone that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2025/04/10/developer-ecosystem-survey-2025-help-shape-the-future-of-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Context Parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Context parameters are an upcoming feature in Kotlin, with a variety of use cases including more powerful extension methods and better tools for DSL development. Kotlin 2.2.0 will feature context parameters in Beta, and dedicated IntelliJ IDEA support will be available from 2025.1. Context parameters replace another experimental feature in the language, namely context receivers. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/update-on-context-parameters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bug-Fix Releases Are Available – MPS 2024.3.2 and MPS 2024.1.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 11:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released updates for MPS 2024.1 and MPS 2024.3 that fix several additional issues. Check them out and see what you think. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3.2 Download MPS 2024.3.2 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Download MPS 2024.1.3 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/04/mps-2024-3-2-has-been-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown in Java Docs? Shut Up and Take My Comments!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 07:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you’re building a cutting-edge Java library, optimizing every method, and writing the most efficient algorithms. At some point, you’ll need to document your code because well-documented code increases adoption (a fact backed by various surveys). Including documentation comments within a Java class ensures that the documentation evolves with the code, keeping it relevant. Using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/markdown-in-java-docs-shut-up-and-take-my-comments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate is ready for you to try! The upcoming stable release delivers initial support for .NET 10 and C# 14 Preview features. It also brings the new Files view for repository-wide visibility, a Roslyn syntax tree visualizer, and numerous enhancements for debugging both .NET and C++ solutions. If you’re ready to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/rider-2025-1-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.1 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper and .NET tools 2025.1 RCs are now available. This ReSharper update delivers initial support for .NET 10 Preview and C# 14 features, along with expanded inspections, smarter refactorings, and noticeable performance improvements. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the next release, you can download the RC build from our website […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/resharper-2025-1-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 18:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Release Candidate is available for download, so we’re one step away from the major release! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. To use this build, an active subscription to IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate is required. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 RC […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/intellij-idea-2025-1-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Tools for JetBrains IDE Plugin Development: Livestream Recording and Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The recording of our livestream is available on JetBrains TV! In the recent session, IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Yann Cébron and Jakub Chrzanowski explored some of the most helpful tools for developing plugins for JetBrains IDEs. From plugin creation to UI debugging, the session covered practical tips and tricks to enhance your workflow. Let’s take […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/essential-tools-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-development-livestream-recording-and-key-takeaways/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Terminal: A New Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 13:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce our reworked terminal architecture, which is available in Beta starting with the 2025.1 versions of JetBrains IDEs. It now runs on a stable, standards-compliant core and uses the IDE’s editor for UI rendering. This change lets us introduce new features while preserving compatibility and performance across various platforms, whether local or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/jetbrains-terminal-a-new-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
