<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:31:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Java 24: Build Games, Prototypes, Utilities, and More—With Less Boilerplate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At ten, I sat in my school’s computer lab, in awe of a line drawing on the screen—my own code had brought it to life. “Yay! I coded that! I can code anything!”, I thought. My teacher, surprised, asked, “Wow! You did that?” It felt like magic, but it was more than that—I realized I […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/java-24-build-games-prototypes-utilities-and-more-with-less-boilerplate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines: SSH Authentication Option, Custom Git URL Support, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 11:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve been busy improving TeamCity Pipelines to make your CI/CD workflows even smoother. Here’s a quick update on what’s new! SSH authentication option Exciting news – we’re expanding the list of authentication options in TeamCity Pipelines! Now, you can easily authenticate using SSH. Once you set up SSH keys, you can push and pull without […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/teamcity-pipelines-ssh-authentication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 EAP 5: Roslyn Syntax Tree Visualizer, Unity Profiler Integration, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 17:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Rider 2025.1 EAP 5 has just been released! You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Here’s what you can expect from this update: Roslyn support enhancements Roslyn syntax tree visualizer Working with Roslyn […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/24/rider-2025-1-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science and AI BSc Open Day in Cyprus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 13:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos is opening its doors! Join us for our Open Day, where you will have the opportunity to meet the program’s professors and students and visit the campus. The JetBrains Foundation supports this bachelor’s program and offers 15 fully funded scholarships for the most […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/02/24/computer-science-and-ai-bsc-open-day-in-cyprus/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 6: Interactive Scratch Files in K2 Mode, Enhanced Dependency Resolution in Kotlin Script Files, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 07:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 6 is here! As we continue shaping the first major release of the year, you can get an early look at what’s coming by trying out the latest EAP build. You can download it from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: Intro, Dependencies, and First Integration Test</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 15:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following the enthusiastic response to our Plugin Testing: Performance, UI, and Functional Testing session at JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024, we’re launching a series of blog posts diving deeper into plugin testing strategies. This first post will guide you through setting up your testing environment and creating your first integration test, with detailed step-by-step instructions. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/02/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-intro-dependencies-and-first-integration-test/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doc-Powered AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 14:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with the 2024.3 version of JetBrains IDEs, AI Assistant can not only access the context from your project but also the IDE’s own documentation. Whenever you have a question about how to accomplish a task in a JetBrains IDE, such as WebStorm, IntelliJ IDEA, or PyCharm, AI Assistant is here to help. How do […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/doc-powered-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar – Uno Platform &amp; Hot Design for Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Tuesday, March 11, 2025, 15:00 – 16:30 UTC (check other timezones) for our free live webinar, Uno Platform &amp;amp; Hot Design for Rider, with Andres Pineda. Register now and get a reminder, or join on YouTube Hot Design is the industry’s first visual designer for cross-platform .NET applications. It transforms your running app […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/19/webinar-uno-platform-amp-hot-design-for-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Your React App Deployment With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial was brought to you by Kumar Harsh, a software developer and technical author. If you regularly work with React projects, you probably already know how tricky it can be to deploy them smoothly. Issues like manual errors, inconsistent deployment practices, and slow iteration cycles often turn React app deployment into a challenging process […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/automate-your-react-app-deployment-with-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces a New Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The YouTrack 2025.1 release introduces a bold new design that helps you navigate your projects and tasks more quickly. This new look and feel reflects years of learning about how teams work on projects. The new design introduces: Every day, hundreds of thousands of teams count on YouTrack to drive their business forward. We understand […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/02/youtrack-introduces-a-new-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do LLMs Benefit Developer Productivity?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 13:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LLMs are everywhere! I am sure you have heard of large language models (LLMs) and may have seen demonstrations of what they can do. You may have even tried to play with some of the popular ones yourself. No matter your opinion of or experience with LLMs, you cannot deny that they are a popular […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/how-do-llms-benefit-developer-productivity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 5: More LLMs in JetBrains AI Assistant, Improved Gutter for VCS, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 12:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 5 is out! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 5 Let’s take a look at this week’s fresh additions! If you missed our previous overviews […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDEs Aren’t Just for Developers: How QA, Tech Writers, and Designers Benefit Too</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 12:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud development environments (CDEs) have become a game-changer for development teams, and for good reason. They simplify workflows, reduce project setup time, and eliminate configuration headaches. While most discussions about CDEs focus exclusively on software developers, in reality, the benefits of CDEs extend far beyond coders. They can boost productivity for every team member involved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/02/cdes-aren-t-just-for-developers-how-qa-tech-writers-and-designers-benefit-too/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: TDD and Generative AI – A Perfect Pairing?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 11:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Bouke Nijhuis, where we’ll explore how test-driven development (TDD) and AI can work together to generate production-ready code. Date: February 27, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this talk, we will explore whether generative AI can generate working code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/new-livestream-tdd-and-generative-ai-a-perfect-pairing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Is the Best Python Web Framework: Django, Flask, or FastAPI?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 10:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Search for Python web frameworks, and three names will consistently come up: Django, Flask, and FastAPI. Our latest Python Developer Survey Results confirm that these three frameworks remain developers’ top choices for backend web development with Python. All three frameworks are open-source and compatible with the latest versions of Python. But how do you determine […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/02/django-flask-fastapi/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
