<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 07:11:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2024.3 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 07:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The second major release of CLion this year, 2024.2, introduced many improvements and advanced features. These include full line code completion for С++ that runs locally, Zephyr West support, and updates to the new CLion Nova language engine. If you still haven’t tried CLion 2024.2, download and try it today. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 We’ve begun […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/09/2024-3-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Jupyter Notebooks in PyCharm Professional</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 13:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm is one of the most well-known data science tools, offering excellent out-of-the-box support for Python, SQL, and other languages. PyCharm also provides integrations for Databricks, Hugging Face and many other important tools. All these features allow you to write good code and work with your data and projects faster. PyCharm Professional’s support for Jupyter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/how-to-use-jupyter-notebooks-in-pycharm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate Tester’s Day With JetBrains Aqua – 50% OFF!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Aqua is proud to join the global tech community in celebrating International Tester’s Day on September 9. This day recognizes the crucial contributions of QA professionals, who ensure that the software we rely on functions flawlessly and delivers a superior user experience. Buy Aqua – 50% OFF Why testers are our everyday heroes In […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qa/2024/09/celebrate-tester-s-day-with-jetbrains-aqua-50-off/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.40 Is Here With Compose Preview for Android, Inlay Hints for Generating Documentation for PHP and Groovy, and Other Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 07:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.40 is now available! In this release, we’ve introduced some new features while also focusing on many important bug fixes. Your feedback is vital to making Fleet even better. Please report any problems you encounter to our issue tracker, or add a vote to an existing issue to express your support. You can update […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/09/fleet-1-40-is-here-with-compose-preview-for-android-inlay-hints-for-generating-documentation-for-php-and-groovy-and-other-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the September edition of PHP Annotated! After a brief summer break, we’re back with all things PHP. This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise—we’ve done it for you. Highlights […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/09/php-annotated-september-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 12 Podcasts for Java Developers in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 08:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 2024, learning new things as a Java developer has never been easier or more fun! How about kicking off your morning with a cup of coffee while some of the biggest names in the industry chat directly into your ear? Or, imagine being stuck in traffic on your way to work, but instead of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/top-12-podcasts-for-java-developers-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing and Licensing Changes in RustRover and the Rust Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RustRover was initially released without support for web frontend technologies and databases. This decision was primarily based on EAP usage statistics and early research. It also allowed us to price RustRover more competitively. However, after the release, we received a large number of requests from our community asking us to support these technologies. Another piece […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/09/05/pricing-and-licensing-changes-in-rustrover-and-the-rust-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel Trends 2024: The Latest Market Insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we move through 2024, Laravel continues to solidify its position as one of the most popular PHP frameworks, powering a multitude of web applications across the globe. In this blog post, we’ll analyze the recently published State of Laravel 2024 survey results, highlighting key takeaways and what they mean for developers, companies, and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/09/laravel-trends-2024-the-latest-market-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This edition is packed with the latest news on Java, Kotlin, and other influential technologies in the IT world. Don’t miss out on exploring IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2, staying up to date with Java 23, grabbing your tickets for KotlinConf 2025, and learning about the newest developments […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/java-annotated-monthly-september-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘JEP Explained’ – a series of interviews on Java 23 features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The release of Java 23 is around the corner, September 17, 2024, to be precise. What’s new in this Java version and why should you care about it? If you want to know more than just the syntax of these new features – the bigger picture, behind the scenes stories, and real life experiences of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/jep-explained-a-series-of-interviews-on-java-23-features/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
