<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:25:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid Common Pitfalls With JPA and Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was written together with Thorben Janssen, who has more than 20 years of experience with JPA and Hibernate and is the author of “Hibernate Tips: More than 70 Solutions to Common Hibernate Problems” and the JPA newsletter. Kotlin and Jakarta Persistence (also known as JPA) are a popular combination for server-side development. Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/how-to-avoid-common-pitfalls-with-jpa-and-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.11.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The second bug-fix update for TeamCity On-Premises 2025.11 is ready to be installed! In this update, we have addressed a number of issues, such as: All TeamCity bug-fix updates include performance and security improvements, so we recommend that you never skip these minor updates. See TeamCity 2025.11.2 Release Notes for the complete list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/teamcity-2025-11-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platform Debugger Architecture Redesign for Remote Development in 2026.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ Platform provides a powerful debugger framework that plugins can extend to support various programming languages and runtime environments. To enable remote development scenarios – where the IDE interface runs on your local machine while code executes on a remote server – we’ve redesigned the debugger architecture. This guide walks you through the changes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/01/platform-debugger-architecture-redesign-for-remote-development-in-2026-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update your Kotlin projects for Android Gradle Plugin 9.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Android Gradle plugin 9.0 is now available, and it includes two major changes that will affect existing Kotlin projects: This post provides some details about these changes and points you to the resources that you’ll need to update your existing projects. You’ll also need to update tools and plugins that depend on AGP to their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/update-your-projects-for-agp9/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TransformConf: a New Conference on AI in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TransformConf, a new event focused on how AI is transforming software development, is coming in 2026! Save the date: September 15–16, London, UK. Early bird tickets are already available! AI is revolutionizing software development – that much barely needs saying. AI is already a daily tool for 85% of developers, and 68% expect AI proficiency […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2026/01/15/transformconf-a-new-conference-on-ai-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala 3.8 Support in the Scala Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, As I write these words, the Scala compiler team is wrapping up the Scala 3.8 release. It’s the last major release before a feature freeze. The next one, 3.9, will be the new Long-Term Support version. The compiler team decided that most of the work between 3.8 and 3.9 will go into stabilization, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2026/01/15/scala-38-support-in-the-scala-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Global Project Configuration: One Place to Manage All Your Qodana Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Global Project Configuration is a new feature that helps Qodana users manage linter settings across an entire organization or team – all from one location. Until now, maintaining consistent code quality rules meant updating configuration profiles in every individual repository. Whether you were approving new licenses, adjusting rule severity, or defining custom patterns for hardcoded […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2026/01/introducing-global-project-configuration-one-place-to-manage-all-your-qodana-rules/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights Into China’s Developer Landscape: Key Trends From the JetBrains Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every year, thousands of developers take part in the JetBrains Developer Ecosystem Survey, helping us map the evolving landscape of software development worldwide. Published in eight languages with data from 20 geographical regions, the survey includes China – a fast-evolving market that shares many global characteristics while retaining distinct traits of its own. For example, Java […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2026/01/insights-into-china-s-developer-landscape-key-trends/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.10.0: Unified @Preview, Navigation 3, and Stable Compose Hot Reload</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Multiplatform 1.10.0 has been released! We’re continually developing our multiplatform APIs and expanding support for Jetpack libraries commonly used on Android. Here are the highlights of this release: Get Started with Compose Multiplatform For a complete overview of the changes, check out What’s new in Compose Multiplatform 1.10.0 or the release notes on GitHub. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/compose-multiplatform-1-10-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to Compose Hot Reload 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Hot Reload has just been promoted to stable with our 1.0.0 release. We worked hard to build a technology that is easy to use and well-integrated into existing tools while also requiring zero configuration from users. The tool is bundled with Compose Multiplatform, starting from version 1.10 (see our dedicated release blog post). While […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/the-journey-to-compose-hot-reload-1-0-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2026.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re now working on our next major release, which we plan to deliver in March. In our latest stable version (v2025.3), we introduced many features and enhancements, so for the next release, we’ve decided to focus on maintenance and bug fixes rather than introducing new functionality. With that in mind, we’ve prioritized the following areas […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2026/01/2026-1-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 4: Delegation and Sub-Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 08:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously in this series: In the previous installment, we saw how to set up tracing, which brings us to two new questions: What should we experiment with based on the information this tool provides? And what parts of our agent could we improve using its observations? The first idea we had was to experiment with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/01/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-4-delegation-and-sub-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
