<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 09:37:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discontinuation of the SpaceCode Private Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 09:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2024/27_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dear customers, Today we are announcing the discontinuation of the SpaceCode Private Preview, which we launched in May 2024. On May 27, 2024, we announced that we had decided to discontinue Space and pivot it to a new product: SpaceCode. The plan was for SpaceCode to focus primarily on Git hosting and code reviews. For […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/space/2024/11/27/discontinuation-of-the-spacecode-private-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Roundup: Kodee’s Top Picks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 09:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2024/26_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone! Time flies, doesn’t it? It’s already my second edition of Kotlin Roundup, and I can’t wait to share the latest from the Kotlin ecosystem. Did you know that the JetBrains team regularly publishes a newsletter featuring major Kotlin ecosystem news? Sign up to stay up to date with all things Kotlin.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/kotlin-roundup-kodee-s-top-picks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve Advent of Code 2024 Puzzles in Kotlin and Win Prizes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DRAdvent of Code is the perfect opportunity to level up your Kotlin skills, whether you are a beginner or looking to finally tackle that advanced Kotlin feature you’ve been curious about. Here’s what’s in store: So join in, solve some Advent of Code puzzles, and enjoy the holiday coding spirit with Kotlin! About Advent of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/advent-of-code-2024-in-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant Integrates Google Gemini and Local LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve now added Gemini 1.5 Pro and Gemini 1.5 Flash to the lineup of LLMs used by JetBrains AI Assistant. These LLMs join forces with OpenAI models and local models. What’s special about Google models? Gemini 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash on Google Cloud’s Vertex AI will deliver advanced reasoning and impressive performance, unlocking several […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/11/jetbrains-ai-assistant-integrates-google-gemini-and-local-llms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Nova Improvements, Debug Servers, OpenCV Image Viewer, and Zephyr West Debugging in CLion 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 11:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion 2024.3 is now available. This latest version of the JetBrains IDE for C and C++ includes the following key features and updates: You can download CLion 2024.3 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu, or via a patch update from version 2024.2. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/11/2024-3-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Go Apps with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 11:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We live in a world where things change at a rapid pace, and the latest and greatest quickly becomes outdated. The same goes for deploying applications to servers. You used to have to physically travel to a data center to deploy your changes. Later on, we moved to VMs. Then containers came along and changed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/11/20/deploying-go-apps-with-kubernetes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
