<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:33:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in PyCharm 2024.2.2!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.2.2 is here with many key updates, including Python support improvements, new Django features, and enhancements to the Data View tool window! Visit our What’s New page for more details on all these features and to explore many others. You can download the latest version from our download page or update your current version […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/pycharm-2024-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn Rust in 2024: A Complete Beginner’s Guide to Mastering Rust Programming</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So, you’re thinking about choosing Rust as your next programming language to learn. You already know what it means to write code and have some experience with at least one programming language, probably Python or JavaScript. You’ve heard about Rust here and there. People say it’s a modern systems programming language that brings safety and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/09/20/how-to-learn-rust/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2024.3 Starts its Early Access Program!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 04:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Say hello to the first build of ReSharper 2024.3 Early Access Program! This build is mostly about improving C++ support, but it still has something new for C# developers as well. Let’s have a look! ReSharper Code Cleanup Now you can substitute a default Code Cleanup profile with another one for particular files via .editorconfig […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/20/resharper-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper C&#43;&#43; 2024.3 Starts its Early Access Program!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 04:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for ReSharper C++ 2024.3 has just begun! Move to Folder The Move to Folder refactoring now also handles C++ files (RSCPP-17126). After moving selected files to the new location, the refactoring will update the #include directives that reference the moved files. Language support ReSharper now supports the following new language features: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rscpp/2024/09/20/resharper-cpp-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.3 Early Access Program Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 04:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s start the last Early Access Program for JetBrains Rider this year! Rider 2024.3 EAP brings the following updates: Support for hot reloading C++ with Live++ We’ve been working with the folks at Live++ to bring seamless C++ hot reloading support to Rider! There’s no new UI, but the user experience will be a lot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/20/rider-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 2: Enhanced HotSwap in the Debugger, Faster Compilation in Multi-Module Projects, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 15:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 2 build is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 2 Discover the newly introduced features below! Debugger Enhanced HotSwap feature In the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in Writerside: The Good Docs Project Templates Right in Your Editor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 13:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “I hate to write, but I love having written,” a famous saying goes. Don’t we all – especially those of us who write functional texts, like technical documentation? We often have too little time to even convey the basic idea, let alone categorize and structure the information – whether it’s a how-to guide, a reference, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/09/new-in-writerside-the-good-docs-project-templates-right-in-your-editor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Approach to Build Runners | TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 11:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In TeamCity Pipelines, build runners tell the system how to build, test, and package your code. For this latest release, we’ve revamped how build runners work. Here’s what’s new: New design for creating a build step With this most recent release of TeamCity Pipelines, we’ve made creating build steps even more straightforward. You can now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/09/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue7-build-runners/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use FastAPI for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 08:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Cheuk Ting Ho, a data scientist who contributes to multiple open-source libraries, such as pandas, Polars, and Jupyter Notebook. FastAPI provides a quick way to build a backend service with Python. With a few decorators, you can turn your Python function into an API application. It is widely used […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/how-to-use-fastapi-for-machine-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.2 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 20:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released a new minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 – 2024.2.2. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. Here are some of the notable updates: To find out more details about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Quality Booster: Live Qodana Demo and Best Practices for Code Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a live demo of Qodana, the static code analysis platform from JetBrains. Discover how to integrate Qodana with your IDE and your CI pipeline, build quality gates, and catch critical issues early. Date: September 30, 2024 Time: 6 pm CET (4 pm UTC) Register for the webinar Session abstract Whether you’re new to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/09/code-quality-booster-live-qodana-demo-and-best-practices-for-code-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Introduces Free Online Clubs for School Students</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 09:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting in October, we invite teenagers interested in math, programming, and AI to join our free online clubs. Whether you want to participate in Olympiads or planning to study at high-intensity and prestigious STEM programs, our clubs will help you prepare and meet like-minded people from different countries. Take a closer look at the clubs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/09/18/jetbrains-introduces-free-online-clubs-for-school-students/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2024.3 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for CLion 2024.3 is officially launched. The first EAP build 243.12818.61 is now available, giving you an early glimpse into the enhancements we’ll include in the upcoming major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/09/2024-3-eap-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the new YouTrack 2024.3 release, one of the most hotly anticipated functionalities in the YouTrack roadmap – apps – goes live! Apps help teams customize YouTrack to fit their specific needs, improving project management, reporting, automation, and integration with other tools. You can now use and create apps to extend YouTrack’s functionality and add […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/09/youtrack-introduces-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 23 and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 15:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            New and updated Java language features, core API, and the JVM – Java 23 packs it all – for new Java developers to senior developers. IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 is ready with its support for Java 23 features. Keeping pace with new Java version releases could be difficult – what changed, why, and how to use […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/java-23-and-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a GraphQL Client in .NET with JetBrains Rider and StrawberryShake</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 14:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many teams are using GraphQL for their API needs, thanks to its powerful query language and flexibility. Unlike traditional REST APIs, GraphQL lets you fetch the data you need in a single request, making your applications more efficient and responsive. However, it can be daunting getting started creating schemas, writing queries, and integrating GraphQL into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/17/building-a-graphql-client-in-net-with-jetbrains-rider-and-strawberryshake/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RubyMine 2024.3 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re starting the RubyMine 2024.3 Early Access Program today. In this blog post, we’ll inform you about the upcoming features and updates in this release cycle. What’s coming in RubyMine 2024.3? AI Assistant For RubyMine 2024.3, we’re working on several Ruby-specific AI features, focusing on context improvements for AI-powered unit test generation, explanation […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/09/the-rubymine-2024-3-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Remote Development Challenges With CodeCanvas: A CDE Orchestration Tool by JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 07:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the public release of CodeCanvas, JetBrains’ new platform for orchestrating cloud development environments (CDEs). To better understand CodeCanvas and why it is important for JetBrains’ remote development strategy, let’s dive a bit into history and context. Remote development trend Many companies still rely on local development, a method that has several […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/09/17/introducing-codecanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Developing Spring Boot Applications With Joy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 12:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode, where we will explore how to build modern Spring Boot applications using IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate with Siva Reddy. Date: September 26, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Spring Boot is the most popular application framework in the Java […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Ways To Use Jupyter Notebooks inside PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 10:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Jupyter notebooks allow you to tell stories by creating and sharing data, equations, and visualizations sequentially, with a supporting narrative as you go through the notebook. Jupyter notebooks in PyCharm Professional provide functionality above and beyond that of browser-based Jupyter notebooks, such as code completion, dynamic plots, and quick statistics, to help you explore and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/7-ways-to-use-jupyter-notebooks-inside-pycharm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Htmx for Spring Boot Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 09:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting a new project can be both exciting and challenging at the same time. Choosing what technologies will help you deliver your solution comes with the cost associated with those choices. Each additional technology can bring issues and dependencies that can lead to incremental decreases in progress that can grind your project to a stop. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/introduction-to-htmx-for-spring-boot-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
