<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:45:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mellum: How We Trained a Model to Excel in Code Completion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code completion has always been a defining strength of JetBrains products. So, when adding AI into our products, we knew it had to deliver top-tier code completion. This post covers how we trained the model behind our cloud-based completion. Initial research: What about obvious model options? We started by testing both closed-source LLMs via APIs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/04/mellum-how-we-trained-a-model-to-excel-in-code-completion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Java Code in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 09:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will look at how to debug Java code using the IntelliJ IDEA debugger. We will look at how to fix a failing test, how to find out where an Exception is thrown, and how to find problems with our data. And we will learn some neat tricks about the debugger […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/debugging-java-code-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is It Still Worth Learning to Code in an AI World?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 09:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released some new AI features for the JetBrains Academy plugin. Learners will now be able to use machine translation of course content, theory lookup, and AI hints for Kotlin courses. At first glance, these might seem fairly tame. There are no big LLM integrations, JetBrains AI Assistant is not being marketed toward beginners, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/23/is-it-still-worth-learning-to-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Testing Spring Controllers With MockMvcTester</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Framework 6.2 introduced MockMvcTester to support writing AssertJ style assertions using AssertJ under the hood. If you’re using Spring Boot, the spring-boot-starter-test dependency transitively adds the most commonly used testing libraries such as mockito, assertj, json-path, jsonassert, etc. So, if you’re using Spring Boot 3.4.0 (which uses Spring framework 6.2) or any later version, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/a-practical-guide-to-testing-spring-controllers-with-mockmvctester/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD Security Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 12:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Software development moves fast – really fast. It can also involve multiple teams working from different locations around the world. However, while speed and collaboration can be great for developers and businesses, they can also create security challenges. With more entry points and less time to catch potential threats, each commit, build, and deployment is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/ci-cd-security-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aqua Sunset</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 12:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aqua was originally developed as a dedicated IDE for QA engineers working in automated testing. After carefully evaluating adoption rates, market trends, and user feedback, we have made the difficult decision to discontinue the product. While this was not an easy choice, Aqua did not reach the level of adoption we had anticipated. We believe […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qa/2025/04/aqua-sunset/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana For Code Quality in STEM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your code drives discovery. Keep it precise. In STEM fields, software isn’t just a product, it underpins innovation, research, and life-critical infrastructure. Qodana brings advanced static code analysis to STEM software projects, helping ensure code quality, security, and compliance where it matters most. Qodana for STEM Why code quality matters in STEM Software in science, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/qodana-for-code-quality-in-stem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discord for WebStorm: Less Noise, More Signal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TLDR: We’ve revamped the JetBrains Community Discord with dedicated WebStorm channels for announcements, discussions, help, and Q&amp;amp;As to create a more valuable community resource. We’ll have live office hours on April 23rd to connect directly with our team. Not part of our Discord community yet? Join the JetBrains Community Discord here to start connecting with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/04/discord-for-webstorm-less-noise-more-signal/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taint Analysis: Exploring Hidden Dangers in Your Team’s Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 20:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for an engaging roundtable discussion where our panel of developers will share their firsthand insights on the latest Taint Analysis from JetBrains. Discover how critical checks can improve codebase security and be easily implemented in your code review process. Session abstract Whether you’re new to JetBrains or looking to deepen your understanding of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/taint-analysis-exploring-hidden-dangers-in-your-team-s-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 15:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that the Release Candidate for MPS 2025.1 is now available! Download it today and be among the first to try out the latest features and improvements. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.1 RC Curious about what’s new? Check out this blog post for a deep dive into all the updates. The full list of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/04/the-mps-2025-1-rc-ready/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore 2025.2 Is Out With Report Tabs, Extended DuckDB Support, and Snowflake Key Pair Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 13:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.2 introduces several new features, including report tabs, DuckDB as a data source for SQL cells, Snowflake key pair authentication, and the possibility to use a custom JDBC driver for the Datalore server, which is particularly relevant for the On-Premises version. Datalore Cloud users have already received the new updates automatically, and Datalore On-Premises […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/04/17/datalore-2025-2-is-out-with-report-tabs-extended-duckdb-support-and-snowflake-key-pair-authentication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Gemini 2.5 Pro arrives in JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 12:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant now supports Google’s latest and most intelligent AI model, Gemini 2.5 Pro. This integration makes your JetBrains IDE even smarter, providing enhanced accuracy and deep reasoning capabilities to streamline your coding experience. At JetBrains, we aim to equip developers with AI tools that simplify complex tasks and make everyday coding more productive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/04/google-gemini-2-5-pro-arrives-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarter Kotlin Development With JetBrains AI: Junie and AI Assistant in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 12:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI is now a lot more useful for Kotlin developers. With the public release of Junie and a major update to AI Assistant, two powerful AI tools are now deeply integrated with JetBrains IDEs – and ready to help you move faster with less overhead. Whether you’re starting a new feature or cleaning up […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/smarter-kotlin-development-with-jetbrains-ai-junie-and-ai-assistant-in-your-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse: Enhanced Notification Options</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 10:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this TeamCity Pipelines release, we’re focusing on improving the user experience with more flexible notification options. You can now choose which specific email notifications you want to receive from the system. You can select between default or custom notification options or unsubscribe from everything. The following options are available for custom notifications: To change […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-enhanced-notification-options/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
