<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 10:07:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.4 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 10:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.4 has arrived with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates included in v2024.1.4: To find out more details about the issues […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/intellij-idea-2024-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.1.5 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 10:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WebStorm 2024.1.5, the fifth update for WebStorm 2024.1, is now available! It contains several improvements from the platform. You can update to v2024.1.5 by using the Toolbox App, installing it right from the IDE, or downloading it from our website. Notable improvements Here are some of the notable updates included in v2024.1.5: That’s all for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/06/webstorm-2024-1-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 6: Streamlined Log Management, Enhanced Gradle Build Script Experience, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 06:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 6 is out! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 6 The latest build offers a streamlined user experience with Gradle build scripts, enhanced logging support for Java and Kotlin, and improvements to support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotCover Command Line Tools for Automation Testing Code Coverage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ultimate goal of creating a testing strategy is to be confident that you and your team have done their due diligence to deliver a quality product. Test harnesses typically include a mix of unit tests, integration testing, automation, and manual testing, each with advantages and disadvantages for your overall strategy. Determining the effectiveness of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/20/dotcover-command-line-tools-for-automation-testing-code-coverage/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy for Teams: How to Pitch It to Your Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 11:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a passionate coder using JetBrains Academy, you already know the incredible benefits of our project-based learning platform. Now imagine amplifying those benefits across your entire team. Here is why and how you should pitch JetBrains Academy for Teams to your employer. Why professional development is essential In the ever-evolving world of tech, keeping up […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/06/20/pitch-jetbrains-academy-to-your-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Fleet Plugins for Your Kotlin Codebase</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 09:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet is a code editor designed from scratch to be an extendable platform. Many pieces of Fleet’s functionality are implemented as plugins. While the Fleet team is working toward the Fleet Plugins Public Preview, we decided to share some ideas, details, and examples of why and how external developers are supposed to develop their own […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/06/custom-fleet-plugins-for-your-kotlin-codebase/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.1.4 Is Out! Nova Now Available by Default for New Users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 16:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since November 2023, our team has been diligently working on the implementation of the ReSharper C++/Rider C++ language engine. This project was initiated with a clear focus on our users, aiming to address the long-standing performance and quality issues of CLion, which were caused by the usage of the slowly performing engine. The most notable […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/06/2024-1-4-update-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2 EAP Digest #2: New TypeScript Engine, Ability to Run .ts Files, Git and Markdown Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re halfway through the Early Access Program for WebStorm 2024.2! It’s been a while since we walked you through the latest improvements and features in this release, so it’s about time for an update. Read on to learn about the key changes that made it into the EAP builds in the past few weeks. For […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/06/webstorm-2024-2-eap2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Bring Science Into API Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 13:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced development environment, effective API documentation is not just a nice-to-have, but a necessity. This blog post explores how understanding pattern recognition and learning styles can revolutionize the way we create API documentation. By examining the different types of knowledge present in API references and recognizing diverse developer learning strategies, we can create […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/06/let-s-bring-science-into-api-documentation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Move From pandas to Polars</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 11:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Cheuk Ting Ho, a data scientist who contributes to multiple open-source libraries, such as pandas and Polars. You’ve probably heard about Polars – it is now firmly in the spotlight in the data science community. Are you still using pandas and would like to try out Polars? Are you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/06/how-to-move-from-pandas-to-polars/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains to Integrate Google’s Gemini Models Into AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is planning to soon leverage Google Cloud’s Vertex AI by integrating Google’s Gemini models into its AI-powered coding tool, AI Assistant. This makes JetBrains AI Assistant the first of its kind to use multiple large language models (LLMs). JetBrains AI Assistant AI Assistant helps developers stay focused on creative challenges by handling routine tasks. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/06/jetbrains-to-integrate-google-s-gemini-models-into-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Style for Better Productivity – Tips and Tools from the Metalama Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 11:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While it may seem trivial, one of the first steps in creating a maintainable, team-friendly codebase is reaching a consensus on code style and ensuring its strict enforcement. This includes code formatting (spaces, blank lines, parentheses, and brackets), naming (casings, prefixes, suffixes, etc.), and usage of this, var and more. The ultimate goal? Make running […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/18/code-style-for-better-productivity-tips-and-tools-from-the-metalama-team/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 EAP 3: Improved GDB Performance and Enhancements for Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 15:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.2 EAP build (242.16677.29) is now out! It’s available from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 EAP Here are the highlights: The full release notes are available here. Find out more about our plans for this release in the CLion 2024.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/06/2024-2-eap-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venerable Used Datalore to Reduce Eight-Hour Excel Analysis to Two Minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 09:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Caught in a spiderweb of spreadsheets Like many financial organizations, Venerable faced hurdles due to its dependence on Excel. Changes in a single spreadsheet often triggered a chain reaction of adjustments across countless others, leading to mistakes and a lot of manual work. This setup resulted in a time-consuming, error-prone process that was amplified when […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/06/17/venerable-used-datalore-to-reduce-eight-hour-excel-analysis-to-two-minutes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 EAP 3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 20:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest installment in the Rider 2024.2 Early Access Program has just been released! Let’s take a look at the changes. Bundled .NET Watch Run Configuration plugin dotnet-watch is a .NET global tool specifically designed to monitor file changes during development and promptly reload or restart the target command. One of the standout features of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/14/rider-2024-2-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugger Upskill: Debug Without Breakpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 11:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a typical debugging scenario, you would set breakpoints to tell the debugger when to suspend your program. A breakpoint usually corresponds to the moment that marks the starting point for further investigation. Deciding where to set a breakpoint can be challenging. There might be situations where the exact line is unclear, or you might […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/debugger-upskill-debug-without-breakpoints/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
