<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:26:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – December Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the new year, the JetBrains Academy team wants your IT skills to shine brighter than a Christmas tree! 🎄 This newsletter is packed with global trends in computer science education, must-read books, tips for university entrance exams, IT contests, and some holiday presents to help you level up your skills. 🎁 Enjoy the gift, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/23/jetbrains-academy-december-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IntelliJ Scala Plugin in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2024/20_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Year in Review Time flies. Only a year ago, we saw the release of Scala 3.4.0-RC1, and now we’re trying out Scala 3.6.2 with many new experimental features. The last 12 months have brought many new features to the IntelliJ Scala Plugin as well. A year ago we introduced X-Ray mode, which lets you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/12/20/the-intellij-scala-plugin-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2025.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2024/19_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.1, which we’ll introduce early next year. After reading through your valuable feedback and feature requests, and taking into account our own strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following areas for development: 🚀 The CLion Nova language engine 🛠️ The debugger 🤖 Embedded development 🏗️ Project formats and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/12/2025-1-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Fleet’s New Islands UI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We envisioned Fleet as a coding tool with a clear minimalist design that doesn’t overwhelm and helps keep you focused. Today we’re introducing a new, bolder look for Fleet. We believe that this new direction in Fleet’s UI will help make your developer experience more cohesive, intuitive, and, of course, productive. New islands layout The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/12/introducing-fleets-new-islands-ui/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.44 Is Here With New UI, Zig Language Support, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.44 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about Fleet […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/12/fleet-1-44-is-here-with-new-ui-zig-language-support-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing klibs.io: A New Way to Discover Kotlin Multiplatform Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin Multiplatform is growing rapidly, with its ecosystem expanding and the number of libraries increasing by 35% in 2024 alone. However, with more libraries available than ever, finding the right one for your use case and target platforms can still be a challenge. Whether you’re looking for a solution to handle permissions on iOS and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/introducing-klibs-io-a-new-way-to-discover-kotlin-multiplatform-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Inspires Learners, IDEs Drive Them: Computer Science Education Trends 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Computer science education and literacy are skyrocketing in demand worldwide. To understand the latest trends, challenges, and motivations driving learners, as well as other factors shaping the field, we conducted the 2024 Computer Science Learning Curve Survey. More than 23,991 learners from 16 countries and seven broader regions completed our detailed questionnaire – equivalent to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/17/computer-science-education-trends-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Reasons You Should Use dbt Core in PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dbt Core is a modern data transformation framework. It doesn’t extract or load data and is only responsible for the T in the ELT (extract-load-transform) process. dbt connects to your data warehouse and helps you prepare your data so it can later be used to answer business questions. In this blog post, we’ll talk about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/dbt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
