<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:13:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Context Collection Competition by JetBrains and Mistral AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Build smarter code completions and compete for a share of USD 12,000! In AI-enabled IDEs, code completion quality heavily depends on how well the IDE understands the surrounding code – the context. That context is everything, and we want your help to find the best way to collect it. Join JetBrains and Mistral AI at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/06/context-collection-competition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Predict the Future of AI in Software Development!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 11:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever wanted to share your ideas about AI and have a chance at winning prizes at the same time? As a company dedicated to creating the best possible solutions for software development, we at JetBrains want to know what you think about AI in software development. In this post, we tell you more about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/06/predict-the-future-of-ai-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Learning, Part 2: Get Unstuck With AI Hints in Python and Kotlin Tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 08:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous post, we introduced AI-powered machine translation and inline theory definitions to help make learning smoother and more accessible. Today, we’re excited to share the next big step in bringing intelligent assistance to your programming journey: AI hints. This feature is designed especially for beginners who may get stuck while solving coding tasks […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/06/02/ai-hints-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Answers to Your KMP Questions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            During the Closing Panel at KotlinConf 2025, we received many questions about Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP), but unfortunately didn’t have time to address them all live. So we’ve decided to answer the most popular ones in a follow-up blog post. Will IntelliJ IDEA and Android Studio support full Swift navigation, completion, etc., for iOS code, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/get-answers-to-your-kmp-questions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 15:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the May edition of PHP Annotated! It’s been a minute since the last edition. Turns out time flies when you’re deep in foundation work, and the occasional existential debugging session. But we are back. Here’s everything you might’ve missed in the PHP world, we dug through the noise so you can just enjoy […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/05/php-annotated-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Verifier and API Compatibility Maintenance: Livestream Recording &amp; Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 13:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a recent session, IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocate Róbert Novotný walked through the Plugin Verifier—one of the most important tools for maintaining plugin compatibility across JetBrains IDEs. The session focused on spotting breaking API changes, avoiding internal APIs, and verifying plugin behavior across IDE versions. If you couldn’t join us live, the full recording is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/05/plugin-verifier-and-api-compatibility-maintenance-livestream-recording-amp-key-takeaways/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Live Watches in CLion’s Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest CLion 2025.2 EAP build, 252.18003.25, includes one of the most requested features for embedded development: live watches. It allows you to monitor global variables in real time without stopping the debugger or the program’s execution. This feature is particularly useful for embedded developers working with time-sensitive protocols, such as Bluetooth, or with physical […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/introducing-live-watches/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bug-Fix Releases Are Available for MPS – 2024.3.3, 2024.1.4, 2023.3.3, and 2023.2.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 10:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released updates for multiple major MPS versions that fix several additional issues. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3.3 and others Before using an updated version of MPS, you should be warned about a change that might affect you. As a result of our work to fix an issue related to build plugin dependencies, the build language was […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/05/mps-2024-3-3-has-been-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Java Open-Source Projects Use IntelliJ IDEA: Real-World Examples – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we build tools to help developers stay focused and productive, and we’re especially proud when those tools help power the open-source projects that developers around the world rely on every day. Shaping the direction of Java development, such projects contribute substantially to the vibrant Java ecosystem. This two-part series highlights some of the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/05/27/how-java-open-source-projects-use-intellij-idea-real-world-examples-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Qodana Directly on Your Local or CI Machine Without Docker Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Until now, Qodana linters have run exclusively in Docker containers. While this approach provided consistency and isolation, it also required significant effort for environment configuration, particularly for complex project setups or highly secured systems. Users have had to rely on the bootstrap mechanism to set up custom environments inside the Docker container, often duplicating the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/run-qodana-in-your-ci/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trader Verification Requirement on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 15:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To comply with the Omnibus Directive 2019/2161, JetBrains Marketplace requires plugin vendors to declare whether they act as professional traders or not. This ensures that consumers are properly informed about the legal status of those offering plugins on the platform and their corresponding rights stemming from the EU consumer protection laws.The Digital Services Act (DSA) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/05/trader-verification-requirement-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources, Bytecode, Debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 12:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When debugging Java programs, developers are often under the impression that they’re interacting directly with the source code. This isn’t surprising – Java’s tooling does such an excellent job of hiding the complexity that it almost feels as if the source code exists at runtime. If you’re just starting with Java, you likely remember those […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/sources-bytecode-debugging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
