<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:54:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Went to BazelCon 2025 – Here’s Everything You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, BazelCon was held at the Omni Atlanta Hotel at Centennial Park for a very special occasion: the tenth anniversary of Bazel 🎉 For me, visiting from Europe, Atlanta made quite the first impression. The city felt bigger than anything I’ve seen back home, and with KubeCon happening right next door, the streets were […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/11/bazelcon-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in TeamCity 2025.11: AI Assistant, New Pipeline Features, Enhanced Server Encryption Settings, and More.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity 2025.11 introduces new build steps for pipelines, enhanced encryption settings, and a refreshed experience that makes powerful CI/CD workflows easier to create and manage. Here’s what’s new in this release. Introducing AI Assistant (Early Access) TeamCity is a true powerhouse, but mastering every one of its features can be challenging. To help you get […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/11/teamcity-202511/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.3.0.3: A Fresh Set of Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another set of updates for the 2025.3 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.3.0.3 The most notable fix of this build is that extension methods from source-only NuGet packages are now recognized correctly in the editor and by InspectCode. [RSRP-502165]. You can find the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/27/resharper-and-rider-2025-3-0-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Could Simply Add Nullability Check Support… Without Even Noticing It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            (The Growing Pains of a Good Idea: What Happens After JSpecify Adoption Begins) The good news: JSpecify is finally here JSpecify adoption is accelerating. You don’t even need to “install” it – nullability support now arrives automatically with your dependencies. If you somehow missed the long history behind the JSpecify effort and want a quick […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/one-could-simply-add-nullability-check-support-without-even-noticing-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Spring Data AOT in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring’s AOT engine has been around since the Spring Native days, but Spring Data never really benefited from it – until now. Repository infrastructure is one of the most dynamic parts of the framework, and for years it relied heavily on proxies, reflection, and queries generated at runtime. That flexibility has a price: it slows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/spring-data-aot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Too Much News to Keep Quiet About</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve gathered the latest Kotlin highlights for you – from the Kotlin Reddit AMA and documentation updates to learning programs and Google Summer of Code 2025 projects. Whether you’re here to stay up to date or just looking for something interesting to explore, there’s plenty to dive into. Where You Can Learn More YouTube Highlights
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/kodees-kotlin-roundup-november-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 2: A Deeper Dive Into Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous article, we saw how to build a basic coding agent with list, read, write, and edit capabilities. Today, we’ll dive into how to extend the agents’ capabilities by creating additional tools within the Koog framework. As an example, we’ll be building an ExecuteShellCommandTool, teaching our agent to run code and close the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-2-a-deeper-dive-into-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open-source IntelliJ IDEA: A Simpler Way to Build and Contribute to the Community</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA’s source code has been publicly available for more than 15 years, helping millions of developers learn, experiment, and contribute to their IDE and build their own tools. Now, we’re taking our commitment to open-source to the next level by making it even easier for the community to explore, build, and contribute! What’s New? […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-open-source/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate KMP Watchlist: Level Up Your Skills in 10 Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The best way to skip the “beginner mistakes” phase is to learn from the teams who have already solved them at scale. For Week 3 of KMP Level Up, we’ve curated the Top 10 KotlinConf talks that cover the full spectrum of adoption, from massive production case studies to deep dives into the compiler. Whether […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/the-ultimate-kmp-watchlist/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update, November 2025 – Extensibility Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.9.0 is out, and it brings the first version of our extensibility prototype! Read on for all of the details, and see the release notes for the full list of changes and bug fixes. To get support for Amper’s latest features, use IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Beta (or newer). New Amper website We revamped our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/11/amper-update-november-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Kotlin Adoption Across Your Organization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the fifth post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/scaling-kotlin-adoption-across-your-organization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot 4: Leaner, Safer Apps and a New Kotlin Baseline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Boot 4.0 has officially landed. At JetBrains, we’ve been tracking the updates since the first milestones to ensure that IntelliJ IDEA delivers a smooth and reliable development experience. While many of the core capabilities come directly from Spring Framework 7, Spring Boot remains the adoption enabler that brings everything together: sensible defaults, consistent configuration, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/spring-boot-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more details about the issues resolved, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-2025-2-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Updates and Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of updates and bug fixes for the 2025.3 release of ReSharper and Rider has just been made public. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.3.0.2 For the full list of issues resolved in this build, please refer to our issue tracker. Rider 2025.3.0.2 For the full list of issues we’ve resolved in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/20/resharper-rider-2025-3-0-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn AI-Assisted Programming With Junie: Free Courses From JetBrains Academy and Nebius</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For over 25 years, JetBrains has been driven by a desire to make developers more productive and enhance the developer experience by providing smarter, more efficient tools. JetBrains Academy advances this mission by empowering learners to study computer science and gain hands-on experience with the professional tools they’ll use in their future careers. AI is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/11/20/learn-ai-assisted-programming-with-junie-free-courses-from-jetbrains-academy-and-nebius/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
