<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:15:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From AI-Generated to Production-Ready Code: WebStorm Refactorings for the Modern Workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve all been there. You ask your AI tool to generate a React component, and the initial result works perfectly in the beginning. The AI gives you a functional 250-line component that gets the job done quickly and is exactly what you need for rapid prototyping. But even though AI does indeed excel at generating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/09/from-ai-generated-to-production-ready-code-webstorm-refactorings-for-the-modern-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging Unit Test Generation with in-IDE TestSpark</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Test generation is an essential yet time-consuming part of quality assurance. Automating test-generation techniques means accelerating the development process and improving the quality of the final software. However, traditional automated techniques, and their respective tools, are not usually user-friendly, having a command-line interface and not being integrated with the IDE. To boost acceleration and quality […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/testspark-unit-test-generation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islands Theme: The New Look Coming to JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 16:24:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with version 2025.2.3, JetBrains IDEs will offer a new look: the Islands theme, available in both dark and light modes. This update is a visual refresh, which means that all functionality will remain the same. The new theme can be turned on or off in the Appearance settings. This step brings us closer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/islands-theme-the-new-look-coming-to-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.9.0 Released: Compose Multiplatform for Web Goes Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Multiplatform for web, powered by Wasm, is now in Beta! This major milestone shows that Compose Multiplatform for web is no longer just experimental, but ready for real-world use by early adopters. This is more than a technical step forward. It’s a community achievement, made possible by feedback from early adopters of the Alpha […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/compose-multiplatform-1-9-0-compose-for-web-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – September Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you remember, dancin’ in September? 🎶 This September, let JetBrains keep the rhythm of your studies strong with free JetBrains IDEs and tools for study, a brand-new collaboration between AWS and JetBrains Academy, exclusive opportunities for school students, and more. Ready to groove into learning?
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/09/19/jetbrains-academy-september/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 09:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.2 has arrived with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates included in this version: To find out more details about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/intellij-idea-2025-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A free, online event for the .NET community. JetBrains .NET Days Online returns for two focused days of practical talks, live demos, and real-world tips from community speakers and the JetBrains .NET team. Register now → Event basics Registration: https://lp.jetbrains.com/dotnet-days-2025 Agenda highlights Here’s a preview of what we’ve got in store for you: How to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/18/announcing-jetbrains-net-days-online-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Updates and Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of updates and bug fixes for the 2025.2 release of ReSharper and Rider has just been made public. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.2.2 To make your transition to Visual Studio 2026 seamless, ReSharper now installs a lightweight migration extension bundled with the product. This extension will be carried over automatically by […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/18/resharper-rider-2025-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Common DevOps Problems And How to Solve Them With GoLand</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most popular posts on the /devops subreddit says, “After 24 years in IT, I’m done. I don’t want to debug another YAML file. This is not how I foresee spending my life.” DevOps can be frustrating, and the 3,000+ people who upvoted that post clearly agree. It doesn’t have to be this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/09/17/8-common-devops-problems-and-how-to-solve-them-with-goland/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Debugger: ApplicationContext at Your Fingertips</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA has great support for debugging Java and Kotlin applications. But if you are building Spring Boot applications, you may want to access Spring components along with their metadata. That’s where the Spring Debugger plugin comes in. It makes life easier by letting you explore and use the entire Spring ApplicationContext right from your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/spring-debugger-applicationcontext-at-your-fingertips/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.3 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to kick off the Early Access Program (EAP) for Rider 2025.3! With the first preview build now available, you can try out the new features we’ve been working on and let us know what you think. Your feedback plays a vital role in shaping the final release. If you haven’t joined an EAP […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/17/the-early-access-program-for-rider-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.3 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that the Early Access Program (EAP) has started for both ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.3. The first preview build is now available, giving you an early opportunity to explore what’s coming in the next major release. Your feedback is essential in helping us polish these updates, so we’d love to hear […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/17/the-early-access-program-for-resharper-and-net-tools-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Farewell to Consoles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting from the 2025.3 release, DataGrip and other JetBrains IDEs with database support will stop using the term query console. From now on, we’ll use query file – because consoles were essentially files all along, and it’s time the UI reflected that. We’ve made the workflow simpler, more discoverable, and more consistent. A bit of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/09/16/a-farewell-to-consoles/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ: New AI Quotas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We hear you. And you’re right – the new quotas are a reduction from what you experienced. When we launched, we had little usage data for agentic experiences and no top‑up feature existed, so we set quotas much higher than the real cost of AI usage (tokens from providers) as a temporary measure. That felt […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/faq-new-ai-quota/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the next development cycle and inviting you to join it. The Early Access Program (EAP) for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 is now open, offering an early look at the new features and improvements we’re working on. By evaluating new features and sharing constructive feedback, you help us provide you with powerful, reliable tooling […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/intellij-idea-2025-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 25 LTS and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Java release cadence means we get a new Java version every six months. Java 25 was released on September 16, 2025. At JetBrains, we are committed to supporting new technologies in IntelliJ IDEA and adding useful enhancements for both stable and preview features. In this blog post, we will give you an overview of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/java-25-lts-and-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
