<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:01:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.44 Is Here With New UI, Zig Language Support, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.44 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about Fleet […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/12/fleet-1-44-is-here-with-new-ui-zig-language-support-and-more-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Fleet’s New Islands UI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2024/18_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We envisioned Fleet as a coding tool with a clear minimalist design that doesn’t overwhelm and helps keep you focused. Today we’re introducing a new, bolder look for Fleet. We believe that this new direction in Fleet’s UI will help make your developer experience more cohesive, intuitive, and, of course, productive. New islands layout The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/12/introducing-fleets-new-islands-ui/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing klibs.io: A New Way to Discover Kotlin Multiplatform Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin Multiplatform is growing rapidly, with its ecosystem expanding and the number of libraries increasing by 35% in 2024 alone. However, with more libraries available than ever, finding the right one for your use case and target platforms can still be a challenge. Whether you’re looking for a solution to handle permissions on iOS and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/introducing-klibs-io-a-new-way-to-discover-kotlin-multiplatform-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Inspires Learners, IDEs Drive Them: Computer Science Education Trends 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2024/17_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Computer science education and literacy are skyrocketing in demand worldwide. To understand the latest trends, challenges, and motivations driving learners, as well as other factors shaping the field, we conducted the 2024 Computer Science Learning Curve Survey. More than 23,991 learners from 16 countries and seven broader regions completed our detailed questionnaire – equivalent to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/17/computer-science-education-trends-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Reasons You Should Use dbt Core in PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2024/16_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dbt Core is a modern data transformation framework. It doesn’t extract or load data and is only responsible for the T in the ELT (extract-load-transform) process. dbt connects to your data warehouse and helps you prepare your data so it can later be used to answer business questions. In this blog post, we’ll talk about […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/dbt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With the JetBrains Bazel Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 09:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2024/13_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large Bazel projects are becoming increasingly common in modern software development. Unfortunately, the IDE experience for these projects often leaves much to be desired. In this blog post, we’ll explore the new JetBrains Bazel plugin and how it can enhance your daily work with Bazel projects. We’ll begin with an overview of what Bazel users […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/getting-started-with-the-jetbrains-bazel-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The last Early Access release of 2024 – content reuse ♻️ and more fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reusing content is one of the few things that software developers and technical writers are equally passionate about. Both know that avoiding duplication isn’t just a good practice, it’s essential – and it works for documentation, just as it does for code: When should you start reusing content in technical documentation? The general advice is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/12/the-last-early-access-release-of-2024-content-reuse-and-more-fixes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest in your Career With KotlinConf 2025 Workshops</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            KotlinConf workshops provide engineers with an opportunity to deepen their Kotlin programming skills. These hands-on sessions focus on real-world projects and solutions, guided by hosts who are either members of the JetBrains Kotlin development team or certified Kotlin trainers. These workshops will take place on May 21, 2025, in Copenhagen, and will cater to various […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/invest-in-your-career-with-kotlinconf-2025-workshops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the New Bazel Plugin EAP for IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce the public Early Access Program (EAP) of the new Bazel plugin for IntelliJ IDEA. It is available on JetBrains Marketplace for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3. This initial release supports Bazel projects focusing exclusively on Java and Kotlin. Support for more languages including Python, Go, and Scala is coming soon, while C++ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/introducing-the-new-bazel-plugin-eap-for-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From VDI to CDEs: Solving Remote Development Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) has been a popular solution for remote development, but it is not without challenges. At JetBrains, we’ve recently seen growing interest in Cloud Development Environments (CDEs) as an alternative. To understand why many are thinking about this shift, we contacted our customers and uncovered the key reasons behind the trend. In […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2024/12/from-vdi-to-cdes-solving-remote-development-challenges/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore 2024.5 Is Out With SQLite Support and an Improved Reporting Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 11:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2024.5 introduces SQLite support and an improved reporting experience that includes PDF export capabilities, new filters in interactive tables, and much more. Datalore Cloud customers have already received the new updates automatically, and Datalore On-Premises customers can upgrade by following these instructions. SQLite database support Datalore now offers native support for SQLite! You can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/12/12/datalore-2024-5-is-out-with-sqlite-support-and-an-improved-reporting-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Sentiment Analysis in Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 10:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sentiment analysis is one of the most popular ways to analyze text. It allows us to see at a glance how people are feeling across a wide range of areas and has useful applications in fields like customer service, market and product research, and competitive analysis. Like any area of natural language processing (NLP), sentiment […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/introduction-to-sentiment-analysis-in-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Single Jobs in TeamCity Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now debug individual jobs in TeamCity Pipelines. Instead of running the entire pipeline, just execute a specific job and get instant feedback without extra waiting. When you debug a single job, you can: When debugging one job, its dependencies will also be executed. Read more about job debugging in our docs. Bug fixes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/debug-single-jobs-in-teamcity-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Developer Ecosystem 2024: The Unstoppable Rise of AI, Leading Languages, and Impact on Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year winds down, we’re taking a moment to reflect on what shaped the developer landscape in 2024. Drawing insights from over 23,000 developers worldwide, this year’s JetBrains State of Developer Ecosystem highlights significant trends shaping the development world. The prominence of AI in software is growing, with four out of five companies embracing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2024/12/11/the-state-of-developer-ecosystem-2024-unveiling-current-developer-trends-the-unstoppable-rise-of-ai-adoption-leading-languages-and-impact-on-developer-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
