<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:04:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The last Early Access release of 2024 – content reuse ♻️ and more fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reusing content is one of the few things that software developers and technical writers are equally passionate about. Both know that avoiding duplication isn’t just a good practice, it’s essential – and it works for documentation, just as it does for code: When should you start reusing content in technical documentation? The general advice is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/12/the-last-early-access-release-of-2024-content-reuse-and-more-fixes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest in your Career With KotlinConf 2025 Workshops</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            KotlinConf workshops provide engineers with an opportunity to deepen their Kotlin programming skills. These hands-on sessions focus on real-world projects and solutions, guided by hosts who are either members of the JetBrains Kotlin development team or certified Kotlin trainers. These workshops will take place on May 21, 2025, in Copenhagen, and will cater to various […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/invest-in-your-career-with-kotlinconf-2025-workshops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the New Bazel Plugin EAP for IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce the public Early Access Program (EAP) of the new Bazel plugin for IntelliJ IDEA. It is available on JetBrains Marketplace for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3. This initial release supports Bazel projects focusing exclusively on Java and Kotlin. Support for more languages including Python, Go, and Scala is coming soon, while C++ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/introducing-the-new-bazel-plugin-eap-for-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From VDI to CDEs: Solving Remote Development Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) has been a popular solution for remote development, but it is not without challenges. At JetBrains, we’ve recently seen growing interest in Cloud Development Environments (CDEs) as an alternative. To understand why many are thinking about this shift, we contacted our customers and uncovered the key reasons behind the trend. In […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2024/12/from-vdi-to-cdes-solving-remote-development-challenges/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore 2024.5 Is Out With SQLite Support and an Improved Reporting Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 11:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2024.5 introduces SQLite support and an improved reporting experience that includes PDF export capabilities, new filters in interactive tables, and much more. Datalore Cloud customers have already received the new updates automatically, and Datalore On-Premises customers can upgrade by following these instructions. SQLite database support Datalore now offers native support for SQLite! You can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/12/12/datalore-2024-5-is-out-with-sqlite-support-and-an-improved-reporting-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Sentiment Analysis in Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 10:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sentiment analysis is one of the most popular ways to analyze text. It allows us to see at a glance how people are feeling across a wide range of areas and has useful applications in fields like customer service, market and product research, and competitive analysis. Like any area of natural language processing (NLP), sentiment […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/introduction-to-sentiment-analysis-in-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Single Jobs in TeamCity Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now debug individual jobs in TeamCity Pipelines. Instead of running the entire pipeline, just execute a specific job and get instant feedback without extra waiting. When you debug a single job, you can: When debugging one job, its dependencies will also be executed. Read more about job debugging in our docs. Bug fixes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/debug-single-jobs-in-teamcity-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Developer Ecosystem 2024: The Unstoppable Rise of AI, Leading Languages, and Impact on Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year winds down, we’re taking a moment to reflect on what shaped the developer landscape in 2024. Drawing insights from over 23,000 developers worldwide, this year’s JetBrains State of Developer Ecosystem highlights significant trends shaping the development world. The prominence of AI in software is growing, with four out of five companies embracing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2024/12/11/the-state-of-developer-ecosystem-2024-unveiling-current-developer-trends-the-unstoppable-rise-of-ai-adoption-leading-languages-and-impact-on-developer-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Organize Your Legal Team’s Work In YouTrack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s no secret that YouTrack is used by various sorts of teams, including legal ones. In conversations with our customers, legal technologies and legal operations are emerging as hot topics. YouTrack can help legal firms whose main areas of business are jurisprudence and providing legal services, as well as in-house legal departments at companies in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/12/how-to-organize-your-legal-team-s-work-in-youtrack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover JetBrains Consulting Partner Services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we are committed to empowering developers to do their best work with world-class tools. But even the best tools can deliver so much more when paired with expert guidance. That is why we’ve built a global network of Consulting Partners – professionals dedicated to helping you and your team maximize the value of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/12/10/discover-jetbrains-consulting-partner-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books for Beginner Programmers: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous post, we explored some must-read books for anyone starting their programming journey. This time, we’re focusing on books for specific programming languages, helping you get comfortable with your chosen tech stack. Whether you’re learning Python, Java, Kotlin, or C, there’s something here for everyone. Let’s turn the page and get started!📚 Python […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/10/books-for-beginner-programmers-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Python 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Michael Kennedy, the founder of Talk Python and a PSF Fellow. Hey there. I’m Michael Kennedy, the founder of Talk Python and a Python Software Foundation (PSF) Fellow. I’m thrilled that the PyCharm team invited me to share my thoughts on the state of Python in 2024. If you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/the-state-of-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: GraalVM and GraalPy Meet IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Fabio Niephaus to explore integrations for GraalVM, GraalPy, and other Graal Languages in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: December 19, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract GraalVM has become very popular in the Java community, not just because of its JIT compiler, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/new-livestream-from-code-to-clarity-with-the-redesigned-structure-tool-window-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New! Security Analysis Plugin for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Application security is a critical requirement in modern software development. The latest release of IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 – along with the optional new Security Analysis by Qodana plugin – elevates your security efforts with advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for code written in Java and Kotlin. Trained on popular OWASP security benchmark projects, this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/security-analysis-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 – 2024.3.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. v2024.3.1 introduces advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for Java and Kotlin. This allows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/intellij-idea-2024-3-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream alert: Ace the CSAI Math Entrance Test</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want to study computer science in Europe? Join the Computer Science and AI bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos – with exclusive JetBrains scholarships up for grabs! On December 18, 2024, at 5:00 pm UTC, we’re hosting a special preparation session to help you ace the entrance test for this BSc. You’ll get tips from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/06/livestream-alert-ace-the-csai-math-entrance-test/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Ruby Debugging: From puts to Professional Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Debugging is an essential skill in software development, and in this post, we’ll be looking at how to investigate the behavior of Ruby code. As the RubyMine team, we’ve accumulated considerable expertise in creating tools for Ruby developers, and we’re excited to share our experience and knowledge with you. Recently, at the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/12/mastering_ruby_debugging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code, Learn, Repeat: Get Ready for KotlinConf 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            KotlinConf has always been about more than just code – it’s where ideas spark, skills develop, and the Kotlin community comes together to share knowledge, connect, and celebrate. While we’re still crafting the 2025 program (stay tuned for the big reveal in February), here are the recordings of last year’s top talks to give you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/code-learn-repeat-get-ready-for-kotlinconf-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – November Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year draws to a close, the JetBrains Academy team has some exciting updates for you! In this newsletter, you’ll discover new courses, plugins to enhance your learning, tech career tips, and updates for computer science educators.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/05/jetbrains-academy-november-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3.20 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just published a maintenance update to IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3. This minor release includes several bug fixes and improvements to existing features introduced in the main release. Lambda breakpoints in the debugger We’ve made improvements to how lambda expressions are handled in the debugger. Previously, setting a breakpoint on a line with a lambda […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/12/05/intellij-scala-plugin-2024-3-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – December 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As 2024 wraps up, this December edition of Java Annotated Monthly brings you the latest on JEPs targeted for Java 24, helpful tutorials on Java, Kotlin, and AI, and more. This time, we’ve included thought-provoking non-tech articles perfect for year-end reflection. Plus, we’re thrilled to welcome Josh Long as our featured author, who will be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/java-annotated-monthly-december-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12: UI Updates, Experimental Kubernetes Executor Mode, Conditional Dependencies in Build Chains, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity 2024.12 introduces a redesigned UI, conditional build chains, simplified OAuth token management, and enhanced AWS and Perforce integrations. New features also include support for custom Kotlin DSL libraries, centralized refreshable token management, and single-action build chain approvals, among others. Conditional dependencies in build chains In TeamCity, you can break down complex build processes into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/teamcity-202412/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Do Sentiment Analysis With Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sentiment analysis is a powerful tool for understanding emotions in text. While there are many ways to approach sentiment analysis, including more traditional lexicon-based and machine learning approaches, today we’ll be focusing on one of the most cutting-edge ways of working with text – large language models (LLMs). We’ll explain how you can use these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/how-to-do-sentiment-analysis-with-large-language-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
