<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:46:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fleet Plugins – Now With Сustom Keymaps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            About a month ago, we launched a mechanism for publishing your color theme as a plugin. With the recent updates, we are extending Fleet plugin applicability even further by allowing you to publish your custom keymaps. You can now map Fleet actions to specific key combinations to streamline your development experience and share the resulting […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/09/fleet-plugins-now-with-sustom-keymaps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create With Kotlin Multiplatform and Win a Trip to KotlinConf 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To all students and recent graduates: The Kotlin Foundation is excited to announce the launch of the Kotlin Multiplatform Contest! Showcase your creativity and coding skills by building a cross-platform project using Kotlin Multiplatform and win a trip to KotlinConf 2025, the largest Kotlin event of the year. Take part Kotlin Multiplatform allows you to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/09/kotlin-multiplatform-contest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the New TeamCity Plugin for IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release of the updated TeamCity plugin for IntelliJ IDEA! 🎉 You can now download it directly from JetBrains Marketplace. Using the plugin, you can trigger TeamCity builds directly from within your IDE and test any changes before committing them to the version control system. Why get the new plugin? This […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/09/new-teamcity-plugin-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 08:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 is officially underway! The first EAP build is now available, offering you an early look at the first portion of improvements introduced for the next major release. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next: The WebStorm 2024.3 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In August of this year, we released WebStorm 2024.2, our second major update for 2024. Thank you to everyone who is already using it and providing feedback. With August now behind us, we’d like to announce what we’ve got planned for the next release of WebStorm, which is scheduled for the middle of November, with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/09/what-s-next-the-webstorm-2024-3-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2024.3 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 07:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The second major release of CLion this year, 2024.2, introduced many improvements and advanced features. These include full line code completion for С++ that runs locally, Zephyr West support, and updates to the new CLion Nova language engine. If you still haven’t tried CLion 2024.2, download and try it today. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 We’ve begun […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/09/2024-3-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Jupyter Notebooks in PyCharm Professional</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 13:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm is one of the most well-known data science tools, offering excellent out-of-the-box support for Python, SQL, and other languages. PyCharm also provides integrations for Databricks, Hugging Face and many other important tools. All these features allow you to write good code and work with your data and projects faster. PyCharm Professional’s support for Jupyter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/how-to-use-jupyter-notebooks-in-pycharm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate Tester’s Day With JetBrains Aqua – 50% OFF!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Aqua is proud to join the global tech community in celebrating International Tester’s Day on September 9. This day recognizes the crucial contributions of QA professionals, who ensure that the software we rely on functions flawlessly and delivers a superior user experience. Buy Aqua – 50% OFF Why testers are our everyday heroes In […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qa/2024/09/celebrate-tester-s-day-with-jetbrains-aqua-50-off/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.40 Is Here With Compose Preview for Android, Inlay Hints for Generating Documentation for PHP and Groovy, and Other Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 07:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.40 is now available! In this release, we’ve introduced some new features while also focusing on many important bug fixes. Your feedback is vital to making Fleet even better. Please report any problems you encounter to our issue tracker, or add a vote to an existing issue to express your support. You can update […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/09/fleet-1-40-is-here-with-compose-preview-for-android-inlay-hints-for-generating-documentation-for-php-and-groovy-and-other-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2024/09_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the September edition of PHP Annotated! After a brief summer break, we’re back with all things PHP. This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise—we’ve done it for you. Highlights […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/09/php-annotated-september-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 12 Podcasts for Java Developers in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 08:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 2024, learning new things as a Java developer has never been easier or more fun! How about kicking off your morning with a cup of coffee while some of the biggest names in the industry chat directly into your ear? Or, imagine being stuck in traffic on your way to work, but instead of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/top-12-podcasts-for-java-developers-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing and Licensing Changes in RustRover and the Rust Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RustRover was initially released without support for web frontend technologies and databases. This decision was primarily based on EAP usage statistics and early research. It also allowed us to price RustRover more competitively. However, after the release, we received a large number of requests from our community asking us to support these technologies. Another piece […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/09/05/pricing-and-licensing-changes-in-rustrover-and-the-rust-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel Trends 2024: The Latest Market Insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we move through 2024, Laravel continues to solidify its position as one of the most popular PHP frameworks, powering a multitude of web applications across the globe. In this blog post, we’ll analyze the recently published State of Laravel 2024 survey results, highlighting key takeaways and what they mean for developers, companies, and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/09/laravel-trends-2024-the-latest-market-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This edition is packed with the latest news on Java, Kotlin, and other influential technologies in the IT world. Don’t miss out on exploring IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2, staying up to date with Java 23, grabbing your tickets for KotlinConf 2025, and learning about the newest developments […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/java-annotated-monthly-september-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
