<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 12:19:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The State of Django 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 12:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you curious to discover the latest trends in Django development? In collaboration with the Django Foundation, PyCharm surveyed more than 4,000 Django developers from around the globe and analyzed the trends in framework usage based on their answers. In this blog post, we share the following key findings with you: Dive in to learn […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/06/the-state-of-django/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.1.2: What’s New!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 18:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.1.2 is here with features designed to enhance your productivity and streamline your development workflow. This update includes support for DRF viewsets and routers in the Endpoints tool window, code assistance for TypedDict and Unpack, and improved debugger performance when handling large collections. You can download the latest version from our download page or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/05/pycharm-2024-1-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Major Bug-Fix Release for All Versions: Update Your Server Now</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Summary Details Earlier this year, several critical vulnerabilities were discovered in TeamCity. If abused, the flaws might have enabled an unauthenticated attacker with HTTP(S) access to a TeamCity server to bypass the authentication checks and gain administrative control of the TeamCity server. All versions of TeamCity On-Premises through 2023.11.3 were affected by these vulnerabilities. Customers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/05/teamcity-major-bug-fix-release-for-all-versions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Hackathon, Powered by Google</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’re passionate about new technology and always excited to share our latest in-house fun. This April, we kicked off our internal AI Hackathon in collaboration with Google and with the support of our internal JetBrains AI and AI Assistant team. It was designed to get our teammates to step out of their daily […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/05/jetbrains-ai-hackathon-powered-by-google/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAP: JetBrains Qodana Now Supports C and C&#43;&#43; for In-Depth Code Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Qodana was created to help teams improve code quality across multiple languages. In light of this, we’ve recently launched the EAP for Qodana’s C and C++ linter, a tool designed to run static code analysis and provide deep insights into your work. In this post, we’ll dive into the essential features of Qodana’s C and C++ linter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/05/new-release-in-eap-stage-jetbrains-qodana-s-c-and-c-linter-provides-in-depth-code-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 Things You Didn’t Know About JetBrains Rider’s NuGet Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 09:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing package managers into the modern development workflow has been nothing short of transformative. If you’ve been a .NET developer for a long time, you may remember when we shared .dll files on community sites and consumed them from a lib folder at the root of our solution. Thanks to NuGet, those dark days of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/29/9-things-you-didn-t-know-about-jetbrains-rider-s-nuget-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2 EAP Digest #1: Better Tools Configuration Support, Svelte 5, Git Enhancements, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 08:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve kicked off WebStorm 2024.2 with a new Early Access Program (EAP). Please check out this blog post, where we explain the benefits of the program. If you haven’t already seen what to expect in WebStorm 2024.2, take a moment to explore our roadmap. The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the EAP […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/05/webstorm-2024-2-eap1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
