<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 09:50:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: The JUnit Crew Presents the Latest Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 09:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with JUnit team members to discover the most recent updates to the test automation framework. Date: November 27, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this session, the JUnit team will introduce the recent 5.11 release’s new features, as well as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/new-livestream-the-junit-crew-presents-the-latest-features/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Time-to-Code in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA’s power and wide range of functionality can make it somewhat resource-hungry. Depending on the project you’re working with, the IDE has been known to lag, which can naturally be frustrating. Perhaps the most common scenario in which developers are required to wait is when opening a project. IntelliJ IDEA needs to load and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/faster-time-to-code-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Game Development in Rust with Bevy: Key Insights from Herbert Wolverson’s Livestream</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disclaimer: This article was created using JetBrains Grazie, an AI-based writing and communication companion. With its help, the core topics of this rich and nuanced livestream were conveniently distilled into a compact blog post format. Game development in Rust is gaining momentum, and Bevy, a modern game engine focusing on Rust, is at the forefront […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/11/14/unveiling-game-development-in-rust-with-bevy-key-insights-from-herbert-wolverson-s-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover DataGrip 2024.3: New AI Assistant Features and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2024.3 is here! This is the third major update of 2024. Let’s take a look at what it has to offer. For a detailed description of this update, please visit our What’s New page. AI Assistant Working with data Code editor Connectivity If you’re interested in upgrading to DataGrip 2024.3, or if you have […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/11/14/discover-datagrip-2024-3-new-ai-assistant-features-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline AI Prompting, Coding Assistance for the dataclass_transform Decorator (PEP 681), and More in PyCharm 2024.3!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code smarter, optimize performance, and stay focused on what matters most with the latest updates in PyCharm 2024.3. From enhanced support for AI Assistant and Jupyter notebooks to new features like no-code data filtering, there’s so much to explore. Learn about all the updates on our What’s New page, download the latest version from our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/11/pycharm-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2024.3 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 11:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release is a major update that includes support for PHP 8.4, xdebug_notify(), Pest 3.0, and Pest parallel and mutation testing, and more. If you’re using PhpStorm together with JetBrains AI Assistant, it also got updated with the new AI code completion model, new inline AI prompting, and more. Download PhpStorm 2024.3 PHP 8.4 support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/11/phpstorm-2024-3-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 10:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2024.3 comes with a set of new features and inspections designed to streamline the developer workflow. For AI users, we’ve refined multiline code completion and added a brand-new inline prompts feature. Startup performance for large projects has also been significantly improved, and we’ve added support for some of the latest (and some upcoming) Go […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/11/14/goland-2024-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore On-Premises or Cloud: Which Suits You Best?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In an era where data is the new currency, the ability to quickly gain actionable insights can be a game-changer for businesses and research institutions alike. Shortening the feedback loop between data scientists, analysts, and business intelligence teams can lead to more agile and responsive strategies, ultimately speeding up innovation and optimizing operations. JetBrains has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/11/13/datalore-on-premises-or-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scala 3 support Transparent inline methods (experimental) Transparent inline methods in Scala 3 allow the compiler to reinterpret the method being inlined in the context of information known already at the compile time. Our support of this feature is still experimental and requires more work, but what we offer in this release already covers the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/11/13/intellij-scala-plugin-2024-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share Your Insights on Using Rider and Win a Prize!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to invite you to participate in our research study, which will be an informal interview. In it, we’ll ask you about your workflows, your experiences with Rider, the challenges you typically encounter, and your aspirations, as this will help us tailor our solutions to better meet the needs of developers like you. The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/share-your-insights-on-using-rider-and-win-a-prize/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3, our final major release of the year, is here! This update brings a range of new features and enhancements across the IDE to improve your daily development workflows. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/intellij-idea-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next major CLion release is approaching, and the v2024.3 Release Candidate (RC) is already available. You can download build 243.21565.198 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. You need an active subscription or a trial license to use the CLion 2024.3 RC. DOWNLOAD CLION […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/11/2024-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2024.3: Rails 8 Support, Inline AI Prompts, Integration With RBS Collection, Ruby 3.4 Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2024.3 is now available! The latest version of JetBrains’ IDE for Ruby and Ruby on Rails comes with Rails 8 support, including Kamal 2 code completion, nilability annotations from schema.rb for type support, and Solid Queue and Solid Cache code insights. Enhanced by JetBrains AI Assistant, RubyMine now offers faster and more contextually aware […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/11/rubymine-2024-3-rails-8-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant 2024.3: Refine Your AI Experience With Model Selection, Enhanced Code Completion, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant 2024.3 is here! A highlight of this release is the flexibility to choose your preferred chat model. Select between Google Gemini, OpenAI, or local models to tailor interactions for a more customized experience. This update also brings advanced code completion for all major programming languages, improved context management, and the ability to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/11/jetbrains-ai-assistant-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2024.3: Day-One C# 13 Support, Streamlined Code Cleanup, and Enhanced C&#43;&#43; Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce the release of ReSharper 2024.3! This release marks an important step toward a new approach to our product updates. With version 2024.3, we’re working to align ReSharper’s releases with major .NET SDK updates, aiming to bring you the latest C# capabilities as early as possible. While we can’t guarantee this timing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/resharper-2024-3-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotCover, dotMemory, dotPeek, and dotTrace 2024.3 Have Been Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dotCover 2024.3, dotMemory 2024.3, dotPeek 2024.3, and dotTrace 2024.3 have been released and are ready for download! Let’s take a look at what’s new with these .NET tools. dotMemory 2024.3 dotTrace 2024.3 dotCover 2024.3 dotPeek 2024.3 If you’re also interested in learning more about ReSharper 2024.3 or Rider 2024.3, please visit:
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/dotnet-tools-243-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.3: Same-Day Support for .NET 9 SDK and C# 13, Console Debugging for Game Dev, AI Enhancements, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that Rider 2024.3 is here. This release marks a major change to our team’s development process. Starting with version 2024.3, we’re aiming to align updates to JetBrains Rider and ReSharper with major .NET SDK releases. While this isn’t a guaranteed timeline for every release, our goal is to minimize the wait […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/rider-2024-3-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Development in Rider 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 07:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_24/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Remote development has long held promise for developers seeking flexibility. However, only in recent years has it become an indispensable part of modern development workflows that prioritize collaboration and scalability. Nowadays, developer teams often need to work from different locations while leveraging high-performance, shared environments that feel as reliable as their local setups. With JetBrains […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/remote-development-in-rider-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.3: Built-In Database Tools and SQL Support, Better AI-driven Code Completion, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our third major release of 2024 is here! In this version, you’ll find built-in database tools and SQL support, various quality enhancements, better code completion with AI Assistant, and a whole lot more. DOWNLOAD WEBSTORM 2024.3 If you only have a few minutes to explore the highlights of WebStorm 2024.3, check out our quick review […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/11/webstorm-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Language Support in ReSharper and Rider 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our upcoming 2024.3 release marks a huge milestone for our development process but especially for our users. ReSharper and Rider 2024.3 will be simshipped along with .NET 9 and C# 13! Yes, you heard right—no more waiting an extra few weeks or using our EAP builds to take advantage of the latest and greatest C# […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/12/csharp-language-support-in-resharper-and-rider-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Flyway for Database Migrations in Spring Boot Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most software applications use SQL databases on account of their reliability, consistency, and maturity when it comes to handling structured data. The database schema evolves over time as business requirements change to add new features or update existing ones. Object-relational mapping (ORM) frameworks like JPA/Hibernate provide an easy way to generate a database schema based […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/how-to-use-flyway-for-database-migrations-in-spring-boot-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Docs With Code Samples? Try Out the New Writerside EAP Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 15:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Each Early Access release is designed to make writing documentation easier and more enjoyable. This update is based on your feedback and focuses on improving code blocks, but there is more! Thank you all for sharing your ideas. It’s a pleasure to keep improving our product for you. Code samples in documentation: Stick to the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/11/writing-docs-with-code-samples-try-out-the-new-writerside-eap-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Your Coding Projects With JetBrains AI Assistant: My Journey to Build a Flask Web App</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: In this post, I walk through the process of enhancing a chatbot project from Hyperskill by adding a web interface with Flask, JavaScript, and HTML. I tried out JetBrains AI Assistant and documented how it helped me with common coding tasks like installing frameworks, debugging, and generating code snippets, streamlining my development workflow. From […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/11/boosting-your-coding-projects-with-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
