<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:35:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Query Consoles Are Coming Back</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi DataGrip and Database Tools community, Shortly after the 2025.3 release, your feedback made it clear that the redesigned workflow for query files and query consoles introduced issues in several important scenarios, especially when working with global data sources. After reviewing the impact, we’ve decided that the best course of action is to revert this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/18/query-consoles-are-coming-back/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adopting Kotlin in a Java-centric company is not about flipping a switch or rewriting everything “the right way”. It’s about people, timing, risk, and trust. Over the last four weeks, we’ve published a series of blog posts by Urs Peter, covering all of these aspects of migrating to Kotlin. In this post, we’ll tie the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/the-ultimate-guide-to-successfully-adopting-kotlin-in-a-java-dominated-environment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Programming Courses in 2025: New and Favorite Picks on JetBrains Academy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “It’s tiiiiiiiiiiiime!”, and not just for Mariah Carey on the playlist. Here’s our annual roundup of JetBrains Academy courses – the favorites you loved this year and the new courses launched in 2025. If you’re trying to figure out where to start, what to learn next, or how to invest in your future skills, this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/18/best-programming-courses-in-2025-new-and-favorite-picks-on-jetbrains-academy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When AI Amplifies Your Bad (and Good) Habits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is more like a megaphone than a magic wand. It amplifies what is already there. Whatever habits you bring to your workflow, good or bad, AI will turn up the volume. Every untested component, undocumented design, and ill-specified feature, to name a few, becomes louder when AI enters the mix. Teams with a clear […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/when-ai-amplifies-your-bad-and-good-habits/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.3 Has Been Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MPS 2025.3 introduces a major overhaul of the JavaDoc language, significant changes to generator plans, and a major update to the reflective editor. It also enables keyboard actions in the Logical view and allows TextIcon to offer visually distinct variants for light and dark themes. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 What’s new Check out all the available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/12/mps-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Leaders on the KotlinConf’25 Stage: What Global Brands Built With Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin ecosystem continues to grow among the world’s most recognized brands, including Meta, AWS, Duolingo, Uber, and others. At KotlinConf 2025, these companies took the stage to share practical, real-world engineering stories. KotlinConf is where developers can learn directly from the teams building products at global scale. Software engineers showcase how they are tackling […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/industry-leaders-on-the-kotlinconf25-stage/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip turns 10. Hidden gems of DataGrip.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking back Hello, friends! 10 years ago to this very day, DataGrip was born. That’s right, on December 16, 2016, the first-ever version of DataGrip was released! But the origins of DataGrip go back even further. We had already been working to create a database IDE for quite some time by then, and its codename […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/16/datagrip-turns-10-hidden-gems-of-datagrip/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.3.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.3.0 release is out! This version includes new language features, stable ones, and other features now enabled by default. This release also brings tooling updates, performance improvements for different platforms, and important fixes. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/kotlin-2-3-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs C&#43;&#43;: competition or evolution in systems programming for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C and C++ are the backbone of modern software. Operating systems, databases, game engines, and compilers all trace their roots to these languages. They give developers low-level control over memory, hardware, and performance. It’s a level of control that has defined decades of software development. However, the landscape has shifted, and the Rust vs. C++ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/12/16/rust-vs-cpp-comparison-for-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents, Protocols, and Why We’re Not Playing Favorites</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past few weeks, after we announced ACP protocol support, I’ve gotten lots of messages asking something along these lines: “Microsoft just launched AgentHQ for GitHub and VS Code. So, does this mean JetBrains will drop ACP? Will you only support your own thing now?” The quick answer: We’re not picking sides. Here’s why – […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/agents-protocols-and-why-we-re-not-playing-favorites/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.11.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have rolled out 2025.11.1, the first update for the major 2025.11 version. This bug-fix resolves a number of issues, including: Bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements, so we recommend installing them promptly. See TeamCity 2025.11.1 Release Notes for the complete list of resolved issues. Why update? Staying up to date with minor […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/teamcity-2025-11-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Tame Your Flaky Tests in TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Satish Subrahmanya, draft.dev. It’s 4:47 pm on a Friday. Your feature branch just passed all tests locally, and the code review went smoothly, so you hit the merge button. But then it happens: The CI build fails. The same test suite that passed five minutes ago is now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/how-to-tame-flaky-tests/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 3: Under Observation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously in this series: Two articles in, and our coding agent can already do quite a bit. It can explore projects, read and write code, execute shell commands, and run tests. Adding a definition of done (DoD) in our last article gave it the feedback loop it needed – the agent now iterates until all […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-3-under-observation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Qodana on Kubernetes: More Scalability, More Control</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As engineering teams scale, so do the demands on their tooling. Code quality checks that worked well for one repository or service often need a more resilient, automated, and infrastructure-native setup when development ecosystems grow. That’s exactly why we’re excited to introduce first-class Kubernetes support for Qodana, bringing fully automated deployments, lifecycle management, and future-ready […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/12/deploying-qodana-on-kubernetes-more-scalability-more-control/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: 4 Tools That Keep Systems Running</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference — the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and to contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/12/open-source-in-focus-4-tools-that-keep-systems-running/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Way to Explore kotlinx-benchmark Results with Kotlin Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Benchmarking is an important part of writing efficient Kotlin code. The kotlinx-benchmark library helps you measure and compare performance across different implementations or hardware configurations. However, raw text results only take you so far. Sometimes you need to visualize your data, not just read it. That’s where Kotlin notebooks come in. Kotlin notebooks combine the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/a-better-way-to-explore-kotlinx-benchmark-results-with-kotlin-notebooks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy Plugin 2025.11 is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the holidays just around the corner and the year coming to a cheerful close, we’re ringing in the final JetBrains Academy plugin update of 2025, version 2025.11! This release focuses on the introduction of the standalone Hyperskill plugin, expands achievement-sharing to IDE-based courses, and brings a number of improvements and fixes to make your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/11/jetbrains-academy-plugin-2025-11-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider and ReSharper 2025.3.0.4: Important Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another set of updates for the 2025.3 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. Rider 2025.3.0.4 Multi-agent experience in the AI Chat window: Junie and Claude Agent Claude Agent has become the first third-party AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/11/rider-and-resharper-2025-3-0-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
