<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 14:26:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – March Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 14:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            April is always a busy month in tech. For example, in April 1986, IBM became the first to use a megabit chip. In 1991, Java development began in earnest. And, of course, there’s April Fools’ Day – perfect for programming jokes and clever pranks. This April is certainly no exception! Check out fresh courses, events, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/01/jetbrains-academy-march/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and Deploying Microservices With Spring Boot and TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 13:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial was brought to you by Rajkumar Venkatasamy, draft.dev. Microservice architecture has become a cornerstone for building scalable and maintainable applications. Microservices allow individual services to be developed, deployed, and scaled independently, resulting in faster delivery cycles and improved fault isolation. For example, an e-commerce platform can use independent services to handle product catalogs, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/building-and-deploying-microservices-spring-boot-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper’s Out-of-Process Journey: Major Progress and Next Steps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 09:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Good news, everyone! After years of work on one of our most challenging projects, we’re excited to share major progress on ReSharper’s out-of-process implementation. For those of you who’ve been following our journey, asking thoughtful questions, and patiently waiting for updates, we want to let you know how far we’ve come. Your continued support has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/01/resharper-out-of-process-update/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update April 2025 – IDE and CLI Feature Drop!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 08:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.6.0 is out, with improvements to both the IDE and CLI experience. Read on for all of the details, and see the release notes for the full list of changes and bug fixes. To get support for Amper’s latest features, use IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta (or newer). IDE improvements Improved template workflows Templates allow […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/04/amper-update-april-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening the MPS 2025.1 Early Access Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re starting the EAP for MPS 2025.1. The first EAP build is now ready for you to download and try! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.1 EAP Check out the major new features in this release: Project view performance As a result of fixing MPS-38299 and MPS-37938, navigation in the logical project view has been substantially improved. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/03/the-mps-2025-1-eap-has-started-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Survey for JetBrains IDE Plugin Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you develop plugins for JetBrains IDEs, there is a good chance we have already met on the JetBrains Platform Slack, answered your questions in the plugin developer forum, or provided the IntelliJ Platform documentation you have read. Today, the IntelliJ Platform SDK team needs your help to gather feedback that will shape the future […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/03/a-survey-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 08:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 3 is ready for download! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, from inside the IDE, or by using snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Beta 3 This is the final Beta build, with the release candidate just around the corner. It’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/intellij-idea-2025-1-beta-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch Laravel Foundation Meetup at the JetBrains Office</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 13:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this month, we had the pleasure of hosting a community meetup in our Amsterdam office in collaboration with our partner DLF (the Dutch Laravel Foundation). The event brought together Laravel and PHP developers for an evening of technical talks, networking, and knowledge sharing. The Dutch Laravel Foundation is a non-profit organization that works to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/03/dutch-laravel-foundation-meetup-at-the-jetbrains-office/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDE Workspaces Development: Challenges and Plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 11:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a while since we announced workspaces for IntelliJ IDEA – a feature that lets you manage multiple projects in a single IDE window – and we’ve received tons of feedback and made a lot of improvements since then. We see this feature as a tool to improve the developer experience by allowing you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/03/ide-workspaces-development-challenges-and-plans/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn JavaScript This Week: Start Your Web Applications Journey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JavaScript is the backbone of modern web development, powering dynamic websites and creating interactive user experiences. It’s an essential programming language, whether you’re just starting out or already an experienced developer. JetBrains Academy’s new free course, Introduction to JavaScript, provides a clear and structured approach to mastering JavaScript quickly and effectively. Why learn JavaScript? Why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/03/25/course-javascript/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
