<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:57:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Faster Python: Concurrency in async/await and threading</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have been coding with Python for a while, especially if you have been using frameworks and libraries such as Fast API and discord.py, then you have probably been using async/await or asyncio. You may have heard statements like “multithreading in Python isn’t real”, and you may also know about the famous (or infamous) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/06/concurrency-in-async-await-and-threading/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Blocks in Java: Perfect for Multiline Strings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve likely used String variables to store values that span multiple lines, such as LLM prompts, JSON, HTML, XML, code snippets, and other such values. Some of these, such as a JSON value, include double quotes as part of the data. Imagine the inconvenience of using backslashes () to escape those quotes, indenting lines using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/text-blocks-in-java-perfect-for-multiline-strings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin for Server-Side Development: Community Content Roundup #2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin community keeps delivering valuable content for server-side development. From gRPC best practices to hands-on Ktor tutorials and Spring integrations, here are the latest highlights. 📖 [Article] Kotlin Tips and Tricks You May Not Know: #6 — Inject Functions in Spring Boot – Elena van Engelen-Maslova shares how to inject functions in Spring Boot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/kotlin-for-server-side-development-community-content-roundup-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PhpStorm Helps Maintain PHP Open-Source Projects: Interviews and Real-World Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The PHP ecosystem is driven by passionate developers building tools that power everything from content management systems right the way through to testing libraries and database layers. Behind each project is a dedicated team working to modernize code, improve performance, and move the ecosystem forward. The fact that many of these teams choose PhpStorm to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/06/10/how-phpstorm-helps-maintain-php-open-source-projects-interviews-and-real-world-examples/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL and NoSQL Query langauge support come to ReSharper!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 08:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ReSharper’s query language support for SQL and NoSQL provides C# developers with a more convenient way to work with SQL and NoSQL code directly in Visual Studio with ReSharper, supporting multiple SQL dialects beyond just T-SQL. It includes syntax highlighting, code analysis, auto-completion, and quick fixes to boost efficiency and catch issues early. Based on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/10/sql-and-nosql-query-langauge-support-come-to-resharper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside Ruby Debuggers: TracePoint, Instruction Sequence, and CRuby API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 07:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Debugging is a key part of software development, but most developers use debuggers without knowing how they actually work. The RubyMine team has spent years developing debugging tools for Ruby, and we want to share some of the insights we’ve gained along the way. In this post, we’ll explore the main technologies […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/inside-ruby-debuggers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Penetration Testing? Types, Processes, Tools, And Why It’s All Worth It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 14:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Penetration testing (or “pen testing”) is an authorized, simulated cyberattack designed to test the security of a production system. Ethical hackers perform penetration tests, emulating the behavior of cybercriminals to evaluate your software’s security and identify any weaknesses. During a pen test, these cybersecurity specialists use a range of techniques to attack a system. Once […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/what-is-penetration-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 14:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi there, Java fans! It’s a new month, which means we’ve got a new batch of hot news, deep dives, and tasty tidbits from the Java world for you to enjoy. In this edition, Piotr Przybył joins us in the Featured Content section to share his cultivated list of content finds. We’re also testing a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/java-annotated-monthly-june-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 14:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.2 has arrived with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates included in this version: To find out more details about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/intellij-idea-2025-1-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Truths About Developer Experience: Three Key Insights From Our Research</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 13:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developer experience (DevEx) and developer productivity (DP) are hot topics. Many companies are already working actively to measure and improve them, while others, if not already doing this, are at least aware of them. However, what we’re interested in is what’s really happening inside companies when it comes to DevEx and DP. To get a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/06/hidden-truths-about-developer-experience-three-key-insights-from-our-research/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 13:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The Original Name of .NET Was “Next Generation Windows Services (NGWS)“. Before Microsoft officially named it “.NET,” the platform was internally referred to as NGWS: Next Generation Windows Services. The name “.NET” was adopted in the late 1990s to emphasize the platform’s focus on web-based development and interoperability, as opposed to being […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/03/dotinsights-june-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: How Junie Uses TeamCity to Evaluate Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Junie is an intelligent coding agent developed by JetBrains. It automates the full development loop: reading project files, editing code, running tests, and applying fixes, going far beyond simple code generation. Similar to how developers use tools like ChatGPT to solve coding problems, Junie takes it a step further by automating the entire process. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/how-junie-uses-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! The RubyMine 2025.2 Early Access Program is already available! In this blog post, we’ll share the upcoming features and updates planned for this release cycle. What’s coming in RubyMine 2025.2? Debugger improvements We’re introducing a number of changes aimed at enhancing the debugger installation experience. The entire process will now take less time, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/what-s-next-for-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie and RubyMine: Your Winning Combo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Junie, a powerful AI coding agent from JetBrains, is available in RubyMine! Install the plugin and try it out now! Why Junie is a game-changer Unlike other AI coding agents, Junie leverages the robust power of JetBrains IDEs and reliable large language models (LLMs) to deliver exceptional results with high precision. According to SWE-bench Verified, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/junie-and-rubymine-your-winning-combo/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
