<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:07:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Open-source IntelliJ IDEA: A Simpler Way to Build and Contribute to the Community</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA’s source code has been publicly available for more than 15 years, helping millions of developers learn, experiment, and contribute to their IDE and build their own tools. Now, we’re taking our commitment to open-source to the next level by making it even easier for the community to explore, build, and contribute! What’s New? […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-open-source/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate KMP Watchlist: Level Up Your Skills in 10 Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The best way to skip the “beginner mistakes” phase is to learn from the teams who have already solved them at scale. For Week 3 of KMP Level Up, we’ve curated the Top 10 KotlinConf talks that cover the full spectrum of adoption, from massive production case studies to deep dives into the compiler. Whether […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/the-ultimate-kmp-watchlist/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update, November 2025 – Extensibility Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.9.0 is out, and it brings the first version of our extensibility prototype! Read on for all of the details, and see the release notes for the full list of changes and bug fixes. To get support for Amper’s latest features, use IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Beta (or newer). New Amper website We revamped our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/11/amper-update-november-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Kotlin Adoption Across Your Organization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the fifth post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/scaling-kotlin-adoption-across-your-organization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot 4: Leaner, Safer Apps and a New Kotlin Baseline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Boot 4.0 has officially landed. At JetBrains, we’ve been tracking the updates since the first milestones to ensure that IntelliJ IDEA delivers a smooth and reliable development experience. While many of the core capabilities come directly from Spring Framework 7, Spring Boot remains the adoption enabler that brings everything together: sensible defaults, consistent configuration, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/spring-boot-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more details about the issues resolved, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-2025-2-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Updates and Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of updates and bug fixes for the 2025.3 release of ReSharper and Rider has just been made public. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.3.0.2 For the full list of issues resolved in this build, please refer to our issue tracker. Rider 2025.3.0.2 For the full list of issues we’ve resolved in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/20/resharper-rider-2025-3-0-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn AI-Assisted Programming With Junie: Free Courses From JetBrains Academy and Nebius</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For over 25 years, JetBrains has been driven by a desire to make developers more productive and enhance the developer experience by providing smarter, more efficient tools. JetBrains Academy advances this mission by empowering learners to study computer science and gain hands-on experience with the professional tools they’ll use in their future careers. AI is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/11/20/learn-ai-assisted-programming-with-junie-free-courses-from-jetbrains-academy-and-nebius/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 3 Pro Is Now Available in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest AI model from Google, Gemini 3 Pro, is now live in JetBrains IDEs. From day one, it powers AI Chat and soon will be available in Junie, our coding agent, giving you smarter reasoning, stronger instruction following, and seamless integration into your workflow. What’s new Gemini 3 Pro shows clear improvements that matter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/gemini-3-pro-is-now-available-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Release of MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting today, you can download the second EAP release for MPS 2025.3 and try all the latest updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 EAP 2 This release includes several noteworthy improvements: JavaDoc language overhaul The JavaDoc language has been completely migrated to use the jetbrains.mps.lang.text language for text representation and editing. This change should have minimal impact […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/11/the-mps-2025-3-eap2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping Decision‑Makers Say Yes to Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the fourth post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/helping-decision-makers-say-yes-to-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: Projects We’re Proud to Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference — the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and to contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/11/18/open-source-in-focus-projects-we-re-proud-to-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
