<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:37:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Continuing Positive Impact: This Year’s AI4SE Interns in their New Roles at JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our last post, we introduced the talented intern cohort from our AI for Software Engineering (AI4SE) research partnership with Delft University of Technology (TU Delft). In this post, we’re excited to spotlight the next chapter in their journey: their evolution from interns to full-time members of our tech team. As interns, they didn’t just […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/ai4se-interns-employees-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider Roadmap: What to Expect From the Upcoming Updates and Releases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Rider 2025.2 already out in the wild and the 2025.3 release cycle underway, we want to take a step back and give you a broader picture of where Rider is headed. This roadmap covers our plans for Rider 2025.3 and what you can expect from the minor updates included in the 2025.2 release line. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/25/rider-rider-roadmap-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Python So Popular in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 11:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While other programming languages come and go, Python has stood the test of time and firmly established itself as a top choice for developers of all levels, from beginners to seasoned professionals. Whether you’re working on intelligent systems or data-driven workflows, Python has a pivotal role to play in how your software is built, scaled, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/09/why-is-python-so-popular/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kotlin AI Stack: Build AI Agents With Koog, Code Smarter With Junie, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 08:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is changing how we build software, and Kotlin is ready to meet that change by empowering developers to build AI-powered apps and by enhancing the developer experience through AI-based tools. This post explores both angles: the tools for developing AI-powered apps, both from JetBrains and from the community, and the ways Kotlin is evolving […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/the-kotlin-ai-stack-build-ai-agents-with-koog-code-smarter-with-junie-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ktor roadmap and previews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 19:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As in previous years, we have been working on the Ktor roadmap, and we want to say thank everyone for their contributions and feedback to help us prioritize the roadmap! The OpenAPI and WebRTC support is already in preview since the Ktor 3.3.0 release. Check out the What’s New section for a full overview of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/ktor-roadmap-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From AI-Generated to Production-Ready Code: WebStorm Refactorings for the Modern Workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve all been there. You ask your AI tool to generate a React component, and the initial result works perfectly in the beginning. The AI gives you a functional 250-line component that gets the job done quickly and is exactly what you need for rapid prototyping. But even though AI does indeed excel at generating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/09/from-ai-generated-to-production-ready-code-webstorm-refactorings-for-the-modern-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging Unit Test Generation with in-IDE TestSpark</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Test generation is an essential yet time-consuming part of quality assurance. Automating test-generation techniques means accelerating the development process and improving the quality of the final software. However, traditional automated techniques, and their respective tools, are not usually user-friendly, having a command-line interface and not being integrated with the IDE. To boost acceleration and quality […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/testspark-unit-test-generation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islands Theme: The New Look Coming to JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 16:24:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with version 2025.2.3, JetBrains IDEs will offer a new look: the Islands theme, available in both dark and light modes. This update is a visual refresh, which means that all functionality will remain the same. The new theme can be turned on or off in the Appearance settings. This step brings us closer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/islands-theme-the-new-look-coming-to-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.9.0 Released: Compose Multiplatform for Web Goes Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Multiplatform for web, powered by Wasm, is now in Beta! This major milestone shows that Compose Multiplatform for web is no longer just experimental, but ready for real-world use by early adopters. This is more than a technical step forward. It’s a community achievement, made possible by feedback from early adopters of the Alpha […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/compose-multiplatform-1-9-0-compose-for-web-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – September Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you remember, dancin’ in September? 🎶 This September, let JetBrains keep the rhythm of your studies strong with free JetBrains IDEs and tools for study, a brand-new collaboration between AWS and JetBrains Academy, exclusive opportunities for school students, and more. Ready to groove into learning?
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/09/19/jetbrains-academy-september/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 09:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.2 has arrived with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates included in this version: To find out more details about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/intellij-idea-2025-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A free, online event for the .NET community. JetBrains .NET Days Online returns for two focused days of practical talks, live demos, and real-world tips from community speakers and the JetBrains .NET team. Register now → Event basics Registration: https://lp.jetbrains.com/dotnet-days-2025 Agenda highlights Here’s a preview of what we’ve got in store for you: How to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/18/announcing-jetbrains-net-days-online-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Updates and Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of updates and bug fixes for the 2025.2 release of ReSharper and Rider has just been made public. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.2.2 To make your transition to Visual Studio 2026 seamless, ReSharper now installs a lightweight migration extension bundled with the product. This extension will be carried over automatically by […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/18/resharper-rider-2025-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
