<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:52:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Webinar – Uno Platform &amp; Hot Design for Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Tuesday, March 11, 2025, 15:00 – 16:30 UTC (check other timezones) for our free live webinar, Uno Platform &amp;amp; Hot Design for Rider, with Andres Pineda. Register now and get a reminder, or join on YouTube Hot Design is the industry’s first visual designer for cross-platform .NET applications. It transforms your running app […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/19/webinar-uno-platform-amp-hot-design-for-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Your React App Deployment With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial was brought to you by Kumar Harsh, a software developer and technical author. If you regularly work with React projects, you probably already know how tricky it can be to deploy them smoothly. Issues like manual errors, inconsistent deployment practices, and slow iteration cycles often turn React app deployment into a challenging process […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/automate-your-react-app-deployment-with-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces a New Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The YouTrack 2025.1 release introduces a bold new design that helps you navigate your projects and tasks more quickly. This new look and feel reflects years of learning about how teams work on projects. The new design introduces: Every day, hundreds of thousands of teams count on YouTrack to drive their business forward. We understand […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/02/youtrack-introduces-a-new-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do LLMs Benefit Developer Productivity?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 13:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LLMs are everywhere! I am sure you have heard of large language models (LLMs) and may have seen demonstrations of what they can do. You may have even tried to play with some of the popular ones yourself. No matter your opinion of or experience with LLMs, you cannot deny that they are a popular […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/how-do-llms-benefit-developer-productivity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 5: More LLMs in JetBrains AI Assistant, Improved Gutter for VCS, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 12:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 5 is out! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 5 Let’s take a look at this week’s fresh additions! If you missed our previous overviews […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDEs Aren’t Just for Developers: How QA, Tech Writers, and Designers Benefit Too</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 12:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud development environments (CDEs) have become a game-changer for development teams, and for good reason. They simplify workflows, reduce project setup time, and eliminate configuration headaches. While most discussions about CDEs focus exclusively on software developers, in reality, the benefits of CDEs extend far beyond coders. They can boost productivity for every team member involved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/02/cdes-aren-t-just-for-developers-how-qa-tech-writers-and-designers-benefit-too/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: TDD and Generative AI – A Perfect Pairing?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 11:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Bouke Nijhuis, where we’ll explore how test-driven development (TDD) and AI can work together to generate production-ready code. Date: February 27, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this talk, we will explore whether generative AI can generate working code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/new-livestream-tdd-and-generative-ai-a-perfect-pairing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Is the Best Python Web Framework: Django, Flask, or FastAPI?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 10:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Search for Python web frameworks, and three names will consistently come up: Django, Flask, and FastAPI. Our latest Python Developer Survey Results confirm that these three frameworks remain developers’ top choices for backend web development with Python. All three frameworks are open-source and compatible with the latest versions of Python. But how do you determine […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/02/django-flask-fastapi/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI vs. DeepSeek: Which AI Understands Kotlin Better?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 11:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI models are evolving fast, and DeepSeek-R1 is making waves as a serious competitor to OpenAI. But how well do these models understand Kotlin? Can they generate reliable code, explain tricky concepts, and help with debugging? JetBrains Research tested the latest AI models, including DeepSeek-R1, OpenAI o1, and OpenAI o3-mini, using KotlinHumanEval and a new […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/02/openai-vs-deepseek-which-ai-understands-kotlin-better/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Migrations in the Real World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 11:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Database migrations are critical to modern application development and deployment, enabling teams to evolve their database schema alongside their application code. However, as systems grow in complexity and scale, managing migrations becomes increasingly challenging. At scale, a simple schema update can impact several microservices, terabytes of data, and global user traffic. It requires careful planning, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/database-migrations-in-the-real-world/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore 2025.1 Brings New Welcome Screen, Revamped Admin Panel for On-Premises, and Workspace Import From Git Repository</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.1 introduces a new Welcome screen, a redesigned admin panel for On-Premises installations, the ability to import workspaces from Git repositories, and more. Datalore Cloud customers have already received the new updates automatically, and Datalore On-Premises customers can upgrade by following these instructions. New Welcome screen The new Welcome screen simplifies onboarding. Here, you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/02/13/datalore-2025-1-brings-new-welcome-screen-revamped-admin-panel-for-on-premises-and-workspace-import-from-git-repository/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 3.1.0 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 12:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2025/13_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ktor 3.1.0 is here! This is the first minor release of the year, bringing exciting new features, performance improvements, and bug fixes. This release includes improvements to server-sent events (SSE), documentation enhancements, WebAssembly (Wasm) support, dependency injection design updates, and some initial steps toward gRPC integration. 🚀 Get started with Ktor 3.1.0 now! Ready to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/02/ktor-3-1-0-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.3 with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, by using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most important fixes delivered in v2024.3.3: For a complete […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2024-3-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership insights on Managing Code Quality Conflict</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 17:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The competitive nature of today’s digital business environment makes it critical for software development teams to embrace change, especially if it leads to improved software quality and efficiency. As a manager or team lead, your leadership plays a role in guiding your team through these metamorphoses. At Qodana, we’re all about code quality and security […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/02/managing-conflict/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | February 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The GC.KeepAlive() method in the .NET Framework is not used to prevent garbage collection of an object for the entire method scope, as you might think. Instead, it explicitly ensures that the object remains referenced at a specific point in the code after it’s last used. It’s particularly useful when dealing with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/12/dotinsights-february-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and How JetBrains Built Mellum – the LLM Designed for Code Completion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 12:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, I’m Anton, product manager at JetBrains AI, and I managed training and release of the JetBrains’ first proprietary LLM. 👋 Last year, we launched Mellum, a project I’m incredibly proud of. Mellum isn’t just another LLM – it’s a reflection of JetBrains’ commitment to helping developers work smarter and more efficiently. Today I’d like […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/why-and-how-jetbrains-built-mellum-the-llm-designed-for-code-completion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Debugging for Massive MSVC-Based Projects in CLion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 08:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion provides several bundled debuggers, including a modified version of the LLDB for the MSVC toolchain used on Windows. This custom JetBrains LLDB has a number of performance and accuracy improvements. Among other things, it supports an optimized mechanism for handling PDB files containing debugging data. Recently, the debugger received another performance boost: the Step […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/02/lldb-msvc-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
