<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 08:20:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Vulnerable API Detection in JetBrains IDEs and Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 08:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the start of the year, we announced a partnership with Mend.io to maximize code security in JetBrains tools. The partnership provided us with quality data about vulnerable and malicious packages, allowing our IDEs and Qodana to spot them for you in your projects. Over the last few months, we have been working on integrating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/enhanced-vulnerable-api-detection-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Popular Python Frameworks and Libraries in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 15:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re building APIs, dashboards, or machine learning pipelines, choosing the right framework can make or break your project. Every year, we survey thousands of Python developers to help you understand how the ecosystem is evolving, from tooling and languages to frameworks and libraries. Our insights from the State of Python 2025 offer a snapshot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/09/the-most-popular-python-frameworks-and-libraries-in-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | September 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 11:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The C# language has a GOTO statement? It sure does. This is a case of “just because you could doesn’t mean you should”. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 🌟 Featured Content This month’s featured content is from Chris Woodruff! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/02/dotinsights-september-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 10:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hold on to your helper methods – RubyMine is now FREE for non-commercial use! Whether you’re learning Ruby and Rails, pushing open-source forward, creating dev content, or building your passion project, we want to make sure you have the tools to enjoy what you do even more… for free. Another chapter in the story We […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/09/rubymine-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Our Newest Innovators: Welcoming AI4SE Interns as JetBrains Employees!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 15:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picture this: You’re working on your MSc thesis as an intern in software engineering, not just as an academic exercise, but side-by-side with an industry team, tackling real projects and real problems, refining code, and witnessing your ideas come alive. By the time you’ve graduated, you’re already a valued team member, ready to hit the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/ai4se-interns-jetbrains-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The LSP API Is Now Available to All IntelliJ IDEA Users and Plugin Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 09:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The way developers create plugins implementing the Language Server Protocol (LSP) in JetBrains IDEs is undergoing a significant shift. With PyCharm and IntelliJ IDEA adopting a unified distribution model, we’re removing a key obstacle that has been limiting LSP adoption within the IntelliJ Platform ecosystem. Starting with IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate 2025.2, users can continue using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/the-lsp-api-is-now-available-to-all-intellij-idea-users-and-plugin-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPC World Finals Livestream: ecnerwala and SecondThread Speed-Solving Kotlin Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 19:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us live from the ICPC World Finals in Baku, Azerbaijan, for a special event. This year, we are hosting a head-to-head match where two of the world’s top competitive programmers, Andrew ‘ecnerwala’ He and David ‘SecondThread’ Harmeyer, will speed-solve Kotlin problems in real time. Save the date: September 2, 2025, at 9:30 am UTC […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/icpc-world-finals-livestream-ecnerwala-secondthread-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 09:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 – v2025.2.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 16:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released another update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 – v2025.1.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-1-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog 0.4.0 Is Out: Observable, Predictable, and Deployable Anywhere You Build</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 09:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Featuring Langfuse and W&amp;amp;B Weave Support, Ktor Integration, Native Structured Output, iOS Target, GPT-5, and More. Koog 0.3.0 was about making agents smarter and persistent. Koog 0.4.0 is about making them observable, seamlessly deployable in your stack, and more predictable in their outputs – all while introducing support for new models and platforms. Read on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/08/koog-0-4-0-is-out-observable-predictable-and-deployable-anywhere-you-build/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper’s New Out-of-Process Engine Cuts UI Freezes in Visual Studio by 80%</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio power users love ReSharper’s deep analysis, but the cost has been the occasional UI hiccup that breaks the flow of work. In ReSharper 2025.2, analysis runs in a separate 64-bit worker out of Visual Studio’s UI process. Previously, ReSharper shared Visual Studio’s UI process, so long analyses could stall the UI thread. Now, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/28/resharper-s-new-out-of-process-engine-cuts-ui-freezes-in-visual-studio-by-80/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2025.3 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.3, which we plan to introduce in November. After reviewing your feedback and our strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following: 🚀 Transitioning to the CLion Nova language engine as the default. 🏗️ Improvements to project formats and build tools. 🎛️ Improvements to features for embedded development. 🤖 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/2025-3-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Science With Kotlin: A Powerlifting Case Study</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Adele Carpenter. Adele is a Software Engineer and Consultant at Trifork Amsterdam, where she works on educational systems in the Kotlin/Java/Spring ecosystem and advises customers on their projects. TL;DR This blog post uses a dataset from the sport of powerlifting to get you up and running with Kotlin Notebooks, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/exploring-data-science-with-kotlin-a-powerlifting-case-study/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for the Best School Year Ever? Join Our STEM Clubs, Camps, and Competitions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 07:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The start of a new school year brings new chances to learn, grow, and geek out on the stuff you love. If you’re into math, coding, or AI, we’ve got you covered with fun and challenging activities. Youth Clubs Join one (or more) of our free online clubs to sharpen your skills, prep for olympiads, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/08/27/new-school-year-2025-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
