<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:47:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Exploration With pandas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maybe you’ve heard complicated-sounding phrases such as ‘“Students t-test”, “regression models”, “support vector machines”, and so on. You might think there’s so much you need to learn before you can explore and understand your data, but I am going to show you two tools to help you go faster. These are summary statistics and graphs. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/data-exploration-with-pandas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a CRUD REST API Using Spring Boot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 09:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Boot is an application framework for the Java platform designed to make it easy to build Spring-powered applications. Its opinionated convention-over-configuration approach to building Spring applications improves developer productivity. IntelliJ IDEA provides extensive coding assistance for Spring, including a dedicated project wizard, code highlighting, intelligent context actions, embedded documentation, navigation, and highly customizable run […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/how-to-build-a-crud-rest-api-using-spring-boot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Multiplatform Development Roadmap for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 18:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Kotlin Multiplatform is now firmly established, development teams across the globe – including major companies like Shopify, Forbes, Haier, and Zürcher Kantonalbank – can harness its power in production environments. During Google I/O 2024 in May, Google announced their official support for Kotlin Multiplatform for sharing business logic across Android and iOS. This and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/kotlin-multiplatform-development-roadmap-for-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.3 EAP Digest: Improved Navigation and Rename Refactoring for Framework Components, AI-Based Code Completion Updates, and Tailwind Color Preview for CSS Classes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 13:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s time for the WebStorm 2024.3 EAP digest, which will walk you through the new features and improvements in the upcoming release! The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the EAP builds and keep both your stable and EAP versions up to date. You can also manually download the EAP builds from our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/10/webstorm-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Best Practices 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 12:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JavaScript is undoubtedly the most used programming language in the world and is hugely influential on one of the largest technologies we have all come to rely on – the internet. With this power comes great responsibility, and the JavaScript ecosystem has been rapidly evolving, making it incredibly hard to keep up with the latest […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/10/javascript-best-practices-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDE Services Cloud Release and Floating License Server End-of-Life Announcements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 10:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains IDE Services, the enterprise suite of products dedicated to improving developer productivity across an entire organization, is now available in the cloud! By offering a JetBrains-managed service, IDE Services Cloud simplifies license management, enhances security, and provides seamless scalability, ensuring that organizations can focus more on development and less on administration. As part of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/25/ide-services-cloud-release-and-floating-license-server-end-of-life-announcements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 7: Enhanced AI Assistant for VCS, Debugger Updates, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 16:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re back with another set of features and improvements in the latest IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Early Access Program build! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. As we start winding down the Early Access Program […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Your Company Adopt Remote Development?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 16:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adopting remote development is a significant decision for any company. At JetBrains, we talk to many customers about this shift. While we see growing demand, we also encounter many misconceptions about what remote development with cloud development environments (CDEs) can and cannot do. 1. What problems can you solve with remote development Before diving into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2024/10/should-your-company-adopt-remote-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm and Rider Are Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 12:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a change in our licensing model that we believe will benefit the developer community – WebStorm and Rider are now free for non-commercial use! Read on to learn more about the change and why we’re making it, and be sure to check out the FAQ section below for additional details. What’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/24/webstorm-and-rider-are-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Us Anything! Q&amp;A Session on Reddit With the CLion Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 08:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a while since the last Ask Me Anything session on Reddit with the CLion team. Today, we would like to get back to our roots and spend some time together to give you the opportunity to ask any questions you would like in r/cpp. Our team will be there, ready to provide you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/10/ama-reddit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.4 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 07:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor version for IntelliJ IDEA – 2024.2.4. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, please […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-2-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Interview: Nana Janashia on Her Journey to DevOps and First Impressions of TeamCity Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 16:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to bring you an exclusive interview with Nana Janashia, the mastermind behind the largest DevOps YouTube channel – TechWorld with Nana. Nana has built an incredible career, sharing valuable insights about automation, cloud-native technologies, and everything DevOps with her global audience. But did you know that her journey started in marketing? In this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/exclusive-interview-nana-janashia-teamcity-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth Challenge Returns in November!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Prepare yourselves for the second season of the JetBrains Academy Youth Challenge, the competition for young coders and mathematicians. If you missed out last time or are ready to prove yourself again, this is your chance to win special prizes and compete with students worldwide. Choose your track The challenge continues with two tracks: math […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/10/22/youth-challenge-returns-in-november/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Mellum: JetBrains’ New LLM Built for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has taken a major step forward in advancing AI-driven development tools with the launch of Mellum, a proprietary large language model (LLM) specifically designed to assist software developers. Currently available only with JetBrains AI Assistant, Mellum provides faster, smarter, and more contextually aware code completion. There are hundreds of LLMs. Why Mellum? Unlike typical […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/22/introducing-mellum-jetbrains-new-llm-built-for-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip User Experience Survey Results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Recently, we conducted our first DataGrip UX Survey to better understand and prioritize the pain points that have the greatest impact on your experience. The data and feedback we gathered have helped us refine our plans to focus on what matters most to you. In this post, we’ll highlight the key findings from the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/10/22/datagrip-user-experience-survey-results/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Godot Game Builds With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Godot, an open-source game engine known for its versatility and simplicity, is gaining popularity among both indie developers and the broader game development community. While Godot comes with its own scripting language, GDScript, it also supports the widely-used C# language, familiar to Unity and Unreal Engine developers. In this tutorial, we will use “Dodge the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/automating-godot-game-builds-with-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
