<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:02:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs. Python: Finding the right balance between speed and simplicity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post was brought to you by Damaso Sanoja, draft.dev. Deciding whether to use Python or Rust isn’t just a syntax choice; it’s a career bet. According to the StackOverflow Developer Survey, Python dominates in accessibility, with 66.4% of people learning to code choosing it as their entry point. Python usage skyrocketed from 32% […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/11/10/rust-vs-python-finding-the-right-balance-between-speed-and-simplicity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Go Ecosystem in 2025: Key Trends in Frameworks, Tools, and Developer Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 09:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Go turns 16 this year. To celebrate this milestone, we have taken a closer look at the latest Developer Ecosystem Survey results and examined the evolution of the Go ecosystem over the past five years. According to JetBrains Data Playground, 2.2 million professional developers use Go as their primary programming language – twice as many […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/11/10/go-language-trends-ecosystem-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2025.3 Release Candidate Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next big release for Rider is just around the corner! If you’re eager to get a sneak peek, you can download the Release Candidate version of Rider 2025.3 from our website right now. Here are the feature highlights of the Rider 2025.3 RC build: If you encounter any issues when using the Rider 2025.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/05/the-rider-2025-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper, .NET Tools, and ReSharper C&#43;&#43; 2025.3 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get a preview of all the latest features and improvements set to be shipped with the next major ReSharper by downloading the Release Candidate builds that have just landed. The ReSharper 2025.3 Release Candidate For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to the issue tracker. dotTrace, dotMemory, dotCover and dotPeek […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/05/the-resharper-dotnet-tools-2025-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | November 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? C# includes a feature called “expression-bodied members“, which allows you to define one-line methods, properties, constructors, and destructors in a very concise way. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 🔗 Links Here’s the latest from the developer community. 🔦 From […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/05/dotinsights-november-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – November 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This edition is packed with insightful, practical, and curiosity-fueling reads. From hands-on advice to thought-provoking pieces, we’ve gathered a nice selection of stories that will help you stay sharp and inspired in the tech world. We’re also happy to have Josh Long as our featured content author this month! Expect some top-notch insights and a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/java-annotated-monthly-november-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Kotlin Adoption in Your Company</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the third post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/growing-kotlin-adoption-in-your-company-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Smart Performance Hacks For Faster Python Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Dido Grigorov, a deep learning engineer and Python programmer with 17 years of experience in the field. In the rapidly evolving domain of software development, Python has established itself as a premier language, renowned for its simplicity, readability, and versatility. It underpins a vast range of applications, from web […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/11/10-smart-performance-hacks-for-faster-python-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm Plugins You Might Not Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PhpStorm comes with a ton of built-in features, and you can add even more with plugins. They bring new languages, tools, and small improvements that make everyday coding smoother. Many of the best ones come from independent developers. One of them is Dmitrii Derepko, who built several handy tools for working with web projects and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/11/phpstorm-plugins-you-might-not-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Entry Point: A Single Entry Point for Context-Aware Coding Assistance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern IDEs are powerful tools with many useful features. When we talk about developer productivity, one thing that comes to mind is mastering the IDE – learning its features, like refactorings, navigation, or code generation, and remembering how to invoke them. However, discovering all the relevant features of your IDE, and knowing when and how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/universal-entry-point-a-single-entry-point-for-context-aware-coding-assistance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming the Billion Dollar Mistake: Maarten Balliauw’s Guide to C# Nullable Reference Types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the most recent JetBrains.NET Days Online 2025 event, Maarten Balliauw delivered a comprehensive session on migrating existing codebases to use C# nullable reference types, a feature that’s been available since C# 8 but remains underutilized in many legacy projects. Through practical examples and migration strategies, Maarten demonstrated how to bring null safety to your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/04/maarten-balliauws-guide-to-csharp-nullable-reference-types/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q3 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your quarterly dose of plugin dev news, tools, and tips from JetBrains. ⭐ Community Spotlight JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2025 Is Coming Up Soon 📅 November 5, 2025 | Online | FreeLearn how to build the next great JetBrains plugin! Join our annual free virtual event focused on developing plugins for JetBrains products. Explore topics […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/11/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q3-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring Your Own Key (BYOK) Is Coming Soon to JetBrains AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’ve always believed in giving developers the best possible tools to enhance productivity and creativity. Recently, you’ve shared important feedback about AI usage limits, transparency, and the freedom to choose which AI providers you use. We heard you loud and clear. That’s why we are working to introduce bring-your-own-key (BYOK) support for JetBrains […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/bring-your-own-key-byok-is-coming-soon-to-jetbrains-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Platform 2025.3: What Plugin Developers Should Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we approach the release of IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3, we would like to share key information about changes that may impact your plugin development process. This post addresses common questions from the developer community and provides guidance on maintaining compatibility with the latest IntelliJ Platform versions. No Immediate Upgrade Required If you built your plugin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/11/intellij-platform-2025-3-what-plugin-developers-should-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Trust Leads and Speed Follows in Agentic Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every developer recognises the trade-off. You can take the shortcut that delivers today but breaks tomorrow, or choose the slower approach that earns lasting confidence. This dilemma has become even more poignant with the widespread integration of AI agents into real workflows. Speed feels tempting, but speed without trust usually wastes more time than it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/why-trust-leads-and-speed-follows-in-agentic-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
