<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:42:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released another update for v2025.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This version brings the following valuable refinements: To see the full list of issues addressed in this version, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/intellij-idea-2025-3-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2026.1 Early Access Program Has Begun</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper 2026.1 Early Access Program is now open, and the first EAP build brings a mix of C# productivity improvements, new inspections, performance work, and expanded C++ language support. As always, EAP builds are an opportunity to try upcoming features early and help us refine them before the final release. Here’s what’s new in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/22/resharper-2026-1-early-access-program/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2026.1 Early Access Program Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for Rider 2026.1 has just begun, and the first preview build for the upcoming major release is already out. There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: A reminder of what the EAP is all about The Early Access Program is a long-standing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/22/rider-2026-1-early-access-program-start/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ROI of Developer Experience: How a Better CI/CD Tool Pays for Itself</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Cameron Pavey, draft.dev. Developer experience (DevEx) directly correlates with engineering performance, which in turn drives competitive advantage. And yet many software engineering teams continue to operate on legacy CI/CD platforms that create unnecessary friction, burn developer hours, and ultimately limit business growth. While some teams remain trapped by […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/the-roi-of-dev-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA Conf 2026: Learn From the People Building the JVM Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’re invited to IntelliJ IDEA Conf 2026 – a free online conference for developers working across the JVM ecosystem. Join us for two days of in-depth technical talks, practical insights, and conversations with experts who build and shape modern Java and Kotlin development. The conference will take place online on March 26–27, 2026, with sessions […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/intellij-idea-conf-2026-learn-from-the-people-building-the-jvm-ecosystem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid Common Pitfalls With JPA and Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was written together with Thorben Janssen, who has more than 20 years of experience with JPA and Hibernate and is the author of “Hibernate Tips: More than 70 Solutions to Common Hibernate Problems” and the JPA newsletter. Kotlin and Jakarta Persistence (also known as JPA) are a popular combination for server-side development. Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/how-to-avoid-common-pitfalls-with-jpa-and-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.11.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The second bug-fix update for TeamCity On-Premises 2025.11 is ready to be installed! In this update, we have addressed a number of issues, such as: All TeamCity bug-fix updates include performance and security improvements, so we recommend that you never skip these minor updates. See TeamCity 2025.11.2 Release Notes for the complete list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/teamcity-2025-11-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platform Debugger Architecture Redesign for Remote Development in 2026.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ Platform provides a powerful debugger framework that plugins can extend to support various programming languages and runtime environments. To enable remote development scenarios – where the IDE interface runs on your local machine while code executes on a remote server – we’ve redesigned the debugger architecture. This guide walks you through the changes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/01/platform-debugger-architecture-redesign-for-remote-development-in-2026-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update your Kotlin projects for Android Gradle Plugin 9.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Android Gradle plugin 9.0 is now available, and it includes two major changes that will affect existing Kotlin projects: This post provides some details about these changes and points you to the resources that you’ll need to update your existing projects. You’ll also need to update tools and plugins that depend on AGP to their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/update-your-projects-for-agp9/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TransformConf: a New Conference on AI in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TransformConf, a new event focused on how AI is transforming software development, is coming in 2026! Save the date: September 15–16, London, UK. Early bird tickets are already available! AI is revolutionizing software development – that much barely needs saying. AI is already a daily tool for 85% of developers, and 68% expect AI proficiency […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2026/01/15/transformconf-a-new-conference-on-ai-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala 3.8 Support in the Scala Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, As I write these words, the Scala compiler team is wrapping up the Scala 3.8 release. It’s the last major release before a feature freeze. The next one, 3.9, will be the new Long-Term Support version. The compiler team decided that most of the work between 3.8 and 3.9 will go into stabilization, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2026/01/15/scala-38-support-in-the-scala-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
