<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:39:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taming the Billion Dollar Mistake: Maarten Balliauw’s Guide to C# Nullable Reference Types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the most recent JetBrains.NET Days Online 2025 event, Maarten Balliauw delivered a comprehensive session on migrating existing codebases to use C# nullable reference types, a feature that’s been available since C# 8 but remains underutilized in many legacy projects. Through practical examples and migration strategies, Maarten demonstrated how to bring null safety to your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/04/maarten-balliauws-guide-to-csharp-nullable-reference-types/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q3 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your quarterly dose of plugin dev news, tools, and tips from JetBrains. ⭐ Community Spotlight JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2025 Is Coming Up Soon 📅 November 5, 2025 | Online | FreeLearn how to build the next great JetBrains plugin! Join our annual free virtual event focused on developing plugins for JetBrains products. Explore topics […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/11/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q3-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring Your Own Key (BYOK) Is Coming Soon to JetBrains AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’ve always believed in giving developers the best possible tools to enhance productivity and creativity. Recently, you’ve shared important feedback about AI usage limits, transparency, and the freedom to choose which AI providers you use. We heard you loud and clear. That’s why we are working to introduce bring-your-own-key (BYOK) support for JetBrains […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/bring-your-own-key-byok-is-coming-soon-to-jetbrains-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Platform 2025.3: What Plugin Developers Should Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we approach the release of IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3, we would like to share key information about changes that may impact your plugin development process. This post addresses common questions from the developer community and provides guidance on maintaining compatibility with the latest IntelliJ Platform versions. No Immediate Upgrade Required If you built your plugin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/11/intellij-platform-2025-3-what-plugin-developers-should-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Trust Leads and Speed Follows in Agentic Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every developer recognises the trade-off. You can take the shortcut that delivers today but breaks tomorrow, or choose the slower approach that earns lasting confidence. This dilemma has become even more poignant with the widespread integration of AI agents into real workflows. Speed feels tempting, but speed without trust usually wastes more time than it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/why-trust-leads-and-speed-follows-in-agentic-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Livestream recording] Maximizing TeamCity: New Features in Action and a Look Ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our latest livestream, TeamCity Solutions Engineers Ricardo Leite and Daniel Gallo hosted a livestream packed with exciting updates about TeamCity – from brand-new features already making life easier for CI/CD engineers, to a sneak peek at what’s next for 2026. If you missed it or just want a quick refresher, here are the key […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/10/livestream-recording-maximizing-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grazie’s Next Step: Built-In Language Intelligence for Your IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the last few years, Grazie has grown from a simple proofreading tool into a comprehensive writing assistant for developers, offering intelligent support across different contexts like code comments, documentation, and README files. Starting with the upcoming 2025.3 IDE versions, Grazie will become a native part of IntelliJ-based IDEs through the Natural Languages plugin, bringing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2025/10/grazie-s-next-step-built-in-language-intelligence-for-your-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Becomes Cloud9’s Official AI-Powered Coding Partner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers love coding – it’s a passion we all share. But staying productive means taking time to recharge, and for many of us, that means playing video games. That’s why we’re excited to team up with the legendary Cloud9 Esports as their official AI-Powered Coding Partner. With this partnership, we’re bringing AI-powered coding to the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/10/29/jetbrains-becomes-cloud9s-official-ai-powered-coding-partner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Distributed Systems: Jason Taylor Shows How .NET Aspire Makes the Complex Feel Effortless</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025, Jason Taylor, Microsoft MVP and Solutions Architect at Particular Software, delivered an engaging presentation that transforms how we think about building distributed systems. Through live coding and interactive polls with the audience, Taylor demonstrated how .NET Aspire can turn what’s traditionally been a complex, friction-filled process into something surprisingly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/29/simplifying-distributed-systems-dotnet-aspire-jason-taylor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program Has Started</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re starting the MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program (EAP) today. You can download the first 2025.3 EAP release and try it out now! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 EAP Besides numerous bug fixes, this release brings three major improvements: Light and dark TextIcon options TextIcon’s layers can now be configured to apply to the light, dark, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/10/the-mps-2025-3-eap-has-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Order in the Mayhem: A Novel Concurrency Testing Tool that Improved the Kotlin Compiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever tried to track down a bug in concurrent programs, you know how chaotic and frustrating it can be: everything seems to work fine, then suddenly crashes, and you can’t quite pin down why – all while the bugs slip through. To bring order to this chaos, at JetBrains Research we built LitmusKt […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/10/litmuskt-concurrency-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Launch of Developer Productivity AI Arena: An Open Platform for Benchmarking AI Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For 25 years, JetBrains has shaped the software development landscape across multiple programming languages, advancing how developers and organizations build software. Our focus has always been on improving productivity and the overall developer experience. With the rise of AI, a key challenge now is understanding how to measure the real-world productivity gains provided by AI-assisted […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/10/28/the-launch-of-developer-productivity-ai-arena-an-open-platform-for-benchmarking-ai-coding-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Developer Productivity AI Arena: An Open Platform for AI Coding Agents Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s software development landscape, AI coding agents are evolving rapidly from prototypes into indispensable tools. Yet the industry still lacks an open, neutral, standards-based way to measure the real-world effectiveness of these agents across languages, frameworks, and environments. With over two decades of experience building developer tools that are trusted by millions worldwide, we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/10/28/introducing-developer-productivity-ai-arena-an-open-platform-for-ai-coding-agents-benchmarks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces a Remote MCP Server and New Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The YouTrack 2025.3 release introduces remote MCP (Model Context Protocol) support, which expands the possibilities for those who build integrations with YouTrack. This enables you to securely connect AI-powered tools to YouTrack, allowing your teams to manage their work directly from an LLM, IDE, or agent platform. In addition, many new apps are now available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/10/youtrack-introduces-a-remote-mcp-server-and-new-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Kotlin in Real Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the second post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/evaluating-kotlin-in-real-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.2.4: Another Set of Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A fourth set of updates for the 2025.2 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.2.4 TeamCity extension is back After listening to feedback from teams who rely on it for their CI workflows, we’ve restored […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/28/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-4-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
