<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:24:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big News! JetBrains Qodana’s Code Quality Plugin Is Now Available for Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s no secret that Qodana is a team tool that JetBrains designed to integrate seamlessly with its suite of IDEs, but every team and tech stack is different. One common question remains: “What about other members of our team who still use VS Code or Visual Studio?” To help with this problem, we decided to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/visual-studio-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.03.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The first bug-fix update for version 2025.03, TeamCity On-Premises 2025.03.1, is out and ready to be installed on your servers! This update ships around 30 bug fixes, performance enhancements, and security patches. We highly recommend upgrading to keep your system secure and optimized. The list of resolved issues includes: See TeamCity 2025.03.1 Upgrade Notes for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/teamcity-2025-03-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2025.1: Unified PyCharm, Free AI Tier, Junie Release, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2025.1 brings major updates to improve your development experience. PyCharm is now a unified product, combining PyCharm Professional and Community Edition. Version 2025.1 also brings a free AI tier, the public release of Junie, the launch of Cadence, significant Jupyter enhancements, support for Hatch, Data Wrangler, and many other improvements. Get the latest version […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/04/pycharm-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2025.1: JetBrains Data Wrangler AI Agent, No-Code Data Preparation Flow, AI Quick Charts, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to introduce DataSpell 2025.1, the first major release of 2025. This update focuses on making data cleaning and preparation more intuitive and efficient than ever before. Download DataSpell 2025.1 JetBrains Data Wrangler AI agent With Data Wrangler, you can choose between a no-code flow or full AI automation. Easily toggle between: No-code flow […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/04/dataspell-2025-1-jetbrains-data-wrangler-ai-agent-no-code-data-preparation-flow-ai-quick-charts-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release is a major update that includes improvements in PHPStan annotations, Xdebug, and WordPress support, an AI Free tier and new subscription system for JetBrains AI, and more. Download PhpStorm 2025.1 PHP Code completion for @phpstan-type and @phpstan-import-type This release improves PhpStorm’s PHPStan annotation support, introducing code completion for array shape aliases in @phpstan-type […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/04/phpstorm-2025-1-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Support for new features in Scala 3 Context Bounds and Givens Scala 3.6 introduced a new syntax for context bounds and givens. You can read more about it in SIP-64. In short, before Scala 3.6, it was impossible to name the context bound in the same place where it was defined. The way to do […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2025/04/16/intellij-scala-plugin-2025-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.1 Arrives With Support for Out-of-Project Files in CLion Nova, Qt Renderers, the ST-LINK Debug Server, and West Build Options</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion 2025.1 is now available. This latest version of the JetBrains IDE for C and C++ includes the following key features: You can download CLion 2025.1 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu, or via a patch update from version 2024.3. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.1 CLion Nova […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/04/clion-2025-1-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2025.1 comes with several exciting updates to help you write better Go code and work more efficiently. This release introduces support for golangci-lint, improvements to the Rename refactoring and static analysis, smarter handling of the toolchain directive, and full support for Go 1.24. We’re also bringing major updates for JetBrains AI. Let’s take a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/04/16/goland-2025-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip 2025.1: Schema Context for AI-based Error Explanations, Introspection by Levels for MySQL and MariaDB, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2025.1 is here! This is the first major update of 2025. Let’s take a look at what it has to offer. For a detailed description of this update, visit our What’s New page. AI Assistant Connectivity Working with data Coding assistance
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/04/16/datagrip-2025-1-schema-context-for-ai-based-error-explanations-introspection-by-levels-for-mysql-and-mariadb-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2025.1: Major Improvements to JetBrains AI, Enhanced Angular Support, and Better Monorepo Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our first major release of 2025 is here! This version includes major improvements to JetBrains AI, enhanced Angular support, better monorepo support, a range of user experience improvements, and a whole lot more. DOWNLOAD WEBSTORM 2025.1 To dive deeper into what you can expect in the release, just carry on reading! The new features and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/04/webstorm-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 release has landed! It delivers numerous refinements across the IDE to enhance your productivity, the quality of your code, and your overall comfort. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/intellij-idea-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2025.1: Major AI Assistant Upgrade, Cloud-Based Code Completion for RBS, More Ruby 3.4 Support, Kamal Schema Updates, Enhanced RemDev, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2025.1 introduces a massively upgraded AI Assistant (code completion for RBS, offline mode, more models available, and other features), support for the latest Kamal version, debugging for multi-module projects, and significantly improved remote development. Below is a brief overview of the most notable features. For a detailed description of this update, please visit our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/04/rubymine-2025-1-major-ai-assistant-upgrade/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K2 Mode in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1: Current State and FAQ</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1, K2 mode, a new implementation of Kotlin support, will be enabled by default. This change is an important step in the ongoing effort to improve Kotlin support in the IDE. While this transition brings many improvements and lays the foundation for a smoother, more reliable experience in the future, it’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/k2-mode-in-intellij-idea-2025-1-current-state-and-faq/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Bazel Plugin 2025.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 13:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to tell you about all the changes we’ve made in recent months to improve the Bazel plugin experience in IntelliJ IDEA. Every couple of weeks, we’ve been shipping updates to JetBrains Marketplace with focused fixes and features. Over time, these smaller updates have amounted to substantial enhancements. Most updates are included in the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/what-s-new-in-bazel-plugin-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn AI-Assisted Programming With JetBrains Academy and Nebius</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learning to code with AI isn’t cheating – it’s the next skill every developer needs. AI tools are changing the way we write, test, and maintain code but using them effectively isn’t always straightforward. That’s why we’ve partnered with Nebius, an AI cloud platform known for its expertise in high-performance and AI-first workloads, to bring […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/15/learn-ai-assisted-programming-with-jetbrains-academy-and-nebius/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: GitHub Actions and Setting Up Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog posts, we created integration tests that interact with UI components, assert different properties of UI components, and interact with APIs. Now, it’s time to look at how to set up continuous integration to ensure that we don’t break them in the next commit. We will be creating continuous integration using GitHub […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-github-actions-and-setting-up-continuous-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbox App 2.6 Is Here With Remote Development Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Toolbox App 2.6 introduces support for remote development, allowing you to manage JetBrains tools and projects both locally and on remote servers. You can connect to different host platforms, including Windows, macOS, and Linux, and use the integrated OpenSSH for secure and customizable SSH connections. The Toolbox App supports connections to remote SSH hosts, as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/toolbox-app/2025/04/toolbox-app-2-6-is-here-with-remote-development-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q1 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Option to Cancel Continuity Discounts JetBrains Marketplace now allows plugin authors to cancel continuity discounts for paid plugins. This can be done easily from the Sales tab, with the option to set a specific end date. Customers with active subscriptions for existing plugins will still benefit from the discount, while for new […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q1-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind K2 Mode and How It Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m Yan Zhulanow, and I lead the Kotlin Analysis API team. Last year, we made a series of announcements about Kotlin K2 mode in IntelliJ IDEA. Now, as K2 mode is about to become the default, I am thrilled to tell you more about everything we had to go through to make this release happen. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/the-story-behind-k2-mode-and-how-it-works/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Increase Code Quality in GitHub With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 17:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago we shared a post on how to integrate Qodana with Github Actions on the .NET Community – but a lot has changed since then. Qodana self-hosted has been released, with analysis that can make your code more secure by detecting hardcoded passwords and running taint analysis for JVM. The new Android Linter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/code-quality-in-github/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Language Support in ReSharper and Rider 2025.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our release for ReSharper and Rider 2025.1 is just around the corner, and we have lots of exciting features shipping for the current and next version of C#! This will be a really long post (blame our awesome devs!), so make sure to use the table of contents on the right. Oh, and of course… […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/10/csharp-language-support-in-resharper-and-rider-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 – Help Shape the Future of Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since 2017, we’ve been checking in with developers around the world to better understand how the industry is evolving and how we can build better tools to support you. Now, the Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 is live, and we’d love for you to be part of it. This annual survey is a community milestone that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2025/04/10/developer-ecosystem-survey-2025-help-shape-the-future-of-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Context Parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Context parameters are an upcoming feature in Kotlin, with a variety of use cases including more powerful extension methods and better tools for DSL development. Kotlin 2.2.0 will feature context parameters in Beta, and dedicated IntelliJ IDEA support will be available from 2025.1. Context parameters replace another experimental feature in the language, namely context receivers. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/update-on-context-parameters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bug-Fix Releases Are Available – MPS 2024.3.2 and MPS 2024.1.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 11:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released updates for MPS 2024.1 and MPS 2024.3 that fix several additional issues. Check them out and see what you think. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3.2 Download MPS 2024.3.2 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Download MPS 2024.1.3 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/04/mps-2024-3-2-has-been-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown in Java Docs? Shut Up and Take My Comments!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 07:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you’re building a cutting-edge Java library, optimizing every method, and writing the most efficient algorithms. At some point, you’ll need to document your code because well-documented code increases adoption (a fact backed by various surveys). Including documentation comments within a Java class ensures that the documentation evolves with the code, keeping it relevant. Using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/markdown-in-java-docs-shut-up-and-take-my-comments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate is ready for you to try! The upcoming stable release delivers initial support for .NET 10 and C# 14 Preview features. It also brings the new Files view for repository-wide visibility, a Roslyn syntax tree visualizer, and numerous enhancements for debugging both .NET and C++ solutions. If you’re ready to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/rider-2025-1-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.1 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper and .NET tools 2025.1 RCs are now available. This ReSharper update delivers initial support for .NET 10 Preview and C# 14 features, along with expanded inspections, smarter refactorings, and noticeable performance improvements. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the next release, you can download the RC build from our website […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/resharper-2025-1-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
