<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 18:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.3 with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, by using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most important fixes delivered in v2024.3.3: For a complete […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2024-3-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership insights on Managing Code Quality Conflict</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 17:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The competitive nature of today’s digital business environment makes it critical for software development teams to embrace change, especially if it leads to improved software quality and efficiency. As a manager or team lead, your leadership plays a role in guiding your team through these metamorphoses. At Qodana, we’re all about code quality and security […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/02/managing-conflict/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | February 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The GC.KeepAlive() method in the .NET Framework is not used to prevent garbage collection of an object for the entire method scope, as you might think. Instead, it explicitly ensures that the object remains referenced at a specific point in the code after it’s last used. It’s particularly useful when dealing with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/12/dotinsights-february-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and How JetBrains Built Mellum – the LLM Designed for Code Completion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 12:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, I’m Anton, product manager at JetBrains AI, and I managed training and release of the JetBrains’ first proprietary LLM. 👋 Last year, we launched Mellum, a project I’m incredibly proud of. Mellum isn’t just another LLM – it’s a reflection of JetBrains’ commitment to helping developers work smarter and more efficiently. Today I’d like […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/why-and-how-jetbrains-built-mellum-the-llm-designed-for-code-completion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Debugging for Massive MSVC-Based Projects in CLion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 08:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2025/12_02_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion provides several bundled debuggers, including a modified version of the LLDB for the MSVC toolchain used on Windows. This custom JetBrains LLDB has a number of performance and accuracy improvements. Among other things, it supports an optimized mechanism for handling PDB files containing debugging data. Recently, the debugger received another performance boost: the Step […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/02/lldb-msvc-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Multiplatform Tooling – Shifting Gears</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2025/11_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 15:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2025/11_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A couple of years ago, we initiated the idea of creating a Kotlin Multiplatform IDE to help facilitate the development of KMP applications. We embarked on this venture, building on the Fleet platform, with the intention of releasing it as a standalone IDE. During this time, we have received feedback from our customers, specifically those […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/02/kotlin-multiplatform-tooling-shifting-gears/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Assistant expands with cutting-edge models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2025/11_02_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 13:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2025/11_02_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant offers you the flexibility to choose from a range of advanced cloud-based LLMs from leading providers or use locally hosted models for increased data privacy. We’re continuously updating the platform with the latest high-performance models. Starting from JetBrains IDEs 2024.3.2, you’ll have access to Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet 3.5 and Haiku 3.5, OpenAI’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/ai-assistant-expands-with-cutting-edge-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and Rider 2024.3.5 Bug-Fix Updates Are Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 10:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download. ReSharper 2024.3.5 This update comes with the following fixes: For the full list of issues resolved, please see our issue tracker. Rider 2024.3.5 Notable fixes We’ve addressed an issue in the 2024.3.4 release where the Go to Class feature (Ctrl+N) did not display […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/07/the-resharper-and-rider-2024-3-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 EAP 3: Enhancements for Blazor WASM, User Experience, and the Decompiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 08:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Rider 2025.1 EAP 3 is out! You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Here’s what you can expect from this update: Proper support for Blazor WebAssembly publishing Rider 2025.1 EAP 3 introduces proper support for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/07/rider-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Fresh Picks to Begin 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 06:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, it’s Kodee! Missed me? I hope you had a fantastic break because it’s time for a new edition of Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup! I’ve got some exciting news from the past couple of months just for you. Kotlin YouTube spotlight Did you know there’s a Kotlin YouTube channel packed with awesome content? It’s been buzzing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/02/kodees-kotlin-roundup-fresh-picks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 4: Improvements for Kotlin Development, Automatic Plugin Updates, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 05:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 4 is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 4 Read on to learn about this week’s additions. If you missed our previous overviews […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI o1, o1-mini, and o3-mini models now available in JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant streamlines your workflow and lets you focus on problem-solving instead of writing boilerplate and performing repetitive tasks. Now, we’ve added access to OpenAI o1, o1-mini, and o3-mini models to offer an even more adaptable and personalized experience with AI Assistant. What’s special about OpenAI o1? OpenAI’s o1 series of models are designed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/openai-o1-o1-mini-and-o3-mini-models-now-available-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Option to Cancel Continuity Discounts for Paid Plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 14:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Marketplace is introducing changes to how continuity discounts are handled for paid plugins, giving plugin authors more flexibility in managing their pricing strategies. Here’s everything you need to know about the new option to cancel the continuity discount and how it affects your plugins. What is the continuity discount? The continuity discount is a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/02/option-to-cancel-continuity-discounts-for-paid-plugins/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The JetBrains Platform Gets a New Community Space</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains products, including JetBrains IDEs, YouTrack, TeamCity, and others, are designed with extensibility in mind. While we try to provide our users with a wide feature set, it is impossible to cover all technologies and use cases in a dynamic market like software development. Many ecosystems get new frameworks and libraries every day, and developers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/02/the-jetbrains-platform-gets-a-new-community-space/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – February 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! As we start 2025, we bring you a roundup of the latest advancements in the world of tech. Stay in the loop with a curated list of must-attend events coming up in February, so you can plan your next learning and networking opportunities. Plus, we’re thrilled […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/java-annotated-monthly-february-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of PHP 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 13:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PHP continues to be a cornerstone of web development, powering millions of websites around the world. Its vibrant and dedicated community values its flexibility and ease of use. But what does the current state of PHP development look like? To uncover deeper insights and trends shaping the ecosystem, we’ve turned to our in-house expert, Brent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/02/state-of-php-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant Now Supports Claude Models via Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 11:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The wait is over! Anthropic’s Claude models are here for JetBrains AI Assistant, provisioned in Amazon Bedrock 🎉 With the rise of high-quality language models, each excelling in different tasks, developers need flexible options to meet diverse challenges. That’s why we’re focused on providing multi-model support, helping you create workflows that fit your needs. Anthropic’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/jetbrains-ai-assistant-now-supports-claude-models-via-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is DAST? A Guide to Dynamic Application Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 11:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was brought to you by Matt Keib, draft.dev. Dynamic application security testing (DAST) is a security testing method designed to identify vulnerabilities in applications while running. Unlike static testing methods, which analyze code at rest, DAST interacts with live applications and mimics real-world attacks to uncover security flaws. This makes DAST particularly effective […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/what-is-dast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Django Templates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Django templates are a crucial part of the framework. Understanding what they are and why they’re useful can help you build seamless, adaptable, and functional templates for your Django sites and apps. If you’re new to the framework and looking to set up your first Django project, grasping templates is vital. In this guide, you’ll […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/02/the-ultimate-guide-to-django-templates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Cheuk Ting Ho – New Developer Advocate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 04:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, I am Cheuk, your AI Assistant assistant! Jokes aside, I am the new AI Developer Advocate here at JetBrains. My background is in data science and Python, although I have also recently started learning Rust. I am based in London, UK, and I am very excited to join the team. My home community […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/introducing-cheuk-ting-ho-new-developer-advocate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
