<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:35:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Code Security in JetBrains IDEs and Qodana With Mend.io</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has partnered with Mend.io, a trusted name in application security. This collaboration will help us continue providing the tools you need to develop secure applications with ease and confidence in our IDEs and Qodana. For the best user experience, make sure to use the latest stable version 2024.3.2. Why Mend? Trusted by industry giants […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/maximize-code-security-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana-with-mend-io/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release of TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines. Some highlights of this release include: We recommend upgrading to apply the latest improvements and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/01/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Unreal Engine Project Issues With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you saw our blog post about using Qodana in Unity and .NET projects, you know that we’ve been striving to explore Qodana’s potential for game development. What’s our next stop on this mission? Seeing our code quality platform in action with Unreal Engine, one of the most popular engines for different types of projects […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/01/unreal-engine-project-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2025.1 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the launch of the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major release of ReSharper and the .NET Tools! This initial EAP build is now available for download and offers a preview of the upcoming features and enhancements. Your feedback is crucial in helping us refine these updates, so we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/resharper-2025-1-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 has just begun. This is your chance to preview the new features and enhancements we’ve been working on and share your feedback to help us shape the future of JetBrains Rider. There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: To see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/rider-2025-1-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Files View in Solution Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In modern development, repositories are much more than just .NET solutions. From TypeScript end-to-end tests and Docker compose files to global.json and Playwright configs – your codebase contains numerous essential files that live outside of your C# projects.While these files are fully supported in Rider, they can be hard to find when viewing your solution […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/new-files-view-in-solution-explorer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re starting this year off with the opening of the RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program. In this blog post, you’ll find details about the new features and improvements we’ve been working on. What’s coming in RubyMine 2025.1? AI Assistant The 2024.3 release introduced enhanced cloud-based completion for Ruby code. The upcoming release will […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/01/the-rubymine-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for .env Files: Now Built into PhpStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 20:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .env files are widely used to configure applications by storing configuration settings, environment variables, and sensitive information. This eliminates the need to hardcode these values into the application code. Previously, developers using PhpStorm had to manually install the .env Files Support plugin, originally created by Adel Faizrakhmanov, to unlock dedicated features for working with these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/01/support-for-env-files/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Named a Customers’ Choice Again for Integrated Development Environment Software</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is honored to be recognized as a Customers’ Choice in the 2024 Gartner® Peer Insights™ Voice of the Customer for Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Software – a distinction we are proud to receive for the second consecutive year. Read the Report A trusted vendor We believe JetBrains’ consistent innovation and developer-first approach have earned […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/01/16/gartner-peer-insights-customers-choice/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GoLand 2025.1 Early Access Program Has Started!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for GoLand 2025.1 is now open! In this release cycle, we’re focusing on enhancing Go language support, improving code analysis, and boosting stability to provide a seamless development experience for all the gophers. The first EAP build can be downloaded via the Toolbox App, from our website, or as a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/01/16/the-goland-2025-1-early-access-program-has-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Machine Learning Using Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In recent years, many of our applications have been driven by the high volume of data that we are able to collect and process. Some may refer to us being in the age of data. One of the essential aspects of handling such a large amount of data is anomaly detection – processes that enable […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/anomaly-detection-in-machine-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the new year with the first Early Access Program (EAP) build for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1! This is your chance to get an exclusive first look at the upcoming features and improvements designed to make your coding workflow more efficient than ever. You can download this version from our website, update directly from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for CLion 2025.1 has officially launched. The first EAP build, 251.14649.40, is here to provide an early look at some of the improvements coming in the next major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/01/2025-1-eap-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The Y2K bug, or “Millennium Bug,” was a programming issue caused by storing years with only two digits (e.g., “1999” as “99”) to save memory. As 2000 approached, systems risked interpreting “00” as 1900, leading to potential errors in calculations and data processing. Fears of disruptions in critical systems like banking and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/15/dotinsights-january-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
