<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 08:31:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning Resources for pytest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 08:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we’ll look at how PyCharm helps you when you’re working with pytest, and we will signpost you to a bunch of resources for learning pytest. While some of these resources were created by us here at JetBrains, others were crafted by the storytellers in the pytest community. Using pytest in PyCharm […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/07/learning-resources-for-pytest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Java Still Relevant Nowadays?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 13:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the biggest challenges for technologies nowadays is keeping up to date with the latest developments, remaining relevant to the demands of modern business, and continuing to provide added value for users. The world is changing faster than ever before, and the pace of this change shows no signs of slowing. As a major […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/is-java-still-relevant-nowadays/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make it Happen – With Easter Eggs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 12:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever since the dawn of humanity, we’ve had a fascination with discovery. For Neanderthals, it was fire, for people of the Renaissance it was electricity, and now it’s funny cat gifs and Easter eggs hidden deep within videos. Despite clocking in at just 1 minute and 18 seconds, the “Make it happen. With code. | […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/07/26/make-it-happen-with-easter-eggs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Microsoft Edge? Try Grazie!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 09:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to share that Grazie, our AI writing companion for people in tech, is now available for Microsoft Edge users. This is one more step towards streamlining your non-coding tasks wherever you work. How to get started: Grazie is currently available as a plugin for JetBrains IDEs and as an extension for Microsoft […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2024/07/use-microsoft-edge-try-grazie/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Stimulus in your Rails apps with RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! The RubyMine team is constantly striving to provide support for new technologies for Ruby and Rails. One of the most exciting recent additions to Rails is undoubtedly Hotwire, so we’ve prepared an overview of this suite of frameworks and a tutorial on how to use the most important Turbo and Stimulus features in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/07/how-to-use-stimulus-in-your-rails-apps-with-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.38 Is Here With Support for Virtual Environments Created by Anaconda, Auto-Refresh for Log Files, Improved Proxy Setting Detection, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 12:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.38 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.38 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/07/fleet-1-38-is-here-with-support-for-virtual-environments-created-by-anaconda-auto-refresh-for-log-files-improved-proxy-setting-detection-and-much-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Numbers to Clarity: Using Math to Simplify Data-Heavy Product Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 09:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s world, data platforms are crucial for any organization. These platforms make data storage assets available and provide the necessary tools to work with data effectively. In this blog post, we’ll explore the inner workings of JetBrains’ data kitchen and the role that documentation plays in it. What is the Product Analytics Platform at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/07/from-numbers-to-clarity-using-math-to-simplify-data-heavy-product-documentation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 20 years!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains celebrated 24 years this February! Now, the company comprises 2,200 employees, 40 products, 3M total customers, and 11.4M users who regularly use and trust our tools. But how did it all start? IntelliJ IDEA was the first flagship product we launched, but right after that came ReSharper, which is celebrating 20 years on the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/23/resharper-20-years/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream – Jodie Burchell, Matt Ellis, Khalid Abuhakmeh, and Maarten Balliauw – AI in Game Development With JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Wednesday, August 7, 2024, at 2:00 pm UTC (check other timezones) for a free livestream entitled AI in Game Development With JetBrains AI Assistant, with JetBrains Developer Advocates Jodie Burchell, Matt Ellis, Khalid Abuhakmeh, and Maarten Balliauw. REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Game development has entered a new era with the rise of AI-powered […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/23/livestream-jodie-burchell-matt-ellis-khalid-abuhakmeh-and-maarten-balliauw-ai-in-game-development-with-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Laravel Tutorials and Resources for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 11:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2024/23_07_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Laravel is one of the most popular PHP frameworks, known for its elegant syntax and powerful features. According to the JetBrains Development Ecosystem Report 2023, over 60% of PHP developers use Laravel, and nowadays, many opt for this framework for their professional development. Whether you’re a beginner just starting with web development or an experienced […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/07/the-best-laravel-tutorials-and-resources-for-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dev Containers in JetBrains IDEs – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2024/22_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2024/22_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As cloud technologies and containerization evolve, we enter a new era of software development where flexibility, scalability, and efficiency become key requirements for any project. Dev Containers, or development containers, represent an approach to creating developer workspaces that allows you to focus on the code while worrying less about dependencies and surrounding infrastructure. This tool […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/using-dev-containers-in-jetbrains-ides-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
