<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:24:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘JEP Explained’ – a series of interviews on Java 23 features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The release of Java 23 is around the corner, September 17, 2024, to be precise. What’s new in this Java version and why should you care about it? If you want to know more than just the syntax of these new features – the bigger picture, behind the scenes stories, and real life experiences of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/jep-explained-a-series-of-interviews-on-java-23-features/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? In C#, you can use a feature called caller info attributes to obtain information about the caller of a method. This can be incredibly useful for logging, debugging, or tracing. The attributes CallerMemberName, CallerFilePath, and CallerLineNumber provide information such as the name of the calling method, the path to the source file […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/03/dotinsights-september-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in September</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 10:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new academic season brings fresh opportunities, and at JetBrains Academy, we’re ready to help you make the most of them. With a new compelling project, and fresh educational topics, this September is packed with everything you need to proceed on your coding journey. Let’s take a closer look at these updates. Python 🆕 Project: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/09/03/jetbrains-academy-new-in-september/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us for JetBrains .NET Days Online 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 10:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains .NET Days Online 2024 is back for its sixth edition! This year’s Call for Speakers had so many great submissions from the .NET folks that we couldn’t fit all of the talks we wanted in just one day. Tune in live on September 25–26 for two days of demo-rich sessions and insightful discussions with .NET enthusiasts, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/02/dotnet-days-online-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – August Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 13:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the new academic year approaching, the JetBrains Academy team is excited to bring you fresh updates! Discover new programs and courses designed to advance your tech career. And for computer science tutors we have curated a playlist of videos packed with fun teaching ideas. Dive in now!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/08/30/jetbrains-academy-july-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.07.2 Bug Fix Is Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2024.07.2 bug fix for TeamCity On-Premises just rolled out — download now and keep your servers at peak performance! With every minor update, we deliver a significant number of bug fixes, resolve performance issues, and, most importantly, address security issues. Version 2024.07.2 addresses over 30 issues, including matrix build failures, incorrect information about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/08/teamcity-2024-07-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grazie: What’s New in August</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As August draws to a close, we’re eager to share the latest enhancements to the Grazie browser extension. Introducing Text Playground Meet Text Playground – your new space to refine and polish your writing with AI-powered suggestions for spelling, grammar, and style. To try it, click on the Grazie icon in your browser’s toolbar and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2024/08/grazie-what-s-new-in-august/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.1 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release brings support for a variety of Java 23 language features, including module import declarations, basic Markdown comments, and primitive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/08/intellij-idea-2024-2-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.2.1: What’s New!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.2.1 is here! This release’s key features include initial support for Python 3.13, improvements to the Data View tool window, and enhanced code assistance for Django. Don’t forget to visit our What’s New page to get all the new updates. Download the latest version from our website, or update your current version through our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/08/pycharm-2024-2-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us for JetBrains GameDev Days 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 08:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We invite you to JetBrains GameDev Days 2024, a hybrid event we’re hosting on October 9-10, 2024. Once a year, we invite community speakers to cover topics they are passionate about. We’ve lined up experts from different fields to deliver talks, lead discussions, and share helpful tips on creating exceptional games. Topics will include CI/CD […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/28/join-us-for-jetbrains-gamedev-days-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 07:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Workspace Model, which serves as the internal storage for project models, has exited its experimental phase. Plugin developers can now safely access and modify the workspace model, benefiting from a centralized API, bulk updates, coroutines, and a persistent data structure. This update is particularly relevant for developers working on build tool integration plugins, such […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/08/workspace-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
