<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:14:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and Rider 2024.3.4 Bug-Fix Updates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2025/23_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download. ReSharper 2024.3.4 For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our issue tracker. Rider 2024.3.4 We’ve also fixed several issues affecting .NET MAUI development: For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/23/resharper-and-rider-2024-3-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2: Containerfile Support and Updates for Dockerfiles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 18:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2 is out! With a focus on improving workflows for environments like Docker containers and other remote solutions, this build introduces updates that simplify setup and enhance productivity in these scenarios. You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results of Google Summer of Code 2024 With the Kotlin Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 13:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2024 marked another exciting year with respect to the Kotlin Foundation’s participation in Google Summer of Code (GSoC). GSoC is a global online program that introduces new contributors to open-source development. This year, contributors worked to expand the Kotlin ecosystem under the guidance of mentors from Google, Gradle, Microsoft, and JetBrains. Join our Slack channel […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/01/google-summer-of-code-2024-with-kotlin-results/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Time Series</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 12:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How do you identify unusual patterns in data that might reveal critical issues or hidden opportunities? Anomaly detection helps identify data that deviates significantly from the norm. Time series data, which consists of data collected over time, often includes trends and seasonal patterns. Anomalies in time series data occur when these patterns are disrupted, making […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/anomaly-detection-in-time-series/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing  Perpetual Licenses on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 18:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Marketplace provides various licensing models for paid plugins to suit different user preferences. Now, we are introducing a new option that may change how your users purchase your plugins – perpetual licensing. Licensing options on JetBrains Marketplace The current licensing schemes available on JetBrains Marketplace include: The licensing type (with or without fallback) and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/01/introducing-perpetual-licenses-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 17:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this release, you’ll find improvements to the UI, reworked internals for various components, and a binary-enabled textgen. MPS 2024.3 also brings enhanced support for icons, an applicability condition for quick-fixes, and numerous platform updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 What’s new Let’s check out the new features we’ve prepared for you in this release. Top-level folder […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/01/mps-2024-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Code Security in JetBrains IDEs and Qodana With Mend.io</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has partnered with Mend.io, a trusted name in application security. This collaboration will help us continue providing the tools you need to develop secure applications with ease and confidence in our IDEs and Qodana. For the best user experience, make sure to use the latest stable version 2024.3.2. Why Mend? Trusted by industry giants […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/maximize-code-security-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana-with-mend-io/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release of TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines. Some highlights of this release include: We recommend upgrading to apply the latest improvements and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/01/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Unreal Engine Project Issues With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2025/20_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you saw our blog post about using Qodana in Unity and .NET projects, you know that we’ve been striving to explore Qodana’s potential for game development. What’s our next stop on this mission? Seeing our code quality platform in action with Unreal Engine, one of the most popular engines for different types of projects […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/01/unreal-engine-project-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2025.1 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the launch of the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major release of ReSharper and the .NET Tools! This initial EAP build is now available for download and offers a preview of the upcoming features and enhancements. Your feedback is crucial in helping us refine these updates, so we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/resharper-2025-1-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 has just begun. This is your chance to preview the new features and enhancements we’ve been working on and share your feedback to help us shape the future of JetBrains Rider. There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: To see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/rider-2025-1-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Files View in Solution Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In modern development, repositories are much more than just .NET solutions. From TypeScript end-to-end tests and Docker compose files to global.json and Playwright configs – your codebase contains numerous essential files that live outside of your C# projects.While these files are fully supported in Rider, they can be hard to find when viewing your solution […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/17/new-files-view-in-solution-explorer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_01_2025/17_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re starting this year off with the opening of the RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program. In this blog post, you’ll find details about the new features and improvements we’ve been working on. What’s coming in RubyMine 2025.1? AI Assistant The 2024.3 release introduced enhanced cloud-based completion for Ruby code. The upcoming release will […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/01/the-rubymine-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for .env Files: Now Built into PhpStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 20:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .env files are widely used to configure applications by storing configuration settings, environment variables, and sensitive information. This eliminates the need to hardcode these values into the application code. Previously, developers using PhpStorm had to manually install the .env Files Support plugin, originally created by Adel Faizrakhmanov, to unlock dedicated features for working with these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/01/support-for-env-files/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Named a Customers’ Choice Again for Integrated Development Environment Software</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is honored to be recognized as a Customers’ Choice in the 2024 Gartner® Peer Insights™ Voice of the Customer for Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Software – a distinction we are proud to receive for the second consecutive year. Read the Report A trusted vendor We believe JetBrains’ consistent innovation and developer-first approach have earned […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/01/16/gartner-peer-insights-customers-choice/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GoLand 2025.1 Early Access Program Has Started!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for GoLand 2025.1 is now open! In this release cycle, we’re focusing on enhancing Go language support, improving code analysis, and boosting stability to provide a seamless development experience for all the gophers. The first EAP build can be downloaded via the Toolbox App, from our website, or as a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/01/16/the-goland-2025-1-early-access-program-has-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Machine Learning Using Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In recent years, many of our applications have been driven by the high volume of data that we are able to collect and process. Some may refer to us being in the age of data. One of the essential aspects of handling such a large amount of data is anomaly detection – processes that enable […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/anomaly-detection-in-machine-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
