<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:38:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Compose Multiplatform for iOS is Stable (Plus AI, Web, and More!)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sit back, relax, and let the Kotlin vibes roll in. This roundup is overflowing with news: major moves in Kotlin Multiplatform (Compose Multiplatform for iOS is Stable 🎉), server-side upgrades, Kotlin for web, and smarter Kotlin development with JetBrains AI. Whether you’re building mobile apps, backend services, or playing with interactive notebooks, there’s something here […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/kodees-kotlin-roundup-compose-multiplatform-for-ios-is-stable/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Present and Future of Kotlin for Web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: We remain committed to empowering Kotlin developers with robust and seamless support in Kotlin Multiplatform for web development. To achieve this, we are working on several key areas: Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) aims to help developers share code across different platforms, significantly reducing development time and effort. The web plays a crucial role in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/present-and-future-kotlin-for-web/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.2 – Bug Fixes Have Landed!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of bug fixes for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.2 comes with the following fixes: dotTrace Timeline viewer now correctly locates and lists functions when searching by type name. [DTRC-31451] For the full list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/08/resharper-rider-2025-1-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taint Analysis: WebGoat Demo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 10:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is a text version of the demo provided during the Taint Analysis Livestream: Exploring Hidden Dangers In Your Team’s Code. Today, we’ll use WebGoat as our test application to demonstrate Qodana’s taint analysis functionality. This application is deliberately insecure. The first step is to open the application’s source code (the main branch) in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/taint-analysis-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.03.2 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 09:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re rolling out TeamCity On-Premises 2025.03.2, the second bug-fix update for the major TeamCity version released in back in March. This update addresses a few product issues, such as: Bug-fix updates also include performance improvements and security patches, so it’s always a good idea to install them as they come out. See TeamCity 2025.03.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/05/teamcity-2025-03-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Single Sign On Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 06:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Configure SSO in Qodana Cloud with just a few clicks. If you have a Qodana license with at least 10 users, you can now configure custom single sign on (SSO) support for Qodana Cloud. Quick and easy sign-ons are just another way to make access easier and improve the login experience for your team. Watch […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/new-single-sign-on-is-here/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 – v2025.1.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/intellij-idea-2025-1-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 11:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “C makes it easy to shoot yourself in the foot. C++ makes it harder, but when you do, it blows away your whole leg.” — Bjarne Stroustrup We can’t make С and C++ simpler, but we can make working with them a bit easier. CLion is now free for non-commercial use! Yes, finally. Whether you’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/clion-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.8.0 Released: Compose Multiplatform for iOS Is Stable and Production-Ready</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 16:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today marks a major milestone in the Kotlin Multiplatform journey: the release of Compose Multiplatform 1.8.0, which brings Compose for iOS to Stable. With this update, Kotlin Multiplatform becomes a complete solution for mobile development, enabling flexible code sharing across both business logic and UI without compromising app quality or losing control over platform-specific capabilities. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/compose-multiplatform-1-8-0-released-compose-multiplatform-for-ios-is-stable-and-production-ready/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study in CDEs: Building CodeCanvas with CodeCanvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 13:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains CodeCanvas is a tool for orchestrating Cloud Development Environments (CDEs). These environments aim to solve some of the long-standing issues of local development setups: tedious onboarding, environment drift, resource-heavy builds, and more. When we started building CodeCanvas, we knew dogfooding would be essential. Our goal was to experience the product the same way users […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/05/building-with-codecanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the May edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This month, we have a special guest – Anton Arhipov. He joins us to share standout articles and other discoveries that recently caught his expert eye. Alongside his picks, you’ll find your regular dose of Java and tech news, AI updates, and industry events that are […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/java-annotated-monthly-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? C# allows you to define custom operators for your own types by overloading built-in operators (like +, -, ==, etc.). This is not something most developers use often, and it can make your code behave like native types, which is a powerful but underutilized feature. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/06/dotinsights-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making WebStorm Faster: How We’re Improving Performance Behind the Scenes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At WebStorm, performance isn’t a side project – it’s a core part of what we do. Every millisecond counts when you’re deep in the flow, writing and navigating code. We’ve heard your feedback loud and clear: performance issues break that flow, and they’re frustrating. That’s why improving speed, responsiveness, and reliability is one of our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/05/improving-webstorm-performance-behind-the-scenes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2025.2 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 08:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.2, which we plan to introduce in July. After reviewing your feedback and our strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following areas for development: 🚀 CLion Nova language engine improvements and bug fixes 🎛️ New features for embedded development 🤖 Support for Junie, JetBrains’ smart coding agent Read […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/2025-2-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Unleash the Power of Git with IntelliJ IDEA Version Control Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 08:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Justin Clareburt and discover all of the powerful version control tools available in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: May 15, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Discover all of the powerful UI tooling in IntelliJ IDEA that you never knew was there. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/new-livestream-new-livestream-unleash-the-power-of-git-with-intellij-idea-cersion-control-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – April Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 16:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month brings new opportunities to support your learning and development – from AI-powered features in your IDE and a new AI course with Nebius to practical Python training. Additionally, don’t miss the upcoming free online IntelliJ IDEA Conf. Read on for more details.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/05/02/jetbrains-academy-april/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana 2025.1 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 12:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we continue improving Qodana, we’re excited to introduce a set of powerful updates that enhance performance, improve security analysis, and offer better integration opportunities for you and your team. Let’s take a look at some of the most exciting changes with the Qodana 2025.1 release! Try Qodana OWASP Top 10: covering even more categories […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/qodana-2025-1-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
