<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:47:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Connect MCP Servers to Junie in PhpStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open standard introduced by Anthropic. Think of it as a USB-C port for AI: a consistent way to plug the AI models your AI agent uses into specific tools and data sources. You can connect Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, to a wide variety of officially […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/09/connect-mcp-servers-to-junie-in-phpstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – September 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 08:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month’s Java Annotated Monthly comes with a fresh mix of Java, Kotlin, AI, and tech news, plus a look at some great events you won’t want to miss. We’ve also got a featured section by Marit van Dijk, covering the new Java 25 release, the latest IntelliJ IDEA updates, and a playful take on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/java-annotated-monthly-september-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Static Code Analysis Can Improve Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 18:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developer experience is not only about nice editors and fast build times. It is about reducing friction so developers can focus on solving problems rather than fighting with tools. Among the most effective developer experience tools available today is static code analysis. By examining code without running it, static analysis surfaces potential issues early and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/09/improve-developer-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Set of Updates and Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 15:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first bug-fix update for 2025.2. This build brings important fixes and quality improvements to both ReSharper and Rider, along with some targeted performance optimizations. If you haven’t upgraded to the 2025.2 versions of our products, we highly recommend that you check out these two blog posts: ReSharper 2025.2: Out-of-Process mode, support for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/04/resharper-and-rider-2025-2-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains JavaScript Day 2025 Registration Is Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey everyone! We’re thrilled to invite you to the fifth edition of JetBrains JavaScript Day – a free online event for everyone passionate about JavaScript. Five years in, we’re celebrating by bringing together some of the most inspiring voices in the JavaScript world. They’ll share their stories, ideas, and lessons learned – giving you practical […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/09/jetbrains-javascript-day-2025-registration-is-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Annotation Handling in Kotlin 2.2: Less Boilerplate, Fewer Surprises</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 11:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many developers have run into subtle issues with annotations when working with Kotlin and frameworks like Spring or JPA-based persistence frameworks. For instance, an annotation applied to a constructor parameter might not always end up in the property or backing field where the framework expects it. This often means annotations don’t land where they’re needed. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/improved-annotation-handling-in-kotlin-2-2-less-boilerplate-fewer-surprises/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Vulnerable API Detection in JetBrains IDEs and Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 08:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the start of the year, we announced a partnership with Mend.io to maximize code security in JetBrains tools. The partnership provided us with quality data about vulnerable and malicious packages, allowing our IDEs and Qodana to spot them for you in your projects. Over the last few months, we have been working on integrating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/enhanced-vulnerable-api-detection-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Popular Python Frameworks and Libraries in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 15:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re building APIs, dashboards, or machine learning pipelines, choosing the right framework can make or break your project. Every year, we survey thousands of Python developers to help you understand how the ecosystem is evolving, from tooling and languages to frameworks and libraries. Our insights from the State of Python 2025 offer a snapshot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/09/the-most-popular-python-frameworks-and-libraries-in-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | September 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 11:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The C# language has a GOTO statement? It sure does. This is a case of “just because you could doesn’t mean you should”. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 🌟 Featured Content This month’s featured content is from Chris Woodruff! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/02/dotinsights-september-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 10:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hold on to your helper methods – RubyMine is now FREE for non-commercial use! Whether you’re learning Ruby and Rails, pushing open-source forward, creating dev content, or building your passion project, we want to make sure you have the tools to enjoy what you do even more… for free. Another chapter in the story We […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/09/rubymine-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Our Newest Innovators: Welcoming AI4SE Interns as JetBrains Employees!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 15:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picture this: You’re working on your MSc thesis as an intern in software engineering, not just as an academic exercise, but side-by-side with an industry team, tackling real projects and real problems, refining code, and witnessing your ideas come alive. By the time you’ve graduated, you’re already a valued team member, ready to hit the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/ai4se-interns-jetbrains-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The LSP API Is Now Available to All IntelliJ IDEA Users and Plugin Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 09:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2025/01_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The way developers create plugins implementing the Language Server Protocol (LSP) in JetBrains IDEs is undergoing a significant shift. With PyCharm and IntelliJ IDEA adopting a unified distribution model, we’re removing a key obstacle that has been limiting LSP adoption within the IntelliJ Platform ecosystem. Starting with IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate 2025.2, users can continue using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/the-lsp-api-is-now-available-to-all-intellij-idea-users-and-plugin-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPC World Finals Livestream: ecnerwala and SecondThread Speed-Solving Kotlin Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 19:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us live from the ICPC World Finals in Baku, Azerbaijan, for a special event. This year, we are hosting a head-to-head match where two of the world’s top competitive programmers, Andrew ‘ecnerwala’ He and David ‘SecondThread’ Harmeyer, will speed-solve Kotlin problems in real time. Save the date: September 2, 2025, at 9:30 am UTC […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/icpc-world-finals-livestream-ecnerwala-secondthread-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 09:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 – v2025.2.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
