<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 11:42:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The State of Python 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 11:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Michael Kennedy, the founder of Talk Python and a PSF Fellow. Welcome to the highlights, trends, and key actions from the eighth annual Python Developers Survey. This survey is conducted as a collaborative effort between the Python Software Foundation and JetBrains’ PyCharm team. My name is Michael Kennedy, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/08/the-state-of-python-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps for Startups: CI/CD from the Ground Up</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 10:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The benefits of DevOps are not limited to large enterprises. For startups, DevOps can offer the agility you need to keep responding and adapting to market demands, while maintaining the quality users now expect. Why DevOps Matters for Startups As a startup, you’re probably feeling the pressure to get your product or service to market […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/08/devops-for-startups/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking about trying or upgrading to Datalore Cloud? This August, you can save 30%.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 10:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve recently started a trial or are thinking about trying Datalore, and a Cloud plan is on your radar, now is a good time to consider it. Until the end of August, new users and teams currently using a trial version of Datalore can get 30% off their first payment when subscribing to the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/08/15/save-30/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Quarter, New Qodana 2025.2 Release Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 13:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following the recent rollout of our new Insights dashboard, Native mode, Self-Hosted Lite version, SSO functionality, and Visual Studio plugin, our Qodana 2025.2 update promises another round of improvements and extensions. Take a look at what we’ve been doing as we focus on providing greater access to code quality and security in your organization, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/08/qodana-2025-2-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.07.1 Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 12:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity On-Premises 2025.07.1, the first bug-fix for the recently released TeamCity 2025.07, is ready to be installed on your On-Premises servers. This update addresses a significant number of issues, including: Bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements, so we recommend installing them promptly. See TeamCity 2025.07.1 Release Notes for the complete list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/08/teamcity-2025-07-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Performance Improvements in ReSharper 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 10:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2025.2 release of ReSharper introduces a number of performance and responsiveness improvements across several key areas. This post outlines the most notable updates, including out-of-process support, improved solution startup, faster refactorings, and better Razor/Blazor handling. Out-of-Process mode Public Preview ReSharper 2025.2 is the first stable release to support running ReSharper out of process (OOP) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/14/resharper-performance-improvements-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2025.2 Are Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 10:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ReSharper and the .NET tools 2025.2 are available for download. This release introduces the public preview of ReSharper’s Out-of-Process mode, adds support for the latest C# 14 and C++26 features, and brings a range of improvements for performance, refactorings, and inspections. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the next stable release, you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/14/resharper-and-the-net-tools-2025-2-are-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 Is Here with Junie, In-IDE OpenTelemetry, Game Dev Upgrades, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2025.2 delivers a big step forward in intelligent development tooling, bringing AI deeper into your workflow with Junie – our AI coding agent – along with runtime observability through the new OpenTelemetry plugin, a reworked Monitoring tool window, and improved debugging across platforms. Let’s take a closer look at what’s new. Meet Junie, your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/14/rider-2025-2-is-here-with-junie-in-ide-opentelemetry-game-dev-upgrades-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Fuzz Testing in CLion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 09:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fuzz testing is an effective technique for identifying bugs that are difficult to detect using unit tests or static analysis alone. This article will show you how to perform fuzz testing in CLion, analyze the results, and debug a tested function. We’ll use CI Fuzz, a fuzz testing tool developed by Code Intelligence, a company […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/fuzz-testing-in-clion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – August Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your August learning boost is here – with free tools, career-launching courses, practical advice from the JetBrains Academy team, and your shot at winning a MacBook Pro.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/08/13/jetbrains-academy-august/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simpler, More Transparent Model for AI Quotas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: Starting August 18, 2025, we’re rolling out a new AI quota model that makes AI subscriptions easier to understand and manage, while also letting you seamlessly extend your usage beyond your included quota with transparent pricing in real currency. The initial rollout will apply to individuals and organizations, with AI Enterprise updates to follow. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/08/a-simpler-more-transparent-model-for-ai-quotas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning-Fast Python: Mastering the uv Package Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 13:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out our recent livestream from August 7 on uv, a next-generation Python package manager revolutionizing Python development with speeds 10-100x faster than pip. Released just last year and written in Rust, uv replaces long-standing Python dependency management challenges with a single, lightning-fast tool that just works. Join us as we demonstrate uv‘s game-changing capabilities […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/08/lightning-fast-python-mastering-the-uv-package-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Transactions? Let Spring Debugger Do the Heavy Lifting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 10:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Framework’s declarative transaction management is incredibly powerful, allowing developers to simply add the @Transactional annotation to a method and let Spring handle the transaction details. However, misconfigurations or misunderstandings of how transactions work can lead to frustrating database transaction handling issues. Debugging these problems often means sifting through a lot of AOP proxy code, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/debugging-transactions-let-spring-debugger-do-the-heavy-lifting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: 2.2.20-Beta2, Kotlin LSP Update, Shipaton 2025, and a New Face on the Foundation Board</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kodee here – your ever-cheerful tour guide through the ever-bustling streets of Kotlin-land. Summer may be the season for vacations, but we’re not slowing down! Let’s take a stroll through the latest news. What else to read YouTube highlights Check out some of the most popular videos on our Kotlin YouTube channel: And these are […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kodee-kotlin-roundup-july-25-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell Is Now an AI-First Tool for Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From the 2025.2 version onward, every paid DataSpell subscription includes JetBrains AI Pro for free, reflecting our commitment to bringing AI into our data products. Please note that the bundled AI Pro plan is limited to use inside DataSpell. Download DataSpell 2025.2 AI Pro included at no extra cost! You now get JetBrains AI Pro […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/08/dataspell-is-now-an-ai-first-tool-for-data-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? A feature of C# is null-coalescing operators. The ?? operator (null-coalescing operator) returns the left-hand operand if it is not null; otherwise, it evaluates and returns the right-hand operand. The ??= operator (null-coalescing assignment operator) assigns the right-hand operand’s value to the left-hand operand only if the left-hand operand is null. Welcome to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/12/dotinsights-august-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free JetBrains Student Pack – Your Toolkit for a Future in Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For a successful career in tech, having the right tools from day one makes all the difference. That’s why we created the JetBrains Student Pack – all-in-one development kit designed to help you learn to code, build real-world projects, and kickstart your future career, using the same tools trusted by developers at Google, NASA, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/08/12/jetbrains-student-pack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains with its CLion IDE Is Now an Official ST Authorized Partner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re pleased to announce that JetBrains has joined the ST Partner Program. Through this collaboration, we aim to improve the experience of embedded developers working with ST microcontroller solutions in CLion. Here’s what developers get from this partnership: About ST ST (STMicroelectronics) is a European company that specializes in designing, developing, and manufacturing semiconductor technologies. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/st-authorized-partner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
