<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:32:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 Goes Beta With Enhanced CLion Nova, Debug Servers, and OpenCV Image Viewer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of CLion 2024.3 is now available with key improvements and changes announced for the upcoming release. You can download build 243.21565.87 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 BETA Read the full release notes on YouTrack. Below is a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/11/clion-2024-3-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on Unreal Engine Support in TeamCity: UGS Integration and Open-Sourcing the Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve got a few exciting updates about the Unreal Engine plugin announced in the previous blog post. TL;DR – we’re adding Unreal Game Sync (UGS) integration and open-sourcing the plugin. These updates are all about making the CI/CD experience smoother for Unreal Engine devs and getting the community more involved. UGS Before diving in, let’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/11/unreal-engine-plugin-ugs-integration-and-open-sourcing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in November</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 18:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month, we’ve introduced new projects and topics to help you reach your coding goals in Kotlin, backend development, Git, or AI. Kotlin 🆕 Project: My first project with Kotlin. Easy Imagine that you’re the owner of a new small corner shop. You are doing well and want to determine how much you earned in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/11/05/jetbrains-academy-new-in-november/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update November 2024 – Project File Tooling, Compose Resources, KSP2, and Android Release Builds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 13:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.5.0 is now available! With this release, we’ve improved the IDE experience when working with multiple modules and project.yaml files, made nested completion in Amper configuration files more powerful, introduced support for Compose Resources and KSP2, improved Android release builds, and more! For the full list of changes and bug fixes in Amper 0.5.0, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2024/11/amper-update-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 11:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Java Annotated Monthly is here! Check out the latest news across Java, Spring, AI, and emerging technologies. We offer practical tutorials to enhance your skills, a curated list of November’s top tech events, both online and offline, and an exclusive feature by industry expert Mala Gupta. Stay informed, and stay ahead! Featured Content In this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/java-annotated-monthly-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wow! It’s easy to take the rapid pace of technological advancement for granted, especially given how many of us have been tech-natives for most of our lives. For Mac lovers, Infinite Mac takes a trip across the decades of the 1980s to 2000s through the lens of releases. Experience history all in your browser. Draw […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/04/dotinsights-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dobar Dan! Algorithm and Code Training School Heads to Serbia This Winter!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the beginning of 2025, the Algorithm and Code Training School (ACTS) camp is moving to an exciting new location – Serbia! While our summer camp in Romania was a great success, we’re taking things to the next level with an even more intensive competition format. This camp is perfect for young coders aiming to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/11/04/dobar-dan-algorithm-and-code-training-school-heads-to-serbia-this-winter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Full-Stack App With Go and React</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a language that emerged over 14 years ago, Go has many use cases. From web development, APIs, and CLIs to Wasm, cloud technologies, and even AI-powered tools, its applications are broad. The same goes for demo projects, which have countless variations and purposes! Now, wouldn’t it be great if there was a full-stack, API-oriented, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/11/04/create-a-full-stack-app-with-go-and-react/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Build GraphQL Services With Spring Boot Like Netflix</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Netflix Staff Engineer, Paul Bakker, to discover how Netflix implements GraphQL services with Spring Boot and the DGS framework. Date: November 14, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Netflix uses GraphQL and the DGS framework (recently fully integrated with Spring […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Memory of Stiver</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 13:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On October 20, the original author of the Fernflower Java decompiler, Stiver, passed away after a long fight against glioblastoma. Stiver was a German programmer of Russian origin, primarily developing software for medical equipment. Twenty years ago, he developed a deep professional interest in Java virtual machine internals. You may remember his research blog posts, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/in-memory-of-stiver/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Blogs for Experienced Programmers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following up on our previous article in which we shared some great multi-author blogs to follow, today we have a curated selection of personal blogs from top Java experts. These experts aren’t just the best at what they do – they’re also great at sharing their knowledge in ways that are easy to understand and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/top-java-blogs-for-experienced-programmers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – October Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve got Halloween updates just for you! The JetBrains Academy team has brewed up a cauldron of October goodies, including new events, webinars, Git videos, courses, and contests for students with spooktacular prizes!🎃
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/10/31/jetbrains-academy-october-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – October 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the October edition of PHP Annotated! This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise—we’ve done it for you. Highlights PHP 8.4 RC3 is available for testing Release managers Calvin Buckley, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/10/php-annotated-october-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Your Workflow in IntelliJ IDEA’s Database Tools With AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 13:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In IntelliJ IDEA, you can leverage AI Assistant’s capabilities within Database Tools for more efficient data querying and handling. It can significantly speed up SQL query generation, explain code, suggest fixes, and even create tables and populate them with test data on your command! Let’s get started! Get IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate To enable the AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/streamline-workflow-in-database-tools-with-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Meet at EDUtech Asia 2024 in Singapore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 11:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Meet the JetBrains Academy team at EDUtech Asia 2024 in Singapore on November 6–7. Stop by booth D40 to talk with us about learning and teaching computer science with JetBrains Academy, grab some swag, or just say hi! You’ll also have the opportunity to learn how to use JetBrains IDEs for course creation and teaching, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/10/31/let-s-meet-at-edutech-asia-2024-in-singapore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Beta Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 is now available with all the key improvements and new features coming in the major release. You can download the latest build from our website, from the free Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Beta To see the most notable updates from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smooth Parameter Replacement | TeamCity Pipelines Pulse #8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 15:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2024/30_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to bring you an update on our smooth parameter replacement feature. It’s already made parameter replacement easier, and now we’re taking it even further with some key improvements. In this iteration, we’re rolling out the smooth parameter replacement feature to more areas. You’ll now find it in almost all runner fields except for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/smooth-parameter-replacement-feature-teamcity-pipelines-pulse-8/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
