<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 12:47:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Qodana 2025.1 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 12:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we continue improving Qodana, we’re excited to introduce a set of powerful updates that enhance performance, improve security analysis, and offer better integration opportunities for you and your team. Let’s take a look at some of the most exciting changes with the Qodana 2025.1 release! Try Qodana OWASP Top 10: covering even more categories […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/qodana-2025-1-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Database Management With WebStorm’s Database Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Here’s something that might surprise you: if you’re using WebStorm, you already have access to a professional-grade database IDE. That’s right, the full-featured DataGrip database toolset isn’t just a separate product or an additional paid plugin anymore; it’s bundled into WebStorm. Even if you’re comfortable with other IDEs and their database extensions, you might find […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/05/streamline-database-management-with-webstorm-s-database-tool/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structuring Ktor Projects Using Domain-Driven Design (DDD) Concepts: A Step-by-Step Guide With a Minimalistic CRM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 12:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this guide, we’ll show you how to structure a project using domain-driven design (DDD) concepts, step by step, by building a minimalistic CRM system. Sample code for the article: https://github.com/antonarhipov/ktor-ddd-example Ktor is a highly flexible framework that allows developers to structure their applications however they see fit. Unlike some opinionated frameworks (like Spring Boot), […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/domain-driven-design-guide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mellum Goes Open Source: A Purpose-Built LLM for Developers, Now on Hugging Face</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 11:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2025/30_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mellum doesn’t try to know everything. It’s designed to do one thing really well: code completion. We call it a focal model – built with purposeful depth and not concerned with chasing breadth. But code completion is just the start. Mellum will grow into a family of focal models, each specialized for different coding tasks […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/04/mellum-goes-open-source-a-purpose-built-llm-for-developers-now-on-hugging-face/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jens Oliver Meiert: How WebStorm and AI Assistant Fit Right Into My Workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 17:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For more than two decades, Jens Oliver Meiert has been at the forefront of web development, working with industry giants like Google and Miro, as well as leading engineering teams across various companies. With extensive experience in frontend development, he has witnessed firsthand how tools and workflows have evolved over time. In this interview, Jens […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/04/jens-oliver-meiert-how-webstorm-and-ai-assistant-fit-right-into-my-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Set of Bug Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.1 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 06:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2025/29_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, The ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.1 bug-fix updates have just been released! If you haven’t upgraded to the 2025.1 versions of our products, we highly recommend that you check out these two blog posts: And now, let’s go over the most important fixes in 2025.1.1. ReSharper 2025.1.1 The first bug-fix update fixes the issue […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/29/2025-1-1-hot-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant: Smarter, More Capable, and a New Free Tier</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2025/28_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 15:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2025/28_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release introduces major enhancements to boost productivity and reduce repetitive work. Updates include smarter code completion, support for new cloud models like OpenAI GPT-4.1, Claude 3.7 Sonnet, and Gemini 2.5 Pro, advanced RAG-based context awareness, and a new edit mode for multi-file edits directly from the chat. Plus, our revamped subscription model includes both […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/04/jetbrains-ai-assistant-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Kotlin Notebooks for Productive Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2025/28_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 15:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2025/28_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin Notebook is a new interactive environment for JVM developers. This article will cover the main Notebook features and how you can utilize them to improve your productivity. How to use Kotlin Notebook Kotlin Notebook is bundled with IntelliJ IDEA starting from the 2025.1 release, and it is easier than ever to start working with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/how-to-use-kotlin-notebooks-for-productive-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
