<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:19:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Is Now Part of TeamCity Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2025/26_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2025/26_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We introduced TeamCity Pipelines in March 2024 to make CI/CD setup simpler and more intuitive, without limiting what teams can build and automate. Pipelines brought a new workflow focused on a more guided configuration experience, including a visual editor with drag-and-drop dependencies, YAML for defining building routines from scratch, and a set of practical configuration […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/pipelines-sunset/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Turns 30: A Celebration of Code, Community, and Creativity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2025/25_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 09:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2025/25_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Created by Yukihiro “Matz” Matsumoto and first released in 1995, Ruby arrived with a purpose that was simple but profound: to make coding more human, more intuitive, and more enjoyable. Its object-oriented model, dynamic typing, and elegant syntax offered a fresh alternative to the heavier and more complex languages of that era. As Ruby marks […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/12/ruby-turns-30-a-celebration-of-code-community-and-creativity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Wanted to Ask About Rust – Answered by Herbert Wolverson</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disclaimer: This article was created using AI-based writing and communication companions. With its help, the core topics of this rich and nuanced livestream were conveniently distilled into a compact blog post format. In our recent JetBrains livestream, Vitaly Bragilevsky sat down with Rust expert and educator Herbert Wolverson (Ardan Labs) to talk about everything Rust […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/12/23/everything-you-wanted-to-ask-about-rust-answered-by-herbert-wolverson/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thread Dumps and Project Loom (Virtual Threads)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:14:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2025/23_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve been keeping up with Java virtual threads, you already know that this hot new feature significantly improves hardware utilization for parallel I/O-bound operations. Virtual threads map multiple concurrent I/O operations to a single OS thread without blocking. The novel aspect of this approach is that it requires minimal changes to the codebase, as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/thread-dumps-and-project-loom-virtual-threads/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code in Rust: Winners and Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you to everyone who joined Advent of Code 2025 in Rust! It was inspiring to see many Rustaceans solving algorithmic puzzles, and celebrating the holiday coding season with the community. Before the Advent began, Vitaly Bragilevsky published a blog post on how to use AI in Advent of Code challenge responsibly and effectively. This […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/12/22/advent-of-code-in-rust-winners-and-highlights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
