<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:05:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip and Database Tools UX Survey #2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to launch the second edition of our User Experience Survey for DataGrip and the Database Tools &amp;amp; SQL Plugin! Your feedback from the previous survey helped us better understand your needs and prioritize the features and improvements that matter most to you. Thanks to your input, we’ve already delivered a first set of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/05/13/datagrip-and-database-tools-ux-survey-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Rust the Future of Programming?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 12:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rust is rewriting the rules of modern software development as the fastest-growing programming language. Its unmatched performance, memory safety without garbage collection, and concurrency capabilities are capturing developers’ attention worldwide. According to our data, with 2,267,000 developers using Rust in the last 12 months and 709,000 identifying it as a primary language, Rust’s footprint in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/05/13/is-rust-the-future-of-programming/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Cloud-Ready Apps Locally: Spring Boot, AWS, and LocalStack in Action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developing an application with AWS services can introduce significant local‑development hurdles. Often, developers don’t receive timely AWS access, or a sysadmin inadvertently grants credentials for the wrong account – only to fix the error a week later. Then, when engineers discover they still lack permissions for certain resources, they must endure yet another week-long wait […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/building-cloud-ready-apps-locally-spring-boot-aws-and-localstack-in-action/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Plugin Verifier and API Compatibility Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maintaining plugin compatibility across JetBrains IDEs can be tricky — but the Plugin Verifier is here to help. On Wednesday, May 21, at 2:00 PM UTC, join us for a live session with IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Róbert Novotný and Yann Cébron, focused on the Plugin Verifier and API compatibility maintenance. During the webinar, you’ll discover how: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/05/livestream-plugin-verifier-and-api-compatibility-maintenance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CodeCanvas 2025.1 With Free Tier and Toolbox Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 09:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April, we released CodeCanvas 2025.1 with many important changes. The release brings improved infrastructure flexibility for easier multi-region setups, a new AWS CloudFormation installation option, enhanced environment logs, and more. Today, we want to highlight two major updates: See the full What’s New for the full details. Use CodeCanvas for free With the 2025.1 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/05/codecanvas-2025-1-with-free-tier-and-toolbox-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Think in an AI World: 5 Lessons for Novice Programmers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 14:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the second article of the series How to Learn to Code in an AI World. Don’t miss the first, Is it Still Worth Learning to Code? Imagine the following scenario: A student is enrolled in an introductory computer science course. They have no previous programming experience and don’t consider themselves very good at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/05/12/five-lessons-for-novice-programmers-ai-world/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAST vs DAST: Differences And When to Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anyone working in the software development field knows cybersecurity is a threat you cannot afford to downplay. A cyberattack on a product or service you’ve created carries a risk of serious financial and reputational damage, as well as regulatory penalties, depending on the industry and jurisdiction. Defending your software against cyberattacks means addressing security at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/05/sast-vs-dast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Compose Multiplatform for iOS is Stable (Plus AI, Web, and More!)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sit back, relax, and let the Kotlin vibes roll in. This roundup is overflowing with news: major moves in Kotlin Multiplatform (Compose Multiplatform for iOS is Stable 🎉), server-side upgrades, Kotlin for web, and smarter Kotlin development with JetBrains AI. Whether you’re building mobile apps, backend services, or playing with interactive notebooks, there’s something here […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/kodees-kotlin-roundup-compose-multiplatform-for-ios-is-stable/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Present and Future of Kotlin for Web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: We remain committed to empowering Kotlin developers with robust and seamless support in Kotlin Multiplatform for web development. To achieve this, we are working on several key areas: Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) aims to help developers share code across different platforms, significantly reducing development time and effort. The web plays a crucial role in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/present-and-future-kotlin-for-web/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.2 – Bug Fixes Have Landed!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of bug fixes for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.2 comes with the following fixes: dotTrace Timeline viewer now correctly locates and lists functions when searching by type name. [DTRC-31451] For the full list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/08/resharper-rider-2025-1-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taint Analysis: WebGoat Demo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 10:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is a text version of the demo provided during the Taint Analysis Livestream: Exploring Hidden Dangers In Your Team’s Code. Today, we’ll use WebGoat as our test application to demonstrate Qodana’s taint analysis functionality. This application is deliberately insecure. The first step is to open the application’s source code (the main branch) in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/taint-analysis-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.03.2 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 09:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re rolling out TeamCity On-Premises 2025.03.2, the second bug-fix update for the major TeamCity version released in back in March. This update addresses a few product issues, such as: Bug-fix updates also include performance improvements and security patches, so it’s always a good idea to install them as they come out. See TeamCity 2025.03.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/05/teamcity-2025-03-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Single Sign On Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 06:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Configure SSO in Qodana Cloud with just a few clicks. If you have a Qodana license with at least 10 users, you can now configure custom single sign on (SSO) support for Qodana Cloud. Quick and easy sign-ons are just another way to make access easier and improve the login experience for your team. Watch […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/new-single-sign-on-is-here/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 – v2025.1.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/intellij-idea-2025-1-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 11:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “C makes it easy to shoot yourself in the foot. C++ makes it harder, but when you do, it blows away your whole leg.” — Bjarne Stroustrup We can’t make С and C++ simpler, but we can make working with them a bit easier. CLion is now free for non-commercial use! Yes, finally. Whether you’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/clion-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.8.0 Released: Compose Multiplatform for iOS Is Stable and Production-Ready</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 16:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today marks a major milestone in the Kotlin Multiplatform journey: the release of Compose Multiplatform 1.8.0, which brings Compose for iOS to Stable. With this update, Kotlin Multiplatform becomes a complete solution for mobile development, enabling flexible code sharing across both business logic and UI without compromising app quality or losing control over platform-specific capabilities. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/compose-multiplatform-1-8-0-released-compose-multiplatform-for-ios-is-stable-and-production-ready/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study in CDEs: Building CodeCanvas with CodeCanvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 13:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains CodeCanvas is a tool for orchestrating Cloud Development Environments (CDEs). These environments aim to solve some of the long-standing issues of local development setups: tedious onboarding, environment drift, resource-heavy builds, and more. When we started building CodeCanvas, we knew dogfooding would be essential. Our goal was to experience the product the same way users […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/05/building-with-codecanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the May edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This month, we have a special guest – Anton Arhipov. He joins us to share standout articles and other discoveries that recently caught his expert eye. Alongside his picks, you’ll find your regular dose of Java and tech news, AI updates, and industry events that are […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/java-annotated-monthly-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? C# allows you to define custom operators for your own types by overloading built-in operators (like +, -, ==, etc.). This is not something most developers use often, and it can make your code behave like native types, which is a powerful but underutilized feature. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/06/dotinsights-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making WebStorm Faster: How We’re Improving Performance Behind the Scenes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At WebStorm, performance isn’t a side project – it’s a core part of what we do. Every millisecond counts when you’re deep in the flow, writing and navigating code. We’ve heard your feedback loud and clear: performance issues break that flow, and they’re frustrating. That’s why improving speed, responsiveness, and reliability is one of our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/05/improving-webstorm-performance-behind-the-scenes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
