<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 13:56:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The State of PHP 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 13:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PHP continues to be a cornerstone of web development, powering millions of websites around the world. Its vibrant and dedicated community values its flexibility and ease of use. But what does the current state of PHP development look like? To uncover deeper insights and trends shaping the ecosystem, we’ve turned to our in-house expert, Brent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/02/state-of-php-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant Now Supports Claude Models via Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 11:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The wait is over! Anthropic’s Claude models are here for JetBrains AI Assistant, provisioned in Amazon Bedrock 🎉 With the rise of high-quality language models, each excelling in different tasks, developers need flexible options to meet diverse challenges. That’s why we’re focused on providing multi-model support, helping you create workflows that fit your needs. Anthropic’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/jetbrains-ai-assistant-now-supports-claude-models-via-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is DAST? A Guide to Dynamic Application Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 11:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was brought to you by Matt Keib, draft.dev. Dynamic application security testing (DAST) is a security testing method designed to identify vulnerabilities in applications while running. Unlike static testing methods, which analyze code at rest, DAST interacts with live applications and mimics real-world attacks to uncover security flaws. This makes DAST particularly effective […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/what-is-dast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Django Templates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Django templates are a crucial part of the framework. Understanding what they are and why they’re useful can help you build seamless, adaptable, and functional templates for your Django sites and apps. If you’re new to the framework and looking to set up your first Django project, grasping templates is vital. In this guide, you’ll […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/02/the-ultimate-guide-to-django-templates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Cheuk Ting Ho – New Developer Advocate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 04:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, I am Cheuk, your AI Assistant assistant! Jokes aside, I am the new AI Developer Advocate here at JetBrains. My background is in data science and Python, although I have also recently started learning Rust. I am based in London, UK, and I am very excited to join the team. My home community […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/02/introducing-cheuk-ting-ho-new-developer-advocate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps in Game Development With Rust and Bevy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 13:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some of us might remember this 15-year-old Abstruse Goose comic about our choices in life. Learning the theory of computations might not be the most direct path to video game development. However, you still need to learn programming, some math (at least geometry), and mechanics – or as it’s often somewhat erroneously labeled – physics. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/02/04/first-steps-in-game-development-with-rust-and-bevy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – January Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 14:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2025 is here, and it’s brought lots of new educational content. Dive into the latest tech trends, learning opportunities, insightful events, and nifty plugins to boost your productivity. Happy reading.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/02/03/jetbrains-academy-december-january/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.2 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 13:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.2 bug-fix update is out and ready to be installed on your servers! This update addresses over 30 issues, including: See TeamCity 2024.12.2 Upgrade Notes for the complete list. Why update? Staying up to date with minor releases ensures your TeamCity instance benefits from: Compatibility TeamCity 2024.12.2 shares the same data format […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/teamcity-2024-12-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Debugging GraalVM Native Images With IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 11:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Dmitry Chuyko and Anton Arhipov, where we’ll explore the tools and workflows for debugging GraalVM Native Images with IntelliJ IDEA. Date: February 13, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract GraalVM Native Image allows you to transform your application into a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/new-livestream-debugging-graalvm-native-images-with-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Qt Renderers in CLion’s Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest CLion 2025.1 EAP build, 251.18673.49, includes one of the most requested features: support for Qt renderers (also known as Qt pretty printers and Qt debugging helpers) in the debugger. This feature allows you to view Qt variables such as QString, QByteArray, and other data types in a human-readable form. This enhancement makes it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/02/introducing-qt-renderers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q4 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 11:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Granular plugin feedback In addition to the general star rating of plugins, we’re introducing detailed ratings for more granular feedback. Users can now rate plugins across five categories: Aggregated ratings are shown in the Reviews tab. Find more details in our documentation. Perpetual licenses for paid plugins JetBrains Marketplace now offers perpetual […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/01/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q4-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Conferences and Events in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 11:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Planning your 2025 tech calendar? Java conferences offer more than just technical sessions – they’re your gateway to connecting with a vibrant community of professionals and passionate Java fans, exploring new cities, and finding fresh inspiration. As the IDE of choice for professional development in Java and Kotlin, IntelliJ IDEA is built to support developers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/top-java-conferences-and-events-in-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Debugging for Massive C&#43;&#43; Projects in Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 10:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you work on large Unreal Engine projects in Rider, you’ve likely experienced the dreaded debug-step delay – hit F10 for Step Over, contemplate making coffee, then finally see the next line execute. These delays occur in LLDB Debugger, the engine behind Rider’s debugging capabilities for C++ and other native languages. After months of focused […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/31/faster-debugging-in-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Developer Population Reaches 19.6 Million in 2024: Explore the Updates in Our Data Playground</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 10:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago, we launched the Developer Ecosystem: Data Playground, an interactive dashboard offering insights into the global developer landscape. Today, we’re excited to introduce a significant update that enhances the dashboard with refined data, salary ranges, and even more granular insights into developer demographics and market trends. What’s New? To make it easier to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/01/global-developer-population-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Developer Advocate – Will Vincent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 15:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, I’m a new Python Developer Advocate, focusing especially on web development. If you have any questions or want to share ideas around JetBrains products, most notably PyCharm, say hi at william.vincent@jetbrains.com. Background I’m a former Django Board Member and the author of three books on Django. Since 2019, I’ve co-hosted the Django Chat podcast […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/python-developer-advocate-will-vincent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3: Kotlin K2 Mode Updates, Enhanced Logical Code Structure View, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Early Access Program is in full swing, and build #3 is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3 We’re covering all of the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains and LinkedIn Partner to Launch a Professional Certificate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 17:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has partnered with LinkedIn to offer the Java Foundations Professional Certificate, exclusively available on LinkedIn Learning. With over 1 billion members on the platform and 7 people hired every minute, LinkedIn provides unmatched access to professional growth opportunities. Together, with our expertise in software development and education, we’re combining the best of both worlds: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2025/01/29/jetbrains-and-linkedin-partner-to-launch-a-professional-certificate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 Tips for Productive Java Development With Databases in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 15:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll share nine time-saving ways IntelliJ IDEA can boost your productivity when developing Java applications with databases – whether you’re starting a new project or diving into an ongoing one. Get IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate Create data sources automatically from properties IntelliJ IDEA makes it easy to create a data source for your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/tips-for-productive-java-development-with-databases-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack 2025 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our commitment to you We remain fully committed, as we have been all these years, to developing YouTrack as a platform that evolves with your needs. Our promise to you is to ensure that YouTrack continues to be available in both Server and Cloud versions, giving you the freedom to choose the hosting option that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/01/youtrack-2025-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JITWatch4i: Analyzing IntelliJ IDEA’s Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 11:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction A typical Java or Kotlin programmer spends most of their productive time either creating application code in an editor or searching for bugs in a debugger. Occasionally, they might dive into a profiler when looking for places where the application spends too much time. However, they almost never venture into the Java C1 or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/01/jitwatch4i-analyzing-intellij-idea-s-startup/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 11:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the January edition of PHP Annotated! This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise, we’ve done it for you. Highlights PHP 8.4 PHP 8.4 was officially released on November 21, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/01/php-annotated-january-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Django Views</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 10:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Views are central to Django’s architecture pattern, and having a solid grasp of how to work with them is essential for any developer working with the framework. If you’re new to developing web apps with Django or just need a refresher on views, we’ve got you covered. Gaining a better understanding of views will help […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/django-views/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
