<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog.jetbrains.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:06:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/blog.jetbrains.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot Testing in .NET with Verify</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When writing tests, the ultimate goal should always be to deliver “value”. This value is not just about the number of tests written but about the quality and relevance of the tests. We aim to write, execute, and maintain valuable tests that instill confidence in our application’s ability to withstand the rigors of user production […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/11/snapshot-testing-in-net-with-verify/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Emerging Data Job Trends in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 09:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog post by Thu Vu. The long-term outlook for data jobs – like data scientists, statisticians, and market research analysts – predicts explosive growth, much faster than most other fields. But here’s the catch: Despite the promising stats, data professionals are struggling to find jobs. AI is also shaking things up […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/11/5-emerging-data-job-trends-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2024.1 Release Candidate Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 08:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Release Candidate for MPS 2024.1 is now available for download. Grab it and experience the new functionality before the final 2024.1 release. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.1 RC You can learn about the new features in more detail in this blog post. The full list of fixed issues can be found here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/07/the-mps-2023-3-release-candidate-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try Full Line Code Completion in JetBrains Rider 2024.1.4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released the 2024.1 version of all our IDE products, including the dotUltimate family of products: ReSharper, Rider, dotMemory, dotTrace, dotCover, and dotPeek. Full Line Code Completion (FLCC), a local and fast AI model fine-tuned for product-specific programming languages, is one feature you may have heard of in this release. FLCC was released with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/10/full-line-code-completion-in-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q2 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Flexible trial periods for paid plugins You can now customize trial periods for your paid plugins or simply disable them. Instead of the default 30-day trial, you can now set a shorter trial period or even none at all. Just select the preferred trial period while uploading your plugin to the Marketplace […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q2-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Column Selection DSL in Kotlin DataFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The Kotlin DataFrame library makes extracting values from structured data an easy task. As discussed in our documentation, there are four separate APIs that can be used for this purpose, with the optimal choice depending on your individual situation and requirements. To demonstrate, let’s read in a JSON document containing information about users: The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/07/enhanced-column-selection-dsl-in-kotlin-dataframe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip User Experience Survey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, DataGrip community! At JetBrains, delivering an excellent user experience is always a top priority. Today, we’re launching a survey to gather your feedback and explore how we can make DataGrip even better. Please take a few minutes to complete the DataGrip User Experience Survey. Your input will help us prioritize future improvements. As a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/07/09/datagrip-user-experience-survey/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in July</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This July, we’ve made some improvements to our courses to better serve your learning needs, added certificates for two more courses, and introduced new learning topics. Let’s take a closer look at these updates. Updated courses Our courses have been restructured to align with the latest job requirements. We’ve incorporated real interview questions and regularly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/09/jetbrains-academy-new-in-july/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wayland Support Preview In 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 15:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are delighted to announce that, starting with the 2024.2 Early Access Program (EAP), IntelliJ-based IDEs will offer preliminary support for the Wayland display server protocol on Linux, including Windows Subsystem for Linux a.k.a. WSLg. How To Opt In On Linux, IntelliJ-based IDEs were using exclusively the X11 protocol and an X server to show […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/wayland-support-preview-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New UI Becomes the Default in 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 14:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that we will enable the new UI for all JetBrains IDE users in the upcoming 2024.2 version. We designed the new UI to reduce visual clutter, ensuring easy access to essential features while gradually revealing more advanced functionality as needed. The new UI is clean and modern, providing bigger, easier-to-use […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/07/08/the-new-ui-becomes-the-default-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 EAP 5: Zephyr West Support and Full Line Code Completion for C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 13:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.2 EAP 5 build (242.19890.26) is now out! It’s available from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 EAP Zephyr West support In this EAP build, we introduce a new project model supported by CLion – it’s called the West project model. As we previously mentioned […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/07/2024-2-eap-5-zephyr-west-support-full-line-code-completion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the June edition of PHP Annotated! We’ll recap the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, featuring handpicked news, articles, tools, and videos. Highlights PHP 8.1.29, PHP 8.2.20, and PHP 8.3.8 released ❗️These security updates fix CVE-2024-4577, CVE-2024-5458, CVE-2024-5585, and vulnerability in openssl_private_decrypt() function known as the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/07/php-annotated-june-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Turbo in your Rails apps with RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 14:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! The RubyMine team is constantly striving to provide support for new technologies for Ruby and Rails. One of the most exciting recent additions to Rails is undoubtedly Hotwire, so we’ve prepared an overview of this suite of frameworks and a tutorial on how to use the most important Turbo and Stimulus features in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/07/how-to-use-turbo-in-your-rails-apps-with-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Data Science Platform Downtime – neXDos Says It’s Real With Datalore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JupyterHub Hosting Hurdles neXDos heavily relies on diverse data sources – from stock market APIs to in-house PostgreSQL data – to inform their bespoke investment strategies. Previously, neXDos prototyped, backtested, and future-proofed their trading algorithms by hosting JupyterLab and JupyterHub. But this approach was problematic due to complexity in many areas, including managing the server […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/05/zero-data-science-platform-downtime-nexdos-says-it-s-real-with-datalore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Per-Minute macOS Sonoma M2 Agents in TeamCity Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 08:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently introduced per-minute macOS agents in TeamCity Cloud. Now, we’re switching the macOS agents to macOS Sonoma M2, offering you more power efficiency and greater performance when running your builds on TeamCity. We’re offering a 50% discount on the new per-minute macOS build agents in TeamCity Cloud until January 1, 2025. Enjoy the power […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/07/macos-sonoma-agents-teamcity-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – July 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the July edition of Java Annotated Monthly! We’re excited to feature insights from the ever-brilliant Trisha Gee, who’s been busy curating some top-class content over the past month. This edition is packed with Java news and tips, including a spotlight on the upcoming Java 23. You’ll also find articles on Kotlin, Spring, AI, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/java-annotated-monthly-july-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | July 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 06:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The BinaryFormatter class was traditionally used in .NET for serializing and deserializing objects into a binary format. However, it has been deprecated in 2020 due to serious security vulnerabilities that can allow for remote code execution when deserializing untrusted data. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/05/dotinsights-july-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polars vs. pandas: What’s the Difference?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 13:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve been keeping up with the advances in Python dataframes in the past year, you couldn’t help hearing about Polars, the powerful dataframe library designed for working with large datasets. Unlike other libraries for working with large datasets, such as Spark, Dask, and Ray, Polars is designed to be used on a single machine, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/07/polars-vs-pandas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science with GenAI is Revolutionizing Investment Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 09:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is the formula for success in the investment management industry? Behind every successful firm is a unique combination of domain expertise, cutting-edge technology, relationship management, rapid adaptability, and competition. While data science driven by generative AI (genAI) cannot turn your employees into domain experts overnight, nor can it single-handedly eliminate the competition, it can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/04/data-science-with-genai-is-revolutionizing-investment-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
