<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 16:10:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 16:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced the retirement of the azureedge.net domain by January 15, 2025, driven by Edgio’s (formerly Limelight Networks) business closure. This domain underpins Azure CDN services, .NET installations, and content delivery for various Azure and Microsoft services. The shift requires developers and DevOps teams to update configurations, pipelines, and deployment practices to ensure continuity. […] The article Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phi-4: Microsoft’s New Small Language Model Outperforms Giants in AI Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 21:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Artificial Intelligence and Large Language Models (LLMs), bigger has often better. LLMs like OpenAI’s GPT-4o and Google’s Gemini Pro have dominated headlines for their massive scale and capabilities. However, Microsoft is redefining this narrative with Phi-4, a 14-billion parameter small language model (SLM) that delivers exceptional performance, rivaling models many times its size. Phi-4 […] The article Phi-4: Microsoft’s New Small Language Model Outperforms Giants in AI Reasoning was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
