<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 12:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Empowering SREs with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of technology, the role of Site Reliability Engineers (SREs) is becoming increasingly complex and critical. As organizations strive for higher reliability and performance in their systems, the integration of generative AI technologies, such as those offered by Azure OpenAI, is revolutionizing the field of SRE. Let’s explore how these advancements are […] The article Empowering SREs with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI appeared first on Build5Nines | Cloud, DevOps &amp;amp; SRE Guidance.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Security Architecture: Trust Zones and Security Boundaries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 20:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are many aspects to architecting an Internet of Things (IoT) solution. Security is the most important aspect of any computer system, but it’s especially important with IoT solutions. It seems we are constantly seeing news reports about IoT solutions being hacked or compromised. These compromises are things like Internet connected cameras being hacked to […] The article IoT Security Architecture: Trust Zones and Security Boundaries appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platform Engineering: What is it? And how it applies to DevOps Engineers and SREs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2024/06_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of software development and operations, the need for streamlined processes, robust infrastructure, and efficient deployment practices has become paramount. DevOps Engineer and Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) roles have emerged as two prominent methodologies to address these challenges. However, bridging the gap between development and operations requires a specialized approach. The latest […] The article Platform Engineering: What is it? And how it applies to DevOps Engineers and SREs appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Azure DevOps Pipelines as a Serverless Compute Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2024/05_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2024/05_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At first this sounds crazy, but Azure DevOps Pipelines are actually a Serverless compute engine. When you compare it to other Azure cloud services, it’s sort of a mixture of the features of Azure Functions and Azure Logic Apps mixed with Git source control integration. At first glance, it might seem a bit far-fetched to […] The article Use Azure DevOps Pipelines as a Serverless Compute Engine appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Adoption for IT Managers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2024/04_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 10:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_05_2024/04_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DevOps is a modern approach to software development and operations that emphasizes collaboration, automation, and continuous improvement. The goal of DevOps is to bring development and operations teams together to improve the speed, quality, and reliability of software delivery. This approach is becoming increasingly popular among organizations looking to stay competitive in today’s fast-paced business […] The article DevOps Adoption for IT Managers appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Software Integrity with Artifact Attestations in GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 15:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ensuring the integrity and security of software artifacts is extremely important. With the proliferation of supply chain attacks and the increasing complexity of software development environments, developers need robust tools to safeguard their code and build processes. Recognizing this need, GitHub has introduced Artifact Attestations, a feature designed to provide a verifiable way to link […] The article Enhancing Software Integrity with Artifact Attestations in GitHub Actions appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Front Door: CNAME/alias record is not currently detected</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_05_2024/03_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When configuring a custom domain with Azure Front Door, one common issue that users may encounter is the “CNAME/alias record is not currently detected” message. This can be a confusing and frustrating experience, especially when you’re sure you’ve followed all the steps correctly. In this article, we’ll explore why this issue occurs and provide a […] The article Azure Front Door: CNAME/alias record is not currently detected appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring .NET Aspire: Building Cloud-Native Apps with Ease</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud-native application development, building scalable, observable, and production-ready distributed systems can be a challenging task. This is where .NET Aspire comes into play. .NET Aspire is an opinionated, cloud-ready stack designed to simplify the development of cloud-native applications by providing a collection of NuGet packages that handle specific cloud-native concerns. […] The article Exploring .NET Aspire: Building Cloud-Native Apps with Ease appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Copilot for Azure: Your AI-Powered Cloud Companion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 18:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot for Azure, the innovative AI companion that is revolutionizing the way we interact with cloud infrastructure and services. In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud management, IT professionals in DevOps Engineer and SRE roles are constantly seeking ways to streamline their workflows and enhance productivity. Copilot for Azure will help you design, operate, optimize, […] The article Microsoft Copilot for Azure: Your AI-Powered Cloud Companion appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Conditional If Variable Does Not Exist (try function)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            They try function in HashiCorp Terraform allows values to be read from a Data Source, input variables, or some other attribute while providing a default value if the evaluation expression errors. This is particularly useful when data is retrieved from an external system in JSON or YAML format and then decoded. The decoded result may […] The article Terraform: Conditional If Variable Does Not Exist (try function) appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AIChatUI: Open Source AI Chat Sample with Azure OpenAI Service &amp; GPT-3 / GPT-4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 17:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since I’ve been working with Azure OpenAI Service from a developer perspective as well, I’ve decided to build a sample application to help demonstrate not just the IaC deployment of Azure OpenAI Service and GPT models, but also to demonstrate some basic use cases of integrating AI into your own enterprise applications. Here’s a screenshot […] The article Introducing AIChatUI: Open Source AI Chat Sample with Azure OpenAI Service &amp;amp; GPT-3 / GPT-4 appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Commit and Push Changes Back to Repository</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 11:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_04_2024/30_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Actions are great at enabling you to automate workflows directly from within a GitHub repository. The workflows are stored in a YAML definition file located within the .github/workflows directory within the repository. GitHub Actions can be used to configure workflows that can perform a variety of actions to perform build and release steps. On […] The article GitHub Actions: Commit and Push Changes Back to Repository appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
