<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 17:29:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Future of Enterprise Computing: How Agentic AI and Multi-Agent Workflows Are Transforming Business Processes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 17:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enterprise computing is undergoing a radical transformation. As businesses strive to remain competitive in an AI-driven world, a new paradigm is emerging: agentic AI and multi-agent systems. These intelligent, autonomous software agents are not just augmenting workflows—they’re redefining them. In the next five years, multi-agent architectures will become a foundational element of enterprise infrastructure, impacting […] The article Future of Enterprise Computing: How Agentic AI and Multi-Agent Workflows Are Transforming Business Processes was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IngressNightmare: Critical Zero-Day Kubernetes Vulnerabilities Put Thousands of Clusters at Risk (March 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A set of ‘critical’ zero-day vulnerabilities, collectively named IngressNightmare, have been discovered in the widely used Ingress-NGINX Controller for Kubernetes that can result in a ‘full takeover‘ of a Kubernetes cluster! These flaws expose over 6,500 publicly exposed clusters to the risk of unauthenticated remote code execution (RCE) and privilege escalation, putting sensitive data and […] The article IngressNightmare: Critical Zero-Day Kubernetes Vulnerabilities Put Thousands of Clusters at Risk (March 2025) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: Get YouTube Video Transcript from URL for use in Generative AI and RAG Summarization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are times when it’s necessary to download the text transcript of a YouTube video using Python. This can be done with the help of the youtube_transcript_api library. Getting access to the text content of YouTube videos can be extremely helpful when using Generative AI and Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to create summarization, analysis, or […] The article Python: Get YouTube Video Transcript from URL for use in Generative AI and RAG Summarization was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
