<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 11:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: The Epic Journey of Microsoft Visual Studio – Code, Craft, and Continuity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 11:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Visual Studio isn’t just an IDE; it is the forge in which several generations of software—from shrink‑wrapped Windows utilities to cloud‑native micro‑services—have been hammered into existence. For nearly three decades it has remained the default cockpit for developers building on Microsoft stacks, adapting to every tectonic shift in programming practice: from COM to .NET, from monolithic […] The article Software Innovation: The Epic Journey of Microsoft Visual Studio – Code, Craft, and Continuity was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub vs Azure DevOps: Is GitHub Ready for Enterprise-Grade Software Development Lifecycle (SDL) Management?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In recent years, GitHub has emerged from its developer-centric roots to become a serious contender for managing the full Software Development Lifecycle (SDL) in enterprise environments. Yet Azure DevOps, Microsoft’s integrated DevOps suite, still retains deep roots in enterprise IT. This article takes a side-by-side look at both platforms to help architects and engineering leads […] The article GitHub vs Azure DevOps: Is GitHub Ready for Enterprise-Grade Software Development Lifecycle (SDL) Management?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: James Gosling – Creator of Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            James Gosling is a name that resonates through the halls of computer science, software engineering, and more recently, cloud computing. Best known as the “Father of Java,” Gosling’s influence stretches far beyond the iconic programming language. His work has quietly but profoundly shaped the modern cloud landscape, enabling countless innovations that rely on scalable, reliable, […] The article Big Thinkers: James Gosling – Creator of Java was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovations: iOS – The Operating System That Put the Future in Your Pocket</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A 18‑year chronicle of Apple’s mobile powerhouse—how it began, how it rewired the software economy, and why its next act is infused with on‑device intelligence. You wake up, glance at a glowing rectangle, and with a tap summon everything from bank balances to baby photos. That daily ritual traces its lineage to a January 2007 […] The article Software Innovations: iOS – The Operating System That Put the Future in Your Pocket was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
