<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:51:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Difference Between Completions and Embeddings in AI Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) models have rapidly evolved to perform various tasks ranging from text generation to natural language understanding. Among the different types of AI-driven models, Completions and Embeddings serve distinct purposes. While they both utilize machine learning techniques, their applications and functionality differ significantly. In this article, we’ll explore the differences between completions and […] The article Difference Between Completions and Embeddings in AI Models was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Copyright for AI-Generated Content? What Businesses Need to Know About the Latest US Copyright Office Rule</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What’s the big deal between AI creation and copyright? Artificial Intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing the way businesses create content, from blog articles and marketing materials to art and software. However, a major decision by the U.S. Copyright Office has made waves: AI-generated content without human involvement cannot be copyrighted. This means that if a business […] The article No Copyright for AI-Generated Content? What Businesses Need to Know About the Latest US Copyright Office Rule was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Azure Blob Storage with Virtual Directories in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Blob Storage is designed as a flat storage system without a traditional hierarchical structure. However, by incorporating forward slashes (/) in blob names, you can simulate a directory-like organization, creating virtual directories within your containers. This approach enhances data organization and accessibility, especially when dealing with large datasets. Conclusion Azure Blob Storage, while inherently […] The article Organizing Azure Blob Storage with Virtual Directories in C# was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s Deep Research Agent: Automated Research and Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 14:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI has recently unveiled “Deep Research,” an advanced AI agent designed to autonomously conduct comprehensive research by synthesizing vast amounts of online information and executing multi-step tasks. This innovation aims to match the capabilities of human research analysts, delivering detailed reports in a fraction of the time traditionally required. Who Is It For? Deep Research […] The article OpenAI’s Deep Research Agent: Automated Research and Analysis was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Podman and How Does it Compare to Docker?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker has long been the dominant container engine, but it’s not the only one. After all, Kubernetes moved away from Docker several years ago to a different engine. An alternative to Docker for running containers on your local machine has been gaining traction in recent years: Podman. Podman is an open-source container engine developed by […] The article What is Podman and How Does it Compare to Docker? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Kubernetes?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 18:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kubernetes is an open-source platform designed to manage, automate, and scale containerized applications efficiently. It has become the go-to solution for orchestrating containers in cloud environments. If you’ve ever wondered how large-scale applications like trading platforms handle fluctuating workloads, Kubernetes is the key player behind the scenes. To better understand Kubernetes, think of an orchestra. […] The article What is Kubernetes? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Trump’s Tariffs Threaten U.S. Dominance in Artificial Intelligence?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The U.S.A. has been the dominant force in Artificial Intelligence so far. The release of DeepSeek R1 recently from a Chinese company is showing to challenge this dominance. AI models aren’t the only factor for the United States to remain dominant in AI. Both AI training and running models are dependent on GPUs (graphics processing […] The article Will Trump’s Tariffs Threaten U.S. Dominance in Artificial Intelligence? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Web Content for Generative AI &#43; RAG Solution as Trimmed Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2025/02_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 14:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2025/02_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has revolutionized how we interact with and generate text-based content, but its capabilities are significantly enhanced when paired with Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG). RAG enables AI models to pull in external, high-quality sources of information, ensuring more accurate and contextually relevant responses. A crucial component of this process is loading and processing web content, […] The article Load Web Content for Generative AI + RAG Solution as Trimmed Markdown was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Diversity of Data in AI Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 13:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) has rapidly become an integral part of modern society, influencing everything from job recruitment to healthcare and criminal justice. However, AI systems are only as good as the data they are trained on. When these datasets lack diversity, AI can inherit and amplify biases, leading to real-world consequences that exacerbate discrimination based […] The article Importance of Diversity of Data in AI Systems was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
