<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 15:19:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: HashiCorp Terraform Revolutionized Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 15:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the current cloud-first world, where agility, automation, and scalability are required, there are few tools that have left as profound a mark on infrastructure management as HashiCorp Terraform. Widely regarded as a cornerstone of modern DevOps practices, Terraform helped usher in a new era of Infrastructure as Code (IaC) that is defined by declarative […] The article Software Innovation: HashiCorp Terraform Revolutionized Infrastructure as Code (IaC) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: The Epic Journey of Microsoft Visual Studio – Code, Craft, and Continuity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 11:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Visual Studio isn’t just an IDE; it is the forge in which several generations of software—from shrink‑wrapped Windows utilities to cloud‑native micro‑services—have been hammered into existence. For nearly three decades it has remained the default cockpit for developers building on Microsoft stacks, adapting to every tectonic shift in programming practice: from COM to .NET, from monolithic […] The article Software Innovation: The Epic Journey of Microsoft Visual Studio – Code, Craft, and Continuity was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
