<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Files vs. A Server with an SMB Share: Key Takeaways from MS Cloud IT Pro Podcast Episode 367</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MS Cloud IT Pro Podcast episode 367, hosted by Ben Segink and Scott Hoag, dives deep into a crucial IT topic: choosing between Azure Files and a traditional server with an SMB share for file storage in the cloud. This episode is essential for IT professionals navigating cloud migration strategies and balancing infrastructure needs. […] The article Azure Files vs. A Server with an SMB Share: Key Takeaways from MS Cloud IT Pro Podcast Episode 367 was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Azure Networking Outage in East US 2 Affecting VMs, App Service, and More! (Started January 8, 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On January 8, 2025, Microsoft Azure started experiencing a significant networking outage in the East US 2 region. This outage has impacted a broad range of Azure services (including Azure App Service, VMs, and more!) causing disruptions for businesses relying on these services for critical workloads. As of the time I’m writing this, the issue […] The article Major Azure Networking Outage in East US 2 Affecting VMs, App Service, and More!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 21:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced the retirement of Azure CDN services from the azureedge.net domain by January 15, 2025, driven by Edgio’s (formerly Limelight Networks) business closure. This domain underpins Azure CDN services, .NET installations, and content delivery for various Azure and Microsoft services. The shift requires developers and DevOps teams to update configurations, pipelines, and deployment […] The article Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Developer CLI: Accelerate App &amp; Infrastructure Deployment on Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers and organizations increasingly adopt cloud solutions, streamlining the deployment of applications and infrastructure becomes a critical part of achieving efficiency and scalability. Microsoft’s Azure Developer CLI (azd) addresses this by providing an integrated, open-source command-line tool that accelerates the journey from local development to Azure deployment. Whether you’re a solo developer or part […] The article Introduction to Azure Developer CLI: Accelerate App &amp;amp; Infrastructure Deployment on Microsoft Azure was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) continues to permeate our daily lives, but the way we interact with these systems remains an evolving landscape. In a recent episode of the Hanselminutes podcast, host Scott Hanselman sat down with designer and technologist Maggie Appleton to explore a fascinating question: What is AI’s UI (User Interface)? Their conversation sheds light […] The article What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
