<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: From JavaScript to Cloud Privacy Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Brendan Eich may be best known as the creator of JavaScript, but his influence extends well beyond programming languages into the very core of internet privacy and emerging cloud ecosystems. Today, as CEO of Brave Software, Eich is a key figure pushing for decentralized, privacy-first approaches to cloud services and digital advertising. His vision challenges […] The article Big Thinkers: From JavaScript to Cloud Privacy Pioneer was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: Docker – Container Revolution that Changed Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Between the constant chatter about “containers,” “microservices,” and “cloud-native,” Docker stands as a major player in the lexicon of contemporary software development. What started as a simple abstraction tool for Linux containers evolved into a cultural shift for software deployment practices, influencing how entire industries build and run their applications. Containers promise greater speed, portability, […] The article Software Innovation: Docker – Container Revolution that Changed Software Development was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Azure Front Door, Traffic Manager, and Load Balancer: Choosing the Right Tool for Global Application Delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern cloud architectures demand flexible, resilient, and scalable traffic distribution strategies. As workloads increasingly span multiple regions and hybrid environments, choosing the right load balancing service in Microsoft Azure becomes a strategic architectural decision. Among Azure’s suite of traffic distribution tools, Azure Front Door, Azure Traffic Manager, and Azure Load Balancer are commonly evaluated — […] The article Comparing Azure Front Door, Traffic Manager, and Load Balancer: Choosing the Right Tool for Global Application Delivery was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Stuck to Senior: How Mentorship Accelerates Your Cloud, DevOps &amp; AI Career</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The journey from junior engineer to senior Cloud, DevOps or even AI professional can feel like climbing an ever-growing mountain. New tools. Shifting best practices. Complicated architectures. Add to that the pressure of staying relevant in a sea of LinkedIn updates and GitHub commits, and it’s easy to get stuck—stuck doing the same tasks, stuck […] The article From Stuck to Senior: How Mentorship Accelerates Your Cloud, DevOps &amp;amp; AI Career was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Tim Berners-Lee – Inventor of the World Wide Web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tim Berners-Lee, a name etched into the bedrock of computing history, stands among the most influential figures to ever touch the digital sphere. Credited with inventing the World Wide Web in 1989, his groundbreaking work at CERN sparked a technological revolution that reshaped communication, commerce, and culture. Over three decades later, Berners-Lee’s visionary spirit persists, […] The article Big Thinkers: Tim Berners-Lee – Inventor of the World Wide Web was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
