<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design of Intelligent, Multi-Agent AI Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Intelligent multi-agent AI systems stand out as a robust solution for solving problems requiring modularity, scalability, and specialized expertise. The rapid evolution of artificial intelligence has brought about the innovative approach of designing multi-agent AI systems that can tackle complex, dynamic, and distributed tasks. These systems rely on multiple AI agents collaborating to achieve goals […] The article Design of Intelligent, Multi-Agent AI Systems was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Fabric vs Azure Service Fabric: Understanding the Differences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2024/24_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 21:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2024/24_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Fabric and Azure Service Fabric share the term &amp;quot;Fabric&amp;quot; but serve different purposes. Microsoft Fabric is a unified data platform for analytics and integration, while Azure Service Fabric focuses on managing scalable microservices applications. Despite the shared name, they cater to distinct audiences and functionalities within the Microsoft ecosystem. The article Microsoft Fabric vs Azure Service Fabric: Understanding the Differences was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
