<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:11:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Empowering DevOps Engineers with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of technology, the role of DevOps Engineers is becoming increasingly complex and critical. As organizations strive for higher reliability and performance, increased automation workflows, and smoother release processes, the integration of generative AI technologies, such as those offered by Azure OpenAI, is revolutionizing the realm of DevOps. DevOps Engineers can now […] The article Empowering DevOps Engineers with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AzAPI Terraform Provider Dynamic Properties Feature instead of jsonencode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AzAPI Terraform provider for Microsoft Azure has introduced a feature known as dynamic properties. This feature simplifies resource definitions by enabling the use of HCL (HashiCorp Configuration Language) blocks instead of JSON blocks that would previously require the use of JSON encoding (via jsonencode) and decoding (via jsondecode). This is a great improvement to […] The article Using AzAPI Terraform Provider Dynamic Properties Feature instead of jsonencode appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI GTP-4o Now Available in Azure OpenAI Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 21:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, OpenAI announced the the new GPT-4o multi-modal model that integrates text, video, and audio capabilities. This new GPT-4o version raises the standard for generative and conversational AI. This new version has some really amazing AI features, like real-time speech translation, and conversational interaction capabilities with vision and audio support. While OpenAI is releasing the […] The article OpenAI GTP-4o Now Available in Azure OpenAI Service appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Scheduled Trigger in GitHub Actions using Cron expression</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are many times when scheduled triggers are very useful when configuring GitHub Actions workflows. Luckily, GitHub Actions supports the ability to configure scheduled triggers that includes support for using cron expressions to define the schedule timing. In this article, we’ll look at configuring scheduled triggers on GitHub Actions workflows and a few tips on […] The article Configure Scheduled Trigger in GitHub Actions using Cron expression appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2024/12_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2024/12_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore how to integrate the Azure Storage SDK into a .NET application. We’ll cover the steps to read and write blobs from Azure Storage, and we’ll also discuss how to obtain your Storage Account Key. By the end of this guide, you’ll have a simple command-line application that can interact with […] The article Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with C# appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with Javascript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore how to integrate the Azure Storage client library for Javascript into a Node.js application. We’ll cover the steps to read and write blobs from Azure Storage, and we’ll also discuss how to obtain your Storage Account Key. By the end of this guide, you’ll have javascript code that can interact […] The article Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with Javascript appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform String ‘replace’ Function  for RegEx String Replacement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp Terraform offers a lot of powerful functions that can be used for string manipulation within your Infrastructure as Code (IaC) projects. Among these functions is the versatile replace function, which enables users to perform both simple string replacements as well as regular expressions (RegEx) based string replacement. In this article, we’ll look deeper into […] The article Using Terraform String ‘replace’ Function for RegEx String Replacement appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices to Promote from DEV to PROD Environments with HashiCorp Terraform using Workspaces and Folders</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When using HashiCorp Terraform to manage infrastructure as code (IaC), promoting changes from the development (DEV) environment to the production (PROD) environment is critical to the process of managing the development lifecycle of the infrastructure for a system. Most often, organizations will also have test (TEST) or staging (STAGE) environments for additional testing to move […] The article Best Practices to Promote from DEV to PROD Environments with HashiCorp Terraform using Workspaces and Folders appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stack Overflow Upset Over Users Deleting Answers After OpenAI Partnership</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 13:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this ever changing and evolving world of user generated versus AI generated content, the recent announcement of Stack Overflow partnering with OpenAI recently has been met with some backlash by the community. There are reports today that several users have attempted to delete their content (questions and answers) from Stack Overflow with some difficulty, […] The article Stack Overflow Upset Over Users Deleting Answers After OpenAI Partnership appeared first on Build5Nines | Cloud, DevOps &amp;amp; SRE Guidance.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Your Own Local, Private, ChatGPT-like AI Experience with Ollama and OpenWebUI (Llama3, Phi3, Gemma, Mistral, and more LLMs!)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 11:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the last couple years the emergence of Large Language Models (LLMs) has revolutionized the way we interact with Artificial Intelligence (AI) systems, enabling them to generate human-like text responses with remarkable accuracy. From powering chatbots and virtual assistants to aiding in natural language processing tasks, LLMs have found widespread applications across every industry. However, […] The article Run Your Own Local, Private, ChatGPT-like AI Experience with Ollama and OpenWebUI (Llama3, Phi3, Gemma, Mistral, and more LLMs!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
