<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 11:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Databricks vs Apache Spark: Key Differences and When to Use Each</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Within the big data and analytics space there are two names at the forefront of conversation: Apache Spark and Databricks. While they’re closely related, they serve very different purposes in the data ecosystem. Understanding their core differences is critical for architects, developers, and data engineers looking to build scalable, high-performance data solutions in the cloud. […] The article Databricks vs Apache Spark: Key Differences and When to Use Each was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Basic: The Language That Brought Programming to the Masses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2025/29_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 13:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2025/29_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the vibrant and fast-paced history of software development, a few languages have quietly but profoundly reshaped the landscape. Among these is Visual Basic (VB) — a language often underestimated in its influence but undeniably responsible for bringing programming out of the ivory towers of computer science and into the hands of everyday developers, business […] The article Visual Basic: The Language That Brought Programming to the Masses was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Scott Guthrie – From Innovator of ASP.NET to Azure’s Global Rise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2025/29_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 12:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2025/29_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the Executive Vice President of Microsoft’s Cloud + AI Group, Scott Guthrie (aka “ScottGu”, pronounces “Scott Goo”) has quietly yet powerfully shaped the trajectory of one of the world’s largest and most influential cloud platforms—Microsoft Azure. His influence extends beyond corporate growth, playing a pivotal role in transforming cloud computing itself, from enterprise-scale deployments […] The article Big Thinkers: Scott Guthrie – From Innovator of ASP.NET to Azure’s Global Rise was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Enterprise Computing: How Agentic AI and Multi-Agent Workflows Are Transforming Business Processes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 17:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enterprise computing is undergoing a radical transformation. As businesses strive to remain competitive in an AI-driven world, a new paradigm is emerging: agentic AI and multi-agent systems. These intelligent, autonomous software agents are not just augmenting workflows—they’re redefining them. In the next five years, multi-agent architectures will become a foundational element of enterprise infrastructure, impacting […] The article Future of Enterprise Computing: How Agentic AI and Multi-Agent Workflows Are Transforming Business Processes was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IngressNightmare: Critical Zero-Day Kubernetes Vulnerabilities Put Thousands of Clusters at Risk (March 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_03_2025/24_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A set of ‘critical’ zero-day vulnerabilities, collectively named IngressNightmare, have been discovered in the widely used Ingress-NGINX Controller for Kubernetes that can result in a ‘full takeover‘ of a Kubernetes cluster! These flaws expose over 6,500 publicly exposed clusters to the risk of unauthenticated remote code execution (RCE) and privilege escalation, putting sensitive data and […] The article IngressNightmare: Critical Zero-Day Kubernetes Vulnerabilities Put Thousands of Clusters at Risk (March 2025) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
