<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:40:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s Vision for 2025 and Beyond: Copilot, Responsible AI, Security and Multicloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Ignite 2024 conference kicks off next week and I’ve analyzed the full session list to gleam insights into the company’s strategic roadmap for 2025 and beyond. This years conference has an unmistakable emphasis on artificial intelligence, security, and multicloud innovation. The 1,846 sessions hosted at the conference spanning a vast array of tech […] The article Microsoft’s Vision for 2025 and Beyond: Copilot, Responsible AI, Security and Multicloud was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Network Security Best Practices to Protect Your Cloud Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2024/09_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 15:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2024/09_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Securing network environments in Microsoft Azure is paramount when organizations migrate their infrastructure and applications to the cloud. Azure, as one of the leading cloud service providers, offers a broad spectrum of security tools and best practices designed to protect resources against a multitude of network threats. Azure network security plays a critical role in […] The article Azure Network Security Best Practices to Protect Your Cloud Infrastructure was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
