<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:54:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Multicloud Security Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2024/02_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enterprises are increasingly adopting multicloud strategies—leveraging a mix of cloud service providers such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services (AWS), and Google Cloud Platform (GCP)—to optimize costs, enhance resilience, and accelerate their digital transformation journeys. The cloud has become the backbone of innovation, scalability, and operational efficiency. With multicloud being such a large part of […] The article Accelerate Your Multicloud Security Strategy was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance AI System Accuracy using RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 04:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2024/01_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) systems, particularly generative models like GPT-4, have transformed numerous industries. However, these models sometimes struggle with accuracy, especially when generating outputs based on limited or outdated training data. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) is an innovative approach designed to address these challenges, combining the generative strengths of AI with the precision of retrieval systems. […] The article Enhance AI System Accuracy using RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of Intelligent, Multi-Agent AI Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Intelligent multi-agent AI systems stand out as a robust solution for solving problems requiring modularity, scalability, and specialized expertise. The rapid evolution of artificial intelligence has brought about the innovative approach of designing multi-agent AI systems that can tackle complex, dynamic, and distributed tasks. These systems rely on multiple AI agents collaborating to achieve goals […] The article Design of Intelligent, Multi-Agent AI Systems was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
