<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:40:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Developer CLI: Accelerate App &amp; Infrastructure Deployment on Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers and organizations increasingly adopt cloud solutions, streamlining the deployment of applications and infrastructure becomes a critical part of achieving efficiency and scalability. Microsoft’s Azure Developer CLI (azd) addresses this by providing an integrated, open-source command-line tool that accelerates the journey from local development to Azure deployment. Whether you’re a solo developer or part […] The article Introduction to Azure Developer CLI: Accelerate App &amp;amp; Infrastructure Deployment on Microsoft Azure was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) continues to permeate our daily lives, but the way we interact with these systems remains an evolving landscape. In a recent episode of the Hanselminutes podcast, host Scott Hanselman sat down with designer and technologist Maggie Appleton to explore a fascinating question: What is AI’s UI (User Interface)? Their conversation sheds light […] The article What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
