<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 13:33:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Terraform vs OpenTofu: What’s the difference?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What’s the difference between HashiCorp’s Terraform and OpenTofu? This is a tale that starts with HashiCorp first developing Terraform, the popular open source, multi-cloud, Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool, and then eventually close sourcing it. As a result, the community forked the most recent open source Terraform version and spun it off into OpenTofu. Let’s […] The article Terraform vs OpenTofu: What’s the difference? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Generative AI?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2024/05_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has emerged as a groundbreaking technology, transforming how we create content. From text and images to music and software code, generative AI models can produce original outputs that often resemble human creativity. For newcomers to the topic, understanding the fundamentals, applications, and implications of generative AI is crucial. Imagine a world where a […] The article What is Generative AI? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is MLOps?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2024/02_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 18:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2024/02_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MLOps, or Machine Learning Operations, is like the backbone of a well-oiled machine in the machine learning domain. It’s an intersection where machine learning meets software engineering and DevOps, aiming to streamline and automate the entire machine learning lifecycle. Think of it as creating a seamless assembly line that takes raw data, processes it, builds […] The article What is MLOps? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 7 Signs You’re Doing DevOps Wrong</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2024/02_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 12:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2024/02_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Chances are you or your manager thinks you’re doing DevOps. But what if you’re doing it wrong? Do you really know what DevOps is? After all, you have a DevOps team, or DevOps tools, right? DevOps is more than a buzzword or a trendy methodology. It’s a fundamental shift in how organizations approach software development […] The article Top 7 Signs You’re Doing DevOps Wrong was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Terraform ‘merge’ Function</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the core strengths of Terraform is its rich set of built-in functions, which empower users to create flexible and reusable configurations. Among these functions, the Terraform merge function is particularly powerful, enabling the seamless combination of multiple maps or objects into a single, cohesive unit. This chapter delves into the nuances of the […] The article Using the Terraform ‘merge’ Function was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
