<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 12:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How is a Deep Research AI Agent Designed?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2025/07_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Deep Research AI Agent is an advanced AI-driven system designed to assist in conducting complex and large-scale research. It leverages cutting-edge artificial intelligence techniques such as natural language processing (NLP), machine learning (ML), and automation to analyze vast amounts of data, extract key insights, and generate summaries. These agents help professionals and organizations streamline […] The article How is a Deep Research AI Agent Designed? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference Between Completions and Embeddings in AI Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2025/06_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) models have rapidly evolved to perform various tasks ranging from text generation to natural language understanding. Among the different types of AI-driven models, Completions and Embeddings serve distinct purposes. While they both utilize machine learning techniques, their applications and functionality differ significantly. In this article, we’ll explore the differences between completions and […] The article Difference Between Completions and Embeddings in AI Models was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
