<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 15:45:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing the Drive: Audi’s ChatGPT Automotive Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 15:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The automotive industry is constantly advancing with new technology integrations, and Audi is taking a significant leap forward with the utilization of ChatGPT, an advanced generative AI developed by OpenAI, into its vehicles. This move not only promises to enhance the user experience but also showcases the potential of AI in transforming the automotive industry. […] The article Revolutionizing the Drive: Audi’s ChatGPT Automotive Integration was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4o Mini: Advancing Cost-Efficient AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 15:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s GPT-4o Mini represents a significant advancement in the field of artificial intelligence, combining high performance with cost efficiency. This model is designed to make advanced AI capabilities more accessible to a broader audience, addressing the needs of businesses, developers, and researchers who require powerful AI tools without the high cost typically associated with such […] The article GPT-4o Mini: Advancing Cost-Efficient AI was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CrowdStrike Launches Guidance Hub for Dealing with Windows Outage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 14:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CrowdStrike, in an effort to mitigate the widespread disruption caused by the recent CrowdStrike content bug, they have launched a comprehensive “Remediation and Guidance Hub.” This initiative comes in response to the catastrophic crash of approximately 8.5 million Windows computers globally, attributed to a problematic update from CrowdStrike’s Falcon platform. The hub aims to provide […] The article CrowdStrike Launches Guidance Hub for Dealing with Windows Outage was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Released CrowdStrike Recovery Tool to Help Repair Affected Windows Machines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 14:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has released a recovery tool designed to aid IT administrators in fixing Windows machines affected by the recent CrowdStrike Falcon agent issue. This problem led to widespread Blue Screen of Death (BSOD) errors, impacting approximately 1% of Windows machines globally! What is the Recovery Tool? The recovery tool creates a bootable USB drive, enabling […] The article Microsoft Released CrowdStrike Recovery Tool to Help Repair Affected Windows Machines was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CrowdStrike Crashed 8.5 Million Windows PCs Globally, estimated by Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 13:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2024/21_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The world of cybersecurity faced a catastrophic event recently when a CrowdStrike bug led to the crashing of 8.5 million PCs, approximately 1% of all Windows machines. The incident affected many industries, including: airlines, hospitals, governments, 911 operators, and more! The fallout from this incident has left tech experts and businesses scrambling to understand the […] The article CrowdStrike Crashed 8.5 Million Windows PCs Globally, estimated by Microsoft was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Antivirus Uses Kernel Mode in Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_07_2024/20_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 21:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_07_2024/20_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The recent CrowdStrike bug that took out 1% of Windows machines (approx. 8.5 million PCs) globally, the question of why Antivirus apps use Kernel Mode has come up for many. This article sheds some light into the reasoning behind why these programs need to operate at the Kernel Mode level within the Windows operating system. […] The article Why Antivirus Uses Kernel Mode in Windows was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the CrowdStrike Bug, Impact on Microsoft Azure, and Global Windows Outage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 18:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On July 18, 2024, CrowdStrike released a update with a bug that significantly impacted Windows machines globally, including virtual machines (VMs) running on multiple cloud platforms, such as Microsoft Azure, AWS, and Google Cloud. The problem originated from an update to the CrowdStrike Falcon agent, which led to unresponsiveness, blue screens (BSOD) and startup failures […] The article Understanding the CrowdStrike Bug, Impact on Microsoft Azure, and Global Windows Outage was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Azure Private Link and How to Deploy with Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 20:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Private Link offers several benefits, including enhanced security, simplified network architecture, and improved performance. It supports various Azure services like Azure Storage and Azure SQL Database, allowing organizations to maintain the privacy and integrity of their data. Moreover, Azure Private Link seamlessly integrates with Azure Virtual Networks (VNets), on-premises networks and supports global connectivity, […] The article What is Azure Private Link and How to Deploy with Terraform was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose Between Azure Cosmos DB for Table and Azure Table Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 22:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Choosing the right database solution is critical for the performance and scalability of your applications. When working with NoSQL, Table data and Microsoft Azure, two prominent options for table storage are Azure Cosmos DB for Table and Azure Table Storage (aka Azure Storage Tables). Both services provide robust solutions for storing semi-structured table data, but […] The article How to Choose Between Azure Cosmos DB for Table and Azure Table Storage was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
