<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 11:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust Security Principles for Generative AI &amp; LLMs in the Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s rapidly evolving digital landscape, enterprises face a constant barrage of cybersecurity threats. As organizations increasingly turn to cutting-edge technologies like Generative Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Large Language Models (LLMs) to drive innovation and efficiency, it’s crucial to ensure that robust security measures are in place. By applying the principles of Zero Trust, enterprises […] The article Zero Trust Security Principles for Generative AI &amp;amp; LLMs in the Enterprise appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals Certification (AZ-900 Exam)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 17:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals certification with the AZ-900 exam tests and validates a candidates foundational knowledge of the cloud and Microsoft Azure. This exam is ideal for individuals from both technical and non-technical backgrounds who want to demonstrate their understanding of cloud concepts, Azure services, and Azure management and governance. Why You Should Earn […] The article Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals Certification (AZ-900 Exam) appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Certifications – Prove Your Expertise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 11:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Keeping up with GitHub requires lots of skill mastery. GitHub is a platform used by over 100 million developers worldwide and offers a suite of certifications designed to elevate your development prowess and demonstrate your mastery of its powerful tools. Whether you’re a software developer, DevOps Engineer, SRE, security specialist, or IT professional, GitHub’s certifications […] The article GitHub Certifications – Prove Your Expertise appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Must-Know AI Terms for Developers, SREs, and DevOps Engineers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 11:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is all the buzz today! But, what does LLM, SLM, Copilot, GPT, ML, NLP and all the other acronyms and terms in the AI space really mean? AI tools are quickly becoming an integral part of every Developers, DevOps Engineers, and Site Reliability Engineers (SREs) daily workflow. AI literacy and understanding key […] The article Top 10 Must-Know AI Terms for Developers, SREs, and DevOps Engineers appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Generative AI App in C# with Phi-3-mini LLM and ONNX</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft recently released the new Phi-3-mini SLM (small language model), and I previously wrote about running Phi3 locally using Ollama. I’ve been exploring the world of hosting AI models in code lately, and this stuff is getting really interested. It turns out that among the tools to run AI models locally, there are developer tools […] The article Build a Generative AI App in C# with Phi-3-mini LLM and ONNX appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hub-and-Spoke Network Topology in Microsoft Azure using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A hub-and-spoke network topology is a popular design pattern used to manage and control network traffic when deploying enterprise workloads to Microsoft Azure. This article will guide you through deploying a hub-and-spoke network in Microsoft Azure using HashiCorp Terraform. We will cover the basic concepts, provide sample Terraform code, discuss security best practices to ensure […] The article Deploying Hub-and-Spoke Network Topology in Microsoft Azure using Terraform appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLDR: Google I/O 2024 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 20:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Google I/O 2024 Keynote was a showcase of technological innovation, underscoring Google’s relentless pursuit of excellence in artificial intelligence (AI). With CEO Sundar Pichai, the event was a celebration of the significant strides made in the past year and a glimpse into the future of AI-driven advancements. Central to the keynote was the Gemini […] The article TLDR: Google I/O 2024 Keynote appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload File from URL to Azure Blob Storage using Azure CLI with Bash and PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 11:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure CLI az storage blob upload command can be used to upload a local file into Azure Blob Storage. However, there are times when it would be easier to upload a file straight from the HTTP(S) URL into Azure Blob Storage. Unfortunately the Azure CLI does not have a command for this specific scenario, […] The article Upload File from URL to Azure Blob Storage using Azure CLI with Bash and PowerShell appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering DevOps Engineers with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of technology, the role of DevOps Engineers is becoming increasingly complex and critical. As organizations strive for higher reliability and performance, increased automation workflows, and smoother release processes, the integration of generative AI technologies, such as those offered by Azure OpenAI, is revolutionizing the realm of DevOps. DevOps Engineers can now […] The article Empowering DevOps Engineers with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AzAPI Terraform Provider Dynamic Properties Feature instead of jsonencode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AzAPI Terraform provider for Microsoft Azure has introduced a feature known as dynamic properties. This feature simplifies resource definitions by enabling the use of HCL (HashiCorp Configuration Language) blocks instead of JSON blocks that would previously require the use of JSON encoding (via jsonencode) and decoding (via jsondecode). This is a great improvement to […] The article Using AzAPI Terraform Provider Dynamic Properties Feature instead of jsonencode appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
