<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It’s Still About the Data: Practical Approach to Building with Agentic AI, LLMs and Generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s no denying the massive wave of excitement around Agentic AI, Multi-Agent Systems, Generative AI, and Large Language Models (LLMs). Whether it’s people experimenting with Copilots, implementing RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation) patterns, spinning up AI agents, or integrating LLMs into enterprise apps, there’s a real energy behind this shift. But as exciting (and disruptive) as this […] The article It’s Still About the Data: Practical Approach to Building with Agentic AI, LLMs and Generative AI was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Terraform State in Azure Blob Storage using Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When your team loses control of its Terraform state file, it loses control of everything in the subscription. An unencrypted or publicly exposed .tfstate isn’t just embarrassing—it’s a roadmap to your entire cloud estate. A breach of the state file is a major security breach that puts the future of your organization at risk. Improperly […] The article Securing Terraform State in Azure Blob Storage using Best Practices was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
