<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Perform Vector Database Similarity Search in .NET Apps using Build5Nines.SharpVector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ability to efficiently search and retrieve documents based on their semantic content has become increasingly important; especially when it comes to building Generative AI systems that implement the Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) design pattern. One powerful approach to achieving this is through the use of vector representations of text data, which enables similarity search […] The article Perform Vector Database Similarity Search in .NET Apps using Build5Nines.SharpVector appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrator’s Introduction to Azure IoT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 20:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Internet of Things (IoT) industry has continued to grow and become more pervasive in people’s everyday lives these last few years. There are MANY useful applications for IoT devices and solutions in both the consumer and industrial space. Some of the solutions we’ve become accustomed to are smart speakers, cameras, Amazon Alexa, and many […] The article Administrator’s Introduction to Azure IoT appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with YAML in Terraform using the `yamldecode` and `yamlencode` Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The functions built into and supported by HashiCorp Terraform include the yamldecode and yamlencode functions for working with YAML data. These functions enable seamless integration and manipulation of YAML within Terraform configurations, enhancing the flexibility and manageability of infrastructure setups. This article explains their usage, and provides some practical applications. Decoding YAML with yamldecode Function […] The article Working with YAML in Terraform using the yamldecode and yamlencode Functions appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Microsoft Copilot for Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot for Azure is an AI-powered tool designed to enhance your efficiency and productivity when working with Azure. Leveraging advanced Large Language Models (LLMs) and the Azure control plane, Copilot for Azure provides deep insights and simplifies the management of Azure services and resources. It aims to streamline operations across both cloud and edge […] The article Introducing Microsoft Copilot for Azure appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Custom 404 Not Found Page with Azure Static Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2024/26_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2024/26_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When managing a website, it’s crucial to ensure a seamless user experience, even when things go wrong. One common scenario is the 404 Not Found error when a visitor tries to access a page that doesn’t exist. Instead of having your visitor see the default Azure Static Web App “not found” page, you can configure […] The article Configure Custom 404 Not Found Page with Azure Static Web Apps appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLDR: Next Gen AI for Developers with Microsoft Cloud by Scott Guthrie at Microsoft Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 10:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scott Guthrie’s talk, “Next Generation AI for Developers with the Microsoft Cloud,” highlighted significant advancements and tools for developers leveraging AI and the Microsoft Cloud. Here’s a TLDR to give you a quicker way to stay updated on all the key announcements. Notable Moments from Scott Guthries Talk Here’s are several notable moments from Scott […] The article TLDR: Next Gen AI for Developers with Microsoft Cloud by Scott Guthrie at Microsoft Build 2024 appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Copilot Internal Architecture Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot is an advanced, Generative AI-powered assistant designed to enhance productivity by integrating with various Microsoft applications and services. It leverages large language models (LLMs) and the extensive data network of Microsoft Graph to provide contextual and intelligent assistance in real-time. FYI, this is not an official write up of the architecture of Microsoft […] The article Microsoft Copilot Internal Architecture Explained appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLDR: Microsoft Build 2024 Keynote with Satya Nadella</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 10:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            During the Microsoft Build 2024 keynote, CEO Satya Nadella delivered a comprehensive overview of Microsoft’s vision and advancements in artificial intelligence (AI). Addressing a global audience, Nadella emphasized how AI is set to transform every aspect of our digital and physical lives, making technology more accessible, efficient, and integrated into daily activities. The presentation covered […] The article TLDR: Microsoft Build 2024 Keynote with Satya Nadella appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Output URL to Azure Portal for Azure Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp Terraform is an extremely powerful IaC tool for managing Microsoft Azure infrastructure through code, from the command-line, and from CI/CD tools like GitHub Actions or Terraform Cloud. Terraform is great for managing and deploying the configurations for Microsoft Azure resources, but tools like the Azure Portal are still needed to view the real Azure […] The article Terraform: Output URL to Azure Portal for Azure Resources appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
