<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unlock GitHub Copilot’s Full Potential: Why Every Repo Needs an AGENTS.md File</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2025/04_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Supercharge Your AI Pair Programming Experience with Project-Specific Context and Control AI-assisted development has rapidly transformed how engineers write code, collaborate, and ship software. GitHub Copilot, powered by OpenAI’s Codex and now evolving with GPT-5 capabilities, is at the center of this revolution — quietly sitting in your IDE, turning natural language prompts into working […] The article Unlock GitHub Copilot’s Full Potential: Why Every Repo Needs an AGENTS.md File was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform &#43; Azure Multi-Region Naming Convention across Azure Regions, Resources, and Terraform Modules</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine this: your application goes down in a major Azure region outage. DNS traffic shifts to the secondary region as designed. Terraform kicks off to scale the backup environment. Everything should just seamlessly work… but it doesn’t. Why? Because names don’t match. Storage accounts are globally unique. Key Vault names are different across regions. Resource […] The article Terraform + Azure Multi-Region Naming Convention across Azure Regions, Resources, and Terraform Modules was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
