<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 16:14:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure CDN POP Locations: Interactive Map of Azure CDN Points of Presence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 16:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Azure CDN (Content Delivery Network) provides secure, reliable content delivery with a broad global reach along with rich features. The Azure CDN POP (point of presence) locations are not the same as the Azure Region locations, and Microsoft has the list of cities for the CDN locations published in the Azure documentation. However, […] The article Azure CDN POP Locations: Interactive Map of Azure CDN Points of Presence appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Convention over Configuration for IaC Deployment Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 02:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Infrastructure as Code (IaC), every aspect of an organization’s infrastructure is defined and managed through code. This infrastructure deployment and configuration automation makes managing the organizations infrastructure much easier over time. Also, by committing the IaC code that configurations the infrastructure into source control, there are change tracking and other benefits for the organizations […] The article Benefits of Convention over Configuration for IaC Deployment Projects appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
