<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://news.mytechramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 18:47:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://news.mytechramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Install Latest Version on macOS and Linux</title>
      <link>https://news.mytechramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 18:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.mytechramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Terraform from HashiCorp is provided as a command-line tool that must first be installed locally before excution. It’s easy to install, as the full tool is contained within a single executable. This makes it easy to put terraform in any folder on your machine for use. Although, to make it executable from anywhere on your […] The article Terraform: Install Latest Version on macOS and Linux appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Tags: Important Organization Strategies and Tips</title>
      <link>https://news.mytechramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 18:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://news.mytechramblings.com/post/25_03_2024/25_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the Microsoft Azure cloud, the organization and management of resources are extremely important for operational efficiency and cost-effectiveness. Azure Tags serve as a fundamental tool in categorizing resources within the Azure environment, providing a versatile means to attach metadata to resources for various purposes, including administration, billing, and monitoring . These key-value pairs enable […] The article Azure Resource Tags: Important Organization Strategies and Tips appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
