<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 01:48:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Acquires Rockset: A Strategic Move in AI and Data Processing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 01:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s recent acquisition of Rockset is a significant milestone in the AI and data management sectors. This acquisition is poised to bolster OpenAI’s capabilities in real-time analytics and data processing, critical areas for advancing AI technology. The acquisition of Rockset, a company renowned for its real-time analytics platform, aligns with OpenAI’s mission to enhance its […] The article OpenAI Acquires Rockset: A Strategic Move in AI and Data Processing was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Building AI Agents with LangChain and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2024/23_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LangChain is a tool for more easily creating AI agents that can autonomously perform tasks. These agents can streamline operations, enhance user experiences, and handle complex processes with minimal human intervention. Building these AI agents can be difficult and this is the reason for why LangChain exists. LangChain is a cutting-edge framework designed to simplify […] The article Introduction to Building AI Agents with LangChain and Python was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting AI Hallucinations using Semantic Entropy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 18:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) and the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) has transformed numerous fields, from healthcare to entertainment, by enabling machines to understand and generate human-like text. However, one significant challenge in deploying AI, especially LLMs, is the phenomenon of AI “hallucinations.” These are instances where the AI generates plausible-sounding but factually incorrect or […] The article Detecting AI Hallucinations using Semantic Entropy was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are AI Agents and Agentic AI?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 15:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_06_2024/22_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI Agents are more advanced implementations of artificial intelligence (AI) built to more autonomously perform tasks, make decisions, and interact with users or other systems. These agents are designed to simulate human-like “cognitive” functions, enabling them to process information, learn from interactions, and adapt to new scenarios without direct human intervention. Where’s the AI intelligence […] The article What are AI Agents and Agentic AI? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Building AI Agents with Microsoft Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 11:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Semantic Kernel is an innovative, open-source SDK designed to seamlessly integrate Large Language Models (LLMs) with conventional programming languages like C#, Python, and Java. By utilizing Semantic Kernel, developers can create powerful, AI-driven applications without needing to become AI experts. This introduction will guide you through the fundamental concepts, features, and benefits of using […] The article Introduction to Building AI Agents with Microsoft Semantic Kernel was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI-Ready Infrastructure in Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 15:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is transforming the landscape of modern enterprises, driving innovation, enhancing operational efficiency, and unlocking new avenues for growth. As businesses strive to harness the full potential of AI, having an AI-ready infrastructure becomes paramount. Microsoft Azure stands out as a leader in this domain, offering a comprehensive suite of tools and services […] The article Build an AI-Ready Infrastructure in Microsoft Azure was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7Rs of Cloud Migration: Guide to a Seamless Migration Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 18:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud computing has revolutionized how organizations manage and deploy their IT resources, offering unparalleled scalability, flexibility, and cost-efficiency. As businesses increasingly migrate their applications and data to the cloud, understanding the best migration strategies becomes crucial. This article introduces the 7 Rs of cloud migration, a comprehensive framework designed to guide organizations through the complexities […] The article The 7Rs of Cloud Migration: Guide to a Seamless Migration Strategy was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
