<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 12:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Azure Front Door, Traffic Manager, and Load Balancer: Choosing the Right Tool for Global Application Delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern cloud architectures demand flexible, resilient, and scalable traffic distribution strategies. As workloads increasingly span multiple regions and hybrid environments, choosing the right load balancing service in Microsoft Azure becomes a strategic architectural decision. Among Azure’s suite of traffic distribution tools, Azure Front Door, Azure Traffic Manager, and Azure Load Balancer are commonly evaluated — […] The article Comparing Azure Front Door, Traffic Manager, and Load Balancer: Choosing the Right Tool for Global Application Delivery was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Stuck to Senior: How Mentorship Accelerates Your Cloud, DevOps &amp; AI Career</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The journey from junior engineer to senior Cloud, DevOps or even AI professional can feel like climbing an ever-growing mountain. New tools. Shifting best practices. Complicated architectures. Add to that the pressure of staying relevant in a sea of LinkedIn updates and GitHub commits, and it’s easy to get stuck—stuck doing the same tasks, stuck […] The article From Stuck to Senior: How Mentorship Accelerates Your Cloud, DevOps &amp;amp; AI Career was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Tim Berners-Lee – Inventor of the World Wide Web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tim Berners-Lee, a name etched into the bedrock of computing history, stands among the most influential figures to ever touch the digital sphere. Credited with inventing the World Wide Web in 1989, his groundbreaking work at CERN sparked a technological revolution that reshaped communication, commerce, and culture. Over three decades later, Berners-Lee’s visionary spirit persists, […] The article Big Thinkers: Tim Berners-Lee – Inventor of the World Wide Web was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: jQuery – The Tiny Library that Transformed the Web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 11:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “Write less, do more.” That motto wasn’t just a clever tagline—it was a revolution. Before modern JavaScript frameworks became the norm, jQuery quietly changed everything. In the web development landscape now dominated by React, Angular, and Vue, it might be easy to forget a time when making a button click actually do something required verbose, […] The article Software Innovation: jQuery – The Tiny Library that Transformed the Web was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write AI Prompts That Output Valid CSV Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2025/28_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2025/28_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with Large Language Models (LLMs), generating structured outputs like CSV (Comma-Separated Values) is invaluable for tasks such as data analysis, reporting, and integration with spreadsheet applications. However, since LLMs are primarily optimized for natural language generation, crafting prompts that yield valid CSV-formatted data requires careful engineering. This article provides strategies and examples to […] The article How to Write AI Prompts That Output Valid CSV Data was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
