<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 17:23:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Microsoft AI Shell Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 17:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            During Microsoft Ignite 2024, Microsoft announced the public preview of AI Shell, a groundbreaking innovation that integrates artificial intelligence directly into command-line workflows. With this release, Microsoft aims to bridge the gap between traditional shell interactions and the growing capabilities of AI, enabling developers and IT professionals to work smarter and faster. What is Microsoft […] The article New Microsoft AI Shell Public Preview was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the new Azure AI Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure AI Agent Service is designed to revolutionize the development and deployment of these AI agents, delivering an enterprise-ready solution tailored to meet the unique needs of modern organizations. Organizations are constantly seeking innovative ways to enhance operational efficiency and streamline workflows. Artificial Intelligence (AI) has emerged as a cornerstone of this transformation, with autonomous […] The article Introducing the new Azure AI Agent Service was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Windows 365 Link: The First Cloud PC Device for Windows 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has unveiled its first-ever Cloud PC device, the Windows 365 Link, a purpose-built tool designed to enhance the user experience for organizations leveraging Windows 365 Cloud PCs. This compact, fanless device is packed with features aimed at boosting productivity, ensuring security, and simplifying IT management. Here’s a breakdown of everything you need to know […] The article Introducing Windows 365 Link: The First Cloud PC Device for Windows 365 was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s Vision for 2025 and Beyond: Copilot, Responsible AI, Security and Multicloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Ignite 2024 conference kicks off next week and I’ve analyzed the full session list to gleam insights into the company’s strategic roadmap for 2025 and beyond. This years conference has an unmistakable emphasis on artificial intelligence, security, and multicloud innovation. The 1,846 sessions hosted at the conference spanning a vast array of tech […] The article Microsoft’s Vision for 2025 and Beyond: Copilot, Responsible AI, Security and Multicloud was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
