<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 11:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Building AI Agents with Microsoft Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 11:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Semantic Kernel is an innovative, open-source SDK designed to seamlessly integrate Large Language Models (LLMs) with conventional programming languages like C#, Python, and Java. By utilizing Semantic Kernel, developers can create powerful, AI-driven applications without needing to become AI experts. This introduction will guide you through the fundamental concepts, features, and benefits of using [因 The article Introduction to Building AI Agents with Microsoft Semantic Kernel was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI-Ready Infrastructure in Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 15:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is transforming the landscape of modern enterprises, driving innovation, enhancing operational efficiency, and unlocking new avenues for growth. As businesses strive to harness the full potential of AI, having an AI-ready infrastructure becomes paramount. Microsoft Azure stands out as a leader in this domain, offering a comprehensive suite of tools and services [因 The article Build an AI-Ready Infrastructure in Microsoft Azure was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7Rs of Cloud Migration: Guide to a Seamless Migration Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 18:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud computing has revolutionized how organizations manage and deploy their IT resources, offering unparalleled scalability, flexibility, and cost-efficiency. As businesses increasingly migrate their applications and data to the cloud, understanding the best migration strategies becomes crucial. This article introduces the 7 Rs of cloud migration, a comprehensive framework designed to guide organizations through the complexities [因 The article The 7Rs of Cloud Migration: Guide to a Seamless Migration Strategy was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Applied Skills Replacing Microsoft Certifications?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 22:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Learn Applied Skills credentials are not replacing Microsoft Certifications. Microsoft is expanding their credentialing portfolio to cater better to learners and customers, allowing validation of specific skill sets with this new offering. Microsoft Certifications are continuing to be role-based, and still assess a broad range of skills essential for success in key roles within [因 The article Are Applied Skills Replacing Microsoft Certifications? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
