<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a Generative AI &#43; RAG App in C# with Phi-3, ONNX, and SharpVector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2024/09_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2024/09_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By combining Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) with Generative AI, you can create a more intelligent and context aware AI solution that can more accurately generate text responses. I’ve previously written about building a generative AI application using C#, Phi-3 and the ONNX Runtime. This article will take the foundation covered in that article and add […] The article Build a Generative AI + RAG App in C# with Phi-3, ONNX, and SharpVector was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG)?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 21:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Diagram: How Does RAG Work? The article What is Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG)? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
Link to article: https://build5nines.com/what-is-retrieval-augmented-generation-rag/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring GitHub Actions to Run Jobs on Specific Branches</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 21:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running jobs on specific branches with GitHub Actions is a common scenario implemented by DevOps and SRE professionals. This allows you to control which branches trigger specific jobs within your workflows. This can be important for maintaining efficient CI/CD processes, especially if you want tests to run on every branch while restricting deployment actions to […] The article Configuring GitHub Actions to Run Jobs on Specific Branches was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Get Current Branch Name for Git Repo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 14:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to get the current branch name in GitHub Actions can be useful for workflows that trigger off of multiple branches of a GitHub repository. The reason this can be useful is that the branch name may be important to mark or tag the code release in some way (i.e. tag a docker image), or […] The article GitHub Actions: Get Current Branch Name for Git Repo was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Download File and Commit to Repository</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A few times I’ve found the need to setup a GitHub Actions workflow that downloads a file and commits that file back to the repository. I had a need to pull in a JSON file and update it periodically to a GitHub repository. There are other scenarios where this may be needed. This article will […] The article GitHub Actions: Download File and Commit to Repository was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform IP Functions for Managing IP Addresses, CIDR Blocks, and Subnets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 03:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Terraform provides functions to manage and manipulate IP addresses and CIDR blocks. These functions are crucial for network automation and orchestration in cloud environments, enabling users to create, manage, and allocate network resources efficiently. This article shows how to use the Terraform IP functions, along with some practical examples to help you get the most […] The article Terraform IP Functions for Managing IP Addresses, CIDR Blocks, and Subnets was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
