<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 18:32:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Search in .NET / C# with Build5Nines.SharpVector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 18:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we often find ourselves building smarter, more context-aware applications. Whether it’s powering a document search tool or implementing Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), semantic search is a powerful capability to have in your toolbox. I recently found myself needing a lightweight, local, in-memory vector database for a .NET / C# project. At the time, there […] The article Semantic Search in .NET / C# with Build5Nines.SharpVector was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: Ruby on Rails – The Framework that Rewired The Web with MVC and Convention</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It wasn’t the first web framework. It may not be the flashiest these days in 2025. But Ruby on Rails was revolutionary when it hit the scene — and its fingerprints are still all over modern web development today. At a time when building web applications was often painful, verbose, and fractured across multiple layers […] The article Software Innovation: Ruby on Rails – The Framework that Rewired The Web with MVC and Convention was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and Anthropic Collaborate to Develop Official C# SDK for Model Context Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced a partnership with Anthropic to develop an official C# Software Development Kit (SDK) for the Model Context Protocol (MCP). This collaboration aims to streamline the integration of large language models (LLMs) into C# applications, addressing the growing demand for advanced AI functionalities in enterprise software development. Enhancing AI Integration in C# Applications […] The article Microsoft and Anthropic Collaborate to Develop Official C# SDK for Model Context Protocol was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: Git – Distributed Version Control System That Changed Everything</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 21:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Few tools have been as transformative — or as quietly omnipresent — as Git. Now twenty years old, Git is not just a version control system; it’s the backbone of global software collaboration. From solo developers hacking on open-source projects to multinational tech giants deploying mission-critical infrastructure, Git is the invisible force managing source code, […] The article Software Innovation: Git – Distributed Version Control System That Changed Everything was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Scott Hanselman – Empowering Developer Community Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Few voices in the Microsoft and .NET space rise above the rest as much as Scott Hanselman. He’s a developer, teacher, speaker, and currently the Vice President of Developer Community at Microsoft. For over two decades, Scott has been a connecting force in the tech world, linking developers to tools, platforms, and to each other. […] The article Big Thinkers: Scott Hanselman – Empowering Developer Community Worldwide was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
