<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 12:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is a Cloud Engineer and How to Become one?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_04_2024/28_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It was once a new concept that enterprises were trying to make sense of, but the term “cloud” has really become ubiquitous across the IT landscape. No matter the industry, your organization is likely depending on some cloud services; from Microsoft Azure, AWS, Microsoft 365, Slack, Teams, GitHub, to so many other services. Behind the […] The article What is a Cloud Engineer and How to Become one? appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenTofu: Open Source Alternative to Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of cloud, hybrid, and on-premises Infrastructure as Code (IaC), where managing and provisioning infrastructure through code has become indispensable, tools like OpenTofu play a pivotal role. The evolutions of IaC tools continues with OpenTofu, as a fork of Terraform that offers a more open-source, community-driven alternative that is managed by the Linux […] The article OpenTofu: Open Source Alternative to Terraform appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Modules using Git Branch as Source</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp Terraform empowers DevOps Engineers and SREs to manage cloud resources efficiently. One of its standout features is the Terraform Modules support, allowing users to organize and reuse infrastructure code effectively as reusable modules. While Terraform’s native module registry serves as a central hub for sharing modules, sometimes you may prefer hosting modules in your […] The article Terraform: Modules using Git Branch as Source appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing IBM’s Acquisition of HashiCorp: A Game-Changer in Hybrid Cloud Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IBM has announced its acquisition of HashiCorp Inc., a leading multi-cloud infrastructure automation company, for $6.4 billion! This acquisition is poised to revolutionize the hybrid cloud landscape, offering enterprises a comprehensive end-to-end solution to navigate the complexities of today’s AI-driven application growth. Let’s look at the details of this cloud changing acquisition and its implications […] The article Analyzing IBM’s Acquisition of HashiCorp: A Game-Changer in Hybrid Cloud Management appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: How are Data Sources used?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In HashiCorp Terraform, data sources serve as a bridge between the Terraform configuration and external systems or information. Essentially, data sources allow Terraform to query external resources, such as cloud platforms, APIs, databases, or other systems, and use the retrieved information within the configuration. Unlike resources, which represent infrastructure components to be managed by Terraform, […] The article Terraform: How are Data Sources used? appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Split main.tf into seperate files</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When using HashiCorp Terraform as the Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool of choice, it becomes critical to organize the Terraform code as the Terraform project becomes more complex. One of the most common practices is to split the Terraform project from a single file (typically named main.tf) into multiple smaller files. This helps increase maintainability […] The article Terraform: Split main.tf into seperate files appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Remove Resource from State File (.tfstate)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Terraform’s declarative approach allows for defining infrastructure as code (IaC), enabling teams to automate the deployment and management of resources across various cloud providers, including Microsoft Azure and Amazon AWS. As infrastructure evolves, there may arise a need to remove resources from the Terraform state that are no longer required. When you manually delete resources […] The article Terraform: Remove Resource from State File (.tfstate) appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure CDN POP Locations: Interactive Map of Azure CDN Points of Presence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 16:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Azure CDN (Content Delivery Network) provides secure, reliable content delivery with a broad global reach along with rich features. The Azure CDN POP (point of presence) locations are not the same as the Azure Region locations, and Microsoft has the list of cities for the CDN locations published in the Azure documentation. However, […] The article Azure CDN POP Locations: Interactive Map of Azure CDN Points of Presence appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
