<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 14:34:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Get Current Branch Name for Git Repo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 14:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to get the current branch name in GitHub Actions can be useful for workflows that trigger off of multiple branches of a GitHub repository. The reason this can be useful is that the branch name may be important to mark or tag the code release in some way (i.e. tag a docker image), or […] The article GitHub Actions: Get Current Branch Name for Git Repo was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Download File and Commit to Repository</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A few times I’ve found the need to setup a GitHub Actions workflow that downloads a file and commits that file back to the repository. I had a need to pull in a JSON file and update it periodically to a GitHub repository. There are other scenarios where this may be needed. This article will […] The article GitHub Actions: Download File and Commit to Repository was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform IP Functions for Managing IP Addresses, CIDR Blocks, and Subnets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 03:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Terraform provides functions to manage and manipulate IP addresses and CIDR blocks. These functions are crucial for network automation and orchestration in cloud environments, enabling users to create, manage, and allocate network resources efficiently. This article shows how to use the Terraform IP functions, along with some practical examples to help you get the most […] The article Terraform IP Functions for Managing IP Addresses, CIDR Blocks, and Subnets was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Lookup Function – Usage and Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 03:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Terraform lookup() function provides a powerful feature that can be used to implement more flexible and easily configurable infrastructure configurations. The lookup() function is essential for retrieving values from maps dynamically. This article explains Terraform maps, in case you’re not familiar yet, and the explores the Terraform lookup() function with usage examples and a […] The article Terraform Lookup Function – Usage and Examples was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell: Automate Terraform Install on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 03:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While HashiCorp Terraform is a single executable, it’s really useful to install it on the local machine so the terraform.exe executable can be run from anywhere. To do this, Terraform needs to be downloaded, placed somewhere on the local machine, and then that path must be added to the system PATH environment variable. I’ve done […] The article PowerShell: Automate Terraform Install on Windows was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perform Vector Database Similarity Search in .NET Apps using Build5Nines.SharpVector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ability to efficiently search and retrieve documents based on their semantic content has become increasingly important; especially when it comes to building Generative AI systems that implement the Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) design pattern. One powerful approach to achieving this is through the use of vector representations of text data, which enables similarity search […] The article Perform Vector Database Similarity Search in .NET Apps using Build5Nines.SharpVector was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrator’s Introduction to Azure IoT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 20:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Internet of Things (IoT) industry has continued to grow and become more pervasive in people’s everyday lives these last few years. There are MANY useful applications for IoT devices and solutions in both the consumer and industrial space. Some of the solutions we’ve become accustomed to are smart speakers, cameras, Amazon Alexa, and many […] The article Administrator’s Introduction to Azure IoT appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with YAML in Terraform using the `yamldecode` and `yamlencode` Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The functions built into and supported by HashiCorp Terraform include the yamldecode and yamlencode functions for working with YAML data. These functions enable seamless integration and manipulation of YAML within Terraform configurations, enhancing the flexibility and manageability of infrastructure setups. This article explains their usage, and provides some practical applications. Decoding YAML with yamldecode Function […] The article Working with YAML in Terraform using the yamldecode and yamlencode Functions appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
