<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DBRX: Databricks Open Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DBRX is Databricks’ newest Large Language Model (LLM) is open source and designed to bring advanced AI capabilities to businesses across multiple industries. This model stands out for its powerful architecture, efficiency, and user-friendly design, making sophisticated AI accessible and adaptable for diverse applications. By combining cutting-edge technology with practical usability, DBRX aims to transform […] The article DBRX: Databricks Open Large Language Model was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is The HashiCorp Infrastructure Cloud?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The cloud is the standard for hosting applications and workloads. However, only a small percentage of organizations realize the full benefits such as cost reduction, enhanced resilience, and new revenue streams. Often, this is due to the complex nature of cloud environments. The HashiCorp Infrastructure Cloud aims to address these challenges, providing a unified platform […] The article What is The HashiCorp Infrastructure Cloud? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
