<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 18:25:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create React App is Now Deprecated: Time to Migrate to Vite or Next.js</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 18:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The React team has officially announced the deprecation of Create React App (CRA) in favor of more modern and efficient tools like Vite and Next.js. If you’ve been using CRA to bootstrap your React applications, now is the time to explore better alternatives that provide improved performance, developer experience, and scalability. Why is Create React […] The article Create React App is Now Deprecated: Time to Migrate to Vite or Next.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Get User Principal Name (UPN) of User Running Deployment without Entra ID Read Permissions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_02_2025/16_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_02_2025/16_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I has a scenario where I needed to configure an Azure PostgreSQL Flexible Server to use Entra ID (Azure AD) authentication and add the Entra user running the HashiCorp Terraform deployment as the Azure PostgreSQL Administrator using the azurerm_postgresql_flexible_server_active_directory_administrator Terraform resource. Generally, you would use the azuread_user data resource in Terraform to get the Entra […] The article Terraform: Get User Principal Name (UPN) of User Running Deployment without Entra ID Read Permissions was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supervised Learning (SSL) in AI Systems: Autonomous Machine Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 21:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is evolving at a rapid pace, with machine learning techniques becoming more sophisticated and efficient. One of the biggest challenges in traditional AI training is the heavy reliance on labeled datasets, which require extensive human effort and resources. However, Self-Supervised Learning (SSL) is revolutionizing the field by enabling AI models to learn […] The article Self-Supervised Learning (SSL) in AI Systems: Autonomous Machine Intelligence was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Functions Cost Considerations and Optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 18:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2025/15_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Functions is a powerful serverless compute service that enables organizations to build event-driven applications with minimal infrastructure management. While its scalability and flexibility make it an attractive choice for modern cloud applications, managing costs effectively is essential to avoid unexpected expenses. This article explores the key factors influencing Azure Functions pricing and provides a […] The article Azure Functions Cost Considerations and Optimization was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
