<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 11:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Scott Hanselman – Empowering Developer Community Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Few voices in the Microsoft and .NET space rise above the rest as much as Scott Hanselman. He’s a developer, teacher, speaker, and currently the Vice President of Developer Community at Microsoft. For over two decades, Scott has been a connecting force in the tech world, linking developers to tools, platforms, and to each other. […] The article Big Thinkers: Scott Hanselman – Empowering Developer Community Worldwide was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write AI Prompts That Output Valid JSON Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 12:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with LLMs, an extremely valuable use case is generating structured data as the output response of the AI prompt. Whether you’re building an app, prototyping a data pipeline, or performing data extraction or transformation, receiving structured outputs like JSON saves time and makes downstream processing seamless. But there’s a challenge: these models are […] The article How to Write AI Prompts That Output Valid JSON Data was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From BASIC to Copilot: 50 Years of Microsoft Technology Innovation and Leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 14:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are few companies in the history of technology — or business, for that matter — that can say they changed the world. Even fewer can say they did it more than once. As Microsoft marks its 50th anniversary, it’s hard not to marvel at just how much of our modern digital life bears its […] The article From BASIC to Copilot: 50 Years of Microsoft Technology Innovation and Leadership was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Anders Hejlsberg – The Architect Shaping the Cloud’s Programming Future from C# to TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 12:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Few names carry as much respect and recognition among software developers as Anders Hejlsberg. As the creator of Turbo Pascal, the chief architect of Delphi, the original designer of C#, and now the lead architect of TypeScript, Hejlsberg has shaped the way millions of developers write code daily. While his earlier work transformed client-side and […] The article Big Thinkers: Anders Hejlsberg – The Architect Shaping the Cloud’s Programming Future from C# to TypeScript was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
