<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 12:45:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Anders Hejlsberg – The Architect Shaping the Cloud’s Programming Future from C# to TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 12:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2025/04_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Few names carry as much respect and recognition among software developers as Anders Hejlsberg. As the creator of Turbo Pascal, the chief architect of Delphi, the original designer of C#, and now the lead architect of TypeScript, Hejlsberg has shaped the way millions of developers write code daily. While his earlier work transformed client-side and […] The article Big Thinkers: Anders Hejlsberg – The Architect Shaping the Cloud’s Programming Future from C# to TypeScript was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build and Deploy an MCP Server with TypeScript and Azure Developer CLI (azd) using Azure Container Apps and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 21:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2025/03_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) are revolutionizing the way we build software. But as the scope of intelligent applications grows, so does the need for structured, contextual communication between LLMs and real-world data, services, and business logic. This is where the Model Context Protocol (MCP) comes in — a lightweight but powerful standard for exposing structured […] The article How to Build and Deploy an MCP Server with TypeScript and Azure Developer CLI (azd) using Azure Container Apps and Docker was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying Terraform Changes to Specific Resources using the -target Argument</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 15:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing Infrastructure as Code (IaC) with Terraform is as common as CI/CD pipelines and incident response playbooks. However, there are moments when you don’t want Terraform to touch everything. Maybe you need to quickly redeploy an Azure Function App, or perhaps a specific Storage Account needs an urgent configuration change without disturbing unrelated resources. The […] The article Applying Terraform Changes to Specific Resources using the -target Argument was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Secures $40 Billion Funding Round Led by SoftBank to Advance AGI Research</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 19:58:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI has announced a substantial new funding round, raising $40 billion at a $300 billion post-money valuation. The financing, revealed on March 31, 2025, is backed by SoftBank Group and will be used to advance OpenAI’s research towards artificial general intelligence (AGI), expand compute capacity, and enhance its AI product ecosystem. Scaling Towards AGI The […] The article OpenAI Secures $40 Billion Funding Round Led by SoftBank to Advance AGI Research was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the HashiCorp Ambassador Award?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 20:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp, the company behind Terraform, Consul, and Vault, has a community recognition award they call “HashiCorp Ambassador.” This award is given to individuals who have committed to the spirit of open source and actively share their knowledge in HashiCorp products to the IT community through content creation and local events that advocate for and adhere […] The article What is the HashiCorp Ambassador Award? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databricks vs Apache Spark: Key Differences and When to Use Each</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Within the big data and analytics space there are two names at the forefront of conversation: Apache Spark and Databricks. While they’re closely related, they serve very different purposes in the data ecosystem. Understanding their core differences is critical for architects, developers, and data engineers looking to build scalable, high-performance data solutions in the cloud. […] The article Databricks vs Apache Spark: Key Differences and When to Use Each was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Basic: The Language That Brought Programming to the Masses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2025/29_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 13:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2025/29_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the vibrant and fast-paced history of software development, a few languages have quietly but profoundly reshaped the landscape. Among these is Visual Basic (VB) — a language often underestimated in its influence but undeniably responsible for bringing programming out of the ivory towers of computer science and into the hands of everyday developers, business […] The article Visual Basic: The Language That Brought Programming to the Masses was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Scott Guthrie – From Innovator of ASP.NET to Azure’s Global Rise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2025/29_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 12:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2025/29_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the Executive Vice President of Microsoft’s Cloud + AI Group, Scott Guthrie (aka “ScottGu”, pronounces “Scott Goo”) has quietly yet powerfully shaped the trajectory of one of the world’s largest and most influential cloud platforms—Microsoft Azure. His influence extends beyond corporate growth, playing a pivotal role in transforming cloud computing itself, from enterprise-scale deployments […] The article Big Thinkers: Scott Guthrie – From Innovator of ASP.NET to Azure’s Global Rise was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
