<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 11:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Cloud: How to Seamlessly Migrate On-Prem File Shares to Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 11:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2025/09_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For many organizations, legacy file servers have long been the backbone of data sharing and collaboration. But as cloud adoption reaches critical mass, those old file shares start to look like an anchor holding you back. Whether it’s scalability, remote access, disaster recovery, or cost optimization, the writing’s on the wall: it’s time to migrate […] The article Unlocking the Cloud: How to Seamlessly Migrate On-Prem File Shares to Azure Storage was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Container Apps vs AKS: Which Is Right for Your Enterprise Application?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When it comes to modernizing enterprise systems in Azure, containerization is the name of the game. But if you’re standing at the crossroads of Azure Container Apps and Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS), the decision isn’t always straightforward. Both options offer robust paths to scalable microservices—but they cater to different levels of control, complexity, and operational […] The article Azure Container Apps vs AKS: Which Is Right for Your Enterprise Application? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
