<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:51:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Book: Build and Deploy Apps using Azure Developer CLI by Chris Pietschmann</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2025/21_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2025/21_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am excited to announce the release of my new book, Build and Deploy Apps using Azure Developer CLI, a practical, hands-on guide for developers and teams who want to streamline cloud-native application deployments on Microsoft Azure using the Azure Developer CLI (azd). Modern application delivery often gets slowed down by inconsistent environments, manual portal steps, […] The article New Book: Build and Deploy Apps using Azure Developer CLI by Chris Pietschmann was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt Noise Is Killing Your AI Accuracy: How to Optimize Context for Grounded Output</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 01:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The most common reason an AI system “hallucinates” in production isn’t that the model is dumb. It’s that we’re drowning it. In the last year, many teams have quietly adopted a pattern that looks sophisticated on paper: throw everything into the prompt. Policies, API schemas, examples, edge cases, brand voice, product specs, meeting notes, customer […] The article Prompt Noise Is Killing Your AI Accuracy: How to Optimize Context for Grounded Output was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
