<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: James Gosling – Creator of Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            James Gosling is a name that resonates through the halls of computer science, software engineering, and more recently, cloud computing. Best known as the “Father of Java,” Gosling’s influence stretches far beyond the iconic programming language. His work has quietly but profoundly shaped the modern cloud landscape, enabling countless innovations that rely on scalable, reliable, […] The article Big Thinkers: James Gosling – Creator of Java was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovations: iOS – The Operating System That Put the Future in Your Pocket</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A 18‑year chronicle of Apple’s mobile powerhouse—how it began, how it rewired the software economy, and why its next act is infused with on‑device intelligence. You wake up, glance at a glowing rectangle, and with a tap summon everything from bank balances to baby photos. That daily ritual traces its lineage to a January 2007 […] The article Software Innovations: iOS – The Operating System That Put the Future in Your Pocket was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Security Risks of “Vibe Coding” for Enterprise AI Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s a quiet rebellion happening in AI development. Developers are increasingly bypassing traditional planning and documentation processes in favor of a faster, more instinctive approach: “vibe coding.” It’s agile, it’s exciting, and in fast-moving teams, it often feels like the only way to keep pace. But when enterprise applications meet compliance-heavy environments, this seat-of-the-pants coding […] The article Hidden Security Risks of “Vibe Coding” for Enterprise AI Projects was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: From JavaScript to Cloud Privacy Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Brendan Eich may be best known as the creator of JavaScript, but his influence extends well beyond programming languages into the very core of internet privacy and emerging cloud ecosystems. Today, as CEO of Brave Software, Eich is a key figure pushing for decentralized, privacy-first approaches to cloud services and digital advertising. His vision challenges […] The article Big Thinkers: From JavaScript to Cloud Privacy Pioneer was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
