<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:05:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Azure Resource and Service Limits and Quotas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Azure imposes limits and quotas on how many resources of each type you can provision per Azure Subscription, and even per Azure Region. Some limits are a hard maximum, while others are a soft limit that can be increases upon request. When working with Virtual Machines (VMs), Storage Accounts, Databases, and other resources in […] The article Microsoft Azure Resource and Service Limits and Quotas was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Data Studio Retires February 28, 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced the official retirement of Azure Data Studio on February 28, 2026. This decision marks a significant shift in Microsoft’s approach to database development tools, as users are encouraged to transition to Visual Studio Code (VS Code) with the appropriate extensions for database management and SQL development. What is Azure Data Studio? Azure […] The article Azure Data Studio Retires February 28, 2026 was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IP Subnet Calculator and Reference (Cloud, Azure, Private, IPv4 CIDR, and more)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 21:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a network engineer, administrator, or Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) you probably have run across CIDR notation for defining IPv4 address spaces for both networks and subnets. CIDR notation is used a lot in the IT infrastructure configuration world. The following is a description of what CIDR notation is, in case you’re not that familiar, […] The article IP Subnet Calculator and Reference (Cloud, Azure, Private, IPv4 CIDR, and more) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Says “Ditch Passwords &amp; Keys”, Use Entra ID Authentication Instead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The era of passwords is coming to an end. In December 2024, Microsoft stated they are blocking 7,000 attacks on passwords per second. A number almost double what they saw just one year prior. As a result, Microsoft is advocating enterprises to move away from traditional authentication methods, such as passwords and API keys. These […] The article Microsoft Says “Ditch Passwords &amp;amp; Keys”, Use Entra ID Authentication Instead was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Azure Architecture Diagrams with Microsoft Visio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Azure offers a broad range of cloud services, and as enterprise deployments grow in complexity, having a clear visual representation can become crucial. Microsoft Visio is an excellent tool for modeling and documenting your Azure infrastructure. This article explores the tools available for you to create Azure architecture diagrams using Microsoft Visio—using built-in templates, […] The article Create Azure Architecture Diagrams with Microsoft Visio was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
