<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build5nines.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 18:11:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/build5nines.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the CrowdStrike Bug, Impact on Microsoft Azure, and Global Windows Outage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 18:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2024/19_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On July 18, 2024, CrowdStrike released a update with a bug that significantly impacted Windows machines globally, including virtual machines (VMs) running on multiple cloud platforms, such as Microsoft Azure, AWS, and Google Cloud. The problem originated from an update to the CrowdStrike Falcon agent, which led to unresponsiveness, blue screens (BSOD) and startup failures […] The article Understanding the CrowdStrike Bug, Impact on Microsoft Azure, and Global Windows Outage was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Azure Private Link and How to Deploy with Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 20:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Private Link offers several benefits, including enhanced security, simplified network architecture, and improved performance. It supports various Azure services like Azure Storage and Azure SQL Database, allowing organizations to maintain the privacy and integrity of their data. Moreover, Azure Private Link seamlessly integrates with Azure Virtual Networks (VNets), on-premises networks and supports global connectivity, […] The article What is Azure Private Link and How to Deploy with Terraform was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose Between Azure Cosmos DB for Table and Azure Table Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 22:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Choosing the right database solution is critical for the performance and scalability of your applications. When working with NoSQL, Table data and Microsoft Azure, two prominent options for table storage are Azure Cosmos DB for Table and Azure Table Storage (aka Azure Storage Tables). Both services provide robust solutions for storing semi-structured table data, but […] The article How to Choose Between Azure Cosmos DB for Table and Azure Table Storage was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
