<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:07:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently build and tune custom log anomaly detection models with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through the process to build an automated mechanism using Amazon SageMaker to process your log data, run training iterations over it to obtain the best-performing anomaly detection model, and register it with the Amazon SageMaker Model Registry for your customers to use it.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/efficiently-build-and-tune-custom-log-anomaly-detection-models-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing personal access token (PAT) usage across Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the new year, we’ll be making moves towards strengthening Microsoft and our customers’ security posture in regards to the usage and creation of personal access tokens (PATs). If you’ve been following this blog, you may have noticed we’ve been distancing away from PATs as the recommended authentication method for Azure DevOps APIs by offering […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/reducing-pat-usage-across-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (December 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 18:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.12.16 registry release, 2024-12-09 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout December. This release includes a command line option to force vcpkg to use classic mode even if a manifest file is found along with bug fixes. Some […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-december-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) continues to permeate our daily lives, but the way we interact with these systems remains an evolving landscape. In a recent episode of the Hanselminutes podcast, host Scott Hanselman sat down with designer and technologist Maggie Appleton to explore a fascinating question: What is AI’s UI (User Interface)? Their conversation sheds light […] The article What is AI’s UI? Key Takeaways from Maggie Appleton’s Interview on Hanselminutes was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack Roadmap for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A belated Happy New Year’s to everybody! The “Critter Stack” had a huge 2024, and I listed off some of the highlights of the improvements we made in Critter Stack Year in Review for 2024. For 2025, we’ve reordered our priority order from what I was writing last summer. I think we might genuinely focus more … Continue reading Critter Stack Roadmap for 2025 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/01/06/critter-stack-roadmap-for-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I tell whether a change to a control was due to the user or due to my program?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You know when it was done by your program because you did it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250106-00/?p=110715 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking insights with Meter Histogram in the profiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you struggling with performance bottlenecks in your applications? Look no further! Visual Studio 2022 introduces the Meter Histogram feature in its performance profiling suite, providing you with the tools to analyze and visualize histogram data like never before. The Meter Histogram is a key enhancement to Visual Studio’s performance profiling suite. This feature enables […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/unlocking-insights-with-meter-histogram-in-the-profiler 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring CollectionsMarshal for Dictionary</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unlike ConcurrentDictionary, Dictionary does not have a GetOrAdd method. This method is useful when you want to add a key-value pair to the dictionary if the key does not exist, or return the value if the key already exists. The naive implementation of this method looks like this: public static TValue GetOrAdd&amp;lt;TKey, TValue&amp;gt;(this Dictionary&amp;lt;TKey, TValue&amp;gt; dict, TKey key, TValue value) where TKey : notnull {…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/exploring-collectionsmarshal-for-dictionary.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Parallel Processing of Collections in Microsoft .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses the performance of various parallelism techniques for iterating over collections in .NET, comparing parallel methods such as Parallel.For and AsParallel() with traditional approaches. It highlights that while parallel methods can enhance performance for large collections, traditional methods often outperform them, particularly with smaller collections. Recommendations and a new method, FastModifyCollection, are introduced for efficient processing.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/01/06/evaluating-the-parallel-processing-of-collections-in-microsoft-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persist Values With AsyncLocal in C# Async Flow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_01_2025/06_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explain the AsyncLocal class and how to persist values across an async flow with the AsyncLocal class in C#. We’ll start by describing the challenge that AsyncLocal solves and continue with examples of how it does that. We’ll scratch the surface of the AsyncLocal inner workings and finish with the cases […] The post Persist Values With AsyncLocal in C# Async Flow appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JasperFx Software in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2025/05_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 18:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2025/05_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can contact JasperFx at any time by dropping us an email at sales@jasperfx.net. 2024 was a good year for JasperFx Software LLC for the simple fact that we’ve proven to have an effective business model and some staying power for the future. Along the way, we partnered with clients in eight different countries on … Continue reading JasperFx Software in 2025 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/01/05/jasperfx-software-in-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important: Switching CDN providers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2025/05_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_01_2025/05_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The current content delivery network (CDN) provider Edgio, used by Azure DevOps is retiring. We’re urgently transitioning to a solution served by Akamai and Azure Front Door CDNs to maintain the responsiveness of our services. What this means for you For most of you, this transition will be seamless. To ensure that you can continue […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/important-switching-cdn-providers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling Azure OpenAI models from C# with Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2025/04_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2025/04_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI opens up a lot of exciting possibilities for developers to use its capabilities within their own applications, but it can feel a bit overwhelming getting started. You have a lot of choices around which models to use and how best to interact with them. In this post I want to go through the steps to implement a basic chat with an LLM hosted in Azure using C#, by taking advantage of the new Microsoft.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing Clean Architecture Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2025/04_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_01_2025/04_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Drawing from years of experience, I share my battle-tested approach to unit testing Clean Architecture use cases in .NET, focusing on the critical balance between code coverage and test quality. Through practical examples and real-world scenarios, I&#39;ll demonstrate how to write effective tests that not only catch bugs but also provide confidence in your code deployments.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/unit-testing-clean-architecture-use-cases 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing an ERROR_KEY_DELETED error when trying to open HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just an exercise to show that it can be done, even though it&#39;s highly unlikely to occur in practice.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250103-00/?p=110704 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Peak Software Development Efficiency with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get the key to mastering software development efficiency for your team with Docker.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mastering-software-development-efficiency/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana 2024.3 Is Here Along With a Special Offer for New Users!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Happy New Year! In case you missed it, the Qodana team ended 2024 with a bang and released Qodana 2024.3. What’s in the latest release? New security functionality, a fresh set of Android linter rules, and more to help your team prioritize code excellence. Let’s take a look at what’s available in more detail. To […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/01/qodana-2024-3-is-here-along-with-a-special-offer-for-new-users/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated System Requirements for  Linux GNU C Library (glibc)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with v2025.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will require glibc 2.28 or higher on Linux x64 systems. This change is being made to address potential security vulnerabilities associated with building and running our software on outdated systems and to ensure our products evolve with modern frameworks and technologies. By enforcing a more recent glibc version, we aim to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/updated-system-requirements-for-linux-gnu-c-library-glibc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>探索Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData与Qdrant和Azure AI搜索的使用</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 05:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_01_2025/03_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Bruno Capuano的Exploring Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData with Qdrant and Azure AI Search 了解如何使用 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData并通过 Qdrant 和 Azure AI 搜索实现语义搜索。 使用 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData 深入了解语义搜索：Qdrant 和 Azure AI 搜索 语义搜索正在改变应用程序查找和解释数据的方式，它专注于含义，而不仅仅是关键字匹配。随着 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData 的发布，.NET 开发人员拥有了一组新的构建模块，用于将基于向量的搜索功能集成到其应用程序中。在本文中，我们将探讨使用本地Qdrant和Azure AI搜索这两种实现方式来进行语义搜索。 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData 快速介绍 Microsoft.Extensions.VectorData 是一组 .NET代码库，旨在管理 .NET 应用程序中基于向量的数据。这些库为与向量存储交互提供了一个统一的 C# 抽象层，使开发人员能够有效地处理嵌入并执行向量相似性查询。 要详细了解该库的架构和功能，推荐阅读 Luis 的精彩博客文章。 在这篇博客文章中，我们将展示两个实际用例： 在本地使用 Qdrant 进行语义搜索。 利用 Azure AI 搜索进行企业级向量搜索。 要运行这些演示，您需要使用 Ollama 为生成嵌入提供的模型之一。在本示例中，使用的模型是 all-minilm。 安装 Ollama。 下载 all-minilm 模型。 准备一个符合 OCI 标准的容器运行时，例如： Docker Desktop 或 Podman。 使用 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e6%8e%a2%e7%b4%a2microsoft-extensions-vectordata%e4%b8%8eqdrant%e5%92%8cazure-ai%e6%90%9c%e7%b4%a2%e7%9a%84%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Slice Architecture isn’t technical</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Migrate to a Vertical Slice Architecture from a monolith? Is it more like microservices? Does it replace Clean Architecture? None of the above. It’s about being driven by cohesion of business capabilities and business processes. It has nothing to do with layers or physical deployment concerns. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds… Read More »Vertical Slice Architecture isn’t technical The post Vertical Slice Architecture isn’t technical appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could I be getting ERROR_KEY_DELETED for HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software when the user logs off?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Probably not, but there are some edge cases.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250102-00/?p=110702 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Secure Development Environments Are Essential for Modern Software Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure development environments are the backbone of modern software teams, ensuring speed and innovation don’t come at the cost of vulnerabilities, inefficiencies, or eroded trust.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-secure-development-environments-are-essential-for-modern-software-teams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Ready</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_01_2025/02_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Release Candidate for MPS 2024.3 is now available for download! Grab it and be among the first to experience the new functionality. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 RC You can learn about the new features in more detail in this blog post. The full list of fixed issues can be found here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/01/the-mps-2024-3-rc-ready/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is it possible to get ERROR_KEY_DELETED when I’m creating a key?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2025/01_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_01_2025/01_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The key that got deleted is not the one you are trying to create.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250101-00/?p=110700 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 year-end link clearance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2024/31_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2024/31_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The cycle completes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241231-01/?p=110698 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sure the Microsoft Visual C&#43;&#43; compiler chooses the right source encoding</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2024/31_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2024/31_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Making sure the file and settings are set correctly.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241231-00/?p=110696 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dock the Code Search window in Visual Studio 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2024/31_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_12_2024/31_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever felt frustrated with the search window cluttering your workspace? The latest feature in Visual Studio 2022 gives you more control over the behavior of the Code and Feature Search window, making your search experience smoother and more efficient. Some users have shared that the search window feels intrusive, interrupting your work by appearing mid-screen […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/dock-the-code-search-window-in-visual-studio-2022 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top .NET Videos &amp; Live Streams of 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s take a look back at the amazing .NET videos, events, and live streams from 2024!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/top-dotnet-videos-live-streams-of-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How various git diff viewers represent file encoding changes in pull requests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The invisible UTF-8 BOM, and sometimes invisible encoding changes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241230-00/?p=110692 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go to line anywhere with Code Search for Visual Studio 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Finding the exact line of code where an issue is occurring can be like searching for a needle in a haystack. Whether you are debugging an error on line 43 of a file or diving into a specific section of code, you can efficiently jump to the right places with this newest addition to Code […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/go-to-line-anywhere-with-code-search-for-visual-studio-2022 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signing commits in Git using SSH keys on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Signing commits in Git is a way to verify the authenticity and integrity of your commits. This ensures that the commits are indeed made by you and have not been tampered with. On Windows, it&#39;s easy to set up SSH-Agent for easy signature. Here&#39;s how you can do it. First, you need to install SSH on Windows. Open a PowerShell window as an administrator and run the following command to install the OpenSSH…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Coding - What is it good for?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_12_2024/30_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you&#39;re like me, 2024 was the year in which using LLM for code generation went from a curiosity that I occasionally tried out when all other avenues failed, to something that has become an essential part of day-to-day development work. Availability and pricing When the year began the availability of these tools was mostly limited to paying customers, but with the majority of LLMs now offering completely free tiers that are perfectly capable of generating code, and now tools like GitHub Copilot (also now offering a free tier) that integrate directly with your IDE, it seems inevitable that in 2025 it will become an integral part of the way most developers write code.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
