<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 21:31:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IP Subnet Calculator and Reference (Cloud, Azure, Private, IPv4 CIDR, and more)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 21:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a network engineer, administrator, or Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) you probably have run across CIDR notation for defining IPv4 address spaces for both networks and subnets. CIDR notation is used a lot in the IT infrastructure configuration world. The following is a description of what CIDR notation is, in case you’re not that familiar, […] The article IP Subnet Calculator and Reference (Cloud, Azure, Private, IPv4 CIDR, and more) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Performance Gains in .NET: The Power of Custom Comparers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_03_2025/02_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article highlights the importance of custom comparers in .NET for enhancing application performance when sorting and ordering collections. It discusses the flexibility and control that custom comparers offer over default comparers and provides examples of creating them. Benchmarks also illustrate the performance benefits, while cautioning that custom comparers may introduce overhead in certain scenarios.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/03/02/unlock-performance-gains-in-net-the-power-of-custom-comparers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senior Developer Means Coding... Less?! - Dev Leader Weekly 85</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss what might be a bit uncomfortable... but do senior engineers actually code less?!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/01/senior-developer-means-coding-less-dev-leader-weekly-85 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-02-28</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 07:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/03/01/weekly-recap-20250228 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Dapr for .NET Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_03_2025/01_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how Dapr helps .NET developers build better microservices with standardized building blocks, practical code examples, and seamless integration with .NET Aspire to simplify your distributed systems journey.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/introduction-to-dapr-for-dotnet-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps Basic usage included with GitHub Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 23:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many customers want to use both GitHub and Azure DevOps together. Until now, unless you purchased Visual Studio subscriptions with GitHub Enterprise, you had to pay separately for both products. With the Sprint 252 release, Azure DevOps Basic usage rights are included with GitHub Enterprise Cloud. Your users access this benefit automatically when they login […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-basic-usage-included-with-github-enterprise 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing AI Shell Preview 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 20:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to share a new preview release of AI Shell!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/ai-shell-preview-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – February Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 20:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Here’s a roundup of all the good stuff from February – AI skills to develop, scholarship opportunities, the latest programming and AI trends, and, as a little extra treat, a discount on a Hyperskill Premium subscription!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/02/28/jetbrains-academy-december-february/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to announce the release of TypeScript 5.8! If you’re not familiar with TypeScript, it’s a language that builds on top of JavaScript by adding syntax for types. Writing types in our code allows us to explain intent and have other tools check our code to catch mistakes like typos, issues with null […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release the Agents! SK Agents Framework RC1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Semantic Kernel Agent Framework Reaches Release Candidate 1 We’re excited to announce that with the release of Semantic Kernel 1.40 (.NET) and 1.22.0 (Python), we’re elevating the Semantic Kernel Agent Framework to Release Candidate 1. This marks a significant milestone in our journey toward providing a robust, versatile framework for building AI agents for enterprise […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/release-the-agents-sk-agents-framework-rc1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline work insights with the Amazon Q Business connector for Smartsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explains how to integrate Smartsheet with Amazon Q Business to use natural language and generative AI capabilities for enhanced insights. Smartsheet, the AI-enhanced enterprise-grade work management platform, helps users manage projects, programs, and processes at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-work-insights-with-the-amazon-q-business-connector-for-smartsheet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: UI Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog post, we created a basic integration test that: Now, let’s explore how to interact with UI elements in our tests. UI hierarchy IntelliJ-based IDEs primarily use Swing and AWT for their user interface, while JCEF is used in specific cases like Markdown rendering. This UI framework organizes elements in a parent-child […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/02/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-ui-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level up your problem-solving and strategic thinking skills with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet in Amazon Bedrock can be used for a variety of business-related cognitive tasks, such as problem-solving, critical thinking and ideation—to help augment human thinking and improve decision-making among knowledge workers to accelerate innovation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/level-up-your-problem-solving-and-strategic-thinking-skills-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing AI implementation costs with Automat-it</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this guest post, we explain how AWS Partner Automat-it helped their customer achieve a more than twelvefold cost savings while keeping AI model performance within the required performance thresholds. This was accomplished through careful tuning of architecture, algorithm selection, and infrastructure management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-ai-implementation-costs-with-automat-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of an era: the final AWS DeepRacer League Championship at re:Invent 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS DeepRacer League is the world&#39;s first global autonomous racing league powered by machine learning (ML). Over the past 6 years, a diverse community of over 560,000 builders from more than 150 countries worldwide have participated in the League to learn ML fundamentals hands-on through the fun of friendly autonomous racing. After an 8-month season of nail-biting virtual qualifiers, finalists convened in person at re:Invent in Las Vegas for one final showdown to compete for prizes and glory in the high-stakes, winner-take-all AWS DeepRacer League Championship.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Copilot Studio agents with Microsoft Entra External ID to give your customers access</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 17:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to integrate Copilot Studio agents with Microsoft Entra External ID using the Generic OAUTH 2.0 service provider option, ensuring your customers can securely log in to your agents.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/integrate-copilot-studio-agents-with-microsoft-entra-external-id-to-give-your-customers-access 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Engine v28: Hardening Container Networking by Default</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 17:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker streamlines developer onboarding and helps organizations set up the right guardrails to give developers the flexibility to innovate within the boundaries of company policies.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-engine-28-hardening-container-networking-by-default/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;/WinRT implementation inheritance: Notes on winrt::implements, part 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Comparing the options.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250228-00/?p=110916 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for Google Summer of Code 2025 and Contribute to the Kotlin Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 13:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin Foundation is once again participating in Google Summer of Code (GSoC), offering contributors an opportunity to work on open-source projects that shape the Kotlin ecosystem. This year, the program is expanding to include even more projects from Kotlin Foundation member companies like JetBrains, Google, Uber, and Gradle, providing contributors with mentorship from some […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/02/google-summer-of-code-2025-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Set of Bug-Fix Updates for ReSharper and Rider 2024.3 Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 10:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download. ReSharper 2024.3.6 This build contains a fix for an issue where xUnit v3 tests resulted in Inconclusive: Test has not run when executed in under .NET Framework. [RSRP-499789] Rider 2024.3.6 Notable fixes For the full list of changes, please see our issue tracker.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/28/resharper-rider-2024-3-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.4 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 07:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released another update for v2024.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This version brings the following refinements: To see the full list of issues addressed in this version, please […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2024-3-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>使用Chroma构建.NET AI应用</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 05:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自 Luis 和 Jiri 的 Building .NET AI apps with Chroma 无论您是构建 AI 解决方案还是想使用高级搜索功能增强现有项目，您现在都可以使用 Chroma 作为 .NET 应用程序中的数据库提供程序。 什么是Chroma？ Chroma 是一款适用于人工智能应用程序的开源数据库。 借助对存储嵌入、元数据过滤、向量搜索、全文搜索、文档存储和多模式检索的支持，您可以使用 Chroma 在应用程序中支持语义搜索和检索增强生成（RAG）功能。 有关更多详情，请访问 Chroma 网站。 在 C# 应用程序中使用Chroma 在本示例中，我们将使用 ChromaDB.Client 来连接到 Chroma 数据库并使用向量搜索来搜索电影。 最简单的开始方式是在本地使用 Chroma Docker 映像。您也可以在 Azure 中部署实例。 连接数据库 创建 C# 控制台应用程序 安装 ChromaDB.Client Nuget 包 创建带有配置选项的 ChromaClient using ChromaDB.Client; var configOptions = new ChromaConfigurationOptions(uri: […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8chroma%e6%9e%84%e5%bb%ba-net-ai%e5%ba%94%e7%94%a8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jakarta EE and MicroProfile on Azure – February 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 03:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the February 2025 update for Jakarta EE and MicroProfile on Azure. It covers topics such as the latest updates to Azure extensions for Quarkus, and the recent refresh to Jakarta EE Solutions for supporting multiple deployments within the same resource group. If you’re interested in providing feedback or collaborating on migrating […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/jakarta-ee-on-azure-february-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Don’t Need No Stinkin’ Repositories and Other Observations on DotNetRocks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 02:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I had a conversation with the DotNetRocks fellows a little while back that posted today, ostensibly about the “Vertical Slice Architecture” approach. We hit several topics along the way mostly related on my — and the Critter Stack’s — philosophy of low code ceremony and reduced layering as the preferred way to succeed in longer … Continue reading We Don’t Need No Stinkin’ Repositories and Other Observations on DotNetRocks →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Update changes for PowerShell 7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 22:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog outlines the expected behavior of MU releases for PowerShell 7.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/microsoft-update-changes-for-powershell-7 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port .NET Framework workloads to Linux with Amazon Q Developer, Part 2: Test Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 21:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This blog series explores how to port different kinds of .NET Framework projects to cross-platform .NET with Amazon Q Developer .NET transformation, currently in public preview. Modernizing a Windows-based .NET Framework solution to run on Linux can reduce operational costs by up to 40%. Part 1 covered porting of class library projects. Here in […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/port-net-framework-workloads-to-linux-with-amazon-q-developer-part-2-test-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 7: Maven 4 Support And Improved Support For Multi-Release JARs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 21:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 is here! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 7 The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Early Access Program is nearing its end, but there’s still time to explore […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerful Devs Hack Together 2025 Wrap Up</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 19:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re almost at the finish line! Our Powerful Devs Hack Together is coming to a close and we encourage you to continue with your AI journey.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/powerful-devs-hack-together-2025-wrap-up 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate healthcare generative AI applications using LLM-as-a-judge on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 17:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to implement this evaluation framework using Amazon Bedrock, compare the performance of different generator models, including Anthropic’s Claude and Amazon Nova on Amazon Bedrock, and showcase how to use the new RAG evaluation feature to optimize knowledge base parameters and assess retrieval quality.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-healthcare-generative-ai-applications-using-llm-as-a-judge-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS DeepRacer: Closing time at AWS re:Invent 2024 –How did that physical racing go?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 17:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In AWS DeepRacer: How to master physical racing?, I wrote in detail about some aspects relevant to racing AWS DeepRacer in the physical world. The previous post was left open-ended—with one last Championship Final left, it was too early to share all my secrets. Now that AWS re:Invent is over, it’s time to share my strategy, how I prepared, and how it went in the end.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-deepracer-closing-time-at-aws-reinvent-2024-how-did-that-physical-racing-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch issues before you commit to Git</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 17:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discovering issues with code changes after committing changes can be frustrating. Fortunately, Visual Studio offers a new feature that helps you catch potential problems early, improving your code quality. Visual Studio now includes a feature powered by GitHub Copilot that lets you review your local code changes before committing them, before they are part of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/catch-issues-before-you-commit-to-git 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;/WinRT implementation inheritance: Notes on winrt::implements, part 7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Inheritance without involving winrt::implements at all.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250227-00/?p=110913 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Says “Ditch Passwords &amp; Keys”, Use Entra ID Authentication Instead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The era of passwords is coming to an end. In December 2024, Microsoft stated they are blocking 7,000 attacks on passwords per second. A number almost double what they saw just one year prior. As a result, Microsoft is advocating enterprises to move away from traditional authentication methods, such as passwords and API keys. These […] The article Microsoft Says “Ditch Passwords &amp;amp; Keys”, Use Entra ID Authentication Instead was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD and Serverless Computing: Best Practices for Microservices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 13:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Mdu Sibisi, freelance writer, draft.dev. Cloud technology has reshaped how developers manage and deliver software. For example, “serverless computing” allows a provider to dynamically manage the allocation and provisioning of servers for you, which makes it ideal for running microservices. When paired with CI/CD practices, serverless computing can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/ci-cd-and-serverless-computing-best-practices-for-microservices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.25, now available, with automatic shut down and simplified configuration management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 09:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read more about the latest Dev Proxy release featuring significant improvements to configuration management, plugin support, and usability.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-25-now-available-with-automatic-shut-down-and-simplified-configuration-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Provider Strategy for App Configuration in Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses a strategy for creating a custom extensible configuration module in python projects.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/multi-provider-strategy-configuration-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Powershell7 with Managed Runcommand</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 21:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, all scripts run through Managed RunCommand will by default use Powershell 5. What if you have a script that requires Powershell7? This is supported via a new feature, but you will need to specify the different script shell. Here’s what you need to do. Ensure your VM has Powershell7 Powershell7 is not installed by […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/using-powershell7-with-managed-runcommand 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (February 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 19:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure SDK releases every month. In this post, you find this month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-february-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal Chat now included in GitHub Copilot Free</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 17:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows Terminal Canary users can now use Terminal Chat with the GitHub Copilot Free plan! 🚀 GitHub Copilot Free is limited to 50 chat messages per month. This includes the usage of Copilot in the CLI, VS Code, and Visual Studio. If you reach your quota, you can upgrade on the web. You can sign […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/terminal-chat-now-included-in-github-copilot-free 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Pattern PXM’s Content Brief is driving conversion on ecommerce marketplaces using AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 17:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pattern is a leader in ecommerce acceleration, helping brands navigate the complexities of selling on marketplaces and achieve profitable growth through a combination of proprietary technology and on-demand expertise. In this post, we share how Pattern uses AWS services to process trillions of data points to deliver actionable insights, optimizing product listings across multiple services.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-pattern-pxms-content-brief-is-driving-conversion-on-ecommerce-marketplaces-using-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to configure cross-account model deployment using Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 17:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this guide, we walk you through step-by-step instructions for configuring cross-account access for Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import, covering both non-encrypted and AWS Key Management Service (AWS KMS) based encrypted scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-to-configure-cross-account-model-deployment-using-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ByteDance processes billions of daily videos using their multimodal video understanding models on AWS Inferentia2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 17:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At ByteDance, we collaborated with Amazon Web Services (AWS) to deploy multimodal large language models (LLMs) for video understanding using AWS Inferentia2 across multiple AWS Regions around the world. By using sophisticated ML algorithms, the platform efficiently scans billions of videos each day. In this post, we discuss the use of multimodal LLMs for video understanding, the solution architecture, and techniques for performance optimization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bytedance-processes-billions-of-daily-videos-using-their-multimodal-video-understanding-models-on-aws-inferentia2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciting new T-SQL features: Regex support, Fuzzy string-matching, and bigint support in DATEADD – preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 16:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the public preview of three powerful T-SQL features that will elevate your SQL queries: Regular Expressions (Regex) support, Fuzzy string-matching, and bigint support in DATEADD. These enhancements are now available in Azure SQL Database and SQL Database in Microsoft Fabric, offering developers more flexibility, efficiency, and precision in their data […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/exciting-new-t-sql-features-regex-support-fuzzy-string-matching-and-bigint-support-in-dateadd-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;/WinRT implementation inheritance: Notes on winrt::implements, part 6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using CRTP to delegate the method.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250226-00/?p=110908 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Better Developer Experience: A Collaboration Between Gradle, Google, and JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The original blog post was published here. Developers are at the heart of everything we do. You are the ones who create all of those new things to make the world better. To do that effectively, you need tools to rely on that are powerful yet easy to use. That’s why Kotlin was created. But […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/building-a-better-developer-experience-a-collaboration-between-gradle-google-and-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Public Preview of the Azure Cosmos DB SDK for Rust!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 13:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the public preview of the Azure Cosmos DB SDK for Rust, a native Rust SDK that enables developers to interact with Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL accounts from their Rust applications. Following the release of Azure SDK for Rust Beta, the Azure Cosmos DB Rust SDK provides an idiomatic API for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-the-public-preview-of-the-azure-cosmos-db-sdk-for-rust 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Application Performance in .NET Using IMeterFactory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 08:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Performance monitoring is essential for ensuring that our applications run efficiently and reliably. .NET offers a set of tools to help with this, accessible via IMeterFactory. In this article, we’ll learn how to use these tools to check the health of our applications, measure performance, and collect data for optimization. So let’s get going. What […] The post Measure Application Performance in .NET Using IMeterFactory appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Optimizing JSON Serialization with Cached Options</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            XML has been replaced by JSON as the primary serialization format. Using the JsonSerializer in .NET offers performance advantages, particularly when caching JsonSerializerOptions. This method enhances speed (1.34x faster) and reduces memory usage. Additionally, adhering to best practices avoids CA1869 rule violations. Consider optimizing your serialization approach for better performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/02/26/microsoft-net-code-analysis-optimizing-json-serialization-with-cached-options/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Year In Review</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_02_2025/26_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Better late than never, as I&#39;m writing this in late February 2025... First, here&#39;s a few links to past years in review: My 2017 Year in…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/2024-year-in-review/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Systems Consistency: Mistake Nobody Warns You About!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 20:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most common and very overlooked issues when writing a distributed system is consistency. You have one thing happening in one part of your system that triggers something else to happen in another part of the system, except it doesn’t happen, and that can be a nightmare to deal with. This is incredibly… Read More »Distributed Systems Consistency: Mistake Nobody Warns You About! The post Distributed Systems Consistency: Mistake Nobody Warns You About!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out about the new features in .NET 10 Preview 1 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, C#, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire 9.1 is here with six great new dashboard features, and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Aspire 9.1 is here! From enhanced dashboard capabilities like Resource Relationships and Localization Overrides to improved Docker integration and flexible console logs, this release is packed with tools to streamline your development process.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-aspire-9-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How IDIADA optimized its intelligent chatbot with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 2021, Applus+ IDIADA, a global partner to the automotive industry with over 30 years of experience supporting customers in product development activities through design, engineering, testing, and homologation services, established the Digital Solutions department. In this post, we showcase the research process undertaken to develop a classifier for human interactions in this AI-based environment using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-idiada-optimized-its-intelligent-chatbot-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate IaC troubleshooting with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how Amazon Bedrock Agents, combined with action groups and generative AI models, streamlines and accelerates the resolution of Terraform errors while maintaining compliance with environment security and operational guidelines.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-iac-troubleshooting-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derive generative AI powered insights from Alation Cloud Services using Amazon Q Business Custom Connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showcase a sample of how Alation’s business policies can be integrated with an Amazon Q Business application using a custom data source connector.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/derive-generative-ai-powered-insights-from-alation-cloud-services-using-amazon-q-business-custom-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI innovation starts here—join Microsoft at NVIDIA GTC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The NVIDIA GTC AI Conference is the place to be to discover the latest AI technology and solutions. The post AI innovation starts here—join Microsoft at NVIDIA GTC appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/ai-innovation-starts-here-join-microsoft-at-nvidia-gtc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating data from DynamoDB to Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 15:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Co-authors: RK Iyer, Mangal Dutta Migrating stateful systems, such as databases, is a complex process. A frequent requirement for customers is to transfer data from DynamoDB to Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL. This process involves several stages, including exporting data from DynamoDB, performing necessary transformations, and importing the data into Azure Cosmos DB. Common migration […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/migrating-data-from-dynamodb-to-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;/WinRT implementation inheritance: Notes on winrt::implements, part 5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When the base class isn&#39;t self-contained.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250225-00/?p=110905 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Azure Architecture Diagrams with Microsoft Visio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Azure offers a broad range of cloud services, and as enterprise deployments grow in complexity, having a clear visual representation can become crucial. Microsoft Visio is an excellent tool for modeling and documenting your Azure infrastructure. This article explores the tools available for you to create Azure architecture diagrams using Microsoft Visio—using built-in templates, […] The article Create Azure Architecture Diagrams with Microsoft Visio was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 24: Build Games, Prototypes, Utilities, and More—With Less Boilerplate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At ten, I sat in my school’s computer lab, in awe of a line drawing on the screen—my own code had brought it to life. “Yay! I coded that! I can code anything!”, I thought. My teacher, surprised, asked, “Wow! You did that?” It felt like magic, but it was more than that—I realized I […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/java-24-build-games-prototypes-utilities-and-more-with-less-boilerplate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines: SSH Authentication Option, Custom Git URL Support, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 11:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve been busy improving TeamCity Pipelines to make your CI/CD workflows even smoother. Here’s a quick update on what’s new! SSH authentication option Exciting news – we’re expanding the list of authentication options in TeamCity Pipelines! Now, you can easily authenticate using SSH. Once you set up SSH keys, you can push and pull without […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/teamcity-pipelines-ssh-authentication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling localized satellite assemblies during dotnet publish</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to reduce the size of the publish output for .NET apps by preventing the publishing of localization resources when they&#39;re not needed
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/disabling-localized-satellite-assemblies-during-dotnet-publish/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Complex Query Scenarios with Entity Framework Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 08:51:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The database is an integral part of every application. However, it contributes most to the performance of any application due to its presence in almost every operation. In the .NET world, Entity Framework Core (EFCore) is one of the developer&#39;s favorite Object-Relational Mapping (ORM). It has simple syntax,
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/handling-complex-query-scenarios-with-entity-framework-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claude 3.7 Now Available in GitHub Copilot for Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 01:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_02_2025/25_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The world of AI is evolving at a breathtaking pace, and today brings an exciting milestone for developers and tech enthusiasts alike. Anthropic’s newest release, Claude 3.7, is now available directly within GitHub Copilot for Visual Studio 2022 17.13, heralding a new era of seamlessly integrated, advanced AI coding assistance. This new Sonnet model supports […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/claude-3-7-now-available-in-github-copilot-for-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compatibility of PostgreSQL Connector with AWS and GCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 22:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI-driven applications continue to evolve, the need for efficient vector-based search capabilities is greater than ever. Microsoft Semantic Kernel makes it easy to integrate these capabilities with PostgreSQL databases using the Postgres connector. Whether you’re leveraging cloud-hosted PostgreSQL instances on Amazon Web Services or Google Cloud, this connector enables seamless interaction, allowing you to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/compatibility-of-postgresql-connector-with-aws-and-gcp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistral-Small-24B-Instruct-2501 is now available on SageMaker Jumpstart and Amazon Bedrock Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 21:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that Mistral-Small-24B-Instruct-2501—a twenty-four billion parameter large language model (LLM) from Mistral AI that’s optimized for low latency text generation tasks—is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart and Amazon Bedrock Marketplace. In this post, we walk through how to discover, deploy, and use Mistral-Small-24B-Instruct-2501.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mistral-small-24b-instruct-2501-is-now-available-on-sagemaker-jumpstart-and-amazon-bedrock-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Learn .NET: GitHub Copilot Event</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for an exciting Let&#39;s Learn .NET live stream event where we will explore GitHub Copilot and its capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/lets-learn-dotnet-github-copilot-event 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Azure Cosmos DB Design Patterns Video Series – Learn, Implement, and Contribute!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 19:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce the Azure Cosmos DB Design Patterns video series—your go-to resource for learning how to design scalable, efficient, and cost-effective applications with Azure Cosmos DB. Built on real-world use cases, each episode explores a proven design pattern, walking through how it works, when to use it, and how to implement it using […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/new-azure-cosmos-db-design-patterns-video-series-learn-implement-and-contribute 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement Role-based Access Control for .NET applications with Amazon Cognito</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 18:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ulili Nhaga contributed to this article. When building applications, ensuring proper security and access control is crucial. One way to achieve this is by implementing a Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) authorization system. This blog post will discuss implementing RBAC for .NET applications using Amazon Cognito with OpenID Connect (OIDC). We will guide you on how […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/implement-role-based-access-control-for-net-applications-with-amazon-cognito/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 EAP 5: Roslyn Syntax Tree Visualizer, Unity Profiler Integration, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 17:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Rider 2025.1 EAP 5 has just been released! You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Here’s what you can expect from this update: Roslyn support enhancements Roslyn syntax tree visualizer Working with Roslyn […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/02/24/rider-2025-1-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leverage vision in Copilot Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 17:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Now, in the preview channel, you can attach images in GitHub Copilot chat to help you illustrate your ideas effectively and get the best responses. Imagine working on a UI development task where describing a design or layout through text just doesn’t cut it. Or perhaps you’re debugging an issue and need to share a […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/attach-images-in-github-copilot-chat 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>std::generator: Standard Library Coroutine Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 17:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            std::generator is a C++23 feature that enables you to write concise, straightforward functions that generate sequences of values on-demand without manually managing state. It builds upon C++20’s coroutines, providing some standard library support for this powerful, but complex, language feature. As of Visual Studio 2022 version 17.13, we ship an implementation of std::generator in our […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/std-generator-standard-library-coroutine-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Model Orchestration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 17:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hybrid model orchestration is a powerful technique that AI applications can use to intelligently select and switch between multiple models based on various criteria, all while being transparent to the calling code. This technique not only allows for model selection based on factors such as the prompt’s input token size and each model’s min/max token […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/hybrid-model-orchestration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;/WinRT implementation inheritance: Notes on winrt::implements, part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Simple inheritance of a self-contained implements.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250224-00/?p=110901 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science and AI BSc Open Day in Cyprus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 13:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos is opening its doors! Join us for our Open Day, where you will have the opportunity to meet the program’s professors and students and visit the campus. The JetBrains Foundation supports this bachelor’s program and offers 15 fully funded scholarships for the most […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/02/24/computer-science-and-ai-bsc-open-day-in-cyprus/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Performance Logging in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 09:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how to optimize .NET logging performance using string interpolation, structured logging, and high-performance extensions. Learn implementation strategies and best practices for production systems.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/high-performance-logging-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 6: Interactive Scratch Files in K2 Mode, Enhanced Dependency Resolution in Kotlin Script Files, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 07:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 6 is here! As we continue shaping the first major release of the year, you can get an early look at what’s coming by trying out the latest EAP build. You can download it from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use client assertions in OpenID Connect and ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 06:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_02_2025/24_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Client assertions is a method of client authentication which can be used in OpenID Connect. This provides an alternative to client secrets. This approach enhances security by using signed tokens (JWTs) to authenticate clients during the token request process or the OAuth PAR request. In ASP.NET Core, client assertions is not supported per default, a […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/02/24/use-client-assertions-in-openid-connect-and-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Spargine: Enhancing Your Applications with the CountryRepository to Validate and Retrieve Country Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_02_2025/23_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_02_2025/23_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source project for .NET 8, providing assemblies and NuGet packages crucial for managing country-specific data such as postal codes and phone numbers. The CountryRepository simplifies data access and validation, streamlining these processes through new features.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/02/23/harnessing-spargine-enhancing-your-applications-with-the-countryrepository-to-validate-and-retrieve-country-data/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
