<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:42:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Get Containerized: Simplifying Complexity for Modern Businesses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adapt to rising tech costs with containers, enabling consistent, efficient app deployment across cloud and hybrid environments.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/lets-get-containerized/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore 2024.5 Is Out With SQLite Support and an Improved Reporting Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 11:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2024.5 introduces SQLite support and an improved reporting experience that includes PDF export capabilities, new filters in interactive tables, and much more. Datalore Cloud customers have already received the new updates automatically, and Datalore On-Premises customers can upgrade by following these instructions. SQLite database support Datalore now offers native support for SQLite! You can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/12/12/datalore-2024-5-is-out-with-sqlite-support-and-an-improved-reporting-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Sentiment Analysis in Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 10:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sentiment analysis is one of the most popular ways to analyze text. It allows us to see at a glance how people are feeling across a wide range of areas and has useful applications in fields like customer service, market and product research, and competitive analysis. Like any area of natural language processing (NLP), sentiment […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/introduction-to-sentiment-analysis-in-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annoucing Javac support in Visual Studio Code Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 08:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, we are pleased to announce partial support of Javac as the underlying compiler in Visual Studio Code Java, JDT, and JDT-LS. The effort to provide this support has been a joint collaboration with Red Hat and Microsoft and is nearly a year in the making. This change aims to ensure timely support for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/annoucing-javac-support-in-visual-studio-code-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – December 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 20:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The December 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include a special review of docstring generation features from Pylance, the new Python Environments extension in preview, Pylance&#39;s &amp;quot;full&amp;quot; language server mode, and much more. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-december-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Boards Hub Rollout Expectations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although the process may seem slow, we are steadily progressing toward rolling out the New Boards Hub to all customers. Our plan is to deprecate the old Boards experience for all Azure DevOps service users by the end Q1 2025. The rollout is advancing on two fronts. First, we are setting the New Boards Hub […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-boards-hub-rollout-expectations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AWS sales uses Amazon Q Business for customer engagement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April 2024, we launched our AI sales assistant, which we call Field Advisor, making it available to AWS employees in the Sales, Marketing, and Global Services organization, powered by Amazon Q Business. Since that time, thousands of active users have asked hundreds of thousands of questions through Field Advisor, which we have embedded in our customer relationship management (CRM) system, as well as through a Slack application.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights from your Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL database using the Amazon Q Business connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through configuring and integrating Amazon Q for Business with Aurora PostgreSQL-Compatible to enable your database administrators, data analysts, application developers, leadership, and other teams to quickly get accurate answers to their questions related to the content stored in Aurora PostgreSQL databases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-from-your-amazon-aurora-postgresql-database-using-the-amazon-q-business-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tealium built a chatbot evaluation platform with Ragas and Auto-Instruct using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate the importance of generative AI in the collaboration between Tealium and the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) team by automating the following: 1/ Evaluating the retriever and the generated answer of a RAG system based on the Ragas Repository powered by Amazon Bedrock, 2/ Generating improved instructions for each question-and-answer pair using an automatic prompt engineering technique based on the Auto-Instruct Repository. An instruction refers to a general direction or command given to the model to guide generation of a response.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Box Ready-To-Code Dev Box images template</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft One Engineering System (1ES) team shares a sample for building Ready-To-Code Dev Box environments pre-configured with the necessary tools, repositories, and settings, ensuring consistency and reliability across teams.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/dev-box-ready-to-code-dev-box-images-template 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless publishing with Azure Functions Flex Consumption</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Struggling with complex deployment processes for your serverless applications? Visual Studio 2022 introduces a seamless solution with the new Azure Functions Flex Consumption hosting plan, now generally available. Imagine a world where deploying your serverless applications to a hosting plan that supports fast scaling and VNet is as simple as a right-click. With the Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/effortless-publishing-with-azure-functions-flex-consumption 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EBSCOlearning scales assessment generation for their online learning content with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate how EBSCOlearning partnered with AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to use the power of generative AI in revolutionizing their learning assessment process. We explore the challenges faced in traditional question-answer (QA) generation and the innovative AI-driven solution developed to address them.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ebscolearning-scales-assessment-generation-for-their-online-learning-content-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Single Jobs in TeamCity Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now debug individual jobs in TeamCity Pipelines. Instead of running the entire pipeline, just execute a specific job and get instant feedback without extra waiting. When you debug a single job, you can: When debugging one job, its dependencies will also be executed. Read more about job debugging in our docs. Bug fixes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/debug-single-jobs-in-teamcity-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the CONTINUE_IF_FAILED equivalent of RETURN_IF_FAILED?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Be careful how you write it, or better: Don&#39;t write it at all.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241211-00/?p=110629 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Developer Ecosystem 2024: The Unstoppable Rise of AI, Leading Languages, and Impact on Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year winds down, we’re taking a moment to reflect on what shaped the developer landscape in 2024. Drawing insights from over 23,000 developers worldwide, this year’s JetBrains State of Developer Ecosystem highlights significant trends shaping the development world. The prominence of AI in software is growing, with four out of five companies embracing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2024/12/11/the-state-of-developer-ecosystem-2024-unveiling-current-developer-trends-the-unstoppable-rise-of-ai-adoption-leading-languages-and-impact-on-developer-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixtral 12B is now available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Pixtral 12B (pixtral-12b-2409), a state-of-the-art vision language model (VLM) from Mistral AI that excels in both text-only and multimodal tasks, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. You can try this model with SageMaker JumpStart, a machine learning (ML) hub that provides access to algorithms and models that can be deployed with one click for running inference. In this post, we walk through how to discover, deploy, and use the Pixtral 12B model for a variety of real-world vision use cases.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invoking Async Power: What Awaits WinForms in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With .NET 9, we’re bringing a suite of new async APIs to WinForms, aimed at making UI updates, dialog interactions, and control management more efficient.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-winforms-async-apis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Organize Your Legal Team’s Work In YouTrack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s no secret that YouTrack is used by various sorts of teams, including legal ones. In conversations with our customers, legal technologies and legal operations are emerging as hot topics. YouTrack can help legal firms whose main areas of business are jurisprudence and providing legal services, as well as in-house legal departments at companies in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/12/how-to-organize-your-legal-team-s-work-in-youtrack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to your slide deck using multimodal foundation models on Amazon Bedrock – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Parts 1 and 2 of this series, we explored ways to use the power of multimodal FMs such as Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings, Amazon Titan Text Embeddings, and Anthropic’s Claude 3 Sonnet. In this post, we compared the approaches from an accuracy and pricing perspective.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/talk-to-your-slide-deck-using-multimodal-foundation-models-on-amazon-bedrock-part-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless publishing to Azure WebJobs on Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of the cumbersome process involved in publishing your .NET console applications to Azure WebJobs on Linux? For developers yearning for a seamless and efficient method to deploy their applications, Visual Studio 2022 introduces a much-anticipated solution. Visual Studio 2022 now supports right-click publishing to Azure WebJobs on Linux, making the deployment process […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/effortless-publishing-to-azure-webjobs-on-linux 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate actions across enterprise applications using Amazon Q Business plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a generative AI-powered assistant that enhances employee productivity by solving problems, generating content, and providing insights across enterprise data sources. Beyond searching indexed third-party services, employees need access to dynamic, near real-time data such as stock prices, vacation balances, and location tracking, which is made possible through Amazon Q Business plugins. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-actions-across-enterprise-applications-using-amazon-q-business-plugins/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compute scaling in Azure Fluid Relay</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the journey of identifying and fine-tuning the optimal Kubernetes autoscaling configuration for Azure Fluid Relay.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/compute-scaling-in-azure-fluid-relay 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ONNX GenAI Connector for Python (Experimental)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 16:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ONNX GenAI Connector for Python (Experimental) With the latest update we added support for running models locally with the onnxruntime-genai. The onnxruntime-genai package is powered by the ONNX Runtime in the background, but first let’s clarify what ONNX, ONNX Runtime and ONNX Runtime-GenAI are. ONNX ONNX is an open-source format for AI models, both for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/onnx-genai-connector-for-python-experimental 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It rather involved being on the other side of this airtight hatchway: Disabling anti-malware scanning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have already infiltrated the process, then you can disable things from the inside.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241210-00/?p=110626 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover JetBrains Consulting Partner Services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we are committed to empowering developers to do their best work with world-class tools. But even the best tools can deliver so much more when paired with expert guidance. That is why we’ve built a global network of Consulting Partners – professionals dedicated to helping you and your team maximize the value of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/12/10/discover-jetbrains-consulting-partner-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Dockerize a React App: A Step-by-Step Guide for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 12:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We show how to dockerize a React app to streamline your development process, eliminate &amp;quot;it works on my machine&amp;quot; problems, and ensure seamless deployments.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-dockerize-react-app/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books for Beginner Programmers: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous post, we explored some must-read books for anyone starting their programming journey. This time, we’re focusing on books for specific programming languages, helping you get comfortable with your chosen tech stack. Whether you’re learning Python, Java, Kotlin, or C, there’s something here for everyone. Let’s turn the page and get started!📚 Python […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/10/books-for-beginner-programmers-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Python 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Michael Kennedy, the founder of Talk Python and a PSF Fellow. Hey there. I’m Michael Kennedy, the founder of Talk Python and a Python Software Foundation (PSF) Fellow. I’m thrilled that the PyCharm team invited me to share my thoughts on the state of Python in 2024. If you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/the-state-of-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the YamlDotNet source generator for Native AOT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how you can use the YamlDotNet source generator to do strongly-typed serialization and deserialization, even in Native AOT apps
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/using-the-yamldotnet-source-generator-for-native-aot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: GraalVM and GraalPy Meet IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Fabio Niephaus to explore integrations for GraalVM, GraalPy, and other Graal Languages in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: December 19, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract GraalVM has become very popular in the Java community, not just because of its JIT compiler, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/new-livestream-from-code-to-clarity-with-the-redesigned-structure-tool-window-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execution Context Management with AsyncLocal and ThreadLocal in .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In modern distributed .NET applications, managing context across execution boundaries is a critical architectural concern. While both AsyncLocal and ThreadLocal provide mechanisms for maintaining contextual data, their implementations and use cases differ significantly in ways that impact system architecture, performance, and maintainability. This
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/execution-context-asynclocal-threadlocal-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Monitor Your App&amp;#x27;s Performance with .NET Benchmarking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:22:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Benchmarking is essential in application development, especially if you aim to scale up your app. Benchmarking enables you to evaluate your application&#39;s resource consumption, which helps you identify potential updates to speed up performance. If not scaling, you will need the application performance to be optimal to enhance
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/how-to-monitor-your-apps-performance-with-net-benchmarking/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marten Event Sourcing Gets Some New Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 22:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software has gotten the chance this work to build out several strategic improvements to both Marten and Wolverine through collaborations with our clients who have had some specific needs. This has been highly advantageous because it’s helped push some significant, long planned technical improvements while getting all important feedback as clients integrate the new … Continue reading Marten Event Sourcing Gets Some New Tools →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/09/marten-event-sourcing-gets-some-new-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Local AI models with .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s look at how to build and run local AI models with .NET Aspire.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/local-ai-models-with-dotnet-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating ML experimentation with enhanced security: AWS PrivateLink support for Amazon SageMaker with MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With access to a wide range of generative AI foundation models (FM) and the ability to build and train their own machine learning (ML) models in Amazon SageMaker, users want a seamless and secure way to experiment with and select the models that deliver the most value for their business. In the initial stages of an ML […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-ml-experimentation-with-enhanced-security-aws-privatelink-support-for-amazon-sagemaker-with-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Python in VS Code Wrapped</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year comes to a close, we would like to take the time to reflect and celebrate the incredible progress the Python extension for VS Code has made in the past year. From merging in top requested features to countless lines of code written and deleted, keep reading to get an inside look to all things
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/2024-python-vscode-wrapped 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a Unified Data Model is Critical: Lessons from Building Microsoft’s Semantic Layer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Some years ago, we were wrestling with a persistent issue in our data stack. Every team had their own way of collecting and structuring data. What was a simple query for one team became a debugging nightmare for another. Discovering the right dataset felt like looking for a needle in a haystack, and standardizing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/udm/unified-data-models-101 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Global System Integrators can make the most of their GitHub Copilot licenses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered code assistant tools like GitHub Copilot have revolutionized the development landscape. We’ve observed significant Copilot adoption among Global System Integrators (GSIs), who are leading the charge in harnessing its potential. While many developers are already utilizing GitHub Copilot in their internal projects, GSI’s are eager to integrate Copilot into their own application development lifecycles. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/dont-let-your-github-copilot-licenses-collect-dust-how-gsis-can-make-their-every-license-count 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep working with non-blocking Code Cleanup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of waiting for Code Cleanup to finish every time you save your work? Visual Studio 2022 will no longer lock up and get in the way of your tasks as it’s cleaning up the code under the covers. Every developer knows the importance of maintaining clean code. However, the traditional Code Cleanup […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/keep-working-with-non-blocking-code-cleanup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to read C&#43;&#43; compiler errors: Failing to create a shared_ptr</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding what you asked the compiler to do, and why it couldn&#39;t comply.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241209-00/?p=110619 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New! Security Analysis Plugin for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Application security is a critical requirement in modern software development. The latest release of IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 – along with the optional new Security Analysis by Qodana plugin – elevates your security efforts with advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for code written in Java and Kotlin. Trained on popular OWASP security benchmark projects, this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/security-analysis-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.1 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 – 2024.3.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. v2024.3.1 introduces advanced interprocedural data flow analysis capabilities for Java and Kotlin. This allows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/intellij-idea-2024-3-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the binary log to find the source of a .NET dependency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding where a dependency comes from can be tedious. This is especially true when you have a large project with many dependencies. Recently, .NET brings a new tool dotnet nuget why to help you understand why a package is installed in your project. However, there is a better way to do it, and it doesn&#39;t requires a recent SDK. dotnet nuget why can explain why a package is included in your project:…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 06:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about the Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern. We are going to see how to implement this pattern in C# and how it can solve certain design problems. Let’s start. What is The Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern? Chain of Responsibility is a behavioral pattern that helps us design a […] The post Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Entra External ID with an Auth0 OpenID Connect identity provider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at implementing an Open ID Connect identity provider in Microsoft Entra External ID. Auth0 is used as the identity provider and an ASP.NET Core application is used to test the authentication. Microsoft Entra External ID federates to Auth0. Client code: https://github.com/damienbod/EntraExternalIdCiam Microsoft Entra External ID supports federation using OpenID Connect and was […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/12/09/using-entra-external-id-with-an-auth0-openid-connect-identity-provider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Resilient Systems with Wolverine’s Transactional Outbox</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 03:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software is completely open for business to help you get the best possible results with the “Critter Stack” tools or really any type of server side .NET development efforts. A lot of what I’m writing about is inspired by work we’ve done with our ongoing clients. I think I’m at the point where I … Continue reading Build Resilient Systems with Wolverine’s Transactional Outbox →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/12/08/build-resilient-systems-with-wolverines-transactional-outbox/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Type Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2024/08_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2024/08_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source project for .NET 8, featuring assemblies and NuGet packages crucial for .NET applications. It includes the TypeExtensions class, offering performance-optimized methods that simplify type handling.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/12/08/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-type-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Package Management in .NET - Simplify NuGet Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_12_2024/07_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_12_2024/07_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing NuGet packages across multiple .NET projects used to be a nightmare of version mismatches and maintenance headaches, but Central Package Management (CPM) offers a powerful solution by letting you control all package versions from a single source of truth. Learn how CPM can simplify your dependency management, prevent version conflicts, and make your .NET development workflow smoother.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/central-package-management-in-net-simplify-nuget-dependencies 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: How to use Elasticsearch Vector Store Connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel for AI Agent development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to use Elasticsearch Vector Store Connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel for AI Agent development Today we’re excited to feature the Elastic team to share more about their Semantic Kernel Elasticsearch Vector Store connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel. Read the entire announcement here. I’ll turn it over to Srikanth Manvi and Florian Bernd to dive […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-how-to-use-elasticsearch-vector-store-connector-for-microsoft-semantic-kernel-for-ai-agent-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistral-NeMo-Instruct-2407 and Mistral-NeMo-Base-2407 are now available on SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Mistral-NeMo-Base-2407 and Mistral-NeMo-Instruct-2407 large language models from Mistral AI that excel at text generation, are available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. In this post, we walk through how to discover, deploy and use the Mistral-NeMo-Instruct-2407 and Mistral-NeMo-Base-2407 models for a variety of real-world use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mistral-nemo-instruct-2407-and-mistral-nemo-base-2407-are-now-available-on-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deletion of Outdated Azul Zulu for Azure Container Images for Better Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We at Microsoft are committed to providing customers with a secure ecosystem of tools for building and deploying applications. As part of this commitment, we continuously update our Java container image offerings to ensure they meet the highest security standards. Back in January 2022, we announced the End of Updates for the Azul Zulu for Azure build of OpenJDK. As […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/deletion-of-outdated-azul-zulu-for-azure-container-images-for-better-security 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSVC Compiler Language Updates in Visual Studio 2022 version 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 17:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In alignment with the Visual Studio 2022 version 17.12 release, and based upon feedback received from the community, the MSVC compiler team would like to provide greater visibility into the C++ language-level fixes for customer-reported issues that made it into the release. This is similar to how the standard library team publishes regular changelogs […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/msvc-compiler-language-updates-in-visual-studio-2022-version-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your Microsoft 365 app performance: Introducing tree shaking in TeamsJS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Microsoft Teams JavaScript client library (TeamsJS) version 2.31.0, we’re excited to make the TeamsJS library fully tree-shakable.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/boost-your-microsoft-365-app-performance-introducing-tree-shaking-in-teamsjs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to read C&#43;&#43; compiler errors: Nonsensical errors from a function declaration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Look closely at what the error message is complaining about.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241206-00/?p=110614 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream alert: Ace the CSAI Math Entrance Test</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want to study computer science in Europe? Join the Computer Science and AI bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos – with exclusive JetBrains scholarships up for grabs! On December 18, 2024, at 5:00 pm UTC, we’re hosting a special preparation session to help you ace the entrance test for this BSc. You’ll get tips from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/06/livestream-alert-ace-the-csai-math-entrance-test/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Ruby Debugging: From puts to Professional Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Debugging is an essential skill in software development, and in this post, we’ll be looking at how to investigate the behavior of Ruby code. As the RubyMine team, we’ve accumulated considerable expertise in creating tools for Ruby developers, and we’re excited to share our experience and knowledge with you. Recently, at the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/12/mastering_ruby_debugging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Evaluation platform on Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Machine Learning is known for training and deploying models, but can also be used for running experiments. This blog post will show us how we have implemented our Evaluation platform on Azure Machine Learning.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/implement-evaluation-platform-on-aml 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing AI trust with new responsible AI tools, capabilities, and resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 23:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With trust as a cornerstone of AI adoption, we are excited to announce at AWS re:Invent 2024 new responsible AI tools, capabilities, and resources that enhance the safety, security, and transparency of our AI services and models and help support customers’ own responsible AI journeys.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advancing-ai-trust-with-new-responsible-ai-tools-capabilities-and-resources/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy RAG applications on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart using FAISS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 21:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build a RAG application on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart using Facebook AI Similarity Search (FAISS).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-rag-applications-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-using-faiss/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up your cluster procurement time with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training plans, to bring down your training cluster procurement wait time. We guide you through a step-by-step implementation on how you can use the (AWS CLI) or the AWS Management Console to find, review, and create optimal training plans for your specific compute and timeline needs. We further guide you through using the training plan to submit SageMaker training jobs or create SageMaker HyperPod clusters.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code, Learn, Repeat: Get Ready for KotlinConf 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            KotlinConf has always been about more than just code – it’s where ideas spark, skills develop, and the Kotlin community comes together to share knowledge, connect, and celebrate. While we’re still crafting the 2025 program (stay tuned for the big reveal in February), here are the recordings of last year’s top talks to give you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/12/code-learn-repeat-get-ready-for-kotlinconf-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – November Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year draws to a close, the JetBrains Academy team has some exciting updates for you! In this newsletter, you’ll discover new courses, plugins to enhance your learning, tech career tips, and updates for computer science educators.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/05/jetbrains-academy-november-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3.20 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just published a maintenance update to IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3. This minor release includes several bug fixes and improvements to existing features introduced in the main release. Lambda breakpoints in the debugger We’ve made improvements to how lambda expressions are handled in the debugger. Previously, setting a breakpoint on a line with a lambda […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/12/05/intellij-scala-plugin-2024-3-is-out-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Code Referencing for GitHub Copilot Chat in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of the uncertainty that comes with using code suggestions from AI tools? We’ve got exciting news for you! Visual Studio 2022 now includes code referencing in GitHub Copilot, ensuring greater transparency and control for developers. We are thrilled to announce that code referencing is now available in GitHub Copilot Chat within Visual […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-code-referencing-for-github-copilot-chat-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dependabot to Manage .NET SDK Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use Dependabot to keep your .NET SDK version up to date with the latest security patches and improvements.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-dependabot-to-manage-dotnet-sdk-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – December 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As 2024 wraps up, this December edition of Java Annotated Monthly brings you the latest on JEPs targeted for Java 24, helpful tutorials on Java, Kotlin, and AI, and more. This time, we’ve included thought-provoking non-tech articles perfect for year-end reflection. Plus, we’re thrilled to welcome Josh Long as our featured author, who will be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/12/java-annotated-monthly-december-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding a Legacy Codebase. Keep it Evergreen</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Nobody wants their codebase to turn into a brownfield mess legacy codebase having to use outdated technology. Here are 3 tips for keeping your codebase evergreen. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in this post. Understanding Stability and Advancements How do you… Read More »Avoiding a Legacy Codebase. Keep it Evergreen The post Avoiding a Legacy Codebase.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Azure Cosmos DB Integration with Spring AI and Langchain4J!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re continuing to simplify AI app development by integrating Azure Cosmos DB’s cost-effective and scalable vector search directly with Spring AI and LangChain4J! These frameworks empower Java developers to efficiently manage fast and accurate data retrieval with Azure Cosmos DB’s scalability and efficient vector indexing and search capabilities, allowing for efficient handling of high-dimensional vectors. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-azure-cosmos-db-integration-with-spring-ai-and-langchain4j 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Won’t waiting for multiple threads one at a time introduce a severe performance issue?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It depends on how long you plan on waiting.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241205-00/?p=110609 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12: UI Updates, Experimental Kubernetes Executor Mode, Conditional Dependencies in Build Chains, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity 2024.12 introduces a redesigned UI, conditional build chains, simplified OAuth token management, and enhanced AWS and Perforce integrations. New features also include support for custom Kotlin DSL libraries, centralized refreshable token management, and single-action build chain approvals, among others. Conditional dependencies in build chains In TeamCity, you can break down complex build processes into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/12/teamcity-202412/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Do Sentiment Analysis With Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sentiment analysis is a powerful tool for understanding emotions in text. While there are many ways to approach sentiment analysis, including more traditional lexicon-based and machine learning approaches, today we’ll be focusing on one of the most cutting-edge ways of working with text – large language models (LLMs). We’ll explain how you can use these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/12/how-to-do-sentiment-analysis-with-large-language-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
