<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Evolving Code Standards Without Chaos - Dev Leader Weekly 91</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to navigate codebases that have evolving code standards.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/04/19/navigating-evolving-code-standards-without-chaos-dev-leader-weekly-91 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-04-18</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 04:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/04/19/weekly-recap-20250418 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Microservices: Core Concepts and Benefits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What are microservices, and why might they be the right architectural choice for your organization? Microservices offer independently deployable, domain-focused components that provide flexibility when applied correctly to solve the right organizational problems.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/understanding-microservices-core-concepts-and-benefits 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Search in .NET / C# with Build5Nines.SharpVector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 18:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we often find ourselves building smarter, more context-aware applications. Whether it’s powering a document search tool or implementing Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), semantic search is a powerful capability to have in your toolbox. I recently found myself needing a lightweight, local, in-memory vector database for a .NET / C# project. At the time, there […] The article Semantic Search in .NET / C# with Build5Nines.SharpVector was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ: Introducing the enhanced Java Code Quality Analyzer!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the latest updates to the Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ, featuring an enhanced Java Code Quality Analyzer to help you write cleaner, safer, and more efficient Java code with Azure SDK client libraries.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-toolkit-for-intellij-introducing-the-enhanced-java-code-quality-analyzer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a FinOps agent using Amazon Bedrock with multi-agent capability and Amazon Nova as the foundation model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we use the multi-agent feature of Amazon Bedrock to demonstrate a powerful and innovative approach to AWS cost management. By using the advanced capabilities of Amazon Nova FMs, we’ve developed a solution that showcases how AI-driven agents can revolutionize the way organizations analyze, optimize, and manage their AWS costs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-finops-agent-using-amazon-bedrock-with-multi-agent-capability-and-amazon-nova-as-the-foundation-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stream ingest data from Kafka to Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases using custom connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For this post, we implement a RAG architecture with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases using a custom connector and topics built with Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (Amazon MSK) for a user who may be interested to understand stock price trends.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/stream-ingest-data-from-kafka-to-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-using-custom-connectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards &#43; GitHub: Recent Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 14:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past several months, we’ve delivered a series of improvements to the Azure Boards + GitHub integration. Whether you’re tracking code, managing pull requests, or connecting pipelines, these updates aim to simplify and strengthen the link between your work items and your GitHub activity. Here’s a recap of everything we’ve released (or are just […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-boards-github-recent-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the feature flag that didn’t stay on long enough, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 14:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Leaving everything the way you found it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250418-43/?p=111081 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: Ruby on Rails – The Framework that Rewired The Web with MVC and Convention</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It wasn’t the first web framework. It may not be the flashiest these days in 2025. But Ruby on Rails was revolutionary when it hit the scene — and its fingerprints are still all over modern web development today. At a time when building web applications was often painful, verbose, and fractured across multiple layers […] The article Software Innovation: Ruby on Rails – The Framework that Rewired The Web with MVC and Convention was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Semantic Kernel Python with Google’s A2A Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 21:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Google’s Agent-to-Agent (A2A) protocol is designed to enable seamless interoperability among diverse AI agents. Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel (SK), an open-source platform for orchestrating intelligent agent interactions, is now being integrated into the A2A ecosystem. In this blog, we demonstrate how Semantic Kernel agents can easily function as an A2A Server, efficiently routing agent calls to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/integrating-semantic-kernel-python-with-googles-a2a-protocol 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Azure MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 19:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces the Azure MCP Server, bringing the power of the cloud to your AI agents.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/introducing-the-azure-mcp-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Zoom as a data accessor to your Amazon Q index</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 18:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how Zoom users can access their Amazon Q Business enterprise data directly within their Zoom interface, alleviating the need to switch between applications while maintaining enterprise security boundaries. Organizations can now configure Zoom as a data accessor in Amazon Q Business, enabling seamless integration between their Amazon Q index and Zoom AI Companion. This integration allows users to access their enterprise knowledge in a controlled manner directly within the Zoom platform.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview 2 of the .NET AI Template Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Preview 2 of the .NET AI Chat Web App template introduces support for .NET Aspire and Qdrant vector database integration, making it easier to create cloud-native AI-powered chat applications with custom data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-ai-template-preview2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of quality assurance: Shift-left testing with QyrusAI and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 16:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how QyrusAI and Amazon Bedrock are revolutionizing shift-left testing, enabling teams to deliver better software faster. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that allows businesses to build and scale generative AI applications using foundation models (FMs) from leading AI providers. It enables seamless integration with AWS services, offering customization, security, and scalability without managing infrastructure.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-future-of-quality-assurance-shift-left-testing-with-qyrusai-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate video insights for contextual advertising using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 16:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Data Automation (BDA) is a new managed feature powered by FMs in Amazon Bedrock. BDA extracts structured outputs from unstructured content—including documents, images, video, and audio—while alleviating the need for complex custom workflows. In this post, we demonstrate how BDA automatically extracts rich video insights such as chapter segments and audio segments, detects text in scenes, and classifies Interactive Advertising Bureau (IAB) taxonomies, and then uses these insights to build a nonlinear ads solution to enhance contextual advertising effectiveness.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Salesforce achieves high-performance model deployment with Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 16:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a joint collaboration between Salesforce and AWS and is being cross-published on both the Salesforce Engineering Blog and the AWS Machine Learning Blog. The Salesforce AI Model Serving team is working to push the boundaries of natural language processing and AI capabilities for enterprise applications. Their key focus areas include optimizing large […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-salesforce-achieves-high-performance-model-deployment-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 15:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that the Release Candidate for MPS 2025.1 is now available! Download it today and be among the first to try out the latest features and improvements. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.1 RC Curious about what’s new? Check out this blog post for a deep dive into all the updates. The full list of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/04/the-mps-2025-1-rc-ready/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 14:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how Microsoft 365 Certification helps ISVs validate General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) compliance.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbox Support for Explicit Assembly References in Windows Forms Out-of-Process Designer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 14:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 17.14 Preview 3 introduces a new feature that enhances the Windows Forms out-of-process designer experience for .NET Framework projects. This release brings Toolbox support for Explicit Assembly References, addressing a long-standing need in legacy application development and migration workflows. What Are Explicit Assembly References? Explicit Assembly References are stand-alone assemblies directly referenced in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/toolbox-support-for-explicit-assembly-references-in-windows-forms-out-of-process-designer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel adds Model Context Protocol (MCP) support for Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 14:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Semantic Kernel (SK) now has first-class support for the Model Context Protocol (MCP) — a standard created by Anthropic to enable models, tools, and agents to share context and capabilities seamlessly. With this release, SK can act as both an MCP host (client) and an MCP server, and you […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-adds-model-context-protocol-mcp-support-for-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the feature flag that didn’t stay on long enough, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding scope and order of destruction.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250417-00/?p=111079 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore 2025.2 Is Out With Report Tabs, Extended DuckDB Support, and Snowflake Key Pair Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 13:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.2 introduces several new features, including report tabs, DuckDB as a data source for SQL cells, Snowflake key pair authentication, and the possibility to use a custom JDBC driver for the Datalore server, which is particularly relevant for the On-Premises version. Datalore Cloud users have already received the new updates automatically, and Datalore On-Premises […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/04/17/datalore-2025-2-is-out-with-report-tabs-extended-duckdb-support-and-snowflake-key-pair-authentication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Gemini 2.5 Pro arrives in JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 12:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant now supports Google’s latest and most intelligent AI model, Gemini 2.5 Pro. This integration makes your JetBrains IDE even smarter, providing enhanced accuracy and deep reasoning capabilities to streamline your coding experience. At JetBrains, we aim to equip developers with AI tools that simplify complex tasks and make everyday coding more productive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/04/google-gemini-2-5-pro-arrives-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarter Kotlin Development With JetBrains AI: Junie and AI Assistant in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 12:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI is now a lot more useful for Kotlin developers. With the public release of Junie and a major update to AI Assistant, two powerful AI tools are now deeply integrated with JetBrains IDEs – and ready to help you move faster with less overhead. Whether you’re starting a new feature or cleaning up […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/smarter-kotlin-development-with-jetbrains-ai-junie-and-ai-assistant-in-your-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse: Enhanced Notification Options</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 10:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this TeamCity Pipelines release, we’re focusing on improving the user experience with more flexible notification options. You can now choose which specific email notifications you want to receive from the system. You can select between default or custom notification options or unsubscribe from everything. The following options are available for custom notifications: To change […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-enhanced-notification-options/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build MCP Remote Servers with Azure Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Build AI-powered tools quickly using Azure Functions to create remote MCP servers that seamlessly integrate with GitHub Copilot and other LLM-based applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/build-mcp-remote-servers-with-azure-functions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Amazon EKS troubleshooting using an Amazon Bedrock agentic workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 20:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to orchestrate multiple Amazon Bedrock agents to create a sophisticated Amazon EKS troubleshooting system. By enabling collaboration between specialized agents—deriving insights from K8sGPT and performing actions through the ArgoCD framework—you can build a comprehensive automation that identifies, analyzes, and resolves cluster issues with minimal human intervention.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-amazon-eks-troubleshooting-using-an-amazon-bedrock-agentic-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices to Monolith</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 20:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s been a noticeable pushback against microservices lately, and we’re seeing a strong swing back toward monoliths. But I have to ask, if you can’t build a solid microservices system, what makes you think you can build a good monolith? YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including… Read More »Microservices to Monolith The post Microservices to Monolith appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host concurrent LLMs with LoRAX</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 19:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) can be used to address these challenges effectively. Specifically, we discuss using LoRA serving with LoRA eXchange (LoRAX) and Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) GPU instances, allowing organizations to efficiently manage and serve their growing portfolio of fine-tuned models, optimize costs, and provide seamless performance for their customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/host-concurrent-llms-with-lorax/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a computer vision-based asset inventory application with low or no training</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 19:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a solution using generative AI and large language models (LLMs) to alleviate the time-consuming and labor-intensive tasks required to build a computer vision application, enabling you to immediately start taking pictures of your asset labels and extract the necessary information to update the inventory using AWS services
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-computer-vision-based-asset-inventory-application-with-low-or-no-training/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot Highlights in Visual Studio 17.14 Preview 3 (Available Now)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 18:24:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 17.14 Preview 3 is now available! The GitHub Copilot experience in Visual Studio is continuously updated to provide the latest advancements in AI-assisted development. The following features and improvements have been recently released in Visual Studio version 17.14 Preview 3. (Remember, preview versions of Visual Studio can be run side by side with […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/github-copilot-highlights-in-visual-studio-17-14-preview-3-available-now 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Copilot team leverages .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 18:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By now, you’ve probably heard of Microsoft Copilot, the innovative tool designed to enhance productivity by providing intelligent assistance across various Microsoft applications. Millions of users use Copilot inside of Windows, on Edge, through the Copilot mobile app, and even on Xbox. What you may not know is that the development team behind Copilot transitioned […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//how-the-copilot-team-leverages-dotnet-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Elastic Beanstalk now integrates with AWS Secrets Manager and Systems Manager Parameter Store</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 16:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Elastic Beanstalk provides deployment and management capabilities for web applications and services. The Elastic Beanstalk service handles operational tasks including load balancing, scaling, and monitoring while users focus on their application code. Elastic Beanstalk allows applications to access configuration data through key-value pairs in environment properties. However, this approach has certain limitations – environment […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/aws-elastic-beanstalk-now-integrates-with-aws-secrets-manager-and-systems-manager-parameter-store/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with the new Advanced Audio Models in Azure OpenAI Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to get started with Azure OpenAI&#39;s next-generation GPT-4o audio models for transcription and text-to-speech applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/get-started-azure-openai-advanced-audio-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big News! JetBrains Qodana’s Code Quality Plugin Is Now Available for Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s no secret that Qodana is a team tool that JetBrains designed to integrate seamlessly with its suite of IDEs, but every team and tech stack is different. One common question remains: “What about other members of our team who still use VS Code or Visual Studio?” To help with this problem, we decided to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/visual-studio-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port .NET Framework workloads to Linux with Amazon Q Developer, Part 3: Web APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 14:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This blog series explores how to port different kinds of .NET Framework projects to cross-platform .NET with Amazon Q Developer Transformation for .NET, currently in public preview. Part 1 covers porting of class library projects and Part 2 covers porting of .NET Test Projects. Here in Part 3 , we walk you through porting […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/port-net-framework-workloads-to-linux-with-amazon-q-developer-part-3-web-apis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.03.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The first bug-fix update for version 2025.03, TeamCity On-Premises 2025.03.1, is out and ready to be installed on your servers! This update ships around 30 bug fixes, performance enhancements, and security patches. We highly recommend upgrading to keep your system secure and optimized. The list of resolved issues includes: See TeamCity 2025.03.1 Upgrade Notes for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/teamcity-2025-03-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the classical model for linking to provide unit test overrides</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overriding a LIB with an OBJ for fun and profit.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250416-00/?p=111077 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2025.1: Unified PyCharm, Free AI Tier, Junie Release, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2025.1 brings major updates to improve your development experience. PyCharm is now a unified product, combining PyCharm Professional and Community Edition. Version 2025.1 also brings a free AI tier, the public release of Junie, the launch of Cadence, significant Jupyter enhancements, support for Hatch, Data Wrangler, and many other improvements. Get the latest version […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/04/pycharm-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2025.1: JetBrains Data Wrangler AI Agent, No-Code Data Preparation Flow, AI Quick Charts, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to introduce DataSpell 2025.1, the first major release of 2025. This update focuses on making data cleaning and preparation more intuitive and efficient than ever before. Download DataSpell 2025.1 JetBrains Data Wrangler AI agent With Data Wrangler, you can choose between a no-code flow or full AI automation. Easily toggle between: No-code flow […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/04/dataspell-2025-1-jetbrains-data-wrangler-ai-agent-no-code-data-preparation-flow-ai-quick-charts-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release is a major update that includes improvements in PHPStan annotations, Xdebug, and WordPress support, an AI Free tier and new subscription system for JetBrains AI, and more. Download PhpStorm 2025.1 PHP Code completion for @phpstan-type and @phpstan-import-type This release improves PhpStorm’s PHPStan annotation support, introducing code completion for array shape aliases in @phpstan-type […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/04/phpstorm-2025-1-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Support for new features in Scala 3 Context Bounds and Givens Scala 3.6 introduced a new syntax for context bounds and givens. You can read more about it in SIP-64. In short, before Scala 3.6, it was impossible to name the context bound in the same place where it was defined. The way to do […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2025/04/16/intellij-scala-plugin-2025-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI Service now authorized for all U.S. Government data classification levels</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the coming years, artificial intelligence will continue to be foundational to technical innovations for national security missions. Already, U.S. defense and intelligence organizations are using AI to enhance productivity, support decision making, and improve mission outcomes. Microsoft Azure is a backbone for this type of AI-driven work, supporting U.S. government missions with high resiliency, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/azure-openai-authorization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.1 Arrives With Support for Out-of-Project Files in CLion Nova, Qt Renderers, the ST-LINK Debug Server, and West Build Options</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion 2025.1 is now available. This latest version of the JetBrains IDE for C and C++ includes the following key features: You can download CLion 2025.1 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu, or via a patch update from version 2024.3. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.1 CLion Nova […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/04/clion-2025-1-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2025.1 comes with several exciting updates to help you write better Go code and work more efficiently. This release introduces support for golangci-lint, improvements to the Rename refactoring and static analysis, smarter handling of the toolchain directive, and full support for Go 1.24. We’re also bringing major updates for JetBrains AI. Let’s take a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/04/16/goland-2025-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip 2025.1: Schema Context for AI-based Error Explanations, Introspection by Levels for MySQL and MariaDB, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2025.1 is here! This is the first major update of 2025. Let’s take a look at what it has to offer. For a detailed description of this update, visit our What’s New page. AI Assistant Connectivity Working with data Coding assistance
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/04/16/datagrip-2025-1-schema-context-for-ai-based-error-explanations-introspection-by-levels-for-mysql-and-mariadb-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2025.1: Major Improvements to JetBrains AI, Enhanced Angular Support, and Better Monorepo Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our first major release of 2025 is here! This version includes major improvements to JetBrains AI, enhanced Angular support, better monorepo support, a range of user experience improvements, and a whole lot more. DOWNLOAD WEBSTORM 2025.1 To dive deeper into what you can expect in the release, just carry on reading! The new features and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/04/webstorm-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 release has landed! It delivers numerous refinements across the IDE to enhance your productivity, the quality of your code, and your overall comfort. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/intellij-idea-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2025.1: Major AI Assistant Upgrade, Cloud-Based Code Completion for RBS, More Ruby 3.4 Support, Kamal Schema Updates, Enhanced RemDev, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 12:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2025.1 introduces a massively upgraded AI Assistant (code completion for RBS, offline mode, more models available, and other features), support for the latest Kamal version, debugging for multi-module projects, and significantly improved remote development. Below is a brief overview of the most notable features. For a detailed description of this update, please visit our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/04/rubymine-2025-1-major-ai-assistant-upgrade/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing IEnumerable Counting in Microsoft.NET: The Fastest Approach Revealed</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_24/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To count elements in an IEnumerable collection, developers typically use the Count() method from System.Linq. Enumerable, with alternatives like TryGetNonEnumeratedCount() and LongCount() also available.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/16/optimizing-ienumerable-counting-in-microsoft-net-the-fastest-approach-revealed/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoMapper and MediatR Licensing Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 05:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_25/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In my last post, I shared the news that I&#39;ve decided to take a commercialization route for AutoMapper and MediatR to ensure their long-term success. While that post was heavy on the motivation, it was intentionally light on the details. I did share that I wanted to be
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/automapper-and-mediatr-licensing-update/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Model Context Protocol (MCP) support in n8n</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 04:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_26/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            n8n now comes with built-in support for Model Context Protocol (MCP), adding both MCP Server Trigger and MCP Client nodes… The post Native Model Context Protocol (MCP) support in n8n appeared first on Daily .NET Tips.
Link to article: https://dailydotnettips.com/native-model-context-protocol-mcp-support-in-n8n/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: Announcing the Neon Serverless Postgres Connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 22:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the Neon Serverless Postgres Connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel We’re excited to introduce the Neon Serverless Postgres Connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel, enabling developers to seamlessly integrate Neon’s serverless Postgres capabilities with AI-driven vector search and retrieval workflows. By leveraging the pgvector extension in Neon and the existing Postgres Vector Store connector, this integration […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-announcing-the-neon-serverless-postgres-connector-for-microsoft-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the .NET &amp; C# Teams at Microsoft Build 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The countdown to Microsoft Build 2025 is on! Join us May 19-22 either in-person in Seattle or online and explore an exciting lineup of .NET and C# content, including sessions on AI integration, app modernization, and the latest language features.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/join-us-at-build-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clario enhances the quality of the clinical trial documentation process with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The collaboration between Clario and AWS demonstrated the potential of AWS AI and machine learning (AI/ML) services and generative AI models, such as Anthropic’s Claude, to streamline document generation processes in the life sciences industry and, specifically, for complicated clinical trial processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/clario-enhances-the-quality-of-the-clinical-trial-documentation-process-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Mixtral 8x7B on Amazon SageMaker with AWS Inferentia2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 17:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to deploy and serve the Mixtral 8x7B language model on AWS Inferentia2 instances for cost-effective, high-performance inference. We&#39;ll walk through model compilation using Hugging Face Optimum Neuron, which provides a set of tools enabling straightforward model loading, training, and inference, and the Text Generation Inference (TGI) Container, which has the toolkit for deploying and serving LLMs with Hugging Face.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-mixtral-8x7b-on-amazon-sagemaker-with-aws-inferentia2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate business productivity with Amazon Q and Amazon Connect</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 17:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to elevate business productivity by leveraging Amazon Q to provide insights that enable research, data analysis, and report potential fraud cases within Amazon Connect.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-business-productivity-with-amazon-q-and-amazon-connect/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Bridging Business and Technology: Transforming Natural Language Queries into SQL with Semantic Kernel Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’d like to welcome back a team of internal Microsoft employees for part 2 of their guest blog series focused on Bridging Business and Technology: Transforming Natural Language Queries into SQL with Semantic Kernel. We’ll turn it over to our authors – Samer El Housseini, Riccardo Chiodaroli, Daniel Labbe and Fabrizio Ruocco to dive […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-bridging-business-and-technology-transforming-natural-language-queries-into-sql-with-semantic-kernel-part-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop for Mac: QEMU Virtualization Option to be Deprecated in 90 Days</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are announcing the upcoming deprecation of QEMU as a virtualization option for Docker Desktop on Apple Silicon Macs. After serving as our legacy virtualization solution during the early transition to Apple Silicon, QEMU will be fully deprecated 90 days from today, on July 14, 2025. This deprecation does not affect QEMU’s role in emulating […]
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-for-mac-qemu-virtualization-option-to-be-deprecated-in-90-days/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K2 Mode in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1: Current State and FAQ</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1, K2 mode, a new implementation of Kotlin support, will be enabled by default. This change is an important step in the ongoing effort to improve Kotlin support in the IDE. While this transition brings many improvements and lays the foundation for a smoother, more reliable experience in the future, it’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/k2-mode-in-intellij-idea-2025-1-current-state-and-faq/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There was a lot of imagined dropping tablets in swimming pools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The archetypical example of needing a replacement computer.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250415-00/?p=111075 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Bazel Plugin 2025.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 13:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to tell you about all the changes we’ve made in recent months to improve the Bazel plugin experience in IntelliJ IDEA. Every couple of weeks, we’ve been shipping updates to JetBrains Marketplace with focused fixes and features. Over time, these smaller updates have amounted to substantial enhancements. Most updates are included in the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/what-s-new-in-bazel-plugin-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2025: Full Schedule</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++ is our free, one-day, virtual conference for the whole C++ community. This year, it is running on the 30th April. We’re pleased to announce the schedule of live talks: 14:00 UTC: Welcome to v1.0 of the meta::[[verse]]! with Inbal Levi 14:30 UTC: Proxy: Next Generation Polymorphism with Mingxin Wang 15:00 UTC: Making […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-cpp-2025-full-schedule 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn AI-Assisted Programming With JetBrains Academy and Nebius</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learning to code with AI isn’t cheating – it’s the next skill every developer needs. AI tools are changing the way we write, test, and maintain code but using them effectively isn’t always straightforward. That’s why we’ve partnered with Nebius, an AI cloud platform known for its expertise in high-performance and AI-first workloads, to bring […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/15/learn-ai-assisted-programming-with-jetbrains-academy-and-nebius/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding GraphQL in .NET: When and why to use it</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:28:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            APIs are the heart of most modern applications. Due to their simplicity and lightweight design, RESTful APIs are a popular choice for client-server communication in most applications. However, APIs can become limiting when fetching complex or related data. The front end may over-fetch or under-fetch the meaningful data. For example,
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-graphql-in-net-when-and-why-to-use-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: GitHub Actions and Setting Up Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog posts, we created integration tests that interact with UI components, assert different properties of UI components, and interact with APIs. Now, it’s time to look at how to set up continuous integration to ensure that we don’t break them in the next commit. We will be creating continuous integration using GitHub […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-github-actions-and-setting-up-continuous-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbox App 2.6 Is Here With Remote Development Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Toolbox App 2.6 introduces support for remote development, allowing you to manage JetBrains tools and projects both locally and on remote servers. You can connect to different host platforms, including Windows, macOS, and Linux, and use the integrated OpenSSH for secure and customizable SSH connections. The Toolbox App supports connections to remote SSH hosts, as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/toolbox-app/2025/04/toolbox-app-2-6-is-here-with-remote-development-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetEscapades.​AspNetCore.​SecurityHeaders 1.0.0 has been released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe the recent major changes to NetEscapades.AspNetCore.SecurityHeaders, a NuGet package for adding security headers to your apps.
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/netescapades-aspnetcore-securityheaders-1-0-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q1 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Option to Cancel Continuity Discounts JetBrains Marketplace now allows plugin authors to cancel continuity discounts for paid plugins. This can be done easily from the Sales tab, with the option to set a specific end date. Customers with active subscriptions for existing plugins will still benefit from the discount, while for new […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q1-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Region Selection in Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer for NoSQL Accounts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You asked—we delivered! Users can now manually select the region Data Explorer sends requests to! When you use Entra Authentication with NoSQL accounts, you can now enable the Region Selection option in settings. This new capability gives you precise control over where your requests are sent, helping you test, troubleshoot, and optimize performance by targeting […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-region-selection-in-azure-cosmos-db-data-explorer-for-nosql-accounts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build multi-agent systems with LangGraph and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to integrate open-source multi-agent framework, LangGraph, with Amazon Bedrock. It explains how to use LangGraph and Amazon Bedrock to build powerful, interactive multi-agent applications that use graph-based orchestration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-multi-agent-systems-with-langgraph-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic text-to-SQL for enterprise workloads with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how enterprises can implement a scalable agentic text-to-SQL solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents, with advanced error-handling tools and automated schema discovery to enhance database query efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dynamic-text-to-sql-for-enterprise-workloads-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: Once I have tricked the user into running a malicious shortcut, I can install malware</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yes, that&#39;s sort of the point.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250414-00/?p=111072 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell, OpenSSH, and DSC team investments for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Planned team investments for 2025 for PowerShell, OpenSSH, DSC, and related tooling.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/powershell-openssh-and-dsc-team-investments-for-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind K2 Mode and How It Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m Yan Zhulanow, and I lead the Kotlin Analysis API team. Last year, we made a series of announcements about Kotlin K2 mode in IntelliJ IDEA. Now, as K2 mode is about to become the default, I am thrilled to tell you more about everything we had to go through to make this release happen. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/the-story-behind-k2-mode-and-how-it-works/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and Anthropic Collaborate to Develop Official C# SDK for Model Context Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced a partnership with Anthropic to develop an official C# Software Development Kit (SDK) for the Model Context Protocol (MCP). This collaboration aims to streamline the integration of large language models (LLMs) into C# applications, addressing the growing demand for advanced AI functionalities in enterprise software development. Enhancing AI Integration in C# Applications […] The article Microsoft and Anthropic Collaborate to Develop Official C# SDK for Model Context Protocol was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview of (Hopefully) Improved Projections in Marten 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 01:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Work is continuing on the “Critter Stack 2025” round of releases, but we have finally got an alpha release of Marten 8 (8.0.0-alpha-5) that’s good enough for friendly users and core team members to try out for feedback. 8.0 won’t be a huge release, but we’re making some substantial changes to the projections subsystem and … Continue reading Preview of (Hopefully) Improved Projections in Marten 8 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling MCP Servers in C# with Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I posted recently about how to allow LLMs to call tools using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI NuGet package in C#. Obviously, a common usage scenario would be to expose MCP servers as tools for your LLM to call. Thankfully, the new ModelContextProtocol NuGet package makes this straightforward. Note: This package is still in pre-release (as is Microsoft.Extensions.AI), so do check the release notes for any breaking changes to the API. I&#39;ve updated my demo application to support calling MCP tools, following the techniques demonstrated in Microsoft&#39;s Chat With Tools sample.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Best Practices and Performance for Comparing Strings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_04_2025/13_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_04_2025/13_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In .NET, string comparison can be performed using methods like ==, Equals(), and Compare(), each with distinct performance metrics. The most efficient method is Equals() with StringComparison. It&#39;s crucial to apply optimization practices for enhanced performance, especially in multilingual comparisons, and consider utilizing configuration files for consistent analysis.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/13/microsoft-net-code-analysis-best-practices-and-performance-for-comparing-strings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Vector Search? A Concise Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_04_2025/12_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_04_2025/12_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vector search finds information based on meaning rather than exact keywords, delivering more intuitive results by converting content into numerical vectors that capture semantic relationships.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/what-is-vector-search-a-concise-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
