<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:31:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visier’s data science team boosts their model output 10 times by migrating to Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we learn how Visier was able to boost their model output by 10 times, accelerate innovation cycles, and unlock new opportunities using Amazon SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/visiers-data-science-team-boosts-their-model-output-10-times-by-migrating-to-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement model-independent safety measures with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how you can use the ApplyGuardrail API in common generative AI architectures such as third-party or self-hosted large language models (LLMs), or in a self-managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) architecture.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-model-independent-safety-measures-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Account management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 14:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Microsoft 365 Certification validates account management controls are in place for your application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-account-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect whether the user is running as an elevated administrator (as opposed to a natural administrator)?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can ask for the elevation type.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241003-00/?p=110336 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your project structure simple!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 21:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What should your project structure look like? How should you structure and organize your HTTP APIs? Here’s one way by Jono Williams and my thoughts and insights about some misconceptions about Domain Driven Design. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in this… Read More »Keep your project structure simple! The post Keep your project structure simple!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Schneider Electric uses Amazon Bedrock to identify high-potential business opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 20:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how the team at Schneider collaborated with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to build a generative AI solution on Amazon Bedrock to solve this problem. The solution processes and evaluates each requests for proposal (RFP) and then routes high-value RFPs to the microgrid subject matter expert (SME) for approval and recommendation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-schneider-electric-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-identify-high-potential-business-opportunities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve operational excellence with well-architected generative AI solutions using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss scaling up generative AI for different lines of businesses (LOBs) and address the challenges that come around legal, compliance, operational complexities, data privacy and security.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-operational-excellence-with-well-architected-generative-ai-solutions-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate workforce productivity through seamless personalization in Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Q Business uses personalization to improve the relevance of responses and how you can align your use cases and end-user data to take full advantage of this capability
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-workforce-productivity-through-seamless-personalization-in-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for building robust generative AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Agents – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to create accurate and reliable agents. Agents helps you accelerate generative AI application development by orchestrating multistep tasks. Agents use the reasoning capability of foundation models (FMs) to break down user-requested tasks into multiple steps.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-for-building-robust-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-agents-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover the New Azure Cosmos DB Samples Gallery!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 18:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to introduce the Azure Cosmos DB Samples Gallery —your ultimate destination for top-tier Azure Cosmos DB samples, technical guidance, and content created by both Microsoft and the community, including Azure OpenAI samples. Who is it for? Designed for developers and technical professionals, this gallery is an invaluable resource for both new and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/new-samples-gallery 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.2-1 and 1.22.8-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 17:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-2-1-and-1-22-8-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the power of app analytics for ISVs in the Developer Portal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 17:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read about the updated app analytics capabilities in the Microsoft 365 Developer Portal.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/unlocking-the-power-of-app-analytics-for-isvs-in-the-developer-portal 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest enhancements to Copilot workflows in Visual Studio: Move seamlessly from Copilot in Quick Info and more…</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 16:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There have been new integrations added to Copilot workflows in Visual Studio to make it even more seamless to navigate between in-editor activities and the Chat window that has context of global workspace, conversational history, and more to get the most out of Copilot, wherever you are. With the latest updates, you can streamline your […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/latest-enhancements-to-copilot-workflows-in-visual-studio-move-seamlessly-from-copilot-in-quick-info-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 4: Updated Run Widget, Support for Maven’s Split Local Repositories, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 4 is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 4 If you missed our previous overviews of the newly added features, visit the IntelliJ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A function for creating an absolute security descriptor from a self-relative one</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just wrap it up.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241002-00/?p=110333 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover Hidden Insights with Profiler’s External Code Decompilation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever wondered what’s happening under the hood of your .NET application? Do you want to quickly and easily identify and fix performance bottlenecks? If so, Visual Studio has the perfect tool for you: the profiler. The profiler allows you to analyze your code’s performance, pinpoint hot paths, detect memory leaks, address thread contention, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/discover-hidden-insights-with-profilers-external-code-decompilation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt AI Directly in the Editor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 06:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With PyCharm, you now have the support of AI Assistant at your fingertips. You can interact with it right where you do most of your work – in the editor. Stuck with an error in your code? Need to add documentation or tests? Just start typing your request on a new line in the editor, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/prompt-ai-directly-in-the-editor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi Step Workflows with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 20:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m working with a JasperFx Software client who is in the beginning stages of building a pretty complex, multi-step file import process that is going to involve several different services. For the sake of example code in this post, let’s say that we have the (much simplified from my client’s actual logical workflow) workflow from … Continue reading Multi Step Workflows with the Critter Stack →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/10/01/multi-step-workflows-with-the-critter-stack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the stable release of the Azure OpenAI library for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 20:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The stable release of the Azure OpenAI library for .NET is now available and it includes support for the entire OpenAI API, GPT-4o, and o1-preview models.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/announcing-the-stable-release-of-the-azure-openai-library-for-net 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using JSON Schema for Structured Output in .NET for OpenAI Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 19:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In one of the previous posts, we demonstrated how to use JSON Schema to get Structured Output with OpenAI and Python version of Semantic Kernel: Using JSON Schema for Structured Output in Python for OpenAI Models. In this post, we will explore how to implement a JSON Schema-based structured output using .NET version of Semantic […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/using-json-schema-for-structured-output-in-net-for-openai-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 3.13 and the Latest Trends: A Developer’s Guide to 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 19:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We invite you to join us in just two days time, on October 3 at 5:00 pm CEST (11:00 am EDT), for a livestream shining a spotlight on Python 3.13 and the trends shaping its development. Our speakers: They will discuss the most notable features of Python 3.13 and examine the industry trends likely to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/python-3-13-and-the-latest-trends-a-developer-s-guide-to-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the stable release of the official OpenAI library for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the stable release of the official OpenAI library for .NET, empowering developers to integrate cutting-edge AI models, including GPT-4o &amp;amp; o1, into their .NET applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-the-stable-release-of-the-official-open-ai-library-for-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the OpenAPI Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 18:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An introduction to the OpenAPI blog, what it is, and what you can expect to find here.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/openapi/welcome-post 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS recognized as a first-time Leader in the 2024 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 18:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS has been recognized as a Leader in the 2024 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms. The post highlights how AWS&#39;s continued innovations in services like Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker have enabled organizations to unlock the transformative potential of generative AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-recognized-as-a-first-time-leader-in-the-2024-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-data-science-and-machine-learning-platforms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless voice-based contextual chatbot for people with disabilities using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we presented how to create a fully serverless voice-based contextual chatbot using Amazon Bedrock with Anthropic Claude.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-voice-based-contextual-chatbot-for-people-with-disabilities-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Private Preview: Read and Read/Write Privileges with Secondary Users for vCore-Based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the private preview of a new feature in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB —Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) Integration for Secondary Users with Read/Read Write Privileges. This enhancement is designed to give organizations more granular control over their database security while maintaining the flexibility and performance that vCore-based Azure Cosmos […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-private-preview-read-and-read-write-privileges-with-secondary 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misunderstanding the “Prevent access to registry editing tools” policy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It prevents access to the tools, but not to the registry itself.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241001-22/?p=110330 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintain access and consider alternatives for Amazon Monitron</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses how customers can maintain access to Amazon Monitron after it is closed to new customers and what some alternatives are to Amazon Monitron.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maintain-access-and-consider-alternatives-for-amazon-monitron/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Blogs to Follow in 2024 – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 15:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a world full of endless articles and tutorials, it’s easy to become overwhelmed by unreliable or irrelevant information. With so much out there, how do you separate the good from the great? This is where we come in! We’ve prepared two articles in which we’ve handpicked the coolest Java blogs that cut through the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/top-java-blogs-to-follow-in-2024-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm’s Interactive Tables for Data Science</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data cleaning, exploration, and visualization are some of the most time-consuming tasks for data scientists. Nearly 50% of data specialists dedicate 30% or more of their time to data preparation. The pandas and Polars libraries are widely used for these purposes, each offering unique advantages. PyCharm supports both libraries, enabling users to efficiently explore, clean, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/10/interactive-tables-for-data-science/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2022 – Recent performance enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 continues to be faster with each version. In this blog post we will highlight a couple of the more significant enhancements you’ll experience in 17.11, such as a more efficient C# language service, faster conditional breakpoints and symbol searches in C++. Reduced CPU usage by C# language service Code Indexing In 17.10 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2022-recent-performance-enhancements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing TeamCity AWS Agents’ Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the key components of TeamCity’s ecosystem is the bundled Amazon Cloud Agents plugin, which allows our customers to leverage cloud agents to scale the performance of their build farms on demand. Given its widespread use and importance, ensuring its optimal performance is essential. As our user base and workload have grown, we’ve noticed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/enhancing-teamcity-aws-agents-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown-Powered Slides in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we have a JetBrains Community Contributor (JBCC) program aimed at helping community content creators get the most out of their JetBrains tools when creating articles, social media posts, videos, and public presentations. It’s a fantastic program where we try to provide help and feedback and learn from each other. One innovative idea we’ve […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/10/01/markdown-powered-slides-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Resolution Timers on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 13:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Go Windows port added support for high-resolution timers in Go 1.23, boosting the resolution of time.Sleep from ~15.6ms to ~0.5ms.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/high-resolution-timers-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Best Practices: Using Tags and Labels to Manage Docker Image Sprawl</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 12:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn best practices for using tags and labels to manage image sprawl in Docker container workflows.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-best-practices-using-tags-and-labels-to-manage-docker-image-sprawl/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation of the macOS-12 Hosted Pipeline Image</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 12:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure DevOps is starting the deprecation process for the macOS-12 (Monterey) hosted pilelines image. While the image is being deprecated, you may experience longer queue times during peak usage hours. Deprecation will begin on October 7 and the image will be fully unsupported by December 3. Pipeline jobs using the macOS-12 image label should be […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/upcoming-deprecation-of-macos-12-hosted-pipeline-image 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.07.3 Bug Fix Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 10:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The TeamCity On-Premises 2024.07.3 bug fix is now available for installation! This update tackles around 20 issues, including problems with failing SSH agents on Windows, incorrect counts of pending changes and available agents, unexpected build cancellations, and more. Each bug fix not only improves performance, but also patches security vulnerabilities, making it highly recommended to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/teamcity-2024-07-3-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major updates to NetEscapades.​AspNetCore.​SecurityHeaders</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe the recent major changes to NetEscapades.AspNetCore.SecurityHeaders, a NuGet package for adding security headers to your apps.
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/major-updates-to-netescapades-aspnetcore-security-headers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Code Readability and Manageability in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 09:23:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Software development, code readability transforms complexity into clarity. Martin Fowler said:
Any fool can write code that a computer can understand. Good programmers write code that humans can understand.
Code should be readable and manageable so other developers can understand and work without additional fatigue. .NET has many ways asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/boosting-code-readability-and-manageability-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.21 with simulating authentication and authorization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 07:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover what&#39;s new in the latest version of Dev Proxy to help you build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-21-with-simulating-authentication-and-authorization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use IHttpClientFactory and WireMock.NET together using Moq</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WireMock.NET is a popular library used to simulate network communication through HTTP. But there is no simple way to integrate the generated in-memory server with an instance of IHttpClientFactory injected via constructor. Right? Wrong!
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/wiremock-ihttpclientfactory-moq/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Event Projections and Subscriptions with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The feature set shown in this post was built earlier this year at the behest of a JasperFx Software client who has some unusually high data throughput and wanted to have some significant ability to scale up Marten and Wolverine‘s ability to handle a huge number of incoming events. We originally put this into what … Continue reading Scaling Event Projections and Subscriptions with the Critter Stack →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import a question answering fine-tuned model into Amazon Bedrock as a custom model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a step-by-step approach of fine-tuning a Mistral model using SageMaker and import it into Amazon Bedrock using the Custom Import Model feature.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/import-a-question-answering-fine-tuned-model-into-amazon-bedrock-as-a-custom-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using task-specific models from AI21 Labs on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will show you how to leverage AI21 Labs’ Task-Specific Models (TSMs) on AWS to enhance your business operations. You will learn the steps to subscribe to AI21 Labs in the AWS Marketplace, set up a domain in Amazon SageMaker, and utilize AI21 TSMs via SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-task-specific-models-from-ai21-labs-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability (GA) of Native Authentication for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the General Availability (GA) of Native Authentication for Microsoft Entra External ID! A feature that allows you to design and control the sign-in experience within your mobile apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/native-auth-for-external-id-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing seamless authentication with Power Pages and Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the public preview of Microsoft Entra External ID as an identity provider for Microsoft Power Pages, streamlining authentication for your external-facing apps. With Power Pages, you can launch a website in minutes, and External ID provides robust tools to secure external identities, with extensive customization options available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-id-and-power-pages 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio at Unreal Fest Seattle 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us in-person at Unreal Fest Seattle 2024 with an in-depth look at how Visual Studio and GitHub Copilot can help modernize your Unreal Engine game development. Session Title: Modernizing Game Development with Visual Studio and AI Session Info: October 3rd, 2024, 2:00 PM-3:00 PM Pacific Time | Room 445 Abstract: Join Microsoft to learn […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-at-unreal-fest-seattle-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Docker for DevOps: What It Is and How It Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We explore the use of Docker for DevOps and explain how the combination can help developers create more efficient and powerful workflows.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-for-devops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – September Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “Wake me up when September ends,” goes the famous song, and here we are! The JetBrains Academy team is back with updates: fresh courses, IT clubs for school students, and ways to boost your portfolio with real-world projects and certificates. Wake up and dive into the tech world with our latest digest!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/09/30/jetbrains-academy-july-digest-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling a single item from a C&#43;&#43; parameter pack by its index, remarks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why such a complicated way to pull the type from the pack?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240930-00/?p=110324 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 IntelliJ IDEA Shortcuts for Efficient Data Querying With the Database Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thanks to the dedicated SQL query console inside IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate’s Database Tools, you can easily modify and extract data from any database connected to your Java application without ever leaving the IDE. The query console comes with an SQL statement-specific code snippets library, code completion, on-the-fly error detection, and useful shortcuts – all to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/top-10-shortcuts-for-efficient-data-querying/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Big Deal About Endpoints for Python Web Development?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Python has almost 30 years of history doing Python web development. Can you believe it? But 3-tier web projects have gotten really complicated and stressful. You’re busy, everything is all over the place – it’s hard! But PyCharm is here to help: bring your work together with the Endpoints tool window. I just made a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/python-web-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling HSTS for localhost using a browser extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Http Strict Transport Security (HSTS) is a security mechanism that instructs the browser to automatically redirect http requests to https before sending a request to the server. When you are developing a web application, you should disable HSTS for localhost. This is because enabling HSTS on localhost has implications for other applications. For instance, some applications start a local web server and…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/avoid-hsts-issues-on-localhost.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless Instrumentation profiling with Persistent Target Selection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 10:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever wished to assess your code’s performance without repeatedly choosing the target process or executable for each instrumentation profiling session? If so, you’re among many developers who find this task cumbersome and prone to errors, especially when profiling the same target repeatedly. We understand your frustration and have a solution: Visual Studio 2022 introduces a […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/effortless-instrumentation-profiling-with-persistent-target-selection 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Recommendations for a Test Automation Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 01:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve been helping a JasperFx Software client with their test automation strategy on a new web application and surrounding suite of services. That makes this a perfectly good time to reevaluate how I think teams can succeed with automated testing as an update to what I thought a decade ago. I think you can justifiably … Continue reading My Recommendations for a Test Automation Strategy →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/29/my-recommendations-for-a-test-automation-strategy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Collection Extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2024/29_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2024/29_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages, offering enhanced functionality for ICollection collections. Features include AddIf, AddRange, AsReadOnlySpan, Upsert, and more. Detailed benchmark results are available on GitHub, and community involvement is encouraged for further improvements. Contact dotnetdave@live.com for contributions or inquiries.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/09/29/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-collection-extensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 中的工作区</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2024/29_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 04:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2024/29_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            亡羊补牢，犹未为晚！ 如果要用一句谚语来形容一下本文要介绍的新功能 – IntelliJ IDEA 中对工作区的支持 – 这句恐怕再贴切不过了。 简介 简单来说，工作区是一个元项目，可让您同时管理多个项目。 无论是协调复杂的开发环境，还是同时处理几个不相关的项目，此功能都非常实用。 急性子须知：下文会涉及一些理论和历史，如果您迫不及待想在 IDE 中使用工作区，请直接跳到如何使用工作区一节立即体验！ 此外，您还可以收看这期在线讲座以获取更多详细信息。 请注意，这项功能目前处于预览阶段，因此您可能会遇到一些 Bug 和限制。 自 2011 年以来，我们的问题跟踪器中就一直有关于工作区支持的工单。 不过，随着 2010 年代中期微服务和单仓库的兴起，工作区似乎失去了开发的必要。 单仓库模型与 IntelliJ IDEA 侧重的“一个项目 – 多个模块”方式完全契合。 然而，用户对工作区的需求依旧在持续增长，这一点可以从 YouTrack 上不断增加的赞和支持性评论中得到证实。 接下来，我们将探究一下为什么时至今日用户仍然需要工作区。 为什么单仓库并没有取代工作区方式 相比其他代码安排（即多仓库）方式，单仓库确实有诸多优势，例如： 改善协作。 所有开发者都能即时查看项目其他部分的进展情况。 只要代码一提交，所有更改都会一目了然。 如果要实现的服务需要与其他团队开发的服务交互，开发者可以查看对方的代码，深入了解其运作方式。 简化依赖项管理。 在大多数情况下，单仓库中的所有项目均使用相同的软件包管理和构建工具，便于跟踪依赖项和版本。 而且，单仓库中的所有应用程序组件通常一起发布，这就规避了项目间依赖项出现问题的风险。 跨项目重构。 由于能够访问整个代码库，IDE 可以为代码引用编制索引，从而能够检测到更改并轻松进行正确的重构。 提升代码的可发现性。 新加入团队的成员可以轻松浏览整个代码库，理解不同项目和组件间的依赖关系。 如果您签出一个单仓码库并用 IntelliJ IDEA 打开，会发现单仓库的结构完美契合“项目-模块”范式。 根文件夹被视为一个“项目”，所有子文件夹则变为“模块”。 因此，从这个角度来看，该模型似乎运行良好，工作区功能的实现可以往后推迟。 不过，单仓库也存在一些不足： […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/workspaces-in-intellij-idea 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You REALLY Need To Write Tests? – Dev Leader Weekly 63</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2024/28_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2024/28_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Do You REALLY Need To Write Tests? – Dev Leader Weekly 63 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss situations where we may or may not want or need to write tests! The post Do You REALLY Need To Write Tests? – Dev Leader Weekly 63 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/09/28/do-you-really-need-to-write-tests-dev-leader-weekly-63/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking It Down: How to Migrate Your Modular Monolith to Microservices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2024/28_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2024/28_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transitioning from a modular monolith to microservices can significantly enhance your system&#39;s scalability and your team&#39;s productivity, but it&#39;s a journey that requires careful planning and execution. In this practical guide, I&#39;ll walk you through the key steps of this migration process, from preparing your monolith and selecting the right module to extract, to implementing effective inter-service communication and data migration strategies, all based on real-world experience with .NET applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture to AWS CloudFormation code using Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 21:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore some ways you can use Anthropic’s Claude 3 Sonnet’s vision capabilities to accelerate the process of moving from architecture to the prototype stage of a solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/architecture-to-aws-cloudformation-code-using-anthropics-claude-3-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Northpower used computer vision with AWS to automate safety inspection risk assessments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 21:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Northpower has worked with their technology partner Sculpt to reduce the effort and carbon required to identify and remediate public safety risks. Specifically, we cover the computer vision and artificial intelligence (AI) techniques used to combine datasets into a list of prioritized tasks for field teams to investigate and mitigate.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-northpower-used-computer-vision-with-aws-to-automate-safety-inspection-risk-assessments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Semantic Kernel for Java 1.3.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 17:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello again Java AI developers! We are announcing the 1.3.0 release of the Semantic Kernel for Java. You can find our updates on the GitHub repository and the artifacts on Maven Central. This release will mark the final experimental version of our Vector Store functionality. Vector search is now available across all our supported vector stores. We’ve implemented approximate search […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-semantic-kernel-for-java-1-3-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (September 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 17:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure SDKs release every month. This post includes the month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-september-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SK Python Kernel Reaches 1,000,000 downloads</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 15:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce that Microsoft Semantic Kernel Python Kernel has reached an incredible milestone of 1,000,000 downloads! This achievement would not have been possible without the unwavering support and enthusiasm of our community. We want to extend our heartfelt thanks to every developer, contributor, and user who has embraced the Python Kernel, providing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/sk-python-kernel-reaches-1000000-downloads 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the crash when destructing a std::map</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Who is corrupting the map?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240927-00/?p=110320 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards, September Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 13:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            September was a productive month for Azure Boards, and we’re excited to share some of the new features coming your way. Area and Iteration Level Fields Area and iteration level fields have been crucial for querying or displaying results based on their specific levels: (Root) Level 1 / Level 2 / Level 3 / etc. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-boards-september-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PromptFlow Serve – Benchmark Result Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we discuss how to test the throughput of PromptFlow pf-serve module and key learnings doing so. We explore the impact on throughput and performance the different WSGI and ASGI hosting methods have and the importance of engineering your Python nodes with the async await pattern for I/O.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/promptflow-performance-testing-analysis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenAI for Aerospace: Empowering the workforce with expert knowledge on Amazon Q and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 18:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we show how you can quickly launch generative AI-enabled expert chatbots, trained on your proprietary document sets, to empower your workforce across specific aerospace roles with Amazon Q and Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/genai-for-aerospace-empowering-the-workforce-with-expert-knowledge-on-amazon-q-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable training platform with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod for innovation: a video generation case study</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 18:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share an ML infrastructure architecture that uses SageMaker HyperPod to support research team innovation in video generation. We will discuss the advantages and pain points addressed by SageMaker HyperPod, provide a step-by-step setup guide, and demonstrate how to run a video generation algorithm on the cluster.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scalable-training-platform-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-for-innovation-a-video-generation-case-study/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.1-3 and 1.22.7-3 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 18:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-1-3-and-1-22-7-3-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using JSON Schema for Structured Output in Python for OpenAI Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In working with AI applications, ensuring that the output generated by a language model is structured and follows a consistent format is critical—especially when handling complex tasks like solving math problems. A powerful way to achieve this is through the use of JSON Schema, which allows the AI model to produce outputs that align with […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/using-json-schema-for-structured-output-in-python-for-openai-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control data access to Amazon S3 from Amazon SageMaker Studio with Amazon S3 Access Grants</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to simplify data access to Amazon S3 from SageMaker Studio using S3 Access Grants, specifically for different user personas using IAM principals.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/control-data-access-to-amazon-s3-from-amazon-sagemaker-studio-with-amazon-s3-access-grants/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 3: Smarter Inline AI Prompts, Improved Terraform and OpenTofu Support, Kubernetes and Docker Compose Updates, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 3 has been released, and it’s packed with new features for you to try out! This build brings inline AI prompts with context awareness, extended support for Terraform, including the new OpenTofu project, notable updates for Kubernetes and Docker Compose, and improvements to remote development environments. You can download this version […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing SharePoint Framework 1.20 with updates on building enterprise extensibility within Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce general availability for the SharePoint Framework 1.20. This time focus is primarily on the Microsoft Viva platform capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-sharepoint-framework-1-20-with-updates-on-building-enterprise-extensibility-within-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Code Completions for C&#43;&#43; Developers: Fine-tuned models are now in limited public beta for GitHub Copilot Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub recently announced that custom models are available for GitHub Copilot Enterprise users in limited public beta. Custom models are fine-tuned on your organization’s proprietary codebases and coding practices to provide more contextually relevant and consistent inline suggestions. How It Works: Security and Privacy in Custom Models The data used to train your organization’s custom […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/tailored-code-completions-for-c-developers-fine-tuned-models-are-now-in-limited-public-beta-for-github-copilot-enterprise 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a chatbot on your own data in 1 hour with Azure SQL, Langchain and Chainlit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Chatbots are the hot topic lately, and now you can create them easily by downloading solutions like OpenWebUI, connect it to Ollama or any OpenAI compatible API, choose your favorite language model, and then run it. It just takes a few minutes and it’s done. But building chatbots is not enough, you most likely want […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-a-chatbot-on-your-own-data-in-1-hour-with-azure-sql-langchain-and-chainlit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you’re going to specify the LVS_SORTASCENDING or LVS_SORTDESCENDING style, you had better be telling the truth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Because the listview control uses it to optimize searching.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240926-00/?p=110316 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Kotlin Heroes: Episode 11 – Your Chance to Win Great Prizes and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 12:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Competitive programming is a fantastic way to sharpen your problem-solving skills in a programming language that you already know, or to explore new programming languages. The Kotlin Heroes contest is the perfect platform for that! Whether you’re a beginner or an experienced coder, Kotlin Heroes gives you the opportunity to challenge yourself, master or learn […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/09/join-kotlin-heroes-episode-11/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a React TODO app in Visual Studio 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this tutorial we will create a React front-end, with JavaScript, of a TODO web app using a Visual Studio 2022. To get started install Visual Studio with the Node.js development workload. This will include the JavaScript/TypeScript (JSTS) projects and the associated support. The code for this app can be found at sayedihashimi/todojswebapp (github.com). Create […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/creating-a-react-todo-app-in-visual-studio-2022 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django Project Ideas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 09:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ready to get started on your Django project? Whether you want to build a personal project, improve your portfolio, or just experiment with a new technology, Django provides the perfect foundation. We’ve compiled a list of Django project ideas that will help you expand your competence, whether you’re new to the framework or looking to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/django-project-ideas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
