<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s EncryptionHelper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2024/29_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2024/29_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a set of open-source .NET 8 packages created by the author since .NET 2, currently in production. It includes the EncryptionHelper class, which offers efficient methods for data encryption, key generation, and password verification.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/12/29/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-encryptionhelper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Rewriting a 40-Year-Old Project Taught Me About Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_12_2024/28_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_12_2024/28_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When tasked with modernizing a 40-year-old manufacturing system written in APL, I faced both technical complexity and organizational challenges that shaped my understanding of successful software development. This article shares key lessons learned during a four-year journey of rewriting critical legacy code while keeping a $10M business running smoothly.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/what-rewriting-a-40-year-old-project-taught-me-about-software-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marten V7.35 Drops for a Little Post Christmas Cheer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_12_2024/27_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 23:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_12_2024/27_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            And of course, JasperFx Software is available for any kind of consulting engagement around the Critter Stack tools, event sourcing, event driven architecture, test automation, or just any kind of server side .NET architecture. Absurdly enough, the Marten community made one major release (7.0 was a big change) and 35 different releases of new functionality. … Continue reading Marten V7.35 Drops for a Little Post Christmas Cheer →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In C&#43;&#43;, failure to meet the requirements does not always mean that you fail if you don’t meet the requirements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_12_2024/27_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_12_2024/27_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Combining SFINAE/requires, standard layout, and overload resolution.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241227-00/?p=110681 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical: .NET Install links are changing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_12_2024/27_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_12_2024/27_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET installers and archives distribution method is currently changing unexpectedly. This change may impact your development, CI, and production infrastructure. It is crucial to validate if you are affected and monitor for any downtime or disruptions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/critical-dotnet-install-links-are-changing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing costs of generative AI applications on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2024/26_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2024/26_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Optimizing costs of generative AI applications on AWS is critical for realizing the full potential of this transformative technology. The post outlines key cost optimization pillars, including model selection and customization, token usage, inference pricing plans, and vector database considerations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-costs-of-generative-ai-applications-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are Win32 resources strings bundled at all? And why bundles of 16?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2024/26_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_12_2024/26_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Balancing multiple performance factors.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241226-00/?p=110679 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I check if two GUIDs are equal when they are provided as strings?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2024/25_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_12_2024/25_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer asked if there was a helper function in the system that accepted two strings and reported whether the GUIDs they represent are equal. This is a tricky question, because you first have to decide what “represent” means. There are many ways of representing a GUID as a string. It could be just 32 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241225-00/?p=110677 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 16:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced the retirement of the azureedge.net domain by January 15, 2025, driven by Edgio’s (formerly Limelight Networks) business closure. This domain underpins Azure CDN services, .NET installations, and content delivery for various Azure and Microsoft services. The shift requires developers and DevOps teams to update configurations, pipelines, and deployment practices to ensure continuity. […] The article Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PEFT fine tuning of Llama 3 on SageMaker HyperPod with AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 15:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we showcase how you can perform efficient supervised fine tuning for a Meta Llama 3 model using PEFT on AWS Trainium with SageMaker HyperPod. We use HuggingFace’s Optimum-Neuron software development kit (SDK) to apply LoRA to fine-tuning jobs, and use SageMaker HyperPod as the primary compute cluster to perform distributed training on Trainium. Using LoRA supervised fine-tuning for Meta Llama 3 models, you can further reduce your cost to fine tune models by up to 50% and reduce the training time by 70%.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A design flaw in the Windows 3D Pipes screen saver pointed out by a customer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Time-wasting.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241224-00/?p=110675 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect securely to your Azure resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2024/24_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022’s Connected Services features are being updated to help you start secure. In the past, for example with Azure Storage, we’d inject the entire connection string into your configuration. With this update, we’ve removed the secrets from the UX – and from what we save to configuration – altogether. This means your code […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/connect-securely-to-your-azure-resources 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Model Context Protocol: Simplifying Building AI apps with Anthropic Claude Desktop and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anthropic recently unveiled the Model Context Protocol (MCP), a new standard for connecting AI assistants and models to reliable data and tools. However, packaging and distributing MCP servers is very challenging due to complex environment setups across multiple architectures and operating systems. Docker is the perfect solution for this – it allows developers to encapsulate […]
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/the-model-context-protocol-simplifying-building-ai-apps-with-anthropic-claude-desktop-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phi-4: Microsoft’s New Small Language Model Outperforms Giants in AI Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 21:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Artificial Intelligence and Large Language Models (LLMs), bigger has often better. LLMs like OpenAI’s GPT-4o and Google’s Gemini Pro have dominated headlines for their massive scale and capabilities. However, Microsoft is redefining this narrative with Phi-4, a 14-billion parameter small language model (SLM) that delivers exceptional performance, rivaling models many times its size. Phi-4 […] The article Phi-4: Microsoft’s New Small Language Model Outperforms Giants in AI Reasoning was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – December Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the new year, the JetBrains Academy team wants your IT skills to shine brighter than a Christmas tree! 🎄 This newsletter is packed with global trends in computer science education, must-read books, tips for university entrance exams, IT contests, and some holiday presents to help you level up your skills. 🎁 Enjoy the gift, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/12/23/jetbrains-academy-december-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top .NET Blogs Posts of 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s take a look back at the top .NET blogs from 2024 from exciting announcements, deep dives on new features, and so much more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/top-dotnet-blogs-posts-of-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Office Add-ins Development Kit GA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Office Add-ins Development Kit for Visual Studio Code is now generally available! After months of public preview, we&#39;ve gathered invaluable feedback from the community and improved the experience.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/office-add-ins-development-kit-ga-announcement 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A common proposed solution to certain categories of IFNDR: Getting the linker to verify identical functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You could do it, but it could cramp your style.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241223-00/?p=110672 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using transcription confidence scores to improve slot filling in Amazon Lex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building voice-enabled chatbots with Amazon Lex, one of the biggest challenges is accurately capturing user speech input for slot values. Transcription confidence scores can help ensure reliable slot filling. This blog post outlines strategies like progressive confirmation, adaptive re-prompting, and branching logic to create more robust slot filling experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-transcription-confidence-scores-to-improve-slot-filling-in-amazon-lex/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Retrieval Augmented Generation accuracy with GraphRAG</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Lettria, an AWS Partner, demonstrated that integrating graph-based structures into RAG workflows improves answer precision by up to 35% compared to vector-only retrieval methods. In this post, we explore why GraphRAG is more comprehensive and explainable than vector RAG alone, and how you can use this approach using AWS services and Lettria.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improving-retrieval-augmented-generation-accuracy-with-graphrag/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security updates to Azure publishing from Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 introduces a new feature to improve the security of publishing applications to Azure App Service. This feature is designed to disable Basic Authentication and enable integrated security for a more secure publishing process. Basic Authentication has been identified as a less secure method for managing app deployments. Visual Studio 2022 addresses this […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/security-updates-to-azure-publishing-from-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading USN Journal with .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you want to detect when a file is created, modified, or deleted, you can use the FileSystemWatcher class in .NET. However, this is only available when the application is running. What if you want to detect changes that occurred while the application was not running? The USN Journal is a feature of the NTFS and ReFS file systems that keeps track of changes to files and directories. It allows…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Query Filters in Entity Framework Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 04:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_12_2024/23_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss Entity Framework Core’s global query filters and how to use them. We will also consider other scenarios related to using query filters that we need to be aware of. Let’s dive in. What Is a Global Query Filter? Global query filters are a handy feature of Entity Framework (EF) […] The post Global Query Filters in Entity Framework Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
