<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 17:55:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (April 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 17:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure SDK releases every month. In this post, you find this month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-april-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Azure Cosmos DB Using the Python SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 16:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re new to Azure Cosmos DB and looking to build applications with Python, you’re in the right place. I’ve created a four-part video series designed to take you from the basics to practical, real-world querying techniques—no prior experience required. Whether you’re setting up your first database, learning how to model your data, or optimizing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/getting-started-with-azure-cosmos-db-using-the-python-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build and deliver an MCP server for production</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 16:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In December of 2024, we published a blog with Anthropic about their totally new spec (back then) to run tools with AI agents: the Model Context Protocol, or MCP. Since then, we’ve seen an explosion in developer appetite to build, share, and run their tools with Agentic AI – all using MCP. We’ve seen new […]
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-to-prod-mcp-servers-with-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Xi’an Jiaotong-Liverpool University scaled hands-on learning with Microsoft Dev Box</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 16:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI and data science rapidly reshape industries, universities worldwide are rethinking how they deliver hands-on learning. At Xi’an Jiaotong-Liverpool University (XJTLU) in China, the School of AI and Advanced Computing embraced Microsoft Dev Box to give students a modern, scalable, and real-world development environment—right from their first year. Here’s how XJTLU transformed their curriculum […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/how-xian-jiaotong-liverpool-university-scaled-hands-on-learning-with-microsoft-dev-box 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If we can have std::atomic&lt;std::shared_ptr&gt;, why not std::atomic&lt;com_ptr&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Controlling the reference count.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250425-00/?p=111118 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Douglas Crockford – The Man Behind JSON and JSLint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2025/25_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Douglas Crockford is a renowned figure in the programming world, celebrated for his pivotal contributions to JavaScript and the creation of JSON (JavaScript Object Notation). While not traditionally categorized under cloud computing, his innovations have profoundly influenced web technologies that underpin modern cloud services. This profile delves into Crockford’s journey, highlighting his impact on the […] The article Big Thinkers: Douglas Crockford – The Man Behind JSON and JSLint was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) in a real-life scenario</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shares some useful tips and lessons learned while using azd during a migration.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-in-a-real-life-scenario 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise-grade natural language to SQL generation using LLMs: Balancing accuracy, latency, and scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 16:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, the AWS and Cisco teams unveil a new methodical approach that addresses the challenges of enterprise-grade SQL generation. The teams were able to reduce the complexity of the NL2SQL process while delivering higher accuracy and better overall performance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enterprise-grade-natural-language-to-sql-generation-using-llms-balancing-accuracy-latency-and-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Field Experience reduced cost and delivered low latency and high performance with Amazon Nova Lite foundation model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 16:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AFX team’s product migration to the Nova Lite model has delivered tangible enterprise value by enhancing sales workflows. By migrating to the Amazon Nova Lite model, the team has not only achieved significant cost savings and reduced latency, but has also empowered sellers with a leading intelligent and reliable solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-field-experience-reduced-cost-and-delivered-low-latency-and-high-performance-with-amazon-nova-lite-foundation-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combine keyword and semantic search for text and images using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon OpenSearch Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 16:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through how to build a hybrid search solution using OpenSearch Service powered by multimodal embeddings from the Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings G1 model through Amazon Bedrock. This solution demonstrates how you can enable users to submit both text and images as queries to retrieve relevant results from a sample retail image dataset.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/combine-keyword-and-semantic-search-for-text-and-images-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-opensearch-service/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: Microsoft Store Assistant — bringing multi expert intelligence to Microsoft Store chat with Semantic Kernel and Azure AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 15:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In October 2024 Microsoft replaced a legacy rule‑based chat bot on Microsoft Store with Microsoft Store Assistant, powered by Azure Open AI, Semantic Kernel, and real‑time page context. The transformation changed a scripted, button-driven experience into a conversation that comprehends the entire public Microsoft portfolio, including Surface and Xbox products, Microsoft 365 subscriptions, Azure services, and the Dynamics and Power Platform […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-microsoft-store-assistant-bringing-multi-expert-intelligence-to-microsoft-store-chat-with-semantic-kernel-and-azure-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: HIPAA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 14:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Microsoft 365 Certification verifies that ISVs have established protocols for managing health information, dealing with emergencies and service disruptions, and complying with key HIPAA regulations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-hipaa 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When I define a window class with no default cursor, what is the explanation for the cursors that appear in my client area?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You said you&#39;d take care of it, but you didn&#39;t.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250424-00/?p=111114 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mellum: How We Trained a Model to Excel in Code Completion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code completion has always been a defining strength of JetBrains products. So, when adding AI into our products, we knew it had to deliver top-tier code completion. This post covers how we trained the model behind our cloud-based completion. Initial research: What about obvious model options? We started by testing both closed-source LLMs via APIs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/04/mellum-how-we-trained-a-model-to-excel-in-code-completion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Java Code in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 09:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2025/24_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will look at how to debug Java code using the IntelliJ IDEA debugger. We will look at how to fix a failing test, how to find out where an Exception is thrown, and how to find problems with our data. And we will learn some neat tricks about the debugger […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/debugging-java-code-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud vs Self-Hosting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 18:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why not self-host using a VPS or dedicated hardware instead of using the cloud? Well, there are a lot of reasons. The cloud isn’t just about scaling; it’s about managed services. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in this post. Dissecting the… Read More »Cloud vs Self-Hosting The post Cloud vs Self-Hosting appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2025: Pre-Conference Videos</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 18:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++ is our free, one-day, virtual conference for the whole C++ community. It is running on 30th April. The first half of our pre-conference videos is now available on YouTube. The videos are: MSVC C++23 Conformance Simplifying your Cross-Platform Development with Visual Studio C++ Dynamic Debugging How Debuggers Work A Year in Review: […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-cpp-2025-pre-conference-videos 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing SharePoint Framework 1.21 with updates on building enterprise extensibility within Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 18:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce general availability for the SharePoint Framework 1.21. This time focus is primarily on technical platform updates and new UX options in SharePoint and in Viva Connections.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-sharepoint-framework-1-21-with-updates-on-building-enterprise-extensibility-within-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Cleaning: A CTA for Azure DevOps OAuth Apps with expired or long-living secrets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 17:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we officially closed the doors on any new Azure DevOps OAuth app registrations. As we prepare for the end-of-life for Azure DevOps OAuth apps in 2026, we’ll begin outreach to engage existing app owners and support them through the migration process to use the Microsoft Identity platform instead for future app development with Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/spring-cleaning-cta-for-azure-devops-oauth-apps-with-expired-or-long-living-secrets 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK modularized libraries for JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 16:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces new modularized libraries for the Azure SDK for JavaScript.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-modularized-libraries-for-javascript 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI-powered document processing platform with open source NER model and LLM on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 16:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how you can build an AI-powered document processing platform with open source NER and LLMs on SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ai-powered-document-processing-platform-with-open-source-ner-model-and-llm-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect sensitive data in RAG applications with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 16:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore two approaches for securing sensitive data in RAG applications using Amazon Bedrock. The first approach focused on identifying and redacting sensitive data before ingestion into an Amazon Bedrock knowledge base, and the second demonstrated a fine-grained RBAC pattern for managing access to sensitive information during retrieval. These solutions represent just two possible approaches among many for securing sensitive data in generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Search PDF Files Locally using .NET / C# and Build5Nines.SharpVector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 15:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ability to extract and semantically search through unstructured documents is becoming not just a convenience, but a necessity. This is especially true for software developers working with large repositories of technical documentation, compliance reports, or knowledge bases. In this article, we’ll explore how to build a semantic search solution using C#, PDFs, and the […] The article Semantic Search PDF Files Locally using .NET / C# and Build5Nines.SharpVector was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless adjustments with an adaptive paste</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 14:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find yourself needing to adjust pasted code to actually work in your project? Visual Studio 2022 introduces the capability to adapt your pasted code with Copilot to reduce the time you spend on making tedious changes. Streamline manual code modifications with adaptive paste When you’re copying and pasting code, the process often comes with extra […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/effortless-adjustments-with-an-adaptive-paste 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What resource ID should I give my application’s main icon?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applying what we know about how Explorer finds the &amp;quot;first&amp;quot; icon in a file.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250423-00/?p=111106 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is It Still Worth Learning to Code in an AI World?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 09:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released some new AI features for the JetBrains Academy plugin. Learners will now be able to use machine translation of course content, theory lookup, and AI hints for Kotlin courses. At first glance, these might seem fairly tame. There are no big LLM integrations, JetBrains AI Assistant is not being marketed toward beginners, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/23/is-it-still-worth-learning-to-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciting updates coming to the Microsoft 365 Developer Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 08:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to share a preview of upcoming updates to the Microsoft 365 Developer Program.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/exciting-updates-coming-to-the-microsoft-365-developer-program 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Hidden Performance in Microsoft .NET: Iterating Over IEnumerable with the Enumerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses the performance benefits of using an Enumerator to iterate over an IEnumerable collection, which can be faster than traditional foreach() or for() loops.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/23/unlocking-hidden-performance-in-microsoft-net-iterating-over-ienumerable-with-the-enumerator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Real‑Time iOS Apps with SignalR: Introducing the Official Swift Client (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 03:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2025/23_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Until now, iOS developers who wanted real‑time, bi‑directional communication with SignalR had to rely on community‑built clients or roll their own Swift implementation—both of which introduced maintenance and compatibility headaches. We’re excited to announce that the official SignalR Swift client is now available in public preview. With this release, you can: Quickly add real‑time […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/building-real%e2%80%91time-ios-apps-with-signalr-introducing-the-official-swift-client-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your LLM performance with Amazon SageMaker Large Model Inference container v15</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 17:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce the launch of Amazon SageMaker Large Model Inference (LMI) container v15, powered by vLLM 0.8.4 with support for the vLLM V1 engine. This release introduces significant performance improvements, expanded model compatibility with multimodality (that is, the ability to understand and analyze text-to-text, images-to-text, and text-to-images data), and provides built-in integration with vLLM to help you seamlessly deploy and serve large language models (LLMs) with the highest performance at scale.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accuracy evaluation framework for Amazon Q Business – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 17:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the first post of this series, we introduced a comprehensive evaluation framework for Amazon Q Business, a fully managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) solution that uses your company’s proprietary data without the complexity of managing large language models (LLMs). The first post focused on selecting appropriate use cases, preparing data, and implementing metrics to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accuracy-evaluation-framework-for-amazon-q-business-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Bedrock Intelligent Prompt Routing for cost and latency benefits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 17:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re happy to announce the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Intelligent Prompt Routing. In this blog post, we detail various highlights from our internal testing, how you can get started, and point out some caveats and best practices. We encourage you to incorporate Amazon Bedrock Intelligent Prompt Routing into your new and existing generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-bedrock-intelligent-prompt-routing-for-cost-and-latency-benefits/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Infosys improved accessibility for Event Knowledge using Amazon Nova Pro, Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Elemental Media Services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 17:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Infosys developed Infosys Event AI to unlock the insights generated from events and conferences. Through its suite of features—including real-time transcription, intelligent summaries, and an interactive chat assistant—Infosys Event AI makes event knowledge accessible and provides an immersive engagement solution for the attendees, during and after the event.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-infosys-improved-accessibility-for-event-knowledge-using-amazon-nova-pro-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-elemental-media-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the AI Dev Gallery: Your Gateway to Local AI Development with .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the new AI Dev Gallery, a Windows application that provides interactive local AI samples, easy model downloads, and source code export - all built with .NET AI building blocks.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-ai-dev-gallery-gateway-to-local-ai-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Conf 2025 Recap: AI, Apps &amp; Scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On April 15, 2025, developers from around the world came together for Azure Cosmos DB Conf 2025—a free virtual event co-hosted by Microsoft and the vibrant Azure Cosmos DB community. From early-morning keynotes to lightning talks and live demos, the event was packed with fresh insights, expert guidance, and real-world examples of how developers are […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-conf-2025-recap-ai-apps-scale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: top of mind</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Things I&#39;m thinking about.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250422-00/?p=111100 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Testing Spring Controllers With MockMvcTester</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Framework 6.2 introduced MockMvcTester to support writing AssertJ style assertions using AssertJ under the hood. If you’re using Spring Boot, the spring-boot-starter-test dependency transitively adds the most commonly used testing libraries such as mockito, assertj, json-path, jsonassert, etc. So, if you’re using Spring Boot 3.4.0 (which uses Spring framework 6.2) or any later version, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/a-practical-guide-to-testing-spring-controllers-with-mockmvctester/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dockerizing MCP – Bringing Discovery, Simplicity, and Trust to the Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the Docker MCP Catalog and Toolkit, a new way to source, use, and scale with MCP tools.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-docker-mcp-catalog-and-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD Security Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 12:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Software development moves fast – really fast. It can also involve multiple teams working from different locations around the world. However, while speed and collaboration can be great for developers and businesses, they can also create security challenges. With more entry points and less time to catch potential threats, each commit, build, and deployment is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/04/ci-cd-security-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aqua Sunset</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 12:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aqua was originally developed as a dedicated IDE for QA engineers working in automated testing. After carefully evaluating adoption rates, market trends, and user feedback, we have made the difficult decision to discontinue the product. While this was not an easy choice, Aqua did not reach the level of adoption we had anticipated. We believe […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qa/2025/04/aqua-sunset/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana For Code Quality in STEM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your code drives discovery. Keep it precise. In STEM fields, software isn’t just a product, it underpins innovation, research, and life-critical infrastructure. Qodana brings advanced static code analysis to STEM software projects, helping ensure code quality, security, and compliance where it matters most. Qodana for STEM Why code quality matters in STEM Software in science, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/qodana-for-code-quality-in-stem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going beyond singleton, scoped, and transient lifetimes—tenant, pooled, and drifter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I investigate some &#39;experimental&#39; dependency injection scopes that provide additional features over Singleton, Scoped, and Transient
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/going-beyond-singleton-scoped-and-transient-lifetimes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discord for WebStorm: Less Noise, More Signal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2025/22_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TLDR: We’ve revamped the JetBrains Community Discord with dedicated WebStorm channels for announcements, discussions, help, and Q&amp;amp;As to create a more valuable community resource. We’ll have live office hours on April 23rd to connect directly with our team. Not part of our Discord community yet? Join the JetBrains Community Discord here to start connecting with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/04/discord-for-webstorm-less-noise-more-signal/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Prompt Optimization Drives LLM Applications Innovation for Yuewen Group</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 22:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the availability of Prompt Optimization on Amazon Bedrock. With this capability, you can now optimize your prompts for several use cases with a single API call or a click of a button on the Amazon Bedrock console. In this blog post, we discuss how Prompt Optimization improves the performance of large language models (LLMs) for intelligent text processing task in Yuewen Group.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started quickly with setting up the Microsoft Dev Box service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 20:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last updated: April 21, 2025 🎯 Introduction Are you an IT admin, platform engineer, or a developer looking to explore a developer-centric, cloud-powered workstation experience? In this post, I’ll show you how to start quickly and try out Microsoft Dev Box using either a Microsoft 365 Business Premium or Microsoft 365 E3 plan — both […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/how-to-get-started-quickly-with-setting-up-the-microsoft-dev-box-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taint Analysis: Exploring Hidden Dangers in Your Team’s Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 20:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for an engaging roundtable discussion where our panel of developers will share their firsthand insights on the latest Taint Analysis from JetBrains. Discover how critical checks can improve codebase security and be easily implemented in your code review process. Session abstract Whether you’re new to JetBrains or looking to deepen your understanding of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/taint-analysis-exploring-hidden-dangers-in-your-team-s-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a location-aware agent using Amazon Bedrock Agents and Foursquare APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 18:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we combine Amazon Bedrock Agents and Foursquare APIs to demonstrate how you can use a location-aware agent to bring personalized responses to your users.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-location-aware-agent-using-amazon-bedrock-agents-and-foursquare-apis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Build an AI App That Can Browse the Internet Using Microsoft’s Playwright MCP Server &amp; Semantic Kernel — in Just 4 Steps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 18:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to feature a returning guest author, Akshay Kokane to share his recent Medium article on Building an AI App That Can Browse the Internet Using Microsoft’s Playwright MCP Server &amp;amp; Semantic Kernel. We’ll turn it over to him to dive in! MCP! It’s the new buzzword in the AI world. So, I thought […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-build-an-ai-app-that-can-browse-the-internet-using-microsofts-playwright-mcp-server-semantic-kernel-in-just-4-steps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an automated generative AI solution evaluation pipeline with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 17:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the importance of evaluating LLMs in the context of generative AI applications, highlighting the challenges posed by issues like hallucinations and biases. We introduced a comprehensive solution using AWS services to automate the evaluation process, allowing for continuous monitoring and assessment of LLM performance. By using tools like the FMeval Library, Ragas, LLMeter, and Step Functions, the solution provides flexibility and scalability, meeting the evolving needs of LLM consumers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB with DiskANN Part 2: Scaling to 1 Billion Vectors with</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 16:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In the first part of our series on Azure Cosmos DB Vector Search with DiskANN, we explored the fundamentals of vector indexing and search capabilities using Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL and demonstrated a few early performance and cost characteristics. In Part 2, we’ll demonstrate how to scale to 1 billion vector datasets, while […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-with-diskann-part-2-scaling-to-1-billion-vectors-with 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictable LLM results with Structured Output and sp_invoke_external_rest_endpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 15:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI recently introduced a powerful new feature for developers: structured output using JSON Schema via the response_format parameter. This makes it possible to request responses from a GPT-4o model that strictly match a given schema—no free-text, no guesswork. If you’re working with Azure SQL, this is a game-changer. Combined with the sp_invoke_external_rest_endpoint stored procedure and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/predictable-llm-output-with-sp_invoke_external_rest_endpoint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ongoing story of seconds on the taskbar</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The cost of ticking.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250421-00/?p=111095 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract Text from PDF Files with Python for use in Generative AI and RAG Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building Generative AI and Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) LLM-based solutions, the quality and structure of input data significantly influences the performance of the LLM models. PDF documents, a prevalent format for information dissemination, often contain rich textual content that can be harnessed for such applications. However, extracting this content in a structured and usable format […] The article Extract Text from PDF Files with Python for use in Generative AI and RAG Solutions was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Microsoft Graph API usage report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 09:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn more about our new journey to give customers more insight and control over how applications access their data through Microsoft Graph.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-the-microsoft-graph-api-usage-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement client assertions for OAuth client credential flows in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 08:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2025/21_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog implements client assertions using an OAuth client credential flow in ASP.NET Core. Client assertions provide a secure way for client authentication without sharing a secret, enhancing the security the OAuth client credentials flow. By using JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) client assertions, this approach ensures strong client identity (application) verification and mitigates risks associated […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/04/21/implement-client-assertions-for-oauth-client-credential-flows-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the ‘Work with Power Fx functions’ Learning Path</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2025/20_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2025/20_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Learn has a growing list of Power Platform training modules. Based on community feedback, we’ve added a new learning path: Work with Power Fx functions. Power Fx functions enable the creation of server-side business logic using Power Fx, a low-code, declarative language. These functions were previously called instant low-code plug-ins. They provide reusable, parameterized […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-the-work-with-power-fx-functions-learning-path 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fastest Way to Get a String’s Length in Microsoft .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2025/20_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2025/20_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article analyzes the performance of different methods for retrieving the character count of a string in .NET, recommending the use of Length as the fastest option. Length is significantly more efficient than Span and Enumerable.Count(), urging developers to refactor for improved performance while validating optimizations with BenchmarkDotNet.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/20/the-fastest-way-to-get-a-strings-length-in-microsoft-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Evolving Code Standards Without Chaos - Dev Leader Weekly 91</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to navigate codebases that have evolving code standards.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/04/19/navigating-evolving-code-standards-without-chaos-dev-leader-weekly-91 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-04-18</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 04:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/04/19/weekly-recap-20250418 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Microservices: Core Concepts and Benefits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2025/19_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What are microservices, and why might they be the right architectural choice for your organization? Microservices offer independently deployable, domain-focused components that provide flexibility when applied correctly to solve the right organizational problems.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/understanding-microservices-core-concepts-and-benefits 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Search in .NET / C# with Build5Nines.SharpVector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 18:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we often find ourselves building smarter, more context-aware applications. Whether it’s powering a document search tool or implementing Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), semantic search is a powerful capability to have in your toolbox. I recently found myself needing a lightweight, local, in-memory vector database for a .NET / C# project. At the time, there […] The article Semantic Search in .NET / C# with Build5Nines.SharpVector was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ: Introducing the enhanced Java Code Quality Analyzer!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the latest updates to the Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ, featuring an enhanced Java Code Quality Analyzer to help you write cleaner, safer, and more efficient Java code with Azure SDK client libraries.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-toolkit-for-intellij-introducing-the-enhanced-java-code-quality-analyzer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a FinOps agent using Amazon Bedrock with multi-agent capability and Amazon Nova as the foundation model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we use the multi-agent feature of Amazon Bedrock to demonstrate a powerful and innovative approach to AWS cost management. By using the advanced capabilities of Amazon Nova FMs, we’ve developed a solution that showcases how AI-driven agents can revolutionize the way organizations analyze, optimize, and manage their AWS costs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-finops-agent-using-amazon-bedrock-with-multi-agent-capability-and-amazon-nova-as-the-foundation-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stream ingest data from Kafka to Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases using custom connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For this post, we implement a RAG architecture with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases using a custom connector and topics built with Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (Amazon MSK) for a user who may be interested to understand stock price trends.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/stream-ingest-data-from-kafka-to-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-using-custom-connectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards &#43; GitHub: Recent Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 14:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past several months, we’ve delivered a series of improvements to the Azure Boards + GitHub integration. Whether you’re tracking code, managing pull requests, or connecting pipelines, these updates aim to simplify and strengthen the link between your work items and your GitHub activity. Here’s a recap of everything we’ve released (or are just […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-boards-github-recent-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the feature flag that didn’t stay on long enough, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 14:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Leaving everything the way you found it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250418-43/?p=111081 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: Ruby on Rails – The Framework that Rewired The Web with MVC and Convention</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It wasn’t the first web framework. It may not be the flashiest these days in 2025. But Ruby on Rails was revolutionary when it hit the scene — and its fingerprints are still all over modern web development today. At a time when building web applications was often painful, verbose, and fractured across multiple layers […] The article Software Innovation: Ruby on Rails – The Framework that Rewired The Web with MVC and Convention was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
