<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 06:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using multiple external identity providers from ASP.NET Core Identity and Duende IdentityServer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 06:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post shows how an ASP.NET Core Identity application can integrate and implement multiple external identity providers. An OIDC client UI uses the solution and is implemented using Duende IdentityServer. The same scheme is used for all the external providers and mapped to the identity for the client UI and the application. Using OpenID […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/05/19/using-multiple-external-identity-providers-from-asp-net-core-identity-and-duende-identityserver/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Maximize Your .NET Performance with Spargine FastLoggerExtensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2025/18_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2025/18_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The FastLoggerExtensions class in the DotNetTips.Spargine.8.Core project optimizes logging within .NET, achieving up to 10x performance improvement over traditional methods. It offers various structured logging methods, aiding effective debugging and enhancing traceability. Community contributions are encouraged to further improve this open-source tool. Contact details for contributions are provided.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/05/18/boost-your-net-projects-maximize-your-net-performance-with-spargine-fastloggerextensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Words Don’t Come Easily - Dev Leader Weekly 95</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2025/17_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2025/17_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss communication styles for software engineers that don&#39;t love speaking up!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/17/when-words-dont-come-easily-dev-leader-weekly-95 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-05-16</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2025/17_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 06:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2025/17_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/17/weekly-recap-20250516 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CQRS Pattern the Way It Should&#39;ve Been From the Start</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2025/17_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2025/17_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement CQRS in .NET without relying on MediatR. This guide walks you through a lightweight setup using simple interfaces, decorators, and DI — no frameworks required.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/cqrs-pattern-the-way-it-should-have-been-from-the-start 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up a custom plugin on Amazon Q Business and authenticate with Amazon Cognito to interact with backend systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a custom plugin with Amazon Q Business for backend integration. This plugin can integrate existing systems, including third-party systems, with little to no development in just weeks and automate critical workflows. Additionally, we show how to safeguard the solution using Amazon Cognito and AWS IAM Identity Center, maintaining the safety and integrity of sensitive data and workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/set-up-a-custom-plugin-on-amazon-q-business-and-authenticate-with-amazon-cognito-to-interact-with-backend-systems/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect hallucinations for RAG-based systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks you through how to create a basic hallucination detection system for RAG-based applications. We also weigh the pros and cons of different methods in terms of accuracy, precision, recall, and cost.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/detect-hallucinations-for-rag-based-systems/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS machine learning supports Scuderia Ferrari HP pit stop analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pit crews are trained to operate at optimum efficiency, although measuring their performance has been challenging, until now. In this post, we share how Amazon Web Services (AWS) is helping Scuderia Ferrari HP develop more accurate pit stop analysis techniques using machine learning (ML).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-machine-learning-supports-scuderia-ferrari-hp-pit-stop-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate edge AI development with SiMa.ai Edgematic with a seamless AWS integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to retrain and quantize a model using SageMaker AI and the SiMa.ai Palette software suite. The goal is to accurately detect individuals in environments where visibility and protective equipment detection are essential for compliance and safety.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-edge-ai-development-with-sima-ai-edgematic-with-a-seamless-aws-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join JetBrains PHPverse to Celebrate 30 Years of PHP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PHP turns 30 this June, and we’re looking forward to celebrating this notable milestone together with you! On June 17, 2025, we’re hosting JetBrains PHPverse 2025, where prominent people from the PHP community will come together and share their thoughts about the state and the future of the modern PHP language and ecosystem. This is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/05/join-jetbrains-phpverse-to-celebrate-30-years-of-php/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Watch Microsoft Build 2025 Online</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Build 2025 Is Almost Here — Here’s How to Make the Most of It Virtually It’s that time again—Microsoft Build is just around the corner! Microsoft Build 2025 kicks off next week (May 19–22)—and now’s the perfect time to get your plan in place. The best part? You don’t have to be in Seattle […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-to-watch-microsoft-build-2025-online 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s with the weird wReserved value at the start of the DECIMAL structure?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s where the discriminant goes when the DECIMAL is put &amp;quot;inside&amp;quot; a VARIANT.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250516-00/?p=111185 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: James Gosling – Creator of Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            James Gosling is a name that resonates through the halls of computer science, software engineering, and more recently, cloud computing. Best known as the “Father of Java,” Gosling’s influence stretches far beyond the iconic programming language. His work has quietly but profoundly shaped the modern cloud landscape, enabling countless innovations that rely on scalable, reliable, […] The article Big Thinkers: James Gosling – Creator of Java was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Live!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for Rider 2025.2 has just begun, and the first preview build for the upcoming major release is already out. There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: A reminder of what the EAP is all about The Early Access Program is a long-standing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/16/rider-2025-2-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.2 Has Begun!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that the Early Access Program (EAP) for ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.2 is now underway! The first build is available for download, giving you a sneak peek into the features and improvements coming in the next major release. As always, your feedback is key to shaping the final version – we’d […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/16/resharper-2025-2-eap-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel: Package previews, Graduations &amp; Deprecations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 08:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Semantic Kernel: Package Previews, Graduations &amp;amp; Deprecations We are excited to share a summary of recent updates and continuous clean-up efforts across the Semantic Kernel .NET codebase. These changes focus on improving maintainability, aligning with the latest APIs, and ensuring a consistent experience for users. Below you’ll find details on package graduations, deprecations, and a […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-package-previews-graduations-deprecations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addendum to o3 and o4-mini system card: Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Codex is a cloud-based coding agent. Codex is powered by codex-1, a version of OpenAI o3 optimized for software engineering. codex-1 was trained using reinforcement learning on real-world coding tasks in a variety of environments to generate code that closely mirrors human style and PR preferences, adheres precisely to instructions, and iteratively runs tests until passing results are achieved.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/o3-o4-mini-codex-system-card-addendum 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing Codex: a cloud-based software engineering agent that can work on many tasks in parallel, powered by codex-1. With Codex, developers can simultaneously deploy multiple agents to independently handle coding tasks such as writing features, answering questions about your codebase, fixing bugs, and proposing pull requests for review.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine 4 is Bringing Multi-Tenancy to EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I think that even in a crowded field of existing “mediator” tools, ASP.Net Core endpoint frameworks, and asynchronous messaging frameworks in .NET that Wolverine has a great opportunity to grow its user base this year. There’s a lot of value that Wolverine brings to the table that I don’t believe other tools do, but it’s … Continue reading Wolverine 4 is Bringing Multi-Tenancy to EF Core →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker at Microsoft Build 2025: Where Secure Software Meets Intelligent Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 22:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year at Microsoft Build, Docker will blend developer experience, security, and AI innovation with our latest product announcements. Whether you attend in person at the Seattle Convention Center or tune in online, you’ll see how Docker is redefining the way teams build, secure, and scale modern applications. Docker’s Vision for Developers At Microsoft Build...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-at-microsoft-build-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Apoidea Group enhances visual information extraction from banking documents with multimodal models using LLaMA-Factory on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 19:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building on this foundation of specialized information extraction solutions and using the capabilities of SageMaker HyperPod, we collaborate with APOIDEA Group to explore the use of large vision language models (LVLMs) to further improve table structure recognition performance on banking and financial documents. In this post, we present our work and step-by-step code on fine-tuning the Qwen2-VL-7B-Instruct model using LLaMA-Factory on SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-apoidea-group-enhances-visual-information-extraction-from-banking-documents-with-multimodal-models-using-llama-factory-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Qualtrics built Socrates: An AI platform powered by Amazon SageMaker and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 19:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Qualtrics built an AI platform powered by Amazon SageMaker and Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-qualtrics-built-socrates-an-ai-platform-powered-by-amazon-sagemaker-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vxceed secures transport operations with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 19:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS partnered with Vxceed to support their AI strategy, resulting in the development of LimoConnect Q, an innovative ground transportation management solution. Using AWS services including Amazon Bedrock and Lambda, Vxceed successfully built a secure, AI-powered solution that streamlines trip booking and document processing.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/vxceed-secures-transport-operations-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 50 Million Developers: The Journey of Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 18:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, I’m thrilled to share that we’ve hit an incredible milestone together: 50 million developers are actively using Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code each month. That’s 50 million of you writing code, debugging late into the night, collaborating on projects, and building the future with us. This isn’t just a statistic—it’s a testament to the real work, innovation, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/celebrating-50-million-developers-the-journey-of-visual-studio-and-visual-studio-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating content safety in your .NET AI applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing content safety evaluations and other imporvements in the Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Evaluation libraries.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/evaluating-ai-content-safety 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re launching our two-month Early Access Program (EAP) for CLion 2025.2. The EAP allows you to try new CLion features and improvements at no cost before the stable release. You can download the first EAP build, 252.13776.55, from the link below or via Toolbox App. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.1 EAP For the first EAP release, we’ve […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/2025-2-eap-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 14:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 has now officially begun! We’d like to share a glimpse of what we’re working on for the upcoming release and invite you to join us on this exciting journey over the coming weeks. There will also be a small change in the way we’ll deliver our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/the-intellij-idea-2025-2-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I force RunOnce commands to run in a specific order?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Run them in the desired order yourself.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250515-00/?p=111181 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovations: iOS – The Operating System That Put the Future in Your Pocket</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A 18‑year chronicle of Apple’s mobile powerhouse—how it began, how it rewired the software economy, and why its next act is infused with on‑device intelligence. You wake up, glance at a glowing rectangle, and with a tap summon everything from bank balances to baby photos. That daily ritual traces its lineage to a January 2007 […] The article Software Innovations: iOS – The Operating System That Put the Future in Your Pocket was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud infrastructure provisioning: best practices for IaC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Infrastructure-as-Code (IaC) is a common DevOps practice that enterprises use to provision and deploy IT infrastructure. Enterprises applying IaC and continuous integration/continuous delivery (CI/CD) pipelines can maintain high availability and manage risk for their cloud environments at scale. However, multi-environment challenges, manual processes, and fragmented guidance still lead to configuration drift, errors, and inconsistencies. These issues are likely to result in downtime, security vulnerabilities, and inefficient resource utilization.
Link to article: https://devblogs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of a JasperFx Support Contract</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 01:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software is the company I founded a little over two years ago to create an Open Core business model around the “Critter Stack” suite of open source tools (primarily Marten and Wolverine, with some smaller supporting tools). So far, our main sources of revenue (right now it’s myself with contributions from Babu Annamalai, but … Continue reading The Value of a JasperFx Support Contract →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/05/14/the-value-of-a-jasperfx-support-contract/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost-effective AI image generation with PixArt-Σ inference on AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 15:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is the first in a series where we will run multiple diffusion transformers on Trainium and Inferentia-powered instances. In this post, we show how you can deploy PixArt-Sigma to Trainium and Inferentia-powered instances.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cost-effective-ai-image-generation-with-pixart-%CF%83-inference-on-aws-trainium-and-aws-inferentia/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize DeepSeek-R1 671b model using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod recipes – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 15:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we use the recipes to fine-tune the original DeepSeek-R1 671b parameter model. We demonstrate this through the step-by-step implementation of these recipes using both SageMaker training jobs and SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/customize-deepseek-r1-671b-model-using-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-recipes-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a financial research assistant using Amazon Q Business and Amazon QuickSight for generative AI–powered insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 15:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Amazon Q Business can help augment your generative AI needs in all the abovementioned use cases and more by answering questions, providing summaries, generating content, and securely completing tasks based on data and information in your enterprise systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-financial-research-assistant-using-amazon-q-business-and-amazon-quicksight-for-generative-ai-powered-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If I mark my thread pool callback as long-running, does it still count toward the thread pool thread limit?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yes, because it&#39;s still in the thread pool.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250514-00/?p=111178 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 11:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MPS 2025.1 allows the build language to serve as a target for code generation. This version also introduces visual and performance enhancements to the Project tool window’s Logical view, several useful improvements to the UI, and numerous platform updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.1 What’s new Let’s check out all the new features waiting for you in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/05/mps-2025-1-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI powers Expedia’s marketing evolution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A conversation with Jochen Koedijk, Chief Marketing Officer of Expedia Group.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/expedia-jochen-koedijk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion and the Open-Source Community: Growing Together</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From the beginning, CLion has been shaped by the needs of C and C++ developers around the world. Our cross-platform IDE was built to simplify development, boost productivity, and make working with C++ more enjoyable. We’re excited to take the next step in our ongoing collaboration with the community: CLion is now free for non-commercial […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/05/14/clion-and-the-open-source-community-growing-together/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try Declarative Gradle EAP3 in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 08:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Declarative Gradle project, aimed at making Gradle build scripts easier to read and use, is at full steam. Last month, EAP3 landed, bringing testing support and more DCL language features, like lists and files. Read the Gradle blog post to learn more about what the EAP, and Declarative Gradle in general, brings you. Like […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/try-declarative-gradle-eap3-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Supercharge Your Code with FastStringBuilder in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a collection of open-source assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8 and 9, aimed at optimizing performance. The FastStringBuilder enhances string manipulation by minimizing memory allocations and boosting speed, featuring methods like Combine and ToDelimitedString. Benchmarks indicate significant improvements over traditional approaches in both speed and memory efficiency.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/05/14/boost-your-net-projects-supercharge-your-code-with-faststringbuilder-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework May 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for May 2025.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-may-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving SnapStart Performance in .NET Lambda Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 21:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS recently added AWS Lambda SnapStart support for .NET Lambda functions to deliver faster function startup performance, from several seconds to as low as sub-second, typically with minimal or no code changes. This post explores techniques to maximize the performance gains of SnapStart for several different types of .NET workloads. For a high-level overview and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/blog-improving-snapstart-performance-in-net-lambdas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate AI Applications with Semantic Caching on Azure Managed Redis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog, we will look at implementing the Semantic caching use case using Azure Managed Redis. Azure has been at the forefront of providing caching solutions for over a decade with the Azure Cache for Redis enterprise. This service empowered developers with a high-performance, scalable cache that significantly enhanced the responsiveness of their applications. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/accelerate-ai-applications-with-semantic-caching-on-azure-managed-redis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eclipse &#43; GitHub Copilot = Lightspeed SAP ABAP Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 21:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Did you catch the GitHub’s recent announcement of ABAP support in GitHub Copilot for Eclipse? It is a significant step forward for SAP developers. This integration brings AI-powered code suggestions and chat functionalities directly into the Eclipse IDE, potentially revolutionizing ABAP development. Let’s break down how it works, how to set it up, and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/eclipse-github-copilot-lightspeed-sap-abap-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Years of Software Architecture: Best And Worst Decisions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 20:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the last 10 years, I’ve been developing a single product, greenfield, designing the architecture from scratch, and evolving it over time. Over this decade-long journey, I’ve made some architectural decisions I’m proud of—and some I definitely regret. Today, I want to share those experiences with you, diving deep into the good and bad decisions… Read More »10 Years of Software Architecture: Best And Worst Decisions The post 10 Years of Software Architecture: Best And Worst Decisions appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 4 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out about the new features in .NET 10 Preview 4 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, C#, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-4 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Amazon Bedrock Agents: A guide to safeguarding against indirect prompt injections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI tools have transformed how we work, create, and process information. At Amazon Web Services (AWS), security is our top priority. Therefore, Amazon Bedrock provides comprehensive security controls and best practices to help protect your applications and data. In this post, we explore the security measures and practical strategies provided by Amazon Bedrock Agents to safeguard your AI interactions against indirect prompt injections, making sure that your applications remain both secure and reliable.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New for C&#43;&#43; Developers in Visual Studio 2022 17.14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 version 17.14 is now generally available! This post summarizes the new features you can find in this release for C++. You can download Visual Studio 2022 from the Visual Studio downloads page or upgrade your existing installation by following the Update Visual Studio Learn page. Standard Library and Compiler We’ve made a myriad of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-for-cpp-developers-in-visual-studio-2022-17-14 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent mode has arrived in preview for Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plan, build, test, and fix — all from one prompt. Agent mode is now available in public preview for all users in Visual Studio 17.14. Agent mode in Visual Studio allows you to define tasks using natural language, with Copilot autonomously planning, editing your codebase, invoking tools, and iterating to resolve issues. Unlike Copilot Chat […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/agent-mode-has-arrived-in-preview-for-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Visual Studio 2022 v17.14 is now generally available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the general availability of Visual Studio 2022 version 17.14! This release continues our mission to empower developers with faster, smarter, and more productive tools across all workloads. There is so much for developers to love in this release, so be sure to check out the release notes for the full list. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2022-v17-14-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build scalable containerized RAG based generative AI applications in AWS using Amazon EKS with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) with Amazon Bedrock to build scalable and containerized RAG solutions for your generative AI applications on AWS while bringing your unstructured user file data to Amazon Bedrock in a straightforward, fast, and secure way.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-scalable-containerized-rag-based-generative-ai-applications-in-aws-using-amazon-eks-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Hexagon built an AI assistant using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recognizing the transformative benefits of generative AI for enterprises, we at Hexagon’s Asset Lifecycle Intelligence division sought to enhance how users interact with our Enterprise Asset Management (EAM) products. Understanding these advantages, we partnered with AWS to embark on a journey to develop HxGN Alix, an AI-powered digital worker using AWS generative AI services. This blog post explores the strategy, development, and implementation of HxGN Alix, demonstrating how a tailored AI solution can drive efficiency and enhance user satisfaction.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build 2025 Preview: Transform Your AI Apps and Agents with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Build is less than a week away, and the Azure Cosmos DB team will be out in force to showcase the newest features and capabilities for building AI apps and agents with scalable, fast, high-performance data. Whether you’re in person at the Seattle Convention Center or watching the live or on-demand digital show, we […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/build-2025-preview-transform-your-ai-apps-and-agents-with-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip and Database Tools UX Survey #2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to launch the second edition of our User Experience Survey for DataGrip and the Database Tools &amp;amp; SQL Plugin! Your feedback from the previous survey helped us better understand your needs and prioritize the features and improvements that matter most to you. Thanks to your input, we’ve already delivered a first set of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/05/13/datagrip-and-database-tools-ux-survey-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the developer set-up for developing Windows for multiple processor architectures?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You usually just pick one and count on your friends for the others.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250513-00/?p=111176 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Rust the Future of Programming?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 12:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rust is rewriting the rules of modern software development as the fastest-growing programming language. Its unmatched performance, memory safety without garbage collection, and concurrency capabilities are capturing developers’ attention worldwide. According to our data, with 2,267,000 developers using Rust in the last 12 months and 709,000 identifying it as a primary language, Rust’s footprint in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/05/13/is-rust-the-future-of-programming/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Cloud-Ready Apps Locally: Spring Boot, AWS, and LocalStack in Action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developing an application with AWS services can introduce significant local‑development hurdles. Often, developers don’t receive timely AWS access, or a sysadmin inadvertently grants credentials for the wrong account – only to fix the error a week later. Then, when engineers discover they still lack permissions for certain resources, they must endure yet another week-long wait […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/building-cloud-ready-apps-locally-spring-boot-aws-and-localstack-in-action/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Plugin Verifier and API Compatibility Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maintaining plugin compatibility across JetBrains IDEs can be tricky — but the Plugin Verifier is here to help. On Wednesday, May 21, at 2:00 PM UTC, join us for a live session with IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Róbert Novotný and Yann Cébron, focused on the Plugin Verifier and API compatibility maintenance. During the webinar, you’ll discover how: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/05/livestream-plugin-verifier-and-api-compatibility-maintenance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Generally Available: Apple identity provider support for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m excited to announce that &amp;quot;Sign in with Apple&amp;quot; is now generally available for external tenants in Entra External ID. The feature has been in public preview since February, and many customers have already integrated Apple as an identity provider for their applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/now-generally-available-apple-identity-provider-support-for-microsoft-entra-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CodeCanvas 2025.1 With Free Tier and Toolbox Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 09:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April, we released CodeCanvas 2025.1 with many important changes. The release brings improved infrastructure flexibility for easier multi-region setups, a new AWS CloudFormation installation option, enhanced environment logs, and more. Today, we want to highlight two major updates: See the full What’s New for the full details. Use CodeCanvas for free With the 2025.1 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/05/codecanvas-2025-1-with-free-tier-and-toolbox-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the new AI template to create a chatbot about a website</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I use the new Microsoft&#39;s new .NET AI template to ingest the contents of a website and create a chatbot that can answer questions with citations
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/using-the-new-ai-template-to-create-a-chatbot-about-a-website/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft deletes in EF Core: How to implement and query efficiently</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What does your application actually do with a record when a user deletes it? Can your application afford to delete a record permanently? One mistake can result in irreparable damage to the application. Today, I will shed light on D of the CRUD. Among all the CRUD operations, Delete is
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/soft-deletes-in-ef-core-how-to-implement-and-query-efficiently/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent community agent to revolutionize IT support with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 17:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how your organization can reduce the end-to-end burden of resolving regular challenges experienced by your IT support teams—from understanding errors and reviewing diagnoses, remediation steps, and relevant documentation, to opening external support tickets using common third-party services such as Jira.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-community-agent-to-revolutionize-it-support-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Claude-Ready Entra ID-Protected MCP Servers with Azure API Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 17:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the launch of custom integrations in Claude, developers and enterprises can now extend Claude’s capabilities by connecting their own hosted Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers as native integrations. This capability allows Claude and any of its agents to perform complex tasks by invoking a variety of APIs exposed through MCP servers. Developers might wonder […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/claude-ready-secure-mcp-apim 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Coding the Future with Java and AI – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 15:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Software development is changing fast, and Java developers are right in the middle of it – especially when it comes to using Artificial Intelligence (AI) in their apps. This report brings together feedback from 647 Java professionals to show where things stand and what is possible as Java and AI come together. One of the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/the-state-of-coding-the-future-with-java-and-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Think in an AI World: 5 Lessons for Novice Programmers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 14:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the second article of the series How to Learn to Code in an AI World. Don’t miss the first, Is it Still Worth Learning to Code? Imagine the following scenario: A student is enrolled in an introductory computer science course. They have no previous programming experience and don’t consider themselves very good at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/05/12/five-lessons-for-novice-programmers-ai-world/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: A program does not run correctly if you run it the wrong way, redux</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trying to make the system run the program automatically.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250512-00/?p=111174 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use C# 14 extensions to simplify enum Parsing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In .NET, many types provide a static Parse method to convert strings into their respective types. For example: int.Parse(&amp;quot;123&amp;quot;); double.Parse(&amp;quot;123.45&amp;quot;); DateTime.Parse(&amp;quot;2023-01-01&amp;quot;); IPAddress.Parse(&amp;quot;192.168.0.1&amp;quot;); However, enums require the use of the Enum.Parse method: Enum.Parse(&amp;quot;Value1&amp;quot;); // MyEnum.Parse(&amp;quot;Value1&amp;quot;); // This doesn&#39;t work Wouldn&#39;t it be more intuitive if enums supported a Parse…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/use-csharp-14-extensions-to-simplify-enum-parsing.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Security Risks of “Vibe Coding” for Enterprise AI Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s a quiet rebellion happening in AI development. Developers are increasingly bypassing traditional planning and documentation processes in favor of a faster, more instinctive approach: “vibe coding.” It’s agile, it’s exciting, and in fast-moving teams, it often feels like the only way to keep pace. But when enterprise applications meet compliance-heavy environments, this seat-of-the-pants coding […] The article Hidden Security Risks of “Vibe Coding” for Enterprise AI Projects was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing HealthBench</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HealthBench is a new evaluation benchmark for AI in healthcare which evaluates models in realistic scenarios. Built with input from 250+ physicians, it aims to provide a shared standard for model performance and safety in health.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/healthbench 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Says… Avoid Going Across the Wire Until Necessary!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network calls create significant performance bottlenecks in modern applications due to latency and unpredictability. Developers should prioritize chunky communication and batch requests to improve efficiency, as demonstrated through API development experiences. Monitoring usage and enforcing standards can enhance performance, emphasizing that optimal design must consider the entire stack, including network performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/05/12/dotnetdave-says-avoid-going-across-the-wire-until-necessary/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement client assertions with client credentials flow using OAuth DPoP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 05:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog looks at implementing client assertions for the client credentials flow using OAuth 2.0 Demonstration of Proof-of-Possession (DPoP). The client credentials flow is an OAuth 2.0 authorization grant type used for machine-to-machine authentication. DPoP further strengthens the security by ensuring that the client possesses a specific key at the time of the request, forcing […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/05/12/implement-client-assertions-with-client-credentials-flow-using-oauth-dpop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
