<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:10:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop for Mac: QEMU Virtualization Option to be Deprecated in 90 Days</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are announcing the upcoming deprecation of QEMU as a virtualization option for Docker Desktop on Apple Silicon Macs. After serving as our legacy virtualization solution during the early transition to Apple Silicon, QEMU will be fully deprecated 90 days from today, on July 14, 2025. This deprecation does not affect QEMU’s role in emulating […]
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-for-mac-qemu-virtualization-option-to-be-deprecated-in-90-days/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K2 Mode in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1: Current State and FAQ</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1, K2 mode, a new implementation of Kotlin support, will be enabled by default. This change is an important step in the ongoing effort to improve Kotlin support in the IDE. While this transition brings many improvements and lays the foundation for a smoother, more reliable experience in the future, it’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/k2-mode-in-intellij-idea-2025-1-current-state-and-faq/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There was a lot of imagined dropping tablets in swimming pools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The archetypical example of needing a replacement computer.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250415-00/?p=111075 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Bazel Plugin 2025.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 13:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to tell you about all the changes we’ve made in recent months to improve the Bazel plugin experience in IntelliJ IDEA. Every couple of weeks, we’ve been shipping updates to JetBrains Marketplace with focused fixes and features. Over time, these smaller updates have amounted to substantial enhancements. Most updates are included in the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/what-s-new-in-bazel-plugin-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2025: Full Schedule</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++ is our free, one-day, virtual conference for the whole C++ community. This year, it is running on the 30th April. We’re pleased to announce the schedule of live talks: 14:00 UTC: Welcome to v1.0 of the meta::[[verse]]! with Inbal Levi 14:30 UTC: Proxy: Next Generation Polymorphism with Mingxin Wang 15:00 UTC: Making […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-cpp-2025-full-schedule 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn AI-Assisted Programming With JetBrains Academy and Nebius</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learning to code with AI isn’t cheating – it’s the next skill every developer needs. AI tools are changing the way we write, test, and maintain code but using them effectively isn’t always straightforward. That’s why we’ve partnered with Nebius, an AI cloud platform known for its expertise in high-performance and AI-first workloads, to bring […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/04/15/learn-ai-assisted-programming-with-jetbrains-academy-and-nebius/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding GraphQL in .NET: When and why to use it</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:28:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            APIs are the heart of most modern applications. Due to their simplicity and lightweight design, RESTful APIs are a popular choice for client-server communication in most applications. However, APIs can become limiting when fetching complex or related data. The front end may over-fetch or under-fetch the meaningful data. For example,
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-graphql-in-net-when-and-why-to-use-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Tests for Plugin Developers: GitHub Actions and Setting Up Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog posts, we created integration tests that interact with UI components, assert different properties of UI components, and interact with APIs. Now, it’s time to look at how to set up continuous integration to ensure that we don’t break them in the next commit. We will be creating continuous integration using GitHub […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/integration-tests-for-plugin-developers-github-actions-and-setting-up-continuous-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbox App 2.6 Is Here With Remote Development Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Toolbox App 2.6 introduces support for remote development, allowing you to manage JetBrains tools and projects both locally and on remote servers. You can connect to different host platforms, including Windows, macOS, and Linux, and use the integrated OpenSSH for secure and customizable SSH connections. The Toolbox App supports connections to remote SSH hosts, as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/toolbox-app/2025/04/toolbox-app-2-6-is-here-with-remote-development-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetEscapades.​AspNetCore.​SecurityHeaders 1.0.0 has been released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe the recent major changes to NetEscapades.AspNetCore.SecurityHeaders, a NuGet package for adding security headers to your apps.
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/netescapades-aspnetcore-securityheaders-1-0-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q1 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Option to Cancel Continuity Discounts JetBrains Marketplace now allows plugin authors to cancel continuity discounts for paid plugins. This can be done easily from the Sales tab, with the option to set a specific end date. Customers with active subscriptions for existing plugins will still benefit from the discount, while for new […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q1-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Region Selection in Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer for NoSQL Accounts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You asked—we delivered! Users can now manually select the region Data Explorer sends requests to! When you use Entra Authentication with NoSQL accounts, you can now enable the Region Selection option in settings. This new capability gives you precise control over where your requests are sent, helping you test, troubleshoot, and optimize performance by targeting […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-region-selection-in-azure-cosmos-db-data-explorer-for-nosql-accounts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build multi-agent systems with LangGraph and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to integrate open-source multi-agent framework, LangGraph, with Amazon Bedrock. It explains how to use LangGraph and Amazon Bedrock to build powerful, interactive multi-agent applications that use graph-based orchestration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-multi-agent-systems-with-langgraph-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic text-to-SQL for enterprise workloads with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how enterprises can implement a scalable agentic text-to-SQL solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents, with advanced error-handling tools and automated schema discovery to enhance database query efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dynamic-text-to-sql-for-enterprise-workloads-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: Once I have tricked the user into running a malicious shortcut, I can install malware</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yes, that&#39;s sort of the point.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250414-00/?p=111072 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell, OpenSSH, and DSC team investments for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Planned team investments for 2025 for PowerShell, OpenSSH, DSC, and related tooling.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/powershell-openssh-and-dsc-team-investments-for-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind K2 Mode and How It Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m Yan Zhulanow, and I lead the Kotlin Analysis API team. Last year, we made a series of announcements about Kotlin K2 mode in IntelliJ IDEA. Now, as K2 mode is about to become the default, I am thrilled to tell you more about everything we had to go through to make this release happen. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/the-story-behind-k2-mode-and-how-it-works/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and Anthropic Collaborate to Develop Official C# SDK for Model Context Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced a partnership with Anthropic to develop an official C# Software Development Kit (SDK) for the Model Context Protocol (MCP). This collaboration aims to streamline the integration of large language models (LLMs) into C# applications, addressing the growing demand for advanced AI functionalities in enterprise software development. Enhancing AI Integration in C# Applications […] The article Microsoft and Anthropic Collaborate to Develop Official C# SDK for Model Context Protocol was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview of (Hopefully) Improved Projections in Marten 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 01:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Work is continuing on the “Critter Stack 2025” round of releases, but we have finally got an alpha release of Marten 8 (8.0.0-alpha-5) that’s good enough for friendly users and core team members to try out for feedback. 8.0 won’t be a huge release, but we’re making some substantial changes to the projections subsystem and … Continue reading Preview of (Hopefully) Improved Projections in Marten 8 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling MCP Servers in C# with Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I posted recently about how to allow LLMs to call tools using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI NuGet package in C#. Obviously, a common usage scenario would be to expose MCP servers as tools for your LLM to call. Thankfully, the new ModelContextProtocol NuGet package makes this straightforward. Note: This package is still in pre-release (as is Microsoft.Extensions.AI), so do check the release notes for any breaking changes to the API. I&#39;ve updated my demo application to support calling MCP tools, following the techniques demonstrated in Microsoft&#39;s Chat With Tools sample.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Best Practices and Performance for Comparing Strings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_04_2025/13_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_04_2025/13_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In .NET, string comparison can be performed using methods like ==, Equals(), and Compare(), each with distinct performance metrics. The most efficient method is Equals() with StringComparison. It&#39;s crucial to apply optimization practices for enhanced performance, especially in multilingual comparisons, and consider utilizing configuration files for consistent analysis.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/13/microsoft-net-code-analysis-best-practices-and-performance-for-comparing-strings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Vector Search? A Concise Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_04_2025/12_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_04_2025/12_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vector search finds information based on meaning rather than exact keywords, delivering more intuitive results by converting content into numerical vectors that capture semantic relationships.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/what-is-vector-search-a-concise-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: Git – Distributed Version Control System That Changed Everything</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 21:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Few tools have been as transformative — or as quietly omnipresent — as Git. Now twenty years old, Git is not just a version control system; it’s the backbone of global software collaboration. From solo developers hacking on open-source projects to multinational tech giants deploying mission-critical infrastructure, Git is the invisible force managing source code, […] The article Software Innovation: Git – Distributed Version Control System That Changed Everything was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Spring Cloud Azure Starter Key Vault JCA: Streamlined TLS and mTLS for Spring Boot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 21:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post shows the Spring Cloud Azure Starter Key Vault Java Crypto Architecture (JCA).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/introducing-spring-cloud-azure-starter-key-vault-jca-streamlined-tls-and-mtls-for-spring-boot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure AI Foundry: Create an MCP Server with Azure AI Agent Service (TypeScript Edition)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 18:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to integrate Azure AI Foundry&#39;s Agent Service with Claude Desktop using the Model Context Protocol (MCP) for powerful integration for MCP clients.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/integrating-azure-ai-agents-mcp-typescript 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AIOps chatbot with Amazon Q Business custom plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use custom plugins for Amazon Q Business to build a chatbot that can interact with multiple APIs using natural language prompts. We showcase how to build an AIOps chatbot that enables users to interact with their AWS infrastructure through natural language queries and commands. The chatbot is capable of handling tasks such as querying the data about Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) ports and Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) buckets access settings.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Revolutionize Business Automation with AI: A Guide to Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel Process Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Revolutionize Business Automation with AI: A Guide to Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel Process Framework Step-by-Step guide on creating your first process with AI Microsoft’s AI Framework, Semantic Kernel, is an easy-to-use C#, Java, and Python-based AI framework that helps you quickly build AI solutions or integrate AI capabilities into your existing app. Semantic Kernel provides various […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-revolutionize-business-automation-with-ai-a-guide-to-microsofts-semantic-kernel-process-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How TransPerfect Improved Translation Quality and Efficiency Using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes how the AWS Customer Channel Technology – Localization Team worked with TransPerfect to integrate Amazon Bedrock into the GlobalLink translation management system, a cloud-based solution designed to help organizations manage their multilingual content and translation workflows. Organizations use TransPerfect’s solution to rapidly create and deploy content at scale in multiple languages using AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-transperfect-improved-translation-quality-and-efficiency-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racing beyond DeepRacer: Debut of the AWS LLM League</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS LLM League was designed to lower the barriers to entry in generative AI model customization by providing an experience where participants, regardless of their prior data science experience, could engage in fine-tuning LLMs. Using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart, attendees were guided through the process of customizing LLMs to address real business challenges adaptable to their domain.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/racing-beyond-deepracer-debut-of-the-aws-llm-league/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Microsoft Graph PowerShell 2.26&#43; compatibility issues with Azure Runbooks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 15:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We know how important Azure Automation workflows and appreciate the critical role played by automation runbooks. Some customers have experienced issues with the release of 2.26.1 of the Microsoft Graph PowerShell SDK, particularly when running PowerShell 7.2 runbooks in Azure Automation. The core challenge is a conflict around .NET 6 where fixing Runbooks would break […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/resolving-microsoft-graph-powershell-2-26-compatibility-issues-with-azure-runbooks 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the UI thread that hung in a kernel call</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I did tell you not to do that.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250411-00/?p=111066 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: Scott Hanselman – Empowering Developer Community Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Few voices in the Microsoft and .NET space rise above the rest as much as Scott Hanselman. He’s a developer, teacher, speaker, and currently the Vice President of Developer Community at Microsoft. For over two decades, Scott has been a connecting force in the tech world, linking developers to tools, platforms, and to each other. […] The article Big Thinkers: Scott Hanselman – Empowering Developer Community Worldwide was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting insights from changes to items in Azure Cosmos DB just got easier!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB’s change feed provides a view of changes to data in your container. This enables patterns like event sourcing, auditing and synchronizing downstream systems. Change feed can be read in real time or on demand, giving you the most flexibility for processing and reprocessing changes. Change feed is available in two modes, latest […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/getting-insights-from-changes-to-items-in-azure-cosmos-db-just-got-easier 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Docker Extension for Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Speed up development with Docker DX extension with real-time feedback, smarter linting, and intuitive Bake/Compose file support in VS Code.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-dx-extension-for-vs-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 3 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out about the new features in .NET 10 Preview 3 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, C#, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce ML training costs with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the challenges of large-scale frontier model training, focusing on hardware failures and the benefits of Amazon SageMaker HyperPod - a solution that minimizes disruptions, enhances efficiency, and reduces training costs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/reduce-ml-training-costs-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Variables &amp; Methods are Evil?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 19:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You might have heard the recommendation to steer clear of static variables or methods. But is that really good advice? Let’s dive into why people say that, with a little nuance, and clarify the topic with some examples. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video… Read More »Static Variables &amp;amp; Methods are Evil? The post Static Variables &amp;amp; Methods are Evil?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Increase Code Quality in GitHub With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 17:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago we shared a post on how to integrate Qodana with Github Actions on the .NET Community – but a lot has changed since then. Qodana self-hosted has been released, with analysis that can make your code more secure by detecting hardcoded passwords and running taint analysis for JVM. The new Android Linter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/04/code-quality-in-github/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft at PyTexas 2025: Join Us for a Celebration of Python and Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 17:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft is thrilled to announce our participation in PyTexas 2025, taking place this year in the vibrant city of Austin, Texas! At this year’s event, Microsoft is proud to contribute to the community’s growth and excitement by hosting a booth and delivering an engaging talk.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/pytexas-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Language Support in ReSharper and Rider 2025.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our release for ReSharper and Rider 2025.1 is just around the corner, and we have lots of exciting features shipping for the current and next version of C#! This will be a really long post (blame our awesome devs!), so make sure to use the table of contents on the right. Oh, and of course… […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/10/csharp-language-support-in-resharper-and-rider-2025-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model customization, RAG, or both: A case study with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The introduction of Amazon Nova models represent a significant advancement in the field of AI, offering new opportunities for large language model (LLM) optimization. In this post, we demonstrate how to effectively perform model customization and RAG with Amazon Nova models as a baseline. We conducted a comprehensive comparison study between model customization and RAG using the latest Amazon Nova models, and share these valuable insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/model-customization-rag-or-both-a-case-study-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate user-personalized communication with Amazon Personalize and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Personalize and Amazon Bedrock to generate personalized outreach emails for individual users using a video-on-demand use case. This concept can be applied to other domains, such as compelling customer experiences for ecommerce and digital marketing use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-user-personalized-communication-with-amazon-personalize-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating regulatory compliance: A multi-agent solution using Amazon Bedrock and CrewAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how AI agents can streamline compliance and fulfill regulatory requirements for financial institutions using Amazon Bedrock and CrewAI. We demonstrate how to build a multi-agent system that can automatically summarize new regulations, assess their impact on operations, and provide prescriptive technical guidance. You&#39;ll learn how to use Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon Bedrock Agents with CrewAI to create a comprehensive, automated compliance solution.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 – Help Shape the Future of Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since 2017, we’ve been checking in with developers around the world to better understand how the industry is evolving and how we can build better tools to support you. Now, the Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025 is live, and we’d love for you to be part of it. This annual survey is a community milestone that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2025/04/10/developer-ecosystem-survey-2025-help-shape-the-future-of-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire 9.2 is Now Available with New Ways to Deploy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Aspire 9.2 is now available with cool new dashboard features and introducing the publishers feature
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-aspire-92-is-now-available-with-new-ways-to-deploy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixtral Large is now available in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to get started with the Pixtral Large model in Amazon Bedrock. The Pixtral Large multimodal model allows you to tackle a variety of use cases, such as document understanding, logical reasoning, handwriting recognition, image comparison, entity extraction, extracting structured data from scanned images, and caption generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pixtral-large-is-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Context Parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Context parameters are an upcoming feature in Kotlin, with a variety of use cases including more powerful extension methods and better tools for DSL development. Kotlin 2.2.0 will feature context parameters in Beta, and dedicated IntelliJ IDEA support will be available from 2025.1. Context parameters replace another experimental feature in the language, namely context receivers. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/04/update-on-context-parameters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 14:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Microsoft 365 Certification ensures ISVs use the latest privacy and personally identifiable information (PII) management controls to protect customer data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-privacy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Function overloading is more flexible (and more convenient) than template function specialization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can change more things in an overload.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250410-00/?p=111063 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bug-Fix Releases Are Available – MPS 2024.3.2 and MPS 2024.1.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 11:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released updates for MPS 2024.1 and MPS 2024.3 that fix several additional issues. Check them out and see what you think. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3.2 Download MPS 2024.3.2 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Download MPS 2024.1.3 here. See the full list of fixed issues here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/04/mps-2024-3-2-has-been-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown in Java Docs? Shut Up and Take My Comments!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 07:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you’re building a cutting-edge Java library, optimizing every method, and writing the most efficient algorithms. At some point, you’ll need to document your code because well-documented code increases adoption (a fact backed by various surveys). Including documentation comments within a Java class ensures that the documentation evolves with the code, keeping it relevant. Using […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/markdown-in-java-docs-shut-up-and-take-my-comments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using an MCP Server in GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2025/10_04_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot is continuing to evolve very rapidly, with the recent launch of &amp;quot;agent mode&amp;quot;, and the ability to connect to &amp;quot;Model Context Protocol&amp;quot; servers which gives you access to a vast array of tools, essentially allowing your agent to access any data, and perform any actions you like. In this post, I&#39;ll walk you through the steps to configure Visual Studio Code to connect to an MCP Server and make use of it in agent mode.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Hybrid Search with Semantic Kernel for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 19:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re thrilled to announce support for Hybrid search with Semantic Kernel Vector Stores for .NET. What is Hybrid Search? Hybrid search performs two parallel searches on a vector database. The union of the results of these two searches are then returned to callers with a combined rank, based on the rankings from each of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-hybrid-search-with-semantic-kernel-for-net 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement human-in-the-loop confirmation with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 19:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus specifically on enabling end-users to approve actions and provide feedback using built-in Amazon Bedrock Agents features, specifically HITL patterns for providing safe and effective agent operations. We explore the patterns available using a Human Resources (HR) agent example that helps employees requesting time off.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-human-in-the-loop-confirmation-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework April 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 19:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for April 2025.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-april-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we ended up rewriting NuGet Restore in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the journey that led to a full rewrite of the NuGet Restore algorithm in .NET 9, achieving break-through scale and performance.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/rewriting-nuget-restore-in-dotnet-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost team productivity with Amazon Q Business Insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 16:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Q Business Insights capabilities and its importance for organizations. We begin with an overview of the available metrics and how they can be used for measuring user engagement and system effectiveness. Then we provide instructions for accessing and navigating this dashboard.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-team-productivity-with-amazon-q-business-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-LLM routing strategies for generative AI applications on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 16:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are increasingly using multiple large language models (LLMs) when building generative AI applications. Although an individual LLM can be highly capable, it might not optimally address a wide range of use cases or meet diverse performance requirements. The multi-LLM approach enables organizations to effectively choose the right model for each task, adapt to different […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multi-llm-routing-strategies-for-generative-ai-applications-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Together: .NET Aspire, Azure Functions, and Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever struggled with integrating serverless technology into your existing .NET projects? The new update in Visual Studio has got you covered. Say hello to the powerful integration of .NET Aspire with Azure Functions, making your development process smoother than ever before. With this release of Visual Studio, Azure Functions developers can enlist in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//net-aspire-and-azure-functions-integration-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Real-Time Insights: Power BI Integration with vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB Now in Public Preview!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 14:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to introduce Power BI integration for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB. This certified solution brings your operational data to life through real-time dashboards, directly in the Power BI interface that your analytics teams already love. You can now connect Power BI Desktop directly to your vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/unlock-real-time-insights-power-bi-integration-with-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-vcore-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: A Comprehensive Guide to Agentic AI with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to welcome Arafat Tehsin, who’s a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for AI. back as a guest author on the Semantic Kernel blog today to cover his work on a Comprehensive Guide to Agentic AI with Semantic Kernel. We’ll turn it over to Arafat to dive in further. The world of AI is evolving […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-a-comprehensive-guide-to-agentic-ai-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the agent debugging experience in Microsoft 365 Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:58:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to debug your agents within Microsoft 365 Copilot to streamline your workflow using the agent debugging experience, now generally available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-the-agent-debugging-experience-in-microsoft-365-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Gemma 3 with Docker Model Runner: Fully Local GenAI Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how to run Gemma 3 models locally using Docker Model Runner, alongside a Comment Processing System as a practical case study.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-gemma-3-locally-with-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Docker Model Runner: A Better Way to Build and Run GenAI Models Locally</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Model Runner is a faster, simpler way to run and test AI models locally, right from your existing workflow.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2025: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 12:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the April 2025 edition of our monthly developer update, summarizing the latest news and developments in Microsoft Entra. This month, we bring you feature updates, public previews, announcements, and other important updates. Read on to learn more and make the most of Microsoft Entra.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-apr-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire and Azure Functions integration preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever struggled with integrating serverless technology into your existing .NET projects? The new update in Visual Studio has got you covered. Say hello to the powerful integration of .NET Aspire with Azure Functions, making your development process smoother than ever before. With this release of Visual Studio, Azure Functions developers can enlist in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/net-aspire-and-azure-functions-integration-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of LLM Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The journey of Large Language Models (LLMs) is moving fast—from understanding language to driving real-world enterprise workflows. But to truly… The post The Evolution of LLM Integration appeared first on Daily .NET Tips.
Link to article: https://dailydotnettips.com/the-evolution-of-llm-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Rider 2025.1 Release Candidate is ready for you to try! The upcoming stable release delivers initial support for .NET 10 and C# 14 Preview features. It also brings the new Files view for repository-wide visibility, a Roslyn syntax tree visualizer, and numerous enhancements for debugging both .NET and C++ solutions. If you’re ready to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/rider-2025-1-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.1 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper and .NET tools 2025.1 RCs are now available. This ReSharper update delivers initial support for .NET 10 Preview and C# 14 features, along with expanded inspections, smarter refactorings, and noticeable performance improvements. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the next release, you can download the RC build from our website […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/04/09/resharper-2025-1-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Retry Logic Made Easy with Spargine’s ExecutionHelper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2025/09_04_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a collection of open-source .NET assemblies and NuGet packages designed for enhanced functionality, featuring the ExecutionHelper methods: ProgressiveRetry() and ProgressiveRetryAsync(). These methods manage transient operation failures with retry logic and progressive delays. Additionally, proactive resource checks like IsNetworkAvailable() improve application reliability by checking resource availability before retrying.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/04/09/boost-your-net-projects-retry-logic-made-easy-with-spargines-executionhelper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Box subscriptions and licensing requirements demystified: What You Need and Why</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 22:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thinking of deploying Microsoft Dev Box service but want to understand the licensing and subscription requirements first? Then, you have come to the right place. This blog post breaks it all down—clearly and simply—so you know exactly what you need and why, whether you’re an IT admin, platform engineer, developer, or a decision-maker. Microsoft Dev […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/microsoft-dev-box-subscriptions-and-licensing-requirements-demystified 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April Patches for Azure DevOps Server and Team Foundation Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 19:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing patches that impact our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server, as well as Team Foundation Server 2018.3.2. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can download the latest version of the product, Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 from the Azure DevOps […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/april-patches-for-azure-devops-server-and-team-foundation-server-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 18:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Release Candidate is available for download, so we’re one step away from the major release! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. To use this build, an active subscription to IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate is required. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 RC […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/intellij-idea-2025-1-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (March 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 18:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.03.19 registry release, 2025-03-13 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout March. This release includes two new commands for our continuous integration system PR reviews, minor bugfixes, a new documentation article on authenticating to NuGet feeds, and a […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-march-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How iFood built a platform to run hundreds of machine learning models with Amazon SageMaker Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 17:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how iFood uses SageMaker to revolutionize its ML operations. By harnessing the power of SageMaker, iFood streamlines the entire ML lifecycle, from model training to deployment. This integration not only simplifies complex processes but also automates critical tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-ifood-built-a-platform-to-run-hundreds-of-machine-learning-models-with-amazon-sagemaker-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an enterprise synthetic data strategy using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Bedrock for synthetic data generation, considering these challenges alongside the potential benefits to develop effective strategies for various applications across multiple industries, including AI and machine learning (ML).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-enterprise-synthetic-data-strategy-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Tools for JetBrains IDE Plugin Development: Livestream Recording and Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The recording of our livestream is available on JetBrains TV! In the recent session, IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Yann Cébron and Jakub Chrzanowski explored some of the most helpful tools for developing plugins for JetBrains IDEs. From plugin creation to UI debugging, the session covered practical tips and tricks to enhance your workflow. Let’s take […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/04/essential-tools-for-jetbrains-ide-plugin-development-livestream-recording-and-key-takeaways/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Process CPU Usage Analysis in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Streamlined Performance Insights Across Processes The Visual Studio Profiler’s CPU Usage tool and Instrumentation tool now supports multi-process analysis, providing a unified view of CPU activity across multiple processes. With performance graphs featuring distinct, color-coded stacked swim lanes for each process, diagnosing and optimizing CPU usage is now more efficient than ever. Tackling Multi-Process Complexity […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/multi-process-cpu-usage-analysis-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Vector Store Connectors update: Faiss, Azure SQL Server and Pinecone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 14:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing New Vector Stores: Faiss, SQL Server, and Pinecone We are thrilled to announce the availability of three new Vector Stores and Vector Store Record Collections: Faiss, SQL Server, and Pinecone. These new connectors will enable you to store and retrieve vector data efficiently, making it easier to work with your own data and data […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/python-vector-store-connectors-update-faiss-azure-sql-server-and-pinecone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Goldilocks zone of software stability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not too new, not too old.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250408-00/?p=111057 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Terminal: A New Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 13:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce our reworked terminal architecture, which is available in Beta starting with the 2025.1 versions of JetBrains IDEs. It now runs on a stable, standards-compliant core and uses the IDE’s editor for UI rendering. This change lets us introduce new features while preserving compatibility and performance across various platforms, whether local or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/04/jetbrains-terminal-a-new-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write AI Prompts That Output Valid JSON Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 12:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with LLMs, an extremely valuable use case is generating structured data as the output response of the AI prompt. Whether you’re building an app, prototyping a data pipeline, or performing data extraction or transformation, receiving structured outputs like JSON saves time and makes downstream processing seamless. But there’s a challenge: these models are […] The article How to Write AI Prompts That Output Valid JSON Data was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verifying tricky git rebases with git range-diff</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at the git range-diff feature, show what it&#39;s for and how it works, explain the output format, and demonstrate it with a toy scenario
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/verifiying-tricky-git-rebases-with-range-diffs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing JSON Serialization in .NET: Newtonsoft.Json vs. System.Text.Json</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 08:19:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2025/08_04_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JavaScript Object Notation (JSON) is a popular data storage and transmitting format. Whether you are a front-end or back-end developer, you must be familiar with it. As a.NET developer, you don&#39;t need an introduction to this text-based data format. The two most prominent libraries are Newtonsoft.Json
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/optimizing-json-serialization-in-net-newtonsoft-json-vs-system-text-json/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
