<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 22:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework May 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for May 2025.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-may-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving SnapStart Performance in .NET Lambda Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 21:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS recently added AWS Lambda SnapStart support for .NET Lambda functions to deliver faster function startup performance, from several seconds to as low as sub-second, typically with minimal or no code changes. This post explores techniques to maximize the performance gains of SnapStart for several different types of .NET workloads. For a high-level overview and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/blog-improving-snapstart-performance-in-net-lambdas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate AI Applications with Semantic Caching on Azure Managed Redis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog, we will look at implementing the Semantic caching use case using Azure Managed Redis. Azure has been at the forefront of providing caching solutions for over a decade with the Azure Cache for Redis enterprise. This service empowered developers with a high-performance, scalable cache that significantly enhanced the responsiveness of their applications. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/accelerate-ai-applications-with-semantic-caching-on-azure-managed-redis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eclipse &#43; GitHub Copilot = Lightspeed SAP ABAP Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 21:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Did you catch the GitHub’s recent announcement of ABAP support in GitHub Copilot for Eclipse? It is a significant step forward for SAP developers. This integration brings AI-powered code suggestions and chat functionalities directly into the Eclipse IDE, potentially revolutionizing ABAP development. Let’s break down how it works, how to set it up, and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/eclipse-github-copilot-lightspeed-sap-abap-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Years of Software Architecture: Best And Worst Decisions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 20:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the last 10 years, I’ve been developing a single product, greenfield, designing the architecture from scratch, and evolving it over time. Over this decade-long journey, I’ve made some architectural decisions I’m proud of—and some I definitely regret. Today, I want to share those experiences with you, diving deep into the good and bad decisions… Read More »10 Years of Software Architecture: Best And Worst Decisions The post 10 Years of Software Architecture: Best And Worst Decisions appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 4 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out about the new features in .NET 10 Preview 4 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, C#, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-4 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Amazon Bedrock Agents: A guide to safeguarding against indirect prompt injections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI tools have transformed how we work, create, and process information. At Amazon Web Services (AWS), security is our top priority. Therefore, Amazon Bedrock provides comprehensive security controls and best practices to help protect your applications and data. In this post, we explore the security measures and practical strategies provided by Amazon Bedrock Agents to safeguard your AI interactions against indirect prompt injections, making sure that your applications remain both secure and reliable.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New for C&#43;&#43; Developers in Visual Studio 2022 17.14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 version 17.14 is now generally available! This post summarizes the new features you can find in this release for C++. You can download Visual Studio 2022 from the Visual Studio downloads page or upgrade your existing installation by following the Update Visual Studio Learn page. Standard Library and Compiler We’ve made a myriad of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-for-cpp-developers-in-visual-studio-2022-17-14 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent mode has arrived in preview for Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plan, build, test, and fix — all from one prompt. Agent mode is now available in public preview for all users in Visual Studio 17.14. Agent mode in Visual Studio allows you to define tasks using natural language, with Copilot autonomously planning, editing your codebase, invoking tools, and iterating to resolve issues. Unlike Copilot Chat […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/agent-mode-has-arrived-in-preview-for-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Visual Studio 2022 v17.14 is now generally available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the general availability of Visual Studio 2022 version 17.14! This release continues our mission to empower developers with faster, smarter, and more productive tools across all workloads. There is so much for developers to love in this release, so be sure to check out the release notes for the full list. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2022-v17-14-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build scalable containerized RAG based generative AI applications in AWS using Amazon EKS with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) with Amazon Bedrock to build scalable and containerized RAG solutions for your generative AI applications on AWS while bringing your unstructured user file data to Amazon Bedrock in a straightforward, fast, and secure way.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-scalable-containerized-rag-based-generative-ai-applications-in-aws-using-amazon-eks-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Hexagon built an AI assistant using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recognizing the transformative benefits of generative AI for enterprises, we at Hexagon’s Asset Lifecycle Intelligence division sought to enhance how users interact with our Enterprise Asset Management (EAM) products. Understanding these advantages, we partnered with AWS to embark on a journey to develop HxGN Alix, an AI-powered digital worker using AWS generative AI services. This blog post explores the strategy, development, and implementation of HxGN Alix, demonstrating how a tailored AI solution can drive efficiency and enhance user satisfaction.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build 2025 Preview: Transform Your AI Apps and Agents with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Build is less than a week away, and the Azure Cosmos DB team will be out in force to showcase the newest features and capabilities for building AI apps and agents with scalable, fast, high-performance data. Whether you’re in person at the Seattle Convention Center or watching the live or on-demand digital show, we […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/build-2025-preview-transform-your-ai-apps-and-agents-with-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip and Database Tools UX Survey #2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to launch the second edition of our User Experience Survey for DataGrip and the Database Tools &amp;amp; SQL Plugin! Your feedback from the previous survey helped us better understand your needs and prioritize the features and improvements that matter most to you. Thanks to your input, we’ve already delivered a first set of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/05/13/datagrip-and-database-tools-ux-survey-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the developer set-up for developing Windows for multiple processor architectures?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You usually just pick one and count on your friends for the others.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250513-00/?p=111176 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Rust the Future of Programming?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 12:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rust is rewriting the rules of modern software development as the fastest-growing programming language. Its unmatched performance, memory safety without garbage collection, and concurrency capabilities are capturing developers’ attention worldwide. According to our data, with 2,267,000 developers using Rust in the last 12 months and 709,000 identifying it as a primary language, Rust’s footprint in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/05/13/is-rust-the-future-of-programming/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Cloud-Ready Apps Locally: Spring Boot, AWS, and LocalStack in Action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developing an application with AWS services can introduce significant local‑development hurdles. Often, developers don’t receive timely AWS access, or a sysadmin inadvertently grants credentials for the wrong account – only to fix the error a week later. Then, when engineers discover they still lack permissions for certain resources, they must endure yet another week-long wait […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/building-cloud-ready-apps-locally-spring-boot-aws-and-localstack-in-action/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream: Plugin Verifier and API Compatibility Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Maintaining plugin compatibility across JetBrains IDEs can be tricky — but the Plugin Verifier is here to help. On Wednesday, May 21, at 2:00 PM UTC, join us for a live session with IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocates Róbert Novotný and Yann Cébron, focused on the Plugin Verifier and API compatibility maintenance. During the webinar, you’ll discover how: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/05/livestream-plugin-verifier-and-api-compatibility-maintenance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Generally Available: Apple identity provider support for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m excited to announce that &amp;quot;Sign in with Apple&amp;quot; is now generally available for external tenants in Entra External ID. The feature has been in public preview since February, and many customers have already integrated Apple as an identity provider for their applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/now-generally-available-apple-identity-provider-support-for-microsoft-entra-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CodeCanvas 2025.1 With Free Tier and Toolbox Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 09:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April, we released CodeCanvas 2025.1 with many important changes. The release brings improved infrastructure flexibility for easier multi-region setups, a new AWS CloudFormation installation option, enhanced environment logs, and more. Today, we want to highlight two major updates: See the full What’s New for the full details. Use CodeCanvas for free With the 2025.1 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/05/codecanvas-2025-1-with-free-tier-and-toolbox-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the new AI template to create a chatbot about a website</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I use the new Microsoft&#39;s new .NET AI template to ingest the contents of a website and create a chatbot that can answer questions with citations
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/using-the-new-ai-template-to-create-a-chatbot-about-a-website/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft deletes in EF Core: How to implement and query efficiently</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What does your application actually do with a record when a user deletes it? Can your application afford to delete a record permanently? One mistake can result in irreparable damage to the application. Today, I will shed light on D of the CRUD. Among all the CRUD operations, Delete is
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/soft-deletes-in-ef-core-how-to-implement-and-query-efficiently/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent community agent to revolutionize IT support with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 17:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how your organization can reduce the end-to-end burden of resolving regular challenges experienced by your IT support teams—from understanding errors and reviewing diagnoses, remediation steps, and relevant documentation, to opening external support tickets using common third-party services such as Jira.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-community-agent-to-revolutionize-it-support-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Claude-Ready Entra ID-Protected MCP Servers with Azure API Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 17:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the launch of custom integrations in Claude, developers and enterprises can now extend Claude’s capabilities by connecting their own hosted Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers as native integrations. This capability allows Claude and any of its agents to perform complex tasks by invoking a variety of APIs exposed through MCP servers. Developers might wonder […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/claude-ready-secure-mcp-apim 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Coding the Future with Java and AI – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 15:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Software development is changing fast, and Java developers are right in the middle of it – especially when it comes to using Artificial Intelligence (AI) in their apps. This report brings together feedback from 647 Java professionals to show where things stand and what is possible as Java and AI come together. One of the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/the-state-of-coding-the-future-with-java-and-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Think in an AI World: 5 Lessons for Novice Programmers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 14:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the second article of the series How to Learn to Code in an AI World. Don’t miss the first, Is it Still Worth Learning to Code? Imagine the following scenario: A student is enrolled in an introductory computer science course. They have no previous programming experience and don’t consider themselves very good at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/05/12/five-lessons-for-novice-programmers-ai-world/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: A program does not run correctly if you run it the wrong way, redux</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trying to make the system run the program automatically.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250512-00/?p=111174 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use C# 14 extensions to simplify enum Parsing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In .NET, many types provide a static Parse method to convert strings into their respective types. For example: int.Parse(&amp;quot;123&amp;quot;); double.Parse(&amp;quot;123.45&amp;quot;); DateTime.Parse(&amp;quot;2023-01-01&amp;quot;); IPAddress.Parse(&amp;quot;192.168.0.1&amp;quot;); However, enums require the use of the Enum.Parse method: Enum.Parse(&amp;quot;Value1&amp;quot;); // MyEnum.Parse(&amp;quot;Value1&amp;quot;); // This doesn&#39;t work Wouldn&#39;t it be more intuitive if enums supported a Parse…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/use-csharp-14-extensions-to-simplify-enum-parsing.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Security Risks of “Vibe Coding” for Enterprise AI Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s a quiet rebellion happening in AI development. Developers are increasingly bypassing traditional planning and documentation processes in favor of a faster, more instinctive approach: “vibe coding.” It’s agile, it’s exciting, and in fast-moving teams, it often feels like the only way to keep pace. But when enterprise applications meet compliance-heavy environments, this seat-of-the-pants coding […] The article Hidden Security Risks of “Vibe Coding” for Enterprise AI Projects was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing HealthBench</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HealthBench is a new evaluation benchmark for AI in healthcare which evaluates models in realistic scenarios. Built with input from 250+ physicians, it aims to provide a shared standard for model performance and safety in health.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/healthbench 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Says… Avoid Going Across the Wire Until Necessary!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network calls create significant performance bottlenecks in modern applications due to latency and unpredictability. Developers should prioritize chunky communication and batch requests to improve efficiency, as demonstrated through API development experiences. Monitoring usage and enforcing standards can enhance performance, emphasizing that optimal design must consider the entire stack, including network performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/05/12/dotnetdave-says-avoid-going-across-the-wire-until-necessary/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement client assertions with client credentials flow using OAuth DPoP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 05:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog looks at implementing client assertions for the client credentials flow using OAuth 2.0 Demonstration of Proof-of-Possession (DPoP). The client credentials flow is an OAuth 2.0 authorization grant type used for machine-to-machine authentication. DPoP further strengthens the security by ensuring that the client possesses a specific key at the time of the request, forcing […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/05/12/implement-client-assertions-with-client-credentials-flow-using-oauth-dpop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Auto Creation of Database or Message Broker Resources in the Critter Stack vNext</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2025/11_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 21:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2025/11_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’d prefer to start with more context, skip to the section named “Why is this important?”. To set up the problem I’m hoping to address in this post, there are several settings across both Marten and Wolverine that need to be configured for the most optimal possible functioning between development, testing, and deployment time … Continue reading Managing Auto Creation of Database or Message Broker Resources in the Critter Stack vNext →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Supercharge Your Performance Tracking with PerformanceStopwatch in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2025/11_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2025/11_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a set of open-source .NET assemblies that includes the PerformanceStopwatch, designed to enhance performance measurement. This tool offers features like lap tracking, alert thresholds, and telemetry integration for real-time diagnostics. It&#39;s a valuable resource for developers aiming to optimize and debug .NET applications efficiently.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/05/11/boost-your-net-projects-supercharge-your-performance-tracking-with-performancestopwatch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These AI Agents Ain&#39;t It - Dev Leader Weekly 94</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss my experience using AI agents to refactor code.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/10/these-ai-agents-aint-it-dev-leader-weekly-94 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-05-09</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 06:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/10/weekly-recap-20250509 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Anemic Models to Behavior-Driven Models: A Practical DDD Refactor in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2025/10_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A practical guide to transforming anemic domain models into behavior-rich aggregates in C# through incremental refactoring, enhancing code maintainability and business rule clarity.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/from-anemic-models-to-behavior-driven-models-a-practical-ddd-refactor-in-csharp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Office Is Modernizing Their App Suite’s UI using Windows App SDK and React Native</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An inside look at how Office has modernized their UI with WinAppSDK and React Native.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/react-native/2025-05-09-office-modernize 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAST vs DAST: Differences And When to Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anyone working in the software development field knows cybersecurity is a threat you cannot afford to downplay. A cyberattack on a product or service you’ve created carries a risk of serious financial and reputational damage, as well as regulatory penalties, depending on the industry and jurisdiction. Defending your software against cyberattacks means addressing security at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/05/sast-vs-dast/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate marketing intelligence with Amazon Bedrock and LLMs for content creation, sentiment analysis, and campaign performance evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the media and entertainment industry, understanding and predicting the effectiveness of marketing campaigns is crucial for success. Marketing campaigns are the driving force behind successful businesses, playing a pivotal role in attracting new customers, retaining existing ones, and ultimately boosting revenue. However, launching a campaign isn’t enough; to maximize their impact and help achieve […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-marketing-intelligence-with-amazon-bedrock-and-llms-for-content-creation-sentiment-analysis-and-campaign-performance-evaluation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2025: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 15:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the May edition of our monthly newsletter, summarizing the latest news and developments in the exciting, ever-evolving world of Microsoft Entra.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-feb-25-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Compose Multiplatform for iOS is Stable (Plus AI, Web, and More!)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sit back, relax, and let the Kotlin vibes roll in. This roundup is overflowing with news: major moves in Kotlin Multiplatform (Compose Multiplatform for iOS is Stable 🎉), server-side upgrades, Kotlin for web, and smarter Kotlin development with JetBrains AI. Whether you’re building mobile apps, backend services, or playing with interactive notebooks, there’s something here […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/kodees-kotlin-roundup-compose-multiplatform-for-ios-is-stable/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRUD APIs are Poor Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m convinced that CRUD APIs and CRUD-driven systems—meaning systems built around Create, Read, Update, and Delete operations—are, in the long run, the hardest to change and evolve. This might sound unintuitive at first, especially since many of us have read blog posts, watched videos, or taken courses on building HTTP APIs under the guise of… Read More »CRUD APIs are Poor Design The post CRUD APIs are Poor Design appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I wait for Clipboard History to recognize a clipboard change before I change it again?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Listen for the change event.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250509-00/?p=111169 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2505.09 – Revamped UX, Improved Usability, and Many New Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 13:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX on Windows version 2505.09, which can be downloaded here. Since our preview announcement at GDC, we have been working hard to deliver the changes we promised and more. Today’s release includes many new improvements to PIX, including big overall changes and changes specific to GPU Captures and Timing Captures. Other improvements, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2505-09 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Thinkers: From JavaScript to Cloud Privacy Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Brendan Eich may be best known as the creator of JavaScript, but his influence extends well beyond programming languages into the very core of internet privacy and emerging cloud ecosystems. Today, as CEO of Brave Software, Eich is a key figure pushing for decentralized, privacy-first approaches to cloud services and digital advertising. His vision challenges […] The article Big Thinkers: From JavaScript to Cloud Privacy Pioneer was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – May 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 22:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The May 2025 release includes updates in the Python Environments extension, a new color picker added by Pylance, branch coverage support, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-may-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 14 – Exploring extension members</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# 14 introduces extension members. See how the extension syntax offers flexibility for extension authors and continuity for developers using extensions
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/csharp-exploring-extension-members 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Developer’s Guide to Build 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Build 2025 is just around the corner (May 19-22), and we’re fired up about all the developer-focused content we’ve got lined up for you! Whether you’re a Visual Studio power user, a VS Code fan, all about Azure, looking for the newest in .NET, or just pumped about AI in development, this year’s Build is […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/a-developers-guide-to-build-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange Web Services code analyzer and usage report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are less than 18 months away from the retirement of Exchange Web Services. Start planning your migration from EWS to Microsoft Graph.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/exchange-web-services-code-analyzer-and-usage-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Present and Future of Kotlin for Web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: We remain committed to empowering Kotlin developers with robust and seamless support in Kotlin Multiplatform for web development. To achieve this, we are working on several key areas: Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) aims to help developers share code across different platforms, significantly reducing development time and effort. The web plays a crucial role in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/05/present-and-future-kotlin-for-web/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.2 – Bug Fixes Have Landed!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of bug fixes for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.2 comes with the following fixes: dotTrace Timeline viewer now correctly locates and lists functions when searching by type name. [DTRC-31451] For the full list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/05/08/resharper-rider-2025-1-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid T-SQL anti-patterns with the free T-SQL analysis tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 15:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            T-SQL Analyzer is a free, open-source, cross platform command line tool for identifying, and reporting the presence of anti-patterns and design issues in SQL Server T-SQL scripts. As a database developer, you can catch any potential bad practices and design problems very early in the project process – this ensures a frictionless path to deployment […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/sql-analysis-dotnet-tool 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabric Mirroring for Azure Cosmos DB: Public Preview Refresh Now Live with New Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the latest refresh of Fabric Mirroring for Azure Cosmos DB, now available with several powerful new features that enhance your data analytics infrastructure. This update significantly improves the experience, making it easier than ever to replicate your Azure Cosmos DB data into OneLake in Microsoft Fabric—giving you more control and flexibility […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/fabric-mirroring-for-azure-cosmos-db-public-preview-refresh-now-live-with-new-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn’t Clipboard History capture rapid changes to clipboard contents?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Clipboard history operates asynchronously, so you are changing it before it can respond to the changes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250508-00/?p=111162 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of Managed Identities as Federated Identity Credentials in your Entra apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 13:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the GA of Managed Identities as Federated Identity Credentials for Microsoft Entra. Enhance security by replacing app secrets with managed identities, simplify setup, and enable seamless cross-tenant access to Entra-protected resources like Azure and Microsoft Graph.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/access-cloud-resources-across-tenants-without-secrets-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: Docker – Container Revolution that Changed Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Between the constant chatter about “containers,” “microservices,” and “cloud-native,” Docker stands as a major player in the lexicon of contemporary software development. What started as a simple abstraction tool for Linux containers evolved into a cultural shift for software deployment practices, influencing how entire industries build and run their applications. Containers promise greater speed, portability, […] The article Software Innovation: Docker – Container Revolution that Changed Software Development was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taint Analysis: WebGoat Demo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 10:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is a text version of the demo provided during the Taint Analysis Livestream: Exploring Hidden Dangers In Your Team’s Code. Today, we’ll use WebGoat as our test application to demonstrate Qodana’s taint analysis functionality. This application is deliberately insecure. The first step is to open the application’s source code (the main branch) in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/taint-analysis-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.03.2 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 09:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re rolling out TeamCity On-Premises 2025.03.2, the second bug-fix update for the major TeamCity version released in back in March. This update addresses a few product issues, such as: Bug-fix updates also include performance improvements and security patches, so it’s always a good idea to install them as they come out. See TeamCity 2025.03.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/05/teamcity-2025-03-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration testing with Dapr and Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post discusses setting up a Pytest integration test framework for a system using Dapr and Testcontainers. This framework was initially setup for a customer to suit their needs and it has been extracted into a sample project to provide a starting point.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/external-data-handling-learnings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Single Sign On Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 06:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2025/08_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Configure SSO in Qodana Cloud with just a few clicks. If you have a Qodana license with at least 10 users, you can now configure custom single sign on (SSO) support for Qodana Cloud. Quick and easy sign-ons are just another way to make access easier and improve the login experience for your team. Watch […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/05/new-single-sign-on-is-here/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the May release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-may-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we built our startup in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tracebit built their B2B SaaS security product using C#.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/why-we-built-our-startup-in-csharp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.3-1 and 1.23.9-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 16:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-3-1-and-1-23-9-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Deutsche Bahn redefines forecasting using Chronos models – Now available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 15:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whereas traditional forecasting methods typically rely on statistical modeling, Chronos treats time series data as a language to be modeled and uses a pre-trained FM to generate forecasts — similar to how large language models (LLMs) generate texts. Chronos helps you achieve accurate predictions faster, significantly reducing development time compared to traditional methods. In this post, we share how Deutsche Bahn is redefining forecasting using Chronos models, and provide an example use case to demonstrate how you can get started using Chronos.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB with DiskANN Part 4: Stable Vector Search Recall with Streaming Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vector search with Azure Cosmos DB In Part 1 and Part 2 of this series, we explored vector search with Azure Cosmos DB and best practices for scaling it to 1 billion vector datasets while maintaining low query latency. In Part 3, we saw how we can create efficient sharded DiskANN indices for multi-tenant apps. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-with-diskann-part-4-stable-vector-search-recall-with-streaming-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 – v2025.1.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/05/intellij-idea-2025-1-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Availability for Data API in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Title: General Availability for Data API in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB We’re excited to announce the general availability of the Data API for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB! Overview The Data API is a RESTful HTTPS interface that enables developers to interact with their MongoDB data hosted in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/general-availability-for-data-api-in-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What were the MS-DOS programs that the moricons.dll icons were intended for?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tallying them up.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250507-00/?p=111157 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 11:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “C makes it easy to shoot yourself in the foot. C++ makes it harder, but when you do, it blows away your whole leg.” — Bjarne Stroustrup We can’t make С and C++ simpler, but we can make working with them a bit easier. CLion is now free for non-commercial use! Yes, finally. Whether you’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/clion-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The San Antonio Spurs use ChatGPT to scale impact on and off the court</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how the San Antonio Spurs are using custom GPTs to enhance fan engagement, streamline operations, and drive innovation across teams.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/san-antonio-spurs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowe’s puts project expertise into every hand</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Lowe’s partnered with OpenAI to build Mylow and Mylow Companion, AI-powered tools that bring expert help to both customers and store associates—making complex home improvement projects easier to plan, navigate, and complete.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/lowes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Enhancing .NET Logging with LoggingHelper in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enhance your .NET logging with LoggingHelper from Spargine! This powerful utility streamlines application and system logging while capturing and handling exceptions across assemblies, including domain-level errors. Check out the latest features and contribute to Spargine on GitHub or NuGet—your feedback helps shape its future!
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/05/07/boost-your-net-projects-enhancing-net-logging-with-logginghelper-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing OpenAI for Countries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new initiative to support countries around the world that want to build on democratic AI rails.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/openai-for-countries 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
