<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A walkthrough of the original Microsoft Building 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I don&#39;t know why, but there is a Matterport walkthrough of the original Microsoft Building 3, which now no longer exists. This walkthrough appears to have been made not too long before the building was demolished to make room for the new Microsoft campus. I can tell by the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250708-00/?p=111357 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Docker Hub MCP Server: A New Way to Discover, Inspect, and Manage Container Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 12:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Hub has become an essential resource for developers worldwide, serving 11 billion monthly image downloads and hosting over 14 million container images. As agentic AI proliferates, we&#39;re seeing a significant shift in how developers work. More and more developers are leveraging MCP (Model Context Protocol) servers to power their AI agents and automated workflows....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-docker-hub-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes of dotnet run app.cs: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I looks at how the new single-file .NET run experience is implemented inside the .NET SDK, focusing on how the virtual-project file is built
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-2-behind-the-scenes-of-dotnet-run-app.cs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the Google x JetBrains Hackathon Tells Us About the Future of AI at JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 09:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In May, 145 JetBrains employees from across teams and time zones paused their regular work to participate in a 48-hour AI hackathon. With support from Google Cloud, the participants built a total of 41 prototypes from scratch. Some were practical, others experimental, but all explored how AI could change how developers work. The Google Cloud […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/07/what-the-google-x-jetbrains-hackathon-tells-us-about-the-future-of-ai-at-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claude Code Thinking Levels: From Think to Ultra-Think</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Claude Code represents Anthropic&#39;s first venture into agentic coding tools, available as a command-line interface that transforms how developers tackle complex engineering challenges. Unlike traditional AI assistants that provide suggestions, Claude Code actively collaborates by reading codebases, editing files, running tests, and even committing changes to repositories. The
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/claude-code-thinking-levels-think-ultrathink/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with 400,000 teachers to shape the future of AI in schools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI partners with the American Federation of Teachers to launch a 5-year initiative equipping 400,000 K-12 educators to lead AI innovation in classrooms.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/aft 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Biosensing AI-Native Apps on Azure with BCI, AI Foundry, and Agents Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 05:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Co‑Author:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/build-biosensing-ai-native-apps-on-azure-with-bci-ai-foundry-and-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How INRIX accelerates transportation planning with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 20:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            INRIX pioneered the use of GPS data from connected vehicles for transportation intelligence. In this post, we partnered with Amazon Web Services (AWS) customer INRIX to demonstrate how Amazon Bedrock can be used to determine the best countermeasures for specific city locations using rich transportation data and how such countermeasures can be automatically visualized in street view images. This approach allows for significant planning acceleration compared to traditional approaches using conceptual drawings.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qwen3 family of reasoning models now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Qwen3, the latest generation of large language models (LLMs) in the Qwen family, is available through Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, you can deploy the Qwen3 models—available in 0.6B, 4B, 8B, and 32B parameter sizes—to build, experiment, and responsibly scale your generative AI applications on AWS. In this post, we demonstrate how to get started with Qwen3 on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and SageMaker JumpStart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a just-in-time knowledge base with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Traditional Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) systems consume valuable resources by ingesting and maintaining embeddings for documents that might never be queried, resulting in unnecessary storage costs and reduced system efficiency. This post presents a just-in-time knowledge base solution that reduces unused consumption through intelligent document processing. The solution processes documents only when needed and automatically removes unused resources, so organizations can scale their document repositories without proportionally increasing infrastructure costs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents as escalators: Real-time AI video monitoring with Amazon Bedrock Agents and video streams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build a fully deployable solution that processes video streams using OpenCV, Amazon Bedrock for contextual scene understanding and automated responses through Amazon Bedrock Agents. This solution extends the capabilities demonstrated in Automate chatbot for document and data retrieval using Amazon Bedrock Agents and Knowledge Bases, which discussed using Amazon Bedrock Agents for document and data retrieval. In this post, we apply Amazon Bedrock Agents to real-time video analysis and event monitoring.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Support Arrives for Work Items</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After several months in private preview and many bug fixes along the way, we’re excited to announce that Markdown support in large text fields is now generally available! 🎉 🦄 How it works By default, all existing and new work items will continue using the HTML editor for large text fields. However, you now have the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/markdown-support-arrives-for-work-items 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Dev to Deploy: Compose as the Spine of the Application Lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 16:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Nobody wants a spineless application development process. What do I mean by this? The spine is the backbone that supports and provides nerve channels for the human body. Without it, we would be floppy, weaker, and would struggle to understand how our extremities were behaving. A slightly tortured analogy, but consider the application lifecycle of...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-compose-powering-the-full-app-lifecycle/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: If I perform this complex series of manual steps, I can crash a program I am running</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A security vulnerability report arrived that went roughly like this. In Program X, click on the triangle icon and hold the mouse down. Drag the triangle icon to the green box in the corner, and while still holding the mouse down, press Alt+F4 to close the window. The program will
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250707-00/?p=111351 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – Troubleshooting Spring Boot Applications with the Spring Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 08:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Marco Belher and explore how to uncover and fix Spring Boot bugs using the Spring Debugger in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: July 17, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Spring Boot hides a lot of complexity to help you build applications […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/new-livestream-troubleshooting-spring-boot-applications-with-the-spring-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft build of Go Telemetry - Helping Us Build Better Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 08:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with Go 1.25, we&#39;re enabling telemetry collection in the Microsoft build of Go to help us better understand how developers use our tools and prioritize future improvements. This data collection will provide valuable insights into usage patterns, performance characteristics, and common workflows that will directly i
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/microsoft-go-telemetry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid the Wrong Job: The Ultimate .NET Interview Question Playbook</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2025/06_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2025/06_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The content provides guidance for Microsoft .NET software engineers preparing for interviews, emphasizing the importance of asking insightful questions to assess a company&#39;s culture, technical processes, and growth potential. It outlines key topics to inquire about, such as code review practices, deployment processes, team dynamics, and performance management, stressing that well-formed questions can reveal the organization&#39;s commitment to quality and support for career development.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/06/avoid-the-wrong-job-the-ultimate-net-interview-question-playbook/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You&#39;re STUCK at Senior Software Engineer - Dev Leader Weekly 101</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss why you might be stuck as a senior software engineer and what to do about it.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/05/why-youre-stuck-at-senior-software-engineer-dev-leader-weekly-101 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-07-04</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 06:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/07/05/weekly-recap-20250704 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using .NET Aspire With the Docker Publisher</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2025/05_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A practical walkthrough of using .NET Aspire&#39;s Docker publisher to generate Docker Compose files from C# code. Learn how to set up an API with Postgres and Redis, publish to Docker Compose, and deploy to a VPS with minimal configuration.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/using-dotnet-aspire-with-the-docker-publisher 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (June 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.06.13 registry release, 2025-04-16,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn&#39;t &lt;CODE&gt;LVIF_&lt;WBR&gt;INDENT&lt;/CODE&gt; work without an image list?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The LVIF_INDENT property of the Win32 classic listview control lets you indent an item in report view. The units of indentation are the size of the image list. But that requires an image list. Why does it require an image list? The indentation feature of the classic listview control was added for Internet Mail an
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250704-00/?p=111348 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 10:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2025/04_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the July edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This issue is packed with fresh articles, helpful tips, and ideas to keep you inspired and motivated in your work. We’re excited to feature Aicha Laafia, a Java engineer passionate about writing clean, green code and empowering women in tech. She’ll share how sustainable coding practices […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/java-annotated-monthly-july-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Secure and Scalable AI Deployments on Azure with HashiCorp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While the promise of AI continues to generate momentum, many organizations face a familiar challenge: getting AI projects beyond the prototype phase. According to Gartner, only 30% of AI initiatives make it into production, and RAND reports that up to 80% fail to deliver expected outcomes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/automating-secure-and-scalable-ai-deployments-on-azure-with-hashicorp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Practices for Building, Testing, and Packaging MCP Servers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently launched a new, reimagined Docker MCP Catalog with improved discovery and a new submission process. Containerized MCP servers offer a secure way to run and scale agentic applications and minimize risks tied to host access and secret management. Developers can submit servers in two ways: Docker-built servers, which include our full security suite...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-server-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.43: Expanded Model Runner, Reimagined MCP Catalog, MCP Server Submissions, and Smarter Gordon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.43 just rolled out a set of powerful updates that simplify how developers run, manage, and secure AI models and MCP tools. Model Runner now includes better model management, expanded OpenAI API compatibility, and fine-grained controls over runtime behavior. The improved MCP Catalog makes it easier to discover and use MCP servers, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-43/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming network operations with AI: How Swisscom built a network assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Swisscom developed their Network Assistant. We discuss the initial challenges and how they implemented a solution that delivers measurable benefits. We examine the technical architecture, discuss key learnings, and look at future enhancements that can further transform network operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transforming-network-operations-with-ai-how-swisscom-built-a-network-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End model training and deployment with Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we guide you through the stages of customizing large language models (LLMs) with SageMaker Unified Studio and SageMaker AI, covering the end-to-end process starting from data discovery to fine-tuning FMs with SageMaker AI distributed training, tracking metrics using MLflow, and then deploying models using SageMaker AI inference for real-time inference. We also discuss best practices to choose the right instance size and share some debugging best practices while working with JupyterLab notebooks in SageMaker Unified Studio.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>German language cheat sheet: On changing quantities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Somehow, I must have missed out on learning phrases of changes in quantity in German, so I need a cheat sheet. Trend
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250703-01/?p=111337 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If the &lt;code&gt;Format­Message&lt;/code&gt; function fails, and I requested that it allocate a buffer, do I have to free the buffer?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer called the Format­Message function with the FORMAT_MESSAGE_ALLOCATE_BUFFER flag, and they weren&#39;t sure what to do if the function fails (by returning 0). Do they have to free the buffer by calling Local­Free? No, you don&#39;t have to free the buffer. In fact, on f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250703-00/?p=111335 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: A Carefully Curated June Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 13:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s time for another edition of Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup! If June flew by while you were deep in development, don’t worry – I’ve gathered all the ecosystem highlights for you in one handy digest. Here’s what you might have missed. Kotlin YouTube highlights That’s all for June! While you’re rewatching conference talks or experimenting with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/kodees-kotlin-roundup-june-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Why Kakao Pay Chose Kotlin for Backend Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 05:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is a JetBrains translation of the original post by katfun.joy, a backend developer at Kakao Pay. Kakao Pay leverages Kotlin with Spring for backend development across various services, including its insurance offerings. Check out Kakao Pay’s story to see how Kotlin helps it address the complex requirements of the insurance industry and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/case-study-why-kakao-pay-chose-kotlin-for-backend-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize RAG in production environments using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart and Amazon OpenSearch Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 20:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to use Amazon OpenSearch Service as a vector store to build an efficient RAG application.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimize-rag-in-production-environments-using-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-and-amazon-opensearch-service/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local AI &#43; .NET = AltText Magic in One C# Script</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Need to generate image descriptions fast? In this post, we’ll show how to combine .NET 10’s new capabilities with local AI models to create smart AltText — all in one simple C# file. It’s a fun way to explore what AI can do beyond chat. AltText Generation with Local AI Models and dotnet run app.cs ✨ I
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/alttext-generator-csharp-local-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing AI agent governance with Boomi and AWS: A unified approach to observability and compliance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Boomi partnered with AWS to help enterprises accelerate and scale AI adoption with confidence using Agent Control Tower.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advancing-ai-agent-governance-with-boomi-and-aws-a-unified-approach-to-observability-and-compliance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Gordon to Containerize Your Apps and Work with Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 18:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These days, almost every tech company is looking for ways to integrate AI into their apps and workflows, and Docker is no exception. They&#39;ve been rolling out some impressive AI capabilities across their products. This is my first post as a Docker Captain and in this post, I want to shine a spotlight on a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/containerize-your-apps-with-ask-gordon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Awesome GitHub Copilot Customizations repo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 17:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we&#39;re excited to announce the launch of the Awesome GitHub Copilot Customizations repo! The Awesome Copilot repo is a community-driven resource with custom instructions, reusable prompts, and custom chat modes that helps you get consisten
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//introducing-awesome-github-copilot-customizations-repo 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (June 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoMapper and MediatR Commercial Editions Launch Today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today I&#39;m excited to announce the official launch and release of the commercial editions of AutoMapper and MediatR. Both of these libraries have moved under their new corporate owner (me), Lucky Penny Software. I formed this company to house these projects separate from my consulting company, but it&amp;amp;
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/automapper-and-mediatr-commercial-editions-launch-today/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unintended yet somehow entirely expected consequences of marking a COM interface as local</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was adding an interface to their out-of-process COM server. They added their interface to the project&#39;s existing IDL file and recompiled the resulting proxy stub DLL. But when they tried to connect to the server, the connection failed with error 0x80040155, also known as REGDB_E_IID­NOT­REG
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250702-00/?p=111332 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker State of App Dev: Dev Ex &amp; Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Report: What’s helping devs thrive — and what’s still holding them back? A look at how culture, tooling, and habits are shaping the developer experience today, per Docker’s 2025 State of Application Development Survey. Great culture, better tools — but developers often still feel stuck. From pull requests stuck in review to tasks without clear...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-state-of-app-dev-dev-ex-productivity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Chronicles: The Office That Time Forgot – Why Microsoft Must Rethink User Experience Now</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/02/ux-chronicles-the-office-that-time-forgot-why-microsoft-must-rethink-user-experience-now/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement ASP.NET Core OpenID Connect with Keycloak to implement Level of Authentication (LoA) requirements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 04:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at implementing an OpenID Connect client in ASP.NET Core and require a level of authentication (LoA) implemented using Keycloak. The applications are hosted using Aspire. The LoA is requested in Keycloak using the arc_values claim. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/IdentityExternalErrorHandling Setup The applications are implemented using Aspire. An ASP.NET Core application uses an OpenID Connect […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/07/02/implement-asp-net-core-openid-connect-with-keykloak-to-implement-level-of-authentication-loa-requirements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us for MCP Dev Days - July 29-30</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 22:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get ready for two days of deep technical insight, community connection, and hands-on learning at MCP Dev Days, a virtual event dedicated to the Model Context Protocol (MCP) — the emerging standard that bridges AI models and the tools they rely on. [cta-button text=&amp;quot;➡️ Register for MCP Dev Days&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;h
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//join-us-for-mcp-dev-days-july-29-30 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio to build complex AI workflows using Amazon Bedrock Flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 20:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use SageMaker Unified Studio to create complex AI workflows using Amazon Bedrock Flows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio-to-build-complex-ai-workflows-using-amazon-bedrock-flows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating AI innovation: Scale MCP servers for enterprise workloads with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a centralized Model Context Protocol (MCP) server implementation using Amazon Bedrock that provides shared access to tools and resources for enterprise AI workloads. The solution enables organizations to accelerate AI innovation by standardizing access to resources and tools through MCP, while maintaining security and governance through a centralized approach.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-ai-innovation-scale-mcp-servers-for-enterprise-workloads-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the right approach for generative AI-powered structured data retrieval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore five different patterns for implementing LLM-powered structured data query capabilities in AWS, including direct conversational interfaces, BI tool enhancements, and custom text-to-SQL solutions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/choosing-the-right-approach-for-generative-ai-powered-structured-data-retrieval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing drug data analysis using Amazon Bedrock multimodal RAG capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock&#39;s multimodal RAG capabilities revolutionize drug data analysis by efficiently processing complex medical documentation containing text, images, graphs, and tables.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-drug-data-analysis-using-amazon-bedrock-multimodal-rag-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DirectStorage 1.3 is now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re releasing DirectStorage 1.3, this update includes a new API and several refinements based on developer feedback. The package is now available for download via NuGet
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directstorage-1-3-is-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Transform for .NET now supports chat about assessments and transformations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Transform for .NET accelerates large-scale modernization of .NET projects, including porting .NET Framework to cross-platform .NET as well as .NET upgrades. Today we are releasing a new feature that allows you to gain insights about transformation jobs using chat from the web console. This new chat capability lets you ask about repository assessments and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/aws-transform-for-net-now-supports-chat-about-assessments-and-transformations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building secure, scalable AI in the cloud with Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Forrester Research shows how Azure helps enterprises scale generative AI securely, overcoming infrastructure and compliance challenges to unlock real business value. The post Building secure, scalable AI in the cloud with Microsoft Azure appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/building-secure-scalable-ai-in-the-cloud-with-microsoft-azure/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sizzle reel that says things that nobody understands</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the end of project milestones, some organizations have a tradition of asking each team within the organization to produce a a &amp;quot;sizzle reel&amp;quot; highlighting the work that they have accomplished. These short videos are then gathered together and shown at the organizational group meeting so everybody can show off their work and receive appropr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250701-00/?p=111328 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Docker MCP Catalog: the Secure Way to Discover and Run MCP Servers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) ecosystem is exploding. In just weeks, our Docker MCP Catalog has surpassed 1 million pulls, validating that developers are hungry for a secure way to run MCP servers. Today, we&#39;re excited to share major updates to the Docker MCP Catalog, including enhanced discovery features and our new open submission process....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-catalog-secure-way-to-discover-and-run-mcp-servers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module Import Declarations: No More Import Hell</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you are proud of yourself for creating an amazing Java application, framework, or a library. You open one of its source files to make some changes and this is what you see: While looking at this long list of imports, are you wondering why you need to know the name of every single class […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/module-import-declarations-no-more-import-hell/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the features of dotnet run app.cs: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss the new single-file .NET run experience, in which you can run a C# file directly, without needing a csproj project file
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-1-exploring-the-dotnet-run-app.cs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No-code personal agents, powered by GPT-4.1 and Realtime API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Genspark built a $36M ARR AI product in 45 days—with no-code agents powered by GPT-4.1 and OpenAI Realtime API.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/genspark 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Remote Development Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 09:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The concept of remote development is deceptively simple: spin up your development environment somewhere that’s not your local machine. The perks range from freeing up local resources to not panicking when your laptop gets stolen. Yet, there are plenty of pitfalls, including flaky setups, poor visibility, and lousy monitoring. Let’s look at some best practices […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/07/10-remote-development-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davide&#39;s Code and Architecture Notes - Software Architecture vs Software Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Software Architecture and Software Design are terms that look similar but refer to two totally different aspects of software. Let’s find the differences and their purposes.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/software-architecture-vs-software-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
