<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 20:34:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Doctors generate faster, more accurate medical charts with Sayvant and Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 20:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is guest authored by Justin Mardjuki, CEO, Sayvant. Emergency rooms and urgent care facilities handle an estimated 350 million visits each year. Acute care environments are fast-paced, unpredictable, and high stakes. In these settings, providing care quickly is paramount. That’s why we created Sayvant, the leading clinical documentation AI solution for acute care. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/doctors-generate-faster-more-accurate-medical-charts-with-sayvant-and-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Kubernetes?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 18:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kubernetes is an open-source platform designed to manage, automate, and scale containerized applications efficiently. It has become the go-to solution for orchestrating containers in cloud environments. If you’ve ever wondered how large-scale applications like trading platforms handle fluctuating workloads, Kubernetes is the key player behind the scenes. To better understand Kubernetes, think of an orchestra. […] The article What is Kubernetes? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the ‘Simplify Microsoft Power Platform Deployments by Using Pipelines’ Learning Path</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 17:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Learn offers many Power Platform learn modules. Now, we are expanding the collection with a new release! Pipelines in Power Platform is a managed environments feature that has been released a while back now! Over time, it has improved significantly with updates like SPN support, deployment pages, extensibility, and personal pipelines. Many people requested […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-the-simplify-microsoft-power-platform-deployments-by-using-pipelines-learning-path 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate video Q&amp;A workflows using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Transcribe, and thoughtful UX design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 17:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The solution presented in this post demonstrates a powerful pattern for accelerating video and audio review workflows while maintaining human oversight. By combining the power of AI models in Amazon Bedrock with human expertise, you can create tools that not only boost productivity but also maintain the critical element of human judgment in important decision-making processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-video-qa-workflows-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-amazon-transcribe-and-thoughtful-ux-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost team innovation, productivity, and knowledge sharing with Amazon Q Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Q Apps can help maximize the value of existing knowledge resources and improve productivity among various teams, ranging from finance to DevOps to support engineers. We share specific examples of how the generative AI assistant can enable surface relevant information, distill complex topics, generate custom content, and execute workflows—all while maintaining robust security and data governance controls.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-team-innovation-productivity-and-knowledge-sharing-with-amazon-q-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stored Procedure Caching in Data API builder Now Supported</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing Procedure Cache Data API builder (DAB) has long supported Level 1 cache for tables and views. Level 1 is an in-memory cache that automatically stores frequent queries or slow-changing data in the API layer, bypassing several database queries. Today, Data API builder (DAB) also supports Level 1 cache for stored procedures. This is important. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/procedure-caching-in-data-api-builder-now-supported 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update to Azure DevOps Allowed IP addresses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce some important upgrades to our networking infrastructure that will enhance the performance and reliability of our service. As part of these infrastructure upgrades, we are introducing new IP addresses that you will need to allow list in your firewall configurations. What’s Changing And Why? We are transitioning from the current […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/update-to-ado-allowed-ip-addresses 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Trump’s Tariffs Threaten U.S. Dominance in Artificial Intelligence?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The U.S.A. has been the dominant force in Artificial Intelligence so far. The release of DeepSeek R1 recently from a Chinese company is showing to challenge this dominance. AI models aren’t the only factor for the United States to remain dominant in AI. Both AI training and running models are dependent on GPUs (graphics processing […] The article Will Trump’s Tariffs Threaten U.S. Dominance in Artificial Intelligence? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize your AI-generated git commit messages</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When it comes to collaborative software development, clear and effective communication is key. One area that often gets overlooked is the Git commit message. Poorly crafted commit messages can lead to confusion and inefficiencies within a team. That’s why we’ve built on the suggestions and feedback for the AI-generated commit messages, and now you can […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/customize-your-ai-generated-git-commit-messages 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On trying to log an exception as it leaves your scope</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can&#39;t watch it from an object on the outside.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250203-00/?p=110830 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – January Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 14:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2025 is here, and it’s brought lots of new educational content. Dive into the latest tech trends, learning opportunities, insightful events, and nifty plugins to boost your productivity. Happy reading.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/02/03/jetbrains-academy-december-january/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.2 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 13:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.2 bug-fix update is out and ready to be installed on your servers! This update addresses over 30 issues, including: See TeamCity 2024.12.2 Upgrade Notes for the complete list. Why update? Staying up to date with minor releases ensures your TeamCity instance benefits from: Compatibility TeamCity 2024.12.2 shares the same data format […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/02/teamcity-2024-12-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from MSTest to xUnit using a Roslyn analyzer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Both MSTest and xUnit are great test framework. If you are curious about, I&#39;ve written many blog posts about them MSTest series If you want to migrate to xUnit from MSTest, I&#39;ve written a Roslyn Analyzer. This analyzer reports all MSTest attributes and assertions in your code. It can also replace most of them with xUnit equivalent. Note that the goal of this analyzer is not to handle 100% of the cases,…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Debugging GraalVM Native Images With IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 11:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Dmitry Chuyko and Anton Arhipov, where we’ll explore the tools and workflows for debugging GraalVM Native Images with IntelliJ IDEA. Date: February 13, 2025 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract GraalVM Native Image allows you to transform your application into a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/02/new-livestream-debugging-graalvm-native-images-with-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Qt Renderers in CLion’s Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest CLion 2025.1 EAP build, 251.18673.49, includes one of the most requested features: support for Qt renderers (also known as Qt pretty printers and Qt debugging helpers) in the debugger. This feature allows you to view Qt variables such as QString, QByteArray, and other data types in a human-readable form. This enhancement makes it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/02/introducing-qt-renderers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple client sign-in customizations using Duende identity provider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 06:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/duende-multi-tenant Setup The solution is setup using three […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/02/03/multiple-client-sign-in-customizations-using-duende-identity-provider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Web Content for Generative AI &#43; RAG Solution as Trimmed Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2025/02_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 14:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2025/02_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has revolutionized how we interact with and generate text-based content, but its capabilities are significantly enhanced when paired with Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG). RAG enables AI models to pull in external, high-quality sources of information, ensuring more accurate and contextually relevant responses. A crucial component of this process is loading and processing web content, […] The article Load Web Content for Generative AI + RAG Solution as Trimmed Markdown was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s ListExtentions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2025/02_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2025/02_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is a set of open-source .NET 8 packages developed to enhance list functionality through the ListExtensions class. It includes various high-performance methods for action execution, element addition, conversions, grouping, shuffling, and validation.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/02/02/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-listextentions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Diversity of Data in AI Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 13:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) has rapidly become an integral part of modern society, influencing everything from job recruitment to healthcare and criminal justice. However, AI systems are only as good as the data they are trained on. When these datasets lack diversity, AI can inherit and amplify biases, leading to real-world consequences that exacerbate discrimination based […] The article Importance of Diversity of Data in AI Systems was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming At School vs Work - Dev Leader Weekly 81</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the differences between coding at work vs coding at school.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/02/01/programming-at-school-vs-work-dev-leader-weekly-81 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Faster with dotNetTips.com Spargine 8: February 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine 8 (v2025.8.2.1) was released on February 1, 2025, featuring NuGet packages for .NET 8 &amp;amp; 9, new classes, methods, and performance enhancements. Key additions include AutoDefaultDictionary and various comparers. The update also enhances country validation methods and dictionary functionalities. Community contributions are encouraged for future improvements.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/02/01/coding-faster-with-dotnettips-com-spargine-8-february-2025-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overriding Default HTTP Resilience Handlers in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2025/01_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While .NET 8&#39;s standard resilience handlers provide excellent defaults for HTTP clients, they lack built-in support for overriding these handlers for specific endpoints that require different resilience strategies. This article demonstrates how to implement a custom solution for overriding default handlers and discusses upcoming improvements planned by the .NET team.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/overriding-default-http-resilience-handlers-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Intelligent Apps with .NET and DeepSeek R1 Today!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 20:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to easily integrate DeepSeek R1 with .NET applications using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI library.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/start-building-an-intelligent-app-with-dotnet-and-deep-seek 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look into the new architecture on RNW 0.76 and 0.77!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve recently released React Native Windows 0.76 and 0.77- marking the first time we invite developers to create RNW experiences on the new architecture.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/react-native/2025-01-29-new-architecture-on-0-76-0-77 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Amazon Bedrock generative AI for resilient supply chain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 19:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By leveraging the generative AI capabilities and tooling of Amazon Bedrock, you can create an intelligent nerve center that connects diverse data sources, converts data into actionable insights, and creates a comprehensive plan to mitigate supply chain risks. This post walks through how Amazon Bedrock Flows connects your business systems, monitors medical device shortages, and provides mitigation strategies based on knowledge from Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases or data stored in Amazon S3 directly.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (January 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure SDK releases every month. In this post, you find this month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-january-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Travelers Insurance classified emails with Amazon Bedrock and prompt engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:18:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how FMs can reliably automate the classification of insurance service emails through prompt engineering. When formulating the problem as a classification task, an FM can perform well enough for production environments, while maintaining extensibility into other tasks and getting up and running quickly. All experiments were conducted using Anthropic’s Claude models on Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-travelers-insurance-classified-emails-with-amazon-bedrock-and-prompt-engineering/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate digital pathology slide annotation workflows on AWS using H-optimus-0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use H-optimus-0 for two common digital pathology tasks: patch-level analysis for detailed tissue examination, and slide-level analysis for broader diagnostic assessment. Through practical examples, we show you how to adapt this FM to these specific use cases while optimizing computational resources.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-digital-pathology-slide-annotation-workflows-on-aws-using-h-optimus-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q4 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 11:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Marketplace updates Granular plugin feedback In addition to the general star rating of plugins, we’re introducing detailed ratings for more granular feedback. Users can now rate plugins across five categories: Aggregated ratings are shown in the Reviews tab. Find more details in our documentation. Perpetual licenses for paid plugins JetBrains Marketplace now offers perpetual […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/01/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q4-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Conferences and Events in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 11:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Planning your 2025 tech calendar? Java conferences offer more than just technical sessions – they’re your gateway to connecting with a vibrant community of professionals and passionate Java fans, exploring new cities, and finding fresh inspiration. As the IDE of choice for professional development in Java and Kotlin, IntelliJ IDEA is built to support developers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/top-java-conferences-and-events-in-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Debugging for Massive C&#43;&#43; Projects in Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 10:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you work on large Unreal Engine projects in Rider, you’ve likely experienced the dreaded debug-step delay – hit F10 for Step Over, contemplate making coffee, then finally see the next line execute. These delays occur in LLDB Debugger, the engine behind Rider’s debugging capabilities for C++ and other native languages. After months of focused […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/31/faster-debugging-in-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Developer Population Reaches 19.6 Million in 2024: Explore the Updates in Our Data Playground</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 10:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago, we launched the Developer Ecosystem: Data Playground, an interactive dashboard offering insights into the global developer landscape. Today, we’re excited to introduce a significant update that enhances the dashboard with refined data, salary ranges, and even more granular insights into developer demographics and market trends. What’s New? To make it easier to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/01/global-developer-population-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek-R1 model now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 02:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DeepSeek-R1 is an advanced large language model that combines reinforcement learning, chain-of-thought reasoning, and a Mixture of Experts architecture to deliver efficient, interpretable responses while maintaining safety through Amazon Bedrock Guardrails integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deepseek-r1-model-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Microsoft Graph Export-Import APIs for Exchange in public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 22:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce the launch of Export-Import APIs in limited Public Preview (Beta), a set of Microsoft Graph APIs that empower applications to discover, export and import contents from Exchange Online mailboxes in full fidelity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-the-microsoft-graph-export-import-apis-for-exchange-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing AMQP v2 stack engine support in the Azure Messaging Event Hubs library for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 20:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post announces a new stable release of the Azure Event Hubs library for Java, with enhanced reliability and performance.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/announcing-amqp-v2-stack-engine-support-in-the-azure-messaging-event-hubs-library-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing collapsed text Indicators</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 19:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 introduces new options for customizing the collapsed text indicator, which helps in distinguishing between different sections of collapsed text in the editor. This aims to make the coding environment more intuitive and easier to use by providing additional customization for visual cues. Customizing your coding environment You can now personalize the color […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/customizing-collapsed-text-indicators 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Migration on February 5th</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 18:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce that the Q# blog will be moving to a new home at Azure Quantum Technical Blog on February 5, 2025. This will enable us to offer you a more seamless and enhanced experience through a single integrated platform, featuring the latest information and resources in quantum computing. Best regards, The […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/qsharp/blog-migration-on-february-5th 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2501.30-preview: Application Specific Driver State, Recreate At GPUVA and Tight Alignment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 18:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2501.30-preview, available for download here. This release has initial support for the exciting new D3D12 features that were released in a preview DirectX Agility SDK today. Please visit this blog post for more information about the Agility SDK release. 2501.30-preview is a preview version of PIX. It is identical to 2501.30 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2501-30-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2501.30 – Support for Shader Hash Bypass, bug fixes, and everything in 2412.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 18:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2501.30, which can be downloaded here. This release includes support for everything that was in the 2412.12 version of PIX, plus the following improvements: Support for Shader Hash Bypass PIX has full support for this new D3D12 feature that allows apps to bypass shader hash validation in D3D12 runtime by […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2501-30 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility SDK 1.716.0-preview: New D3D12 Video Encode Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 18:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today DirectX 12 provides APIs to support GPU video encode acceleration for several applications, as detailed in D3D12 Video Encoding – Windows drivers | Microsoft Learn previous blog posts such as Announcing new DirectX 12 feature – Video Encoding! – DirectX Developer Blog. In this blog post we’re happy to announce a series of new features […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agility-sdk-1-716-0-new-d3d12-video-encode-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline grant proposal reviews using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS Social Responsibility &amp;amp; Impact (SRI) team recognized an opportunity to augment this function using generative AI. The team developed an innovative solution to streamline grant proposal review and evaluation by using the natural language processing (NLP) capabilities of Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we explore the technical implementation details and key learnings from the team’s Amazon Bedrock powered grant proposal review solution, providing a blueprint for organizations seeking to optimize their grants management processes.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Aetion is using generative AI and Amazon Bedrock to unlock hidden insights about patient populations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we review how Aetion’s Smart Subgroups Interpreter enables users to interact with Smart Subgroups using natural language queries. Powered by Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude 3 large language models (LLMs), the interpreter responds to user questions expressed in conversational language about patient subgroups and provides insights to generate further hypotheses and evidence.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-aetion-is-using-generative-ai-and-amazon-bedrock-to-unlock-hidden-insights-about-patient-populations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility SDK 1.716.0-preview &amp; 1.615-retail: Shader hash bypass</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The D3D runtime as of 1.615 officially supports applications opting to bypass shader hash validation. The historical purpose of the hash that the DX shader compiler embeds in every shader binary was to give the D3D runtime to confidence that shaders being given to it are well formed. The assumption was that a hashed shader […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agility-sdk-1-716-0-preview-1-615-retail-shader-hash-bypass 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AgilitySDK 1.716.0-preview and 1.615-retail</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce both a retail release of Shader hash bypass and a preview AgilitySDK release with several new features, available on Agility SDK Downloads today! You can find detailed information about all the features on the individual blog pages: 1.615 Shader hash bypass officially supports applications opting to bypass shader hash validation. It is […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agilitysdk-1-716-0-preview-and-1-615-retail 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document build instructions and more with enhanced C&#43;&#43; awareness from Copilot Chat in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 15:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C++ development often involves nuances beyond the file you’re developing in. This can leave developers with many mental tabs open, balancing all the relevant context for their project to develop their C++ code properly. Copilot Chat in Visual Studio can already utilize context provided by specified files and invoked agents such as @workspace to generate […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/document-build-instructions-and-more-with-enhanced-c-awareness-from-copilot-chat-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Developer Advocate – Will Vincent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 15:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, I’m a new Python Developer Advocate, focusing especially on web development. If you have any questions or want to share ideas around JetBrains products, most notably PyCharm, say hi at william.vincent@jetbrains.com. Background I’m a former Django Board Member and the author of three books on Django. Since 2019, I’ve co-hosted the Django Chat podcast […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/python-developer-advocate-will-vincent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3: Kotlin K2 Mode Updates, Enhanced Logical Code Structure View, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Early Access Program is in full swing, and build #3 is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3 We’re covering all of the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retry on Errors in Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 02:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Coaching my daughter’s 1st/2nd grade basketball team is a trip. I don’t know that the girls are necessarily learning much, but one thing I’d love for them to understand is to “follow your shot” and try for a rebuild for a second shot if the ball doesn’t go in on their first shot. That’s the … Continue reading Retry on Errors in Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/01/29/retry-on-errors-in-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy DeepSeek-R1 distilled Llama models with Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 01:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy distilled versions of DeepSeek-R1 models using Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import. We focus on importing the variants currently supported DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Llama-8B and DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Llama-70B, which offer an optimal balance between performance and resource efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-deepseek-r1-distilled-llama-models-with-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI operating models in enterprise organizations with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 21:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative AI adoption grows, organizations should establish a generative AI operating model. An operating model defines the organizational design, core processes, technologies, roles and responsibilities, governance structures, and financial models that drive a business’s operations. In this post, we evaluate different generative AI operating model architectures that could be adopted.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generative-ai-operating-models-in-enterprise-organizations-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.8 Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 18:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the availability of TypeScript 5.8 Beta. To get started using the beta, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@beta Let’s take a look at what’s new in TypeScript 5.8! Checked Returns for Conditional and Indexed Access Types Consider an API that presents […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-8-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains and LinkedIn Partner to Launch a Professional Certificate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 17:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has partnered with LinkedIn to offer the Java Foundations Professional Certificate, exclusively available on LinkedIn Learning. With over 1 billion members on the platform and 7 people hired every minute, LinkedIn provides unmatched access to professional growth opportunities. Together, with our expertise in software development and education, we’re combining the best of both worlds: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/team/2025/01/29/jetbrains-and-linkedin-partner-to-launch-a-professional-certificate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run DeepSeek R1 Locally for Free with Ollama and OpenWebUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 17:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Awhile back I wrote about how you can run your own local ChatGPT experience for free using Ollama and OpenWebUI with support for LLMs like Llama3, Microsoft Phi, Mistral and more! With the recent, open source release of DeepSeek R1, it’s also supported to run locally with Ollama too! This article will take you through […] The article Run DeepSeek R1 Locally for Free with Ollama and OpenWebUI was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 Tips for Productive Java Development With Databases in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 15:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll share nine time-saving ways IntelliJ IDEA can boost your productivity when developing Java applications with databases – whether you’re starting a new project or diving into an ongoing one. Get IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate Create data sources automatically from properties IntelliJ IDEA makes it easy to create a data source for your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/tips-for-productive-java-development-with-databases-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I create an inserter iterator that does unhinted insertion into an associative container like std::map?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Curiously missing from the standard library.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250129-00/?p=110817 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack 2025 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our commitment to you We remain fully committed, as we have been all these years, to developing YouTrack as a platform that evolves with your needs. Our promise to you is to ensure that YouTrack continues to be available in both Server and Cloud versions, giving you the freedom to choose the hosting option that […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/01/youtrack-2025-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JITWatch4i: Analyzing IntelliJ IDEA’s Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 11:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction A typical Java or Kotlin programmer spends most of their productive time either creating application code in an editor or searching for bugs in a debugger. Occasionally, they might dive into a profiler when looking for places where the application spends too much time. However, they almost never venture into the Java C1 or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/01/jitwatch4i-analyzing-intellij-idea-s-startup/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 11:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the January edition of PHP Annotated! This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise, we’ve done it for you. Highlights PHP 8.4 PHP 8.4 was officially released on November 21, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/01/php-annotated-january-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Django Views</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 10:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Views are central to Django’s architecture pattern, and having a solid grasp of how to work with them is essential for any developer working with the framework. If you’re new to developing web apps with Django or just need a refresher on views, we’ve got you covered. Gaining a better understanding of views will help […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/django-views/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming support lifecycle milestones for older on-premises products</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 23:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Multiple versions of our on-premises product will reach the end of support on October 14, 2025. Customers are encouraged to start planning and deploying upgrades now to ensure that installed products remain supported and secure, and to take advantage of new capabilities offered in successor products. The latest version of our on-premises product is Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/upcoming-support-lifecycle-milestones-for-older-on-premises-products 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes to provisioning Azure DevOps projects using the Azure DevOps Demo Generator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 21:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure DevOps Demo Generator is a tool that allows you to create projects in your Azure DevOps organization, complete with pre-filled sample content. This includes source code, work items, iterations, service connections, and build and release pipelines, all based on a template you select. Starting February 28, 2025, we are eliminating the need for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/changes-to-provisioning-azure-devops-projects-using-the-azure-devops-demo-generator 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop a RAG-based application using Amazon Aurora with Amazon Kendra</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 17:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RAG retrieves data from a preexisting knowledge base (your data), combines it with the LLM’s knowledge, and generates responses with more human-like language. However, in order for generative AI to understand your data, some amount of data preparation is required, which involves a big learning curve. In this post, we walk you through how to convert your existing Aurora data into an index without needing data preparation for Amazon Kendra to perform data search and implement RAG that combines your data along with LLM knowledge to produce accurate responses.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing AI responsiveness: A practical guide to Amazon Bedrock latency-optimized inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 17:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock latency-optimized inference can help address the challenges of maintaining responsiveness in LLM applications. We&#39;ll dive deep into strategies for optimizing application performance and improving user experience. Whether you&#39;re building a new AI application or optimizing an existing one, you&#39;ll find practical guidance on both the technical aspects of latency optimization and real-world implementation approaches. We begin by explaining latency in LLM applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track LLM model evaluation using Amazon SageMaker managed MLflow and FMEval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 17:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to use FMEval and Amazon SageMaker to programmatically evaluate LLMs. FMEval is an open source LLM evaluation library, designed to provide data scientists and machine learning (ML) engineers with a code-first experience to evaluate LLMs for various aspects, including accuracy, toxicity, fairness, robustness, and efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/track-llm-model-evaluation-using-amazon-sagemaker-managed-mlflow-and-fmeval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine for MediatR Users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 15:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I happened to see this post from Milan Jovanović today about a little backlash to the MediatR library. For my part, I think MediatR is just a victim of its own success and any backlash is mostly due to folks misusing it very badly in unnecessarily complicated ways (that’s my experience). That aside, yes, I … Continue reading Wolverine for MediatR Users →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/01/28/wolverine-for-mediatr-users/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My electric toothbrush was acting up, so I tried to reboot it</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It didn&#39;t help.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250128-00/?p=110815 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significance of DeepSeek R1 Model: Disruption, Trust, and the Future of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 14:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The recent release of DeepSeek’s R1 model has sent ripples across the global technology landscape, sparking intense discussions about its disruptive potential, trustworthiness, and implications for the future of artificial intelligence. DeepSeek cost roughly $5.6 million to train, as compared to hundreds of millions that it cost OpenAI to train GPT-4o. This groundbreaking AI innovation […] The article Significance of DeepSeek R1 Model: Disruption, Trust, and the Future of AI was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curious About The State of Software Quality?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 13:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first edition of the JetBrains Qodana Software Quality Report which looks at key findings from 2024. We decided to conduct this research to gain a deeper understanding of best practices for delivering quality software today, and how companies of different sizes and maturity levels determine when their product is production-ready. To […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/01/state-of-software-quality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock key capabilities via Generation 2 VMs in Azure DevTest Labs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 13:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce enhanced support for Generation 2 VMs on Azure DevTest Labs, now in public preview. We listened to your feedback and have improved the support for using Generation 2 VMs in Azure DevTest Labs. Generation 2 Virtual Machines (VMs) support key capabilities that are not supported in Generation 1 VMs such […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/unlock-key-capabilities-via-generation-2-vms-in-azure-devtest-labs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterate across multiple files more efficiently with GitHub Copilot Edits (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot Edits (Preview) in Visual Studio 2022 combines the conversational flow of chat and an inline review experience to help you iterate across your codebase with more control and efficiency. 💡 Here’s how Copilot Edits helps with iterating across multiple files: Preview with clarity: Review a clear summary that highlights affected files and proposed […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/iterate-across-multiple-files-more-efficiently-with-github-copilot-edits-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.3.2: uv Package Management Support and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 10:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.3.2 is here with uv package management support, flame graph visualization, and other improvements! Get the latest version from our download page or update through our free Toolbox App. Read this blog post to learn more about new features. Support for uv package management Take your environment management to the next level with uv […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/pycharm-2024-3-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure Layer Should Always Be Logic-Free: Why?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn why your infrastructure layer should contain zero business logic and how to properly structure your .NET applications using Clean Architecture principles. Includes practical examples and common pitfalls to avoid.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/infrastructure-layer-logic-free-why/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting multiple .NET SDK versions in analyzers and source generators</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe why source generators might need to work with multiple versions of the .NET SDK and how NuGet packages support this in .NET 6
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/supporting-multiple-sdk-versions-in-analyzers-and-source-generators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NuGet packages we use to build elmah.io revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 09:08:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2025/28_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Four years ago, I wrote the blog post The NuGet packages we use to build elmah.io. Since then, we have made several changes to our tech stack as well as upgraded to recent versions of .NET. For this post, I&#39;ll update you on the packages we use
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/the-nuget-packages-we-use-to-build-elmah-io-revisited/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
