<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 12: A shared tracking pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The tracking pointer designs we&#39;ve been using so far have had O(n) complexity on move, where n is the number of outstanding tracking pointers. But we can reduce this to O(1) by the classic technique of introducing another level of indirection. What we can do is give every trackable object
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250826-00/?p=111506 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing an old .NET Core native library loading issue on Alpine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I walk through the process of solving a native library loading issue on alpine with an old .NET runtime, showing the steps we took and the solution
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/fixing-an-old-dotnet-core-native-library-loading-issue-on-alpine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Ruby Debuggers: byebug, debug gem, and the Power of RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 07:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Whether you are a seasoned Ruby developer or just getting started, mastering the debugger will save you time and frustration when tracking down bugs. At RubyMine, we’ve spent years building debugging tools for Ruby. In this blog series, we’re sharing some of the insights we’ve gained along the way. In this post, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/08/unveiling-ruby-debuggers-byebug-debug-gem-and-the-power-of-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping people when they need it most</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How we think about safety for users experiencing mental or emotional distress, the limits of today’s systems, and the work underway to refine them.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/helping-people-when-they-need-it-most 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Connections with Entra ID Support in the DocumentDB VS Code Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 22:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re thrilled to announce a major update to the DocumentDB for VS Code extension that will make life easier for enterprise developers. With
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/secure-your-connections-with-entra-id-support-in-the-documentdb-vs-code-extension 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for Kotlin Multiplatform and Compose Multiplatform – August 2025 Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 18:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post outlines our priorities and the general direction for our Kotlin Multiplatform and Compose Multiplatform projects over the next six to twelve months. Our goals for Kotlin Multiplatform are closely aligned with those detailed in the Kotlin roadmap. Be sure to check it out for more context around the direction we’re heading. Key priorities […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kmp-roadmap-aug-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot for Azure (Preview) Launches in Visual Studio 2022 with Azure MCP Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 18:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The GitHub Copilot for Azure extension is now in Public Preview for Visual Studio 2022 (17.14+). It brings a curated set of Azure developer tools—exposed through the Azure MCP server—directly into GitHub Copilot Agent Mode in Visual Studio. The extension automatically installs and manages the Azure MCP server, so you can query resources, d
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/github-copilot-for-azure-preview-launches-in-visual-studio-2022-with-azure-mcp-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MauiReactor: An MVU Approach for .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog from Adolfo Marinucci. I&#39;m a full-stack developer from Italy, primarily focused on Microsoft technologies ranging from cross-platform applications with .NET MAUI to ASP.NET Core backend services hosted on Azure. I&#39;m the creator of MauiReactor, a UI library for .N
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mauireactor-mvu-for-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 11: Repairing assignment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we made sure that tracking pointers to const objects couldn&#39;t be converted into tracking pointers to non-const objects, but I noted that fixing this introduced a new pro
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250825-00/?p=111497 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Worktree: Managing Multiple Working Directories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Git worktree is a powerful feature that allows you to have multiple working directories associated with a single repository. Instead of switching branches and potentially losing uncommitted work, you can check out different branches in separate directories simultaneously without recloning the repository. Git worktree creates additional working trees linked to the same repository. Each worktree can have a…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/git-worktree-managing-multiple-working-directories.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning and Deploying GPT Models Using Hugging Face Transformers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 11:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hugging Face is currently a household name for machine learning researchers and enthusiasts. One of their biggest successes is Transformers, a model-definition framework for machine learning models in text, computer vision, audio, and video. Because of the vast repository of state-of-the-art machine learning models available on the Hugging Face Hub and the compatibility of Transformers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/08/fine-tuning-and-deploying-gpt-models-using-hugging-face-transformers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the OpenAI Learning Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI announces the launch of OpenAI Learning Accelerator, an initiative that aims to bring advanced AI to India’s educators and millions of learners nationwide through accelerated AI research, training, and deployment.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/learning-accelerator 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Harness the Power of Async Queues with Spargine’s ChannelQueue</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_08_2025/24_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_08_2025/24_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Spargine library introduces ChannelQueue, an efficient, thread-safe queue for .NET asynchronous programming, addressing the lack of a built-in async queue. It supports various features like async operations, bounded capacities, cancellation, and batch processing, making it ideal for managing async data flows and enhancing application responsiveness.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/08/24/boost-your-net-projects-harness-the-power-of-async-queues-with-spargines-channelqueue/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Mistakes of New Managers and Leads - Dev Leader Weekly 106</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss some of the biggest mistakes made by new managers and team leads.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/23/top-mistakes-of-new-managers-and-leads-dev-leader-weekly-106 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-08-22</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 06:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/23/weekly-recap-20250822 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Cost of Abstractions in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not all abstractions are created equal. Some isolate real volatility and protect your system from change. Others quietly pile up complexity and hide performance problems. Learn when to embrace abstractions versus when they become technical debt that slows down your team.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-real-cost-of-abstractions-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone is talkin’ bout vibes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 18:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Leading up to Microsoft Ignite, I wanted to pressure-test something the community keeps talking about: vibe coding. It’s a style of AI-assisted development where you describe outcomes in natural language and your assistant does most of the scaffolding, refacto
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/everyone-is-talkin-bout-vibes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Geospatial Analysis and GIS Workflows with Amazon Bedrock Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applying emerging technologies to the geospatial domain offers a unique opportunity to create transformative user experiences and intuitive workstreams for users and organizations to deliver on their missions and responsibilities. In this post, we explore how you can integrate existing systems with Amazon Bedrock to create new workflows to unlock efficiencies insights. This integration can benefit technical, nontechnical, and leadership roles alike.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-geospatial-analysis-and-gis-workflows-with-amazon-bedrock-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the basics: A comprehensive foundation model selection framework for generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the model landscape expands, organizations face complex scenarios when selecting the right foundation model for their applications. In this blog post we present a systematic evaluation methodology for Amazon Bedrock users, combining theoretical frameworks with practical implementation strategies that empower data scientists and machine learning (ML) engineers to make optimal model selections.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/beyond-the-basics-a-comprehensive-foundation-model-selection-framework-for-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking GPT-5’s Freeform Tool Calling: A New Era of Seamless Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5 models are now available in Azure AI Foundry via Azure OpenAI. Designed for advanced reasoning and generation. One of the core capabilities of the model is tool calling, which enables it to interact with external systems by generating an
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/unlocking-gpt-5s-freeform-tool-calling-a-new-era-of-seamless-integration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate intelligent document processing with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce our open source GenAI IDP Accelerator—a tested solution that we use to help customers across industries address their document processing challenges. Automated document processing workflows accurately extract structured information from documents, reducing manual effort. We will show you how this ready-to-deploy solution can help you build those workflows with generative AI on AWS in days instead of months.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-intelligent-document-processing-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker HyperPod enhances ML infrastructure with scalability and customizability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduced three features in SageMaker HyperPod that enhance scalability and customizability for ML infrastructure. Continuous provisioning offers flexible resource provisioning to help you start training and deploying your models faster and manage your cluster more efficiently. With custom AMIs, you can align your ML environments with organizational security standards and software requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-enhances-ml-infrastructure-with-scalability-and-customizability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin on the Backend – What’s New From KotlinConf 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 15:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            KotlinConf 2025 has firmly placed server-side Kotlin in the spotlight, and rightly so. Between Spring collaboration, an upgraded ecosystem, performance boosts, AI tooling, and the adoption of the language by big companies, this is Kotlin at its (backend) best. Here’s a breakdown of what was announced, what’s new, and what you absolutely must check out […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kotlin-on-the-backend-what-s-new-from-kotlinconf-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 10: Proper conversion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we added the ability to convert tracking pointers to non-const objects into tracking pointers to const objects, but we noted that there&#39;s a problem. The problem is that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250822-00/?p=111494 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Drive Integration, Python 3.11 in Conda Environments, and Security improvements in Datalore 2025.4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 10:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.4 is now available, bringing support for Google Drive folders as data connections, Python 3.11 in conda environments, and a dozen of small behind-the-scenes enhancements and bug fixes. These updates are already available for Datalore Cloud users, and Datalore On-Premises users can get them by updating their Datalore instance. Google Drive integration At Datalore, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/08/22/google-drive-integration-python-3-11-in-conda-environments-and-security-improvements-in-datalore-2025-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 09:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview 2 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.OData.Core 9.0.0 Preview 2
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/odata-net-9-preview-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating life sciences research</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how a specialized AI model, GPT-4b micro, helped OpenAI and Retro Bio engineer more effective proteins for stem cell therapy and longevity research.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/accelerating-life-sciences-research-with-retro-biosciences 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create embeddings in SQL Server 2025 RC0 with a local ONNX model on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 01:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of SQL Server 2025 RC0, we have enabled the ability to use a local ONNX model on th
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/create-embeddings-in-sql-server-2025-rc0-with-a-local-onnx-model-on-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune OpenAI GPT-OSS models using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod recipes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is the second part of the GPT-OSS series focusing on model customization with Amazon SageMaker AI. In Part 1, we demonstrated fine-tuning GPT-OSS models using open source Hugging Face libraries with SageMaker training jobs, which supports distributed multi-GPU and multi-node configurations, so you can spin up high-performance clusters on demand. In this post, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-openai-gpt-oss-models-using-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-recipes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline code nodes now supported in Amazon Bedrock Flows in public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the public preview of support for inline code nodes in Amazon Bedrock Flows. With this powerful new capability, you can write Python scripts directly within your workflow, alleviating the need for separate AWS Lambda functions for simple logic. This feature streamlines preprocessing and postprocessing tasks (like data normalization and response formatting), simplifying generative AI application development and making it more accessible across organizations.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate enterprise AI implementations with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business offers AWS customers a scalable and comprehensive solution for enhancing business processes across their organization. By carefully evaluating your use cases, following implementation best practices, and using the architectural guidance provided in this post, you can deploy Amazon Q Business to transform your enterprise productivity. The key to success lies in starting small, proving value quickly, and scaling systematically across your organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-enterprise-ai-implementations-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up delivery of ML workloads using Code Editor in Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how you can use the new Code Editor and multiple spaces support in SageMaker Unified Studio. The sample solution shows how to develop an ML pipeline that automates the typical end-to-end ML activities to build, train, evaluate, and (optionally) deploy an ML model.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/speed-up-delivery-of-ml-workloads-using-code-editor-in-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Separate Databases? Explaining Like You’re Five</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 18:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I want to give you three different examples and reasons why you might want to separate customers and orders into different databases. The person who asked the question left out a lot of nuance and context, so I am going straight to the point. You will find all three examples boil down to the same… Read More »Why Separate Databases? Explaining Like You’re Five The post Why Separate Databases? Explaining Like You’re Five appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Infosys Topaz leverages Amazon Bedrock to transform technical help desk operations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog, we examine the use case of a large energy supplier whose technical help desk agents answer customer calls and support field agents. We use Amazon Bedrock along with capabilities from Infosys Topaz™ to build a generative AI application that can reduce call handling times, automate tasks, and improve the overall quality of technical support.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-infosys-topaz-leverages-amazon-bedrock-to-transform-technical-help-desk-operations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance your CLI testing workflow with the new dotnet test</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The dotnet test command is part of the .NET CLI and is used to run tests in a given solution. It supports multiple test frameworks, including MSTest, xUnit, NUnit and TUnit. The command recognizes two main test platforms: VSTest and Microsoft.Testing.Platform
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-test-with-mtp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Control over Your Copilot Code Suggestions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Copilot code completions and suggestions in the editor speed you up in your daily programming and coding activities, at every keystroke. They help you finish the line you&#39;re typing or anticipate your next edit, making your workflow smoother and faster. At the same time, editor is where you focus and put in the deep work. Based on your feedback
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/better-control-over-your-copilot-code-suggestions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: Schema Compare, Schema Designer, Local SQL Server Container GA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code continues to evolve, delivering features that make SQL development more visual, more consistent, and more developer-friendly. In version v1.35.0, we’re announcing the General Availability (GA) of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-schema-container 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototyping an AI Tutor with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every developer remembers their first docker run hello-world. The mix of excitement and wonder as that simple command pulls an image, creates a container, and displays a friendly message. But what if AI could make that experience even better? As a technical writer on Docker’s Docs team, I spend my days thinking about developer experience....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-build-an-ai-tutor-with-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 9: Conversion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we added the ability to create tracking pointers from const objects. But we discovered that you could not convert a tracking_ptr to a tra
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250821-00/?p=111492 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling domain expertise in complex, regulated domains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Blue J is transforming tax research with AI-powered tools built on GPT-4.1. By combining domain expertise with Retrieval-Augmented Generation, Blue J delivers fast, accurate, and fully-cited tax answers—trusted by professionals across the US, Canada, and the UK.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/blue-j 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create personalized products and marketing campaigns using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 21:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Built using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock, The Fragrance Lab represents a comprehensive end-to-end application that illustrates the transformative power of generative AI in retail, consumer goods, advertising, and marketing. In this post, we explore the development of The Fragrance Lab. Our vision was to craft a unique blend of physical and digital experiences that would celebrate creativity, advertising, and consumer goods while capturing the spirit of the French Riviera.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tyson Foods elevates customer search experience with an AI-powered conversational assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 21:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Tyson Foods collaborated with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to revolutionize their customer interaction through an intuitive AI assistant integrated into their website. The AI assistant was built using Amazon Bedrock,
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/tyson-foods-elevates-customer-search-experience-with-an-ai-powered-conversational-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance AI agents using predictive ML models with Amazon SageMaker AI and Model Context Protocol (MCP)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 20:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to enhance AI agents’ capabilities by integrating predictive ML models using Amazon SageMaker AI and the MCP. By using the open source Strands Agents SDK and the flexible deployment options of SageMaker AI, developers can create sophisticated AI applications that combine conversational AI with powerful predictive analytics capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-ai-agents-using-predictive-ml-models-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-model-context-protocol-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Multi-Agent Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Written by: Maggie Liu, Thiago Rotta, Vinicius Souza, James Tooles, &amp;amp;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/designing-multi-agent-intelligence 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot Diagnostics toolset for .NET In Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We know how much energy developers pour into debugging bugs and diagnosing performance in .NET. That’s why we’ve doubled down on making the debugging and profiling experience in Visual Studio not just easier, but genuinely enjoyable meeting you exactly where your real work happens. The same tools you rely on are now able to keep up with yo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/github-copilot-diagnostics-toolset-for-dotnet-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Advanced Shader Delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year at gamescom, Microsoft is highlighting new gaming features coming for Windows, particularly for handheld devices. We want to highlight one of the DirectX team’s most exciting new contributions to the PC gaming ecosystem, whic
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/introducing-advanced-shader-delivery 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring Your Own Model to Chat in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that you can now bring your own language model into Visual Studio Chat. You can connect API keys from providers (OpenAI, Anthropic, and Google) to access a wider range of models. This makes it ea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/bring-your-own-model-visual-studio-chat 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent Factory: Building your first AI agent with the tools to deliver real-world outcomes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agents are only as capable as the tools you give them—and only as trustworthy as the governance behind those tools. The post Agent Factory: Building your first AI agent with the tools to deliver real-world outcomes appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/agent-factory-building-your-first-ai-agent-with-the-tools-to-deliver-real-world-outcomes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 8: Tracking const objects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we added the ability to create non-modifying tracking pointers, but it required that you start with a non-const trackable object. But what if you want to create a non-modifying tracking pointer to an object to which you have only a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250820-00/?p=111490 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Supply Chain Paradox: When “Hardened” Images Become a Vendor Lock-in Trap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The market for pre-hardened container images is experiencing explosive growth as security-conscious organizations pursue the ultimate efficiency: instant security with minimal operational overhead. The value proposition is undeniably compelling—hardened images with minimal dependencies promise security &amp;quot;out of the box,&amp;quot; enabling teams to focus on building and shipping applications rather than constantly revisiting low-level configuration management....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hardened-container-images-security-vendor-lock-in/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Copilot Studio Agent Academy: Your Mission Starts Now</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to Copilot Studio Agent Academy Whether you&#39;re just starting your journey with AI agents or looking to sharpen your skills in Microsoft Copilot Studio, we&#39;ve got your mission briefing ready and it&#39;s time to suit up! We&#39;re thrilled to introduce Copilot Studio Agent Academy, a new, self-paced curricu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-copilot-studio-agent-academy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ground Truth Curation Process for AI Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Imagine you&#39;re building a powerful new AI assistant to support real business tasks — like answering maintenance questions in a manufacturing plant or surfacing insights from historical service data. To ensure that this AI system produces accurate and useful responses, we need a reliable way to measure its performance.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/ground-truth-curation-for-ai-systems 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Reduced API Response Time by 70% in a Large .NET Project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 08:33:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Slow APIs hurt users&#39; experience and the owners&#39; pocket. Users become disappointed, and the server costs more if APIs are not up to standard in large projects. I also faced a similar issue in my project. However, I cut down the performance overhead marginally. This article breaks down
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/penhow-i-reduced-api-response-time-by-70-in-a-large-net-project/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify access control and auditing for Amazon SageMaker Studio using trusted identity propagation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to enable and use trusted identity propagation in Amazon SageMaker Studio, which allows organizations to simplify access management by granting permissions to existing AWS IAM Identity Center identities. The solution demonstrates how to implement fine-grained access controls based on a physical user&#39;s identity, maintain detailed audit logs across supported AWS services, and support long-running user background sessions for training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simplify-access-control-and-auditing-for-amazon-sagemaker-studio-using-trusted-identity-propagation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Data Wrangler powered Notebook Results Table</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have ever found yourself rewriting the last line of a notebook cell repeatedly just to get an overview of your data, you&#39;re not alone. In VS Code the default output for Pandas DataFrames is a static, truncated HTML table and it often fails to answer essential questions, such as: Do we have rogue blank values somewhere we di
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/data-wrangler-results-table 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (August 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-august-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Context Protocol (MCP) is Now Generally Available in Visual Studio 🎉</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that MCP support is now GA in Visual Studio—unlocking richer, real-time context from your entire development stack and expanding the power of Agent Mode like never before. Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open standard that makes it easy for AI agents to connect with external tools and services—think of it
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/mcp-is-now-generally-available-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking document information localization with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock, specifically Amazon Nova Pro, to achieve high-accuracy document field localization while dramatically simplifying implementation. We show how these models can precisely locate and interpret document fields with minimal frontend effort, reducing processing errors and manual intervention.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/benchmarking-document-information-localization-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Infosys built a generative AI solution to process oil and gas drilling data with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We built an advanced RAG solution using Amazon Bedrock leveraging Infosys Topaz™ AI capabilities, tailored for the oil and gas sector. This solution excels in handling multimodal data sources, seamlessly processing text, diagrams, and numerical data while maintaining context and relationships between different data elements. In this post, we provide insights on the solution and walk you through different approaches and architecture patterns explored, like different chunking, multi-vector retrieval, and hybrid search during the development.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-OSS - A C# Guide with Ollama</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-OSS is OpenAI&#39;s first open-weight model since GPT-2, and it&#39;s a game-changer for developers who want powerful AI without the cloud dependency. You get two flavors - gpt-oss-120b and gpt-oss-20b - both delivering solid performance on coding, math, and tool use while keeping your data completely private. The 20B model is especially interesti
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/gpt-oss-csharp-ollama 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Proxy 4: The Next Leap in C&#43;&#43; Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Proxy 4 is here! After years of innovation and sustained use in the Windows OS codebase (since 2022), Proxy has matured from a bold experiment into a production-grade, modern C++ library for runtime polymorphism. The theory behind Proxy is original, and its design is now proven at scale. We are excited to invite the broader C++ community to jo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/announcing-proxy-4-the-next-leap-in-c-polymorphism 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline NGINX Configuration with Docker Desktop Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker periodically highlights blog posts featuring use cases and success stories from Docker partners and practitioners. This story was contributed by Dylen Turnbull and Timo Stark. With over 29 years in enterprise and open-source software development, Dylen Turnbull has held roles at Symantec, Veritas, F5 Networks, and most recently as a Developer Advocate for NGINX....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/streamline-nginx-configuration-with-docker-desktop-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents with Docker MCP Toolkit: A Developer’s Real-World Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI agents in the real world often involves more than just making model calls — it requires integrating with external tools, handling complex workflows, and ensuring the solution can scale in production. In this post, we’ll walk through a real-world developer setup for creating an agent using the Docker MCP Toolkit. To make things...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-ai-agent-developer-setup/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline employee training with an intelligent chatbot powered by Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to design and implement custom plugins for Amazon Q Business to create an intelligent chatbot that streamlines employee training by retrieving answers from training materials. The solution implements secure API access using Amazon Cognito for user authentication and authorization, processes multiple document formats, and includes features like RAG-enhanced responses and email escalation capabilities through custom plugins.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-employee-training-with-an-intelligent-chatbot-powered-by-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 7: Non-modifying trackers, second try</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we tried to add non-modifying trackers to our tracking pointers implementation. I noted at the end that our attempt was wrong. The problem is in the code we
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250819-00/?p=111488 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting an xUnit test project to TUnit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss the new TUnit testing framework, why I ported one of my libraries to use it instead of xUnit and related issues I had to deal with
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/converting-an-xunit-project-to-tunit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operations that Span Multiple Event Streams with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s just say that Marten incurs some serious benefits to being on top of PostgreSQL and its very strong support for transactional integrity as opposed to some of the high profile commercial Event Sourcing tools who are spending a lot of time and energy on their “Dynamic Consistency Boundary” concept because they lack the ACID … Continue reading Operations that Span Multiple Event Streams with the Critter Stack →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
