<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:05:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker @ Black Hat 2025: CVEs have everyone’s attention, here’s the path forward</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CVEs dominated the conversation at Black Hat 2025. Across sessions, booth discussions, and hallway chatter, it was clear that teams are feeling the pressure to manage vulnerabilities at scale. While scanning remains an important tool, the focus is shifting toward removing security debt before it enters the software supply chain. Hardened images, compliance-ready tooling, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-black-hat-2025-secure-software-supply-chain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway: Transforming enterprise AI agent tool development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, a fully managed service that revolutionizes how enterprises connect AI agents with tools and services by providing a centralized tool server with unified interface for agent-tool communication. The service offers key capabilities including Security Guard, Translation, Composition, Target extensibility, Infrastructure Manager, and Semantic Tool Selection, while implementing sophisticated dual-sided security architecture for both inbound and outbound connections.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway-transforming-enterprise-ai-agent-tool-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a scalable containerized web application on AWS using the MERN stack with Amazon Q Developer – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a traditional SDLC, a lot of time is spent in the different phases researching approaches that can deliver on requirements: iterating over design changes, writing, testing and reviewing code, and configuring infrastructure. In this post, you learned about the experience and saw productivity gains you can realize by using Amazon Q Developer as a coding assistant to build a scalable MERN stack web application on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Salesforce’s model endpoints with Amazon SageMaker AI inference components</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how the Salesforce AI Platform team optimized GPU utilization, improved resource efficiency and achieved cost savings using Amazon SageMaker AI, specifically inference components.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-salesforces-model-endpoints-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-inference-components/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practitioner’s view on how Docker enables security by default and makes developers work better</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post was written by Docker Captains, experienced professionals recognized for their expertise with Docker. It shares their firsthand, real-world experiences using Docker in their own work or within the organizations they lead. Docker Captains are technical experts and passionate community builders who drive Docker’s ecosystem forward. As active contributors and advocates, they share...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-docker-enables-security-by-default/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a RAG chat-based assistant on Amazon EKS Auto Mode and NVIDIA NIMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the implementation of a practical RAG chat-based assistant using a comprehensive stack of modern technologies. The solution uses NVIDIA NIMs for both LLM inference and text embedding services, with the NIM Operator handling their deployment and management. The architecture incorporates Amazon OpenSearch Serverless to store and query high-dimensional vector embeddings for similarity search.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-rag-chat-based-assistant-on-amazon-eks-auto-mode-and-nvidia-nims/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Identity: Securing agentic AI at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Identity, a comprehensive identity and access management service purpose-built for AI agents that enables secure access to AWS resources and third-party tools. The service provides robust identity management features including agent identity directory, agent authorizer, resource credential provider, and resource token vault to help organizations deploy AI agents securely at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-identity-securing-agentic-ai-at-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 5: Copying our tracking pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our previous attempt to create a tracking pointer class had the perhaps-undesirable property that copying a const tracking pointer is not permitted. This requirement arose because copying a tracking p
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250815-00/?p=111484 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking about trying or upgrading to Datalore Cloud? This August, you can save 30%.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 10:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve recently started a trial or are thinking about trying Datalore, and a Cloud plan is on your radar, now is a good time to consider it. Until the end of August, new users and teams currently using a trial version of Datalore can get 30% off their first payment when subscribing to the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/08/15/save-30/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.44: Smarter AI Modeling, Platform Stability, and Streamlined Kubernetes Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 20:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Docker Desktop 4.44, we’ve focused on delivering enhanced reliability, tighter AI modeling controls, and simplified tool integrations so you can build on your terms. Docker Model Runner Enhancements Inspectable Model Runner Workflows Now you can inspect AI inference requests and responses directly from Docker Model Runner (DMR), helping you troubleshoot and debug model behavior...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-44/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the blog post Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock, we demonstrated how to build a scalable IDP pipeline using Anthropic foundation models on Amazon Bedrock. Although that approach delivered robust performance, the introduction of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation brings a new level of efficiency and flexibility to IDP solutions. This post explores how Amazon Bedrock Data Automation enhances document processing capabilities and streamlines the automation journey.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiteboard to cloud in minutes using Amazon Q, Amazon Bedrock Data Automation, and Model Context Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share the Amazon Bedrock Data Automation Model Context Protocol (MCP) server, for seamless integration between Amazon Q and your enterprise data. In this post, you will learn how to use the Amazon Bedrock Data Automation MCP server to securely integrate with AWS Services, use Bedrock Data Automation operations as callable MCP tools, and build a conversational development experience with Amazon Q.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/whiteboard-to-cloud-in-minutes-using-amazon-q-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-model-context-protocol/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing agentic Retrieval Augmented Generation to Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how Amazon Q Business is transforming enterprise data interaction through Agentic Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bringing-agentic-retrieval-augmented-generation-to-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 for Microsoft Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI announced GPT-5 last week in &amp;quot;GPT-5 and the new era of work&amp;quot;. Working with OpenAI, we rolled out GPT-5 support the day it launched, making sure you can use and build with it and integrate it into your applications immediately. We&#39;ve got you covered with a dev-focused rundo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/gpt-5-for-microsoft-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the NuGet MCP Server Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month, we announced support for building custom MCP servers with .NET and publishing them to NuGet. Building on that foundation, today we&#39;re announcing the official NuGet MCP Server, which enables you to integrate real-time NuGet package information
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/nuget-mcp-server-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering students with disabilities: University Startups’ generative AI solution for personalized student pathways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            University Startups, headquartered in Bethesda, MD, was founded in 2020 to empower high school students to expand their education beyond a traditional curriculum. University Startups is focused on special education and related services in school districts throughout the US. In this post, we explain how University Startups uses generative AI technology on AWS to enable students to design a specific plan for their future either in education or the work force.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The GitHub Prompt Injection Data Heist</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 3 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that validate the critical vulnerabilities threatening AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker MCP Toolkit provides enterprise-grade protection. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) promised to revolutionize how AI agents interact with developer tools, making GitHub repositories, Slack channels, and databases...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-github-prompt-injection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations with Amazon Nova understanding models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to prompt Amazon Nova understanding models to cite sources in responses. Further, we will also walk through how we can evaluate the responses (and citations) for accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/citations-with-amazon-nova-understanding-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data encryption with customer-managed key (CMK) for Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB vCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Built-in security for every configuration Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB vCore is designed with security as a foundational principle. Regardless of how your cluster is configured—whether it&#39;s a sing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/data-encryption-with-customer-managed-key-cmk-for-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-vcore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 4: Using a circular doubly linked list</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our previous attempt to create a tracking pointer class had the downside of incurring a potential memory allocation when a tracking pointer is copied or moved. We can get rid of this allocation by mak
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250814-00/?p=111482 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Quarter, New Qodana 2025.2 Release Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 13:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following the recent rollout of our new Insights dashboard, Native mode, Self-Hosted Lite version, SSO functionality, and Visual Studio plugin, our Qodana 2025.2 update promises another round of improvements and extensions. Take a look at what we’ve been doing as we focus on providing greater access to code quality and security in your organization, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/08/qodana-2025-2-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Context Protocol (MCP) for GitHub Copilot in Xcode is Now Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 13:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Model Context Protocol (MCP) support with GitHub Copilot is now generally available for Xcode! Developers can now enable GitHub Copilot with MCP in Xcode to enhance coding intelligence and context awareness. What&#39;s new With MCP support in Xcode, developers can now connect Copilot to both local and remote MCP servers that follow the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/mcp-for-ghc-in-xcode-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.07.1 Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 12:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity On-Premises 2025.07.1, the first bug-fix for the recently released TeamCity 2025.07, is ready to be installed on your On-Premises servers. This update addresses a significant number of issues, including: Bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements, so we recommend installing them promptly. See TeamCity 2025.07.1 Release Notes for the complete list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/08/teamcity-2025-07-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Codebase Awareness in Visual Studio Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Smarter Code Search in Visual Studio: From BM25 to Semantic Search In our lat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/improving-codebase-awareness-in-visual-studio-chat 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Performance Improvements in ReSharper 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 10:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2025.2 release of ReSharper introduces a number of performance and responsiveness improvements across several key areas. This post outlines the most notable updates, including out-of-process support, improved solution startup, faster refactorings, and better Razor/Blazor handling. Out-of-Process mode Public Preview ReSharper 2025.2 is the first stable release to support running ReSharper out of process (OOP) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/14/resharper-performance-improvements-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2025.2 Are Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 10:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ReSharper and the .NET tools 2025.2 are available for download. This release introduces the public preview of ReSharper’s Out-of-Process mode, adds support for the latest C# 14 and C++26 features, and brings a range of improvements for performance, refactorings, and inspections. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the next stable release, you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/14/resharper-and-the-net-tools-2025-2-are-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 Is Here with Junie, In-IDE OpenTelemetry, Game Dev Upgrades, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2025.2 delivers a big step forward in intelligent development tooling, bringing AI deeper into your workflow with Junie – our AI coding agent – along with runtime observability through the new OpenTelemetry plugin, a reworked Monitoring tool window, and improved debugging across platforms. Let’s take a closer look at what’s new. Meet Junie, your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/14/rider-2025-2-is-here-with-junie-in-ide-opentelemetry-game-dev-upgrades-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Fuzz Testing in CLion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 09:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fuzz testing is an effective technique for identifying bugs that are difficult to detect using unit tests or static analysis alone. This article will show you how to perform fuzz testing in CLion, analyze the results, and debug a tested function. We’ll use CI Fuzz, a fuzz testing tool developed by Code Intelligence, a company […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/fuzz-testing-in-clion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizable and Extensible Evaluation of a GenAI Application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction You have built out a generative AI application. Now are you wondering how to assess that your application is returning quality results? Have you considered using Azure AI Foundry to evaluate your application? If you are wondering how to start programmatically evaluating your application in a way that is both adaptable an
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/customizable-extensible-evaluations-of-genai-application 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Redmond to San Diego: VS Live! Highlights, Session Examples, and What’s Next</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s something special about hosting developers at Microsoft HQ — and this year’s Visual Studio Live! Redmond reminded me why I love these events. The energy in every room was electric. From the moment the first session kicked off, developers leaned in, asked smart, challenging questions, and took every opportunity to connect with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/from-redmond-to-san-diego-vs-live-highlights-session-examples-and-whats-next 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securely launch and scale your agents and tools on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 21:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime simplifies the deployment and management of AI agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/securely-launch-and-scale-your-agents-and-tools-on-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PwC and AWS Build Responsible AI with Automated Reasoning on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 19:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents how AWS and PwC are developing new reasoning checks that combine deep industry expertise with Automated Reasoning checks in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails to support innovation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pwc-and-aws-build-responsible-ai-with-automated-reasoning-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI: From Dev to Prod with Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 18:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building on our previous post about implementing dev-to-prod promotion with GitHub Actions, this follow-up demonstrates the same &amp;quot;build once, deploy everywhere&amp;quot; pattern using Azure DevOps Pipelines. You&#39;ll learn how to leverage Azure Dev
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-developer-cli-from-dev-to-prod-with-azure-devops-pipelines 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GPT-5 Launch Broke the AI Internet (And Not in a Good Way)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What That Means for Devs and AI App Companies When GPT-5 dropped, OpenAI killed off a bunch of older APIs without much warning. A whole lot of apps face-planted overnight. If your app hard-codes itself to one provider, one API shape, or one model, this is the nightmare scenario. This is also different from losing...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/gpt5-api-deprecation-ai-app-failure/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon scaled Rufus by building multi-node inference using AWS Trainium chips and vLLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, Amazon shares how they developed a multi-node inference solution for Rufus, their generative AI shopping assistant, using Amazon Trainium chips and vLLM to serve large language models at scale. The solution combines a leader/follower orchestration model, hybrid parallelism strategies, and a multi-node inference unit abstraction layer built on Amazon ECS to deploy models across multiple nodes while maintaining high performance and reliability.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-scaled-rufus-by-building-multi-node-inference-using-aws-trainium-chips-and-vllm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent financial analysis agent with LangGraph and Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes an approach of combining three powerful technologies to illustrate an architecture that you can adapt and build upon for your specific financial analysis needs: LangGraph for workflow orchestration, Strands Agents for structured reasoning, and Model Context Protocol (MCP) for tool integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-financial-analysis-agent-with-langgraph-and-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory: Building context-aware agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory, a fully managed service that enables AI agents to maintain both immediate and long-term knowledge, transforming one-off conversations into continuous, evolving relationships between users and AI agents. The service eliminates complex memory infrastructure management while providing full control over what AI agents remember, offering powerful capabilities for maintaining both short-term working memory and long-term intelligent memory across sessions.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational natural language interface for Amazon Athena queries using Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore an innovative solution that uses Amazon Bedrock Agents, powered by Amazon Nova Lite, to create a conversational interface for Athena queries. We use AWS Cost and Usage Reports (AWS CUR) as an example, but this solution can be adapted for other databases you query using Athena. This approach democratizes data access while preserving the powerful analytical capabilities of Athena, so you can interact with your data using natural language.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – August Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your August learning boost is here – with free tools, career-launching courses, practical advice from the JetBrains Academy team, and your shot at winning a MacBook Pro.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/08/13/jetbrains-academy-august/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps OAuth Client Secrets Now Shown Only Once</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re making an important change to how Azure DevOps displays OAuth client secrets to align with industry best practices and improve our overall security posture. Starting September, newly generated client secrets will be shown only once at the time of creation. After that, they will no longer be retrievable via the UI or
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-oauth-client-secrets-now-shown-only-once 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerToys 0.93 is here: faster Command Palette, new dashboard UX and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/powertoys-0-93-is-here-faster-command-palette-new-dashboard-ux-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simpler, More Transparent Model for AI Quotas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: Starting August 18, 2025, we’re rolling out a new AI quota model that makes AI subscriptions easier to understand and manage, while also letting you seamlessly extend your usage beyond your included quota with transparent pricing in real currency. The initial rollout will apply to individuals and organizations, with AI Enterprise updates to follow. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/08/a-simpler-more-transparent-model-for-ai-quotas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Managed Instance for Apache Cassandra v5.0 Generally Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 14:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-managed-instance-for-apache-cassandra-v5-0-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 3: Using a &lt;code&gt;std::vector&lt;/code&gt;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we tried to build our &amp;quot;tracking pointers&amp;quot; out of nodes in a std::list, but we found that the std::list was not expressive enough to support the operations we needed.¹ So instea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250813-00/?p=111459 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning-Fast Python: Mastering the uv Package Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 13:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out our recent livestream from August 7 on uv, a next-generation Python package manager revolutionizing Python development with speeds 10-100x faster than pip. Released just last year and written in Rust, uv replaces long-standing Python dependency management challenges with a single, lightning-fast tool that just works. Join us as we demonstrate uv‘s game-changing capabilities […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/08/lightning-fast-python-mastering-the-uv-package-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.0-1 Microsoft build now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 12:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-0-1-microsoft-build-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Transactions? Let Spring Debugger Do the Heavy Lifting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 10:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Framework’s declarative transaction management is incredibly powerful, allowing developers to simply add the @Transactional annotation to a method and let Spring handle the transaction details. However, misconfigurations or misunderstandings of how transactions work can lead to frustrating database transaction handling issues. Debugging these problems often means sifting through a lot of AOP proxy code, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/debugging-transactions-let-spring-debugger-do-the-heavy-lifting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: 2.2.20-Beta2, Kotlin LSP Update, Shipaton 2025, and a New Face on the Foundation Board</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kodee here – your ever-cheerful tour guide through the ever-bustling streets of Kotlin-land. Summer may be the season for vacations, but we’re not slowing down! Let’s take a stroll through the latest news. What else to read YouTube highlights Check out some of the most popular videos on our Kotlin YouTube channel: And these are […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kodee-kotlin-roundup-july-25-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train and deploy AI models at trillion-parameter scale with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod support for P6e-GB200 UltraServers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 19:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we review the technical specifications of P6e-GB200 UltraServers, discuss their performance benefits, and highlight key use cases. We then walk though how to purchase UltraServer capacity through flexible training plans and get started using UltraServers with SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/train-and-deploy-ai-models-at-trillion-parameter-scale-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-support-for-p6e-gb200-ultraservers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 7 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the seventh preview release of .NET 10 with enhancements across the .NET Runtime, SDK, libraries, C#, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more. Check out the full release notes linked below and get started today. [cta-button align=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Download .NET 10 Preview 7&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;https://get
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-7 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Indegene’s AI-powered social intelligence for life sciences turns social media conversations into insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Indegene’s Social Intelligence Solution uses advanced AI to help life sciences companies extract valuable insights from digital healthcare conversations. Built on AWS technology, the solution addresses the growing preference of HCPs for digital channels while overcoming the challenges of analyzing complex medical discussions on a scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-indegenes-ai-powered-social-intelligence-for-life-sciences-turns-social-media-conversations-into-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking enhanced legal document review with Lexbe and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, Lexbe, a legal document review software company, demonstrates how they integrated Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services to transform their document review process, enabling legal professionals to instantly query and extract insights from vast volumes of case documents using generative AI. Through collaboration with AWS, Lexbe achieved significant improvements in recall rates, reaching up to 90% by December 2024, and developed capabilities for broad human-style reporting and deep automated inference across multiple languages.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate AIOps with SageMaker Unified Studio Projects, Part 2: Technical implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus on implementing this architecture with step-by-step guidance and reference code. We provide a detailed technical walkthrough that addresses the needs of two critical personas in the AI development lifecycle: the administrator who establishes governance and infrastructure through automated templates, and the data scientist who uses SageMaker Unified Studio for model development without managing the underlying infrastructure.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-aiops-with-sagemaker-unified-studio-projects-part-2-technical-implementation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate AIOps with Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio projects, Part 1: Solution architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents architectural strategies and a scalable framework that helps organizations manage multi-tenant environments, automate consistently, and embed governance controls as they scale their AI initiatives with SageMaker Unified Studio.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-aiops-with-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio-projects-part-1-solution-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 Now Available in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 17:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share that GPT-5, OpenAI’s latest frontier model, is now rolling out in GitHub Copilot for Visual Studio. GPT-5 offers faster responses and even better performance for writing and understanding code. This release brings a new level of capability to
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/gpt-5-now-available-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunting Living Secrets: Secret Validity Checks Arrive in GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 16:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever waded through a swamp of secret scanning alerts wondering, “Which of these are actually dangerous right now?” — this enhancement is for you. Secret validity checks in GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps (and the standalone Secret Protection experience) add a high‑signa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/hunting-living-secrets-secret-validity-checks-arrive-in-github-advanced-security-for-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI agents made easy with Goose and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI agents can be a complex task. But it also can be a fairly simple combination of answers to the following questions: What is the AI backend that powers my intelligent fuzzy computation? What tools do you need to give to the AI to access external systems or execute predefined software commands? What is...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-ai-agents-with-goose-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft is a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Container Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re proud to announce that Microsoft has once again been recognized as a Leader in the 2025 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Container Management, for the third year in a row. The post Microsoft is a Leader in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Container Management appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/microsoft-is-a-leader-in-the-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-container-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Security with Continuous Access Evaluation (CAE) comes to Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that Continuous Access Evaluation (CAE) is now supported on Azure DevOps, bringing a new level of near real-time security enforcement to your development workflows. 🔐 What Is CAE?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/real-time-security-with-continuous-access-evaluation-cae-comes-to-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell Is Now an AI-First Tool for Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From the 2025.2 version onward, every paid DataSpell subscription includes JetBrains AI Pro for free, reflecting our commitment to bringing AI into our data products. Please note that the bundled AI Pro plan is limited to use inside DataSpell. Download DataSpell 2025.2 AI Pro included at no extra cost! You now get JetBrains AI Pro […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/08/dataspell-is-now-an-ai-first-tool-for-data-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? A feature of C# is null-coalescing operators. The ?? operator (null-coalescing operator) returns the left-hand operand if it is not null; otherwise, it evaluates and returns the right-hand operand. The ??= operator (null-coalescing assignment operator) assigns the right-hand operand’s value to the left-hand operand only if the left-hand operand is null. Welcome to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/12/dotinsights-august-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free JetBrains Student Pack – Your Toolkit for a Future in Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For a successful career in tech, having the right tools from day one makes all the difference. That’s why we created the JetBrains Student Pack – all-in-one development kit designed to help you learn to code, build real-world projects, and kickstart your future career, using the same tools trusted by developers at Google, NASA, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/08/12/jetbrains-student-pack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 2: Using a &lt;code&gt;std::list&lt;/code&gt;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we worked out how we want a proposed &amp;quot;tracking pointer&amp;quot; to work. Now we can try implementing it. One idea is to give each trackable object a list of all the tracking pointers that a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250812-00/?p=111454 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mssql-python vs pyodbc: Benchmarking SQL Server Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 11:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/mssql-python-vs-pyodbc-benchmarking-sql-server-performance 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running .NET in the browser without Blazor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to run .NET in your browser without using Blazor, and instead rely on lower-level abstractions provided by [JSImport] and [JSExport]
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/running-dotnet-in-the-browser-without-blazor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains with its CLion IDE Is Now an Official ST Authorized Partner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re pleased to announce that JetBrains has joined the ST Partner Program. Through this collaboration, we aim to improve the experience of embedded developers working with ST microcontroller solutions in CLion. Here’s what developers get from this partnership: About ST ST (STMicroelectronics) is a European company that specializes in designing, developing, and manufacturing semiconductor technologies. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/st-authorized-partner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Audit Logs in EF Core Without Polluting Your Entities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:16:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most modern applications require the historical audit logging of changes made to database entities. The audit log provides you with insights into all changes made, including their timestamps and the users responsible for those changes. The logs ensure transparency, allowing stakeholders to observe what changes were made to business-critical data,
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/implementing-audit-logs-in-ef-core-without-polluting-your-entities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s letter to Governor Newsom on harmonized regulation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just sent a letter to Gov. Gavin Newsom calling for California to lead the way in harmonizing state-based AI regulation with national—and, by virtue of US leadership, emerging global—standards.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/letter-to-governor-newsom-on-harmonized-regulation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling accounting capacity with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Built with OpenAI o3, o3-Pro, GPT-4.1, and GPT-5, Basis’ AI agents help accounting firms save up to 30% of their time and expand capacity for advisory and growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/basis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Amazon Bedrock Pricing for a Chatbot Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 19:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll look at Amazon Bedrock pricing through the lens of a practical, real-world example: building a customer service chatbot. We&#39;ll break down the essential cost components, walk through capacity planning for a mid-sized call center implementation, and provide detailed pricing calculations across different foundation models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/demystifying-amazon-bedrock-pricing-for-a-chatbot-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune OpenAI GPT-OSS models on Amazon SageMaker AI using Hugging Face libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 19:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Released on August 5, 2025, OpenAI’s GPT-OSS models, gpt-oss-20b and gpt-oss-120b, are now available on AWS through Amazon SageMaker AI and Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we walk through the process of fine-tuning a GPT-OSS model in a fully managed training environment using SageMaker AI training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-openai-gpt-oss-models-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-using-hugging-face-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GA of Bicep templates support for Microsoft Entra ID resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that Bicep templates for Microsoft Entra ID resources is generally available from July 29th, 2025. Bicep templates bring declarative infrastructure as code (IaC) capabilities to Microsoft Graph resources. This new capability will initially be available for core Microsoft Entra ID resources. Bicep templat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/bicep-templates-for-microsoft-entra-id-resources-is-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling ≠ Glue: Why changing AI workflows still feels like duct tape</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s a weird contradiction in modern AI development. We have better tools than ever. We’re building smarter systems with cleaner abstractions. And yet, every time you try to swap out a component in your stack, things fall apart. Again. This isn’t just an inconvenience. It’s become the norm. You’d think with all the frameworks and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-changing-ai-workflows-still-feels-like-duct-tape/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 1: Concept art</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Suppose you have a C++ object, and you want to be able to create a &amp;quot;tracking pointer&amp;quot; that points to the object and follows it as it moves. // Concept art - final product may differ in significant ways struct Widget : trackable_object { ⟦ ... ⟧ }; Widget w; tracking_ptr p(w); asse
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250811-00/?p=111451 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify Date &amp; Time Formatting with Spargine’s DateTimeFormat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_08_2025/10_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_08_2025/10_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The DateTimeFormat type in Spargine simplifies date and time formatting for .NET developers. It provides a strongly typed set of options, reducing the need to memorize format strings. Available through the DotNetTips.Spargine.Extensions project, it streamlines formatting using the ToFormattedString() extension method for efficient coding.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/08/10/boost-your-net-projects-simplify-date-time-formatting-with-spargines-datetimeformat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remocal and Minimum Viable Models: Why Right-Sized Models Beat API Overkill</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 12:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A practical approach to escaping the expensive, slow world of API-dependent AI The $20K Monthly Reality Check You built a simple sentiment analyzer for customer reviews. It works great. Except it costs $847/month in API calls and takes 2.3 seconds to classify a single review. Your &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; document classifier burns through $3,200/month. Your chatbot feature?...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/remocal-minimum-viable-models-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Complex Side Projects With Purpose - Dev Leader Weekly 105</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss building side projects, adding complexity, and doing so intentionally!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/09/building-complex-side-projects-with-purpose-dev-leader-weekly-105 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-08-08</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 06:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/09/weekly-recap-20250808 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Most Common REST API Design Mistakes (and How to Avoid Them)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Five REST API design mistakes I see all the time, with practical fixes. Use consistent resource naming, evolve contracts instead of bumping versions, add envelopes, pagination and filtering, return Problem Details, and bake in auth, authz, and rate limits from day one.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-5-most-common-rest-api-design-mistakes-and-how-to-avoid-them 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Recipe AI Agent with Koog and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, I’m Philippe Charriere, a Principal Solutions Architect at Docker. I like to test new tools and see how they fit into real-world workflows. Recently, I set out to see if JetBrains&#39; Koog framework could run with Docker Model Runner, and what started as a quick test turned into something a lot more interesting than...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-a-recipe-ai-agent-with-koog-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under what conditions could a &lt;code&gt;Read­File&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Write­File&lt;/code&gt; fail to transfer all of the bytes, and how do I detect that?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to understand the conditions under which the Read­File and Write­File functions would fail to transfer all of the bytes, and how to detect that this has occurred. The obvious reason why the Read­File functions would fail to transfer all the bytes is if there aren&#39;t that man
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250808-00/?p=111447 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KotlinX RPC 0.9.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 13:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release of kotlinx.rpc introduces significant improvements aimed at the long-term stability, maintenance, and evolution of the library. We’ve focused on decoupling dependencies and simplifying the API to create a more robust and user-friendly experience. Ready to get started? Build your next project with the interactive generator at start.ktor.io, or check out our samples on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kotlinx-rpc-0-9-1-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Faster with dotNetTips.com Spargine 8: August 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am delighted to announce the release of Spargine 8 (v2025.8.8.6) on August 6th, 2025. Spargine, my open-source project, now offers NuGet packages for .NET 8 &amp;amp; 9. These enhancements have been integrated across all my projects, many of which are currently in production. I encourage you to explore these updates and share any feedback … Continue reading Coding Faster with dotNetTips.com Spargine 8: August 2025 Release →
Link to article: https://dotnettips.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
