<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 06:24:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modular Monolith Architecture In .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 06:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss the concept of Modular Monolith Applications, and how they compare with traditional Monoliths and Microservices. We will also explain the different communication patterns we can implement between our modules. In the last decade, most enterprise businesses have switched from monolith applications to microservice applications because monolith applications have coupling […] The post Modular Monolith Architecture In .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – Build 2024 Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 22:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces Azure Developer CLI (azd) support for AI Studio and the new templates to build and deploy AI applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-build-2024-recap 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Year of JasperFx Software</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 21:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After about 25 years or so in the software industry, I finally founded my own business named JasperFx Software last year at about this time with the general strategy of building a services and product company around the “Critter Stack” tools (Marten, Wolverine, Weasel, and soon to be some others) as well as any or … Continue reading One Year of JasperFx Software →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/28/one-year-of-jasperfx-software/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrator’s Introduction to Azure IoT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 20:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Internet of Things (IoT) industry has continued to grow and become more pervasive in people’s everyday lives these last few years. There are MANY useful applications for IoT devices and solutions in both the consumer and industrial space. Some of the solutions we’ve become accustomed to are smart speakers, cameras, Amazon Alexa, and many […] The article Administrator’s Introduction to Azure IoT appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 19:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month, we are releasing fixes that impact our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. The following version of the product has been patched. Azure DevOps Server 2019.1.2 Patch 9 If you have Azure DevOps Server 2019.1.2, you should install Azure DevOps Server 2019.1.2 Patch 9.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/may-patches-for-azure-devops-server-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build 2024: What’s new for Microsoft Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 18:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how you can expand the knowledge of Copilot for Microsoft 365 with Microsoft Graph connectors and build custom solutions leveraging the data and services in Microsoft Graph APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-2024-whats-new-for-microsoft-graph 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VisualStudio.Extensibility 17.10: Debug your extensions with the Diagnostics Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 18:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine creating extensions that run faster and smoother than ever before! If you haven’t been following along lately, we’ve been working on improving the VisualStudio.Extensibility SDK. VisualStudio.Extensibility helps you build extensions that run outside the main IDE process for improved performance and reliability.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visualstudio-extensibility-17-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build 2024 Recap: Bridging the chasm between your ML and app devs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 17:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week, Semantic Kernel had a huge milestone during Microsoft Build. Both its Python and Java libraries achieved V1.0 status, guaranteeing that neither of them would have breaking changes for non-experimental features moving forward. This is a big deal for our customers,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/build-2024-recap-bridging-the-chasm-between-your-ml-and-app-devs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DXC 1.8.2405 Available Now, Including HLSL 202x</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The HLSL team is excited to announce DXC 1.8.2405 which is a packed release! In addition to a healthy assortment of bug fixes and quality of life improvements, this release features two things we’re really excited about. First this is the first DXC release to contain Windows binaries built with Clang alongside the binaries built with MSVC,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/dxc-1-8-2405-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code CMake Tools Extension 1.18 Update: Quick Start with CMake and more…</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 16:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The May release of CMake Tools in VS Code is now available. With this release, we have some new updates to the extension to improve CMake integrations with the extension’s support. Some major highlights include improvements to the CMake: Quick Start command and support for CMake presets v7 and v8.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-code-cmake-tools-extension-1-18-update-quick-start-with-cmake-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Windows Containers Support for BuildKit Released in v0.13.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are introducing experimental support for Windows Containers in BuildKit, with the aim of making this available soon in your standard Docker Build.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/experimental-windows-containers-support-for-buildkit-released-in-v0-13-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I force a DLL to register itself if it won’t respond to regsvr32?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can&#39;t force something that isn&#39;t there.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240528-00/?p=109815 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with YAML in Terraform using the `yamldecode` and `yamlencode` Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The functions built into and supported by HashiCorp Terraform include the yamldecode and yamlencode functions for working with YAML data. These functions enable seamless integration and manipulation of YAML within Terraform configurations, enhancing the flexibility and manageability of infrastructure setups. This article explains their usage, and provides some practical applications. Decoding YAML with yamldecode Function […] The article Working with YAML in Terraform using the yamldecode and yamlencode Functions appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking primary constructor member capture using a Roslyn Analyzer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe a Rosyln analyzer you can use to enforce that primary constructors are only used for initialization and never to capture as fields
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/blocking-primary-constructor-member-capture-using-an-analyzer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2 EAP Digest #1: Better Tools Configuration Support, Svelte 5, Git Enhancements, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 08:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve kicked off WebStorm 2024.2 with a new Early Access Program (EAP). Please check out this blog post, where we explain the benefits of the program. If you haven’t already seen what to expect in WebStorm 2024.2, take a moment to explore our roadmap. The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the EAP […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/05/webstorm-2024-2-eap1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Azure DevOps Copilot using .NET 8, Semantic Kernel and Azure OpenAI GPT-4o</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 09:35:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to create an Azure DevOps Copilot that utilizes a small subset of the Azure DevOps REST API. To achieve this, we will be using Semantic Kernel along with .NET 8 and Azure OpenAI.
Link to article: https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-an-azure-devops-copilot-using-semantic-kernel-and-azure-openai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fastest Ways to Perform Base 10 Conversions in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 05:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Performing base 10 conversions is fundamental when learning basic computer science and mathematical concepts. Since we know computer systems understand binary, such conversions can help us form different number representations that we can use for various applications such as encoding and cryptography. In this article, we will explore the fastest way to convert a base […] The post Fastest Ways to Perform Base 10 Conversions in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing links to source code for .NET API Docs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET API reference docs now link directly to the source code! Learn how the links are generated, and some of ideas for future improvements.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-docs-link-to-source-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there any difference between String­From­IID and String­From­CLSID?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not really.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240527-00/?p=109812 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to test a Roslyn analyzer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you write a Roslyn analyzer, you should also write tests for it. The Roslyn SDK provides a set of NuGet packages that you can use to test your analyzers. In this post, I describe how to test a Roslyn analyzer using the Roslyn SDK NuGet packages. First, Roslyn SDK NuGet packages are not available on NuGet.org. You need to add the following package source to your project file:…
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Microsoft Copilot for Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot for Azure is an AI-powered tool designed to enhance your efficiency and productivity when working with Azure. Leveraging advanced Large Language Models (LLMs) and the Azure control plane, Copilot for Azure provides deep insights and simplifies the management of Azure services and resources. It aims to streamline operations across both cloud and edge […] The article Introducing Microsoft Copilot for Azure appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Collection Examination: A Comparative Analysis of Predicate Methods in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores four methods for examining items in a collection using predicates, with a focus on performance. A Twitter poll revealed that over 50% of developers favored the LINQ Any() method, prompting the author to verify its efficiency in comparison to other options like Count() and Exists().
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/27/optimizing-collection-examination-a-comparative-analysis-of-predicate-methods-in-c/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C#12 引入主构造函数：简化代码重构</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 07:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译于David Pine的这篇文章：Refactor your C# code with primary constructors 作为 .NET 8 一部分的 C# 12 引入了一组引人注目的新功能！ 在这篇文章中，我们将探讨其中一个功能，特别是主构造函数，解释其用法和相关性。 然后，我们将演示一个重构示例，以展示如何将其应用到您的代码中，并讨论其好处和潜在的缺陷。 这将帮助您了解这一更改的影响并有助于您决定是否采用该功能。 主构造函数1️⃣ 主构造函数被认为是一项“C#日常”的开发人员功能。 它们允许您在一个简洁的声明中定义类或结构及其构造函数。 这可以帮助您减少需要编写的样板代码量。 如果您一直在关注 C# 版本，您可能熟悉记录类型，其中包括主构造函数的第一个示例。 与记录类型的区别 记录类型作为类或结构的类型修饰符引入，这简化了构建简单类（如数据容器）的语法。 记录可以包括主构造函数。 该构造函数不仅生成一个支持字段，而且还为每个参数公开一个公共属性。 与传统的类或结构类型不同，在传统的类或结构类型中，主构造函数参数可以在整个类定义中访问，而记录被设计为透明的数据容器。 他们本质上支持基于值的相等，这与他们作为数据持有者的预期角色相一致。 因此，它们的主构造函数参数可以作为属性访问是合乎逻辑的。 重构示例✨ .NET 提供了许多模板，如果您曾经创建过Worker Service，您可能见过以下Worker类模板代码： namespace Example.Worker.Service { public class Worker : BackgroundService { private readonly ILogger
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/c12-%e5%bc%95%e5%85%a5%e4%b8%bb%e6%9e%84%e9%80%a0%e5%87%bd%e6%95%b0%ef%bc%9a%e7%ae%80%e5%8c%96%e4%bb%a3%e7%a0%81%e9%87%8d%e6%9e%84 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a Microsoft Entra ID external authentication method using ASP.NET Core and OpenIddict</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 05:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article shows how to implement a Microsoft Entra ID external authentication method (EAM) using ASP.NET Core, OpenIddict and FIDO2/passkeys. The application using ASP.NET Core Identity to manage the accounts and the passkeys. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/MfaServer The following flow diagram from the Microsoft docs explains how EAM works. Refer to the documentation for a full explanation. […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/05/27/implement-a-microsoft-entra-id-external-authentication-method-using-asp-net-core-and-openiddict/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Compare Two Dictionaries in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 05:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will first explore several ways to compare two dictionaries in C#. Then, we will compare and rank the performance of these approaches using the BenchmarkDotNet library. When we work with Dictionary objects in C#, checking their equality is a common task we’re likely to encounter. Without further ado, let’s get started. […] The post How to Compare Two Dictionaries in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Custom 404 Not Found Page with Azure Static Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2024/26_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2024/26_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When managing a website, it’s crucial to ensure a seamless user experience, even when things go wrong. One common scenario is the 404 Not Found error when a visitor tries to access a page that doesn’t exist. Instead of having your visitor see the default Azure Static Web App “not found” page, you can configure […] The article Configure Custom 404 Not Found Page with Azure Static Web Apps appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Utilizing Common Attributes in Classes in Microsoft .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2024/26_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2024/26_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Attributes for class members offer metadata and instructions for interaction with those members. This post highlights common member attributes like DebuggerDisplay, DefaultValue, DisallowNull, EditorBrowsable, MemberNotNull, MemberNotNullWhen, Range, and ReadOnly, detailing their purpose and benefits in enhancing code quality, documentation, and IDE support. Utilize these attributes to aid development processes.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/26/understanding-and-utilizing-common-attributes-in-classes-in-microsoft-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Delegating Handlers to Extend HttpClient in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2024/26_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 05:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2024/26_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore HttpClient’s delegating handlers in ASP.NET Core. These handlers act as a middleware pipeline for HTTP requests and responses, allowing us to intercept, process, and modify HTTP traffic before it reaches external applications. What Are Delegating Handlers? Delegating Handlers in HttpClient closely resembles ASP.NET Core’s middleware architecture. Each handler processes incoming […] The post Using Delegating Handlers to Extend HttpClient in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback is Deeper Than You Think – Dev Leader Weekly 45</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Feedback is Deeper Than You Think – Dev Leader Weekly 45 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss why feedback is important at all levels of engineering AND how it works two ways. The post Feedback is Deeper Than You Think – Dev Leader Weekly 45 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/05/25/feedback-is-deeper-than-you-think-dev-leader-weekly-45/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLDR: Next Gen AI for Developers with Microsoft Cloud by Scott Guthrie at Microsoft Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 10:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scott Guthrie’s talk, “Next Generation AI for Developers with the Microsoft Cloud,” highlighted significant advancements and tools for developers leveraging AI and the Microsoft Cloud. Here’s a TLDR to give you a quicker way to stay updated on all the key announcements. Notable Moments from Scott Guthries Talk Here’s are several notable moments from Scott […] The article TLDR: Next Gen AI for Developers with Microsoft Cloud by Scott Guthrie at Microsoft Build 2024 appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the StronglyTypedId Package in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 05:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look at the StronglyTypedId NuGet package and how it helps us enhance type safety and code readability in our .NET projects by generating strongly-typed IDs for our entities. Let’s get started. Benefits of Using StronglyTypedId Before we look at how to install and utilize the StronglyTypedId NuGet package, let’s consider why […] The post Introduction to the StronglyTypedId Package in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift Left With Architecture Testing in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_05_2024/25_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this newsletter, we&#39;ll explore how architecture testing can safeguard our project&#39;s architecture. Architecture tests can help us shift left and detect architectural issues faster.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/shift-left-with-architecture-testing-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNW 0.74 Launches: A Gallery Glow-up and Fabric Foundations!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve recently released React Native 0.74! Alongside all the fantastic features from React Native, we&#39;ve been hard at work enhancing the Windows experience, refreshing our Gallery App, and setting the stage for Fabric support.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/react-native/2024-05-24-improved-gallery-fabric-0-74 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Graph town hall APIs now available in beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 15:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the retirement of Teams live events in favor of Teams town hall, we’re announcing the preview (beta) release of new Microsoft Graph town hall APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-graph-town-hall-apis-now-available-in-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting the contents of a Windows Runtime Vector from C&#43;&#43;/WinRT in one call</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The one-stop shop for updating a Windows Runtime Vector.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240524-00/?p=109804 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Copilot Internal Architecture Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot is an advanced, Generative AI-powered assistant designed to enhance productivity by integrating with various Microsoft applications and services. It leverages large language models (LLMs) and the extensive data network of Microsoft Graph to provide contextual and intelligent assistance in real-time. FYI, this is not an official write up of the architecture of Microsoft […] The article Microsoft Copilot Internal Architecture Explained appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Enum Handling in Spargine: Beyond Enums and into Versatility</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This content explains the usage of Enums in programming, cautioning against relying solely on Enum values for human-readable names from databases due to potential performance issues. It introduces EnumHelper and EnumExtensions in Spargine, providing methods like GetValues() and GetDescription(). The article also discusses the Enumeration class as a solution to surpass Enum limitations, offering flexibility for custom names and methods like FromDisplayName. This extends Enum functionality and provides more versatility when Enum&#39;s constraints are exceeded.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>宣布 Java on Azure 开发工具支持 Java on Azure Container Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 07:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            在Build 2024 期间宣布，Azure Container Apps 现在可为 Java 开发人员提供丰富的操作功能。(详细内容请参见本博客）。 我们很高兴地与大家分享，Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ 为 Azure Container Apps（Java on ACA）提供了支持，并提供了灵活的部署选项。有了这项支持，Java 开发人员可以使用 GitHub 代码库中的源代码或本地工件构建和部署他们的应用程序，用于新的 ACA 应用程序或现有的 ACA 应用程序。这将增强开发人员在云中运行容器化 Java 应用程序的能力，并加强安全态势，更好地调整容器环境的内存配置。 观看下面的演示，构建并部署您的第一个 Java on ACA 应用程序, 资源 以下是有助于进一步了解 Java on Azure Container Apps 链接列表： Java on Azure Container Apps 概述 Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ 文档
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-azure-aca 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start Simple, Scale Fast: Azure Storage for Distributed Computing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Storage Accounts are one of the simplest resources on Azure, but simultaneously one of the most useful and reused building blocks across the Microsoft Cloud ecosystem. Blobs, leases, and queues are fundamental components that enable powerful patterns. Let&#39;s dig into why Storage Accounts should be in your Azure toolkit.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/azure-storage-for-distributed-computing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does the Default ASP.NET Core Identity Password Hasher Work?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 05:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will delve into the default ASP.NET Core Identity Password Hasher. We will focus on understanding how it transforms plain text passwords into secure hashes and highlighting its security features. Let’s dive in. How the Password Hashing Process Works When discussing password hashing, we typically consider two scenarios. Firstly, when a user […] The post How Does the Default ASP.NET Core Identity Password Hasher Work? appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Java on Azure Container Apps Support for Java on Azure Developer Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 04:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            During Build 2024, it was announced that Azure Container Apps now offers a rich set of operational capabilities for Java Developers. (Full details on this blog). We are excited to share that Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ has provided support for Java on Azure Container Apps(Java on ACA) with flexible deployment options.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-azure-aca 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectively Sharing Resources Between Modules in a Modular Monolith</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_05_2024/24_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the key challenges in developing a modular monolith is managing the communication between different modules, especially when it comes…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/effectively-sharing-resources-between-modules-modular-monolith/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Initializing Reference Type Static Fields Inline for Enhanced Code Readability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article advocates for initializing reference type static fields inline to enhance code readability and prevent unexpected behavior caused by uninitialized static fields. Microsoft recommends initializing these fields at the point of declaration to improve clarity. The article provides examples demonstrating the issue and the recommended solution, emphasizing the use of static constructors for initialization.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/23/code-it-any-way-you-want-initializing-reference-type-static-fields-inline-for-enhanced-code-readability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Mixtral 8x7B pre-training with expert parallelism on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 19:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mixture of Experts (MoE) architectures for large language models (LLMs) have recently gained popularity due to their ability to increase model capacity and computational efficiency compared to fully dense models. By utilizing sparse expert subnetworks that process different subsets of tokens, MoE models can effectively increase the number of parameters while requiring less computation per […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-mixtral-8x7b-pre-training-with-expert-parallelism-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing cloud native apps with Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 17:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce the general availability of .NET Aspire, a comprehensive stack aimed at simplifying the way .NET cloud-native apps are built and managed. .NET Aspire offers developers like you an improved, opinionated framework for constructing distributed applications, ensuring a seamless and consistent development experience.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/developing-cloud-native-apps-with-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locking In On Concurrency Control</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 16:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Concurrency in a multi-user collaborative environment can be challenging. However, understanding the use case is crucial in picking a solution for handling concurrency. Let’s dive into different solutions for concurrency control in various situations. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in this… Read More »Locking In On Concurrency Control The post Locking In On Concurrency Control appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Docker Desktop Support for Windows on Arm: New AI Innovation Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop now supports running on Windows on Arm (WoA) devices. With this integration, Docker Desktop extends its reach to a new wave of hardware architectures, broadening the horizons for containerized application development.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-docker-desktop-support-for-windows-on-arm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (May 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 16:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure SDKs release every month. This post includes the month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-may-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a prepopulated Windows Runtime Vector from C&#43;&#43;/WinRT without going through an explicit std::vector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Creating the vector inline.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240523-00/?p=109797 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLDR: Microsoft Build 2024 Keynote with Satya Nadella</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 10:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            During the Microsoft Build 2024 keynote, CEO Satya Nadella delivered a comprehensive overview of Microsoft’s vision and advancements in artificial intelligence (AI). Addressing a global audience, Nadella emphasized how AI is set to transform every aspect of our digital and physical lives, making technology more accessible, efficient, and integrated into daily activities. The presentation covered […] The article TLDR: Microsoft Build 2024 Keynote with Satya Nadella appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>宣布 Java on Azure 开发工具支持 Azure Functions Flex Consumption</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 09:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Functions Flex Consumption 刚刚在微软 Build 2024大会期间发布（详情请参见本博客）。我们很高兴地与大家分享，Azure Functions 的 IntelliJ Azure Toolkit 和 Maven 插件现在也已经支持 Flex Consumption。有了这项支持，Java 开发人员可以使用我们的工具轻松创建和部署他们的 Flex Consumption 应用程序。您可以在 Flex Consumption 上以可忽略的冷启动延迟和持续就绪实例运行无服务器 Java 应用程序，以实现事件驱动的扩展。 观看下面的演示，使用 Flex Consumption 构建您的 Azure Functions 应用程序， 如果您正在使用 Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ： 如果您正在使用 Azure Functions 的 Maven 插件： 在未来几个月中，我们还计划扩展 Gradle 插件对 Flex Consumption 的支持。 资源 以下是有助于进一步了解 Flex Consumption 预览版的链接列表： 在 Flex Consumption 计划中创建和管理函数应用程序 Azure Functions Flex Consumption 文档 针对 IntelliJ 的 Azure Toolkit 文档 Azure Functions 的 Maven 插件 Azure Functions 的 Gradle 插件
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Compare Two Files in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 06:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to compare two files in C#. There are several reasons why we might want to compare two files in our code, such as integrity checks, detecting duplicate files, version control, synchronization, and more. But what are the different ways we can compare two files using C#, and why […] The post How to Compare Two Files in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Architecture Sucks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The other day I was participating in a conversation online in an architecture forum. One of the participants was complaining about the mess…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/clean-architecture-sucks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new for Office Add-ins at Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 22:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog, the Office Platform team announces the new capabilities and features announced at Build 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/whats-new-for-office-add-ins-at-build-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Release of Semantic Kernel Python 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 19:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the release of the long-awaited Semantic Kernel Python SDK 1.0.0! This milestone version brings a plethora of enhancements and new features designed to empower AI and app developers with more robust and versatile tools. Exciting New Feature: Shared Prompts Across Languages One of the groundbreaking features of this release is the ability to share prompts across different programming languages.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-python-1-0-0-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating fashion product descriptions by fine-tuning a vision-language model with SageMaker and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 19:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to predict domain-specific product attributes from product images by fine-tuning a VLM on a fashion dataset using Amazon SageMaker, and then using Amazon Bedrock to generate product descriptions using the predicted attributes as input. So you can follow along, we’re sharing the code in a GitHub repository.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generating-fashion-product-descriptions-by-fine-tuning-a-vision-language-model-with-sagemaker-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New for C&#43;&#43; Developers in Visual Studio 2022 17.10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 18:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that Visual Studio 2022 version 17.10 is now generally available! This post summarizes the new features you can find in this release for C++. You can download Visual Studio 2022 from the Visual Studio downloads page or upgrade your existing installation by following the Update Visual Studio Learn page.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-for-cpp-developers-in-visual-studio-2022-17-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of Semantic Kernel Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 17:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last year we published the initial release of Semantic Kernel for Java. It has been nearly a year of work building and shaping this SDK to help developers quickly and idiomatically build intelligent Java apps with OpenAI. Throughout this time, all teams behind Semantic Kernel SDKs (for Python,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-the-general-availability-of-semantic-kernel-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you have to create a Windows Runtime Vector from C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, do it as late as possible</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stay with the std::vector until you really need the Window Runtime Vector.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240522-00/?p=109795 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Documentation Gets an AI-Powered Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 13:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the Docker Docs AI, a documentation assistant designed to provide instant, accurate answers directly from the Docker docs pages. Features include language options, answers from multiple sources, and contextual and debugging help.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-documentation-ai-powered-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Strategic Imperative of AI in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 13:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We examine the incredible growth of AI and explore its potential power to transform industries and help enterprises accelerate innovation.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/the-strategic-imperative-of-ai-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Output URL to Azure Portal for Azure Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp Terraform is an extremely powerful IaC tool for managing Microsoft Azure infrastructure through code, from the command-line, and from CI/CD tools like GitHub Actions or Terraform Cloud. Terraform is great for managing and deploying the configurations for Microsoft Azure resources, but tools like the Azure Portal are still needed to view the real Azure […] The article Terraform: Output URL to Azure Portal for Azure Resources appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Functions Flex Consumption Support for Java on Azure Developer Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 10:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Functions Flex Consumption has just been announced during Microsoft Build 2024 (Full details on this blog), we are excited to share that Flex Consumption is now also supported on Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ and Maven plugins for Azure Functions. With this support,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/announcing-flex-consumption-support-for-java-on-azure-developer-tools 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First preview of Visual Studio 2022 v17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 10:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the release of Visual Studio 2022 v17.11 Preview 1, the first preview of our next update for Visual Studio 2022. This preview focuses on quality-of-life improvements for all developers and workloads. See the release notes for full list of features.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/first-preview-of-visual-studio-2022-v17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance: Exploring the Performance Impact of the ‘in’ Keyword in C# 7.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the impact of the &#39;in&#39; keyword in C# 7.2 on method parameters, ensuring reference treatment for enhanced performance. Explore a practical example and insights in our latest article.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/22/general-performance-exploring-the-performance-impact-of-the-in-keyword-in-c-7-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Global Default JSON Serialization Options in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 05:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JSON serialization is the process of transforming .NET objects into JSON format, which ensures data exchange within applications. Implementing global default JSON serialization settings in ASP.NET Core Web API maintains uniformity across applications. In this article, we’ll explore the various methods for setting global default JSON serialization options in the ASP.NET Core Web API. Before […] The post How to Set Global Default JSON Serialization Options in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announced at Build 2024: DiskANN-powered vector database, cross-region replication in vCore, and a new era of databases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 04:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Build 2024 kicked off this week aiming to answer the question “How will AI shape your future?” You’ll find the answer in the incredible lineup of sessions at this year’s event – featuring talks on generative AI, building copilots, cloud platforms,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/build2024-cosmos-roundup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
