<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The Drive-By Localhost Breach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 4 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that expose the devastating vulnerabilities in AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker MCP Gateway provides enterprise-grade protection against sophisticated attack vectors. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) has transformed how developers integrate AI agents with their development environments. Tools like...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mpc-horror-stories-cve-2025-49596-local-host-breach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging Unit Test Generation with in-IDE TestSpark</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Test generation is an essential yet time-consuming part of quality assurance. Automating test-generation techniques means accelerating the development process and improving the quality of the final software. However, traditional automated techniques, and their respective tools, are not usually user-friendly, having a command-line interface and not being integrated with the IDE. To boost acceleration and quality […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/testspark-unit-test-generation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sleep-pc: a .NET Native AOT tool to make Windows sleep after a timeout</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe a small native AOT .NET tool that I built to force a Windows PC to go to sleep after a timer expires
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/sleep-pc-a-dotnet-tool-to-make-windows-sleep-after-a-timeout/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression Trees in C#: Building Dynamic LINQ Queries at Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:05:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tired of endless if-else blocks just to build queries? What if your LINQ queries could write themselves at runtime? Today, we will unfold expression trees, which can be used to create dynamic queries at runtime. I will show how to use expression trees in your project and understand their advantages
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/expression-trees-in-c-building-dynamic-linq-queries-at-runtime/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a secure MCP server using OAuth and Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 05:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article shows how to implement a secure model context protocol (MCP) server using OAuth and Entra ID. The MCP server is implemented using ASP.NET Core and uses Microsoft Entra ID to secure the API. An ASP.NET Core application using Azure OpenAI and semantic kernel is used to implement the MCP client for the agent […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/09/23/implement-a-secure-mcp-server-using-oauth-and-entra-id/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancements to XAML Live Preview in Visual Studio for .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The XAML Live Preview feature in Visual Studio 2022 version 17.14 introduces a significant usability improvement for .NET MAUI projects: the XAML Live Preview window is now available during design time, eliminating the requirement to initiate a debug session. This change streamlines the UI dev
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/enhancements-to-xaml-live-preview-in-visual-studio-for-net-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the new SqlVector type with EF Core and Dapper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure SQL vector support has been generally available for a few months now, and the ecosystem is quickly evolving to make working with vectors in your applications as seamless and efficient as possible. With the release of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/using-the-new-sqlvector-type-with-ef-core-and-dapper 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid ML experimentation for enterprises with Amazon SageMaker AI and Comet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showed how to use SageMaker and Comet together to spin up fully managed ML environments with reproducibility and experiment tracking capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/rapid-ml-experimentation-for-enterprises-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-comet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islands Theme: The New Look Coming to JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 16:24:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with version 2025.2.3, JetBrains IDEs will offer a new look: the Islands theme, available in both dark and light modes. This update is a visual refresh, which means that all functionality will remain the same. The new theme can be turned on or off in the Appearance settings. This step brings us closer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/islands-theme-the-new-look-coming-to-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Trusted Publishing enhances security on NuGet.org</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce Trusted Publishing on nuget.org — a simpler, safer way to publish NuGet packages from GitHub Actions. Rather than relying on long‑lived API keys, your workflow can use a short‑lived GitHub OIDC token to request a temporary, single‑use NuGet API key. These keys expire quickly (≈ 1 hour), eliminating long‑
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/enhanced-security-is-here-with-the-new-trust-publishing-on-nuget-org 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why was Windows 3.0&#39;s WinHelp called an online help system when it ran offline?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I described Windows 3.0&#39;s WinHelp as &amp;quot;a program for browsing online help files.&amp;quot; But Windows 3.0 predated the Internet, and these help files were available even if the computer was not
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250922-00/?p=111619 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch migrate .sln files to .slnx format across repositories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET has introduced a new solution file format called .slnx that offers significant improvements over the traditional .sln format: Better readability: XML-based structure that&#39;s human-readable Simplified merging: Reduces merge conflicts compared to the legacy format Easier parsing: Can be manipulated programmatically outside IDEs (for .NET devs, you can use microsoft/vs-solutionpersistence) To start using…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/batch-migrate-sln-files-to-slnx-format-across-repositories.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American-made innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            American-made innovation
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/american-made-innovation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.9.0 Released: Compose Multiplatform for Web Goes Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Multiplatform for web, powered by Wasm, is now in Beta! This major milestone shows that Compose Multiplatform for web is no longer just experimental, but ready for real-world use by early adopters. This is more than a technical step forward. It’s a community achievement, made possible by feedback from early adopters of the Alpha […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/compose-multiplatform-1-9-0-compose-for-web-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a safe, observable AI infrastructure for 1 million classrooms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how SchoolAI, built on OpenAI’s GPT-4.1, image generation, and TTS, powers safe, teacher-guided AI tools for 1 million classrooms worldwide—boosting engagement, oversight, and personalized learning.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/schoolai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and NVIDIA announce strategic partnership to deploy 10 gigawatts of NVIDIA systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and NVIDIA announce a strategic partnership to deploy 10 gigawatts of AI datacenters powered by NVIDIA systems, with the first phase launching in 2026.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-nvidia-systems-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Mastering ObservableList in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_09_2025/21_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_09_2025/21_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ObservableList enhances the typical List by integrating event notifications for dynamic collection changes, making it ideal for MVVM applications in WPF, MAUI, and Xamarin. It supports multiple constructors, provides essential methods for collection management, and raises relevant events to keep UI synchronized, ensuring responsive and maintainable applications.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/09/21/boost-your-net-projects-mastering-observablelist-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These Junior Devs Just Don&#39;t Get It! - Dev Leader Weekly 110</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2025/20_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2025/20_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL; DR:
Stop the blame game Timebox efforts and invite curiosity on reviews Check out the livestream (or watch the recording) on Monday, September 22nd, at 7:00 PM Pacific!
Empowering Junior Developers on Reviews If you have juniors on your team, you may have run into this:
Pull requests piling up Reviews slowing down ... and everyone quietly frustrated
Is it just because your code is too complex? Maybe not. Should we point the finger at the junior developers and blame them?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-09-19</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2025/20_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 05:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2025/20_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Like what you read or watched from the recap? I&#39;d love if you helped share on Reddit or Daily.dev so others can see!
Weekly Recap I&#39;m Speaking at Commit Your Code Conference in Dallas!
Excited to be travelling back down to Dallas to speak, and this time, it&#39;s at Commit Your Code! Here&#39;s what I&#39;m going to be talking about...
The Other Side of Software Engineering Interviews - Principal Engineering Manager AMA
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Locking in .NET: Coordinating Work Across Multiple Instances</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2025/20_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2025/20_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to coordinate work across multiple application instances using distributed locking in .NET, preventing race conditions and ensuring data consistency in scaled-out systems. Explore implementation approaches from PostgreSQL advisory locks to the DistributedLock library for production-ready solutions.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/distributed-locking-in-dotnet-coordinating-work-across-multiple-instances 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move your AI agents from proof of concept to production with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore helps you transition your agentic applications from experimental proof of concept to production-ready systems. We follow the journey of a customer support agent that evolves from a simple local prototype to a comprehensive, enterprise-grade solution capable of handling multiple concurrent users while maintaining security and performance standards.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/move-your-ai-agents-from-proof-of-concept-to-production-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a GraphQL API with AWS AppSync Using Direct Lambda Resolvers in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GraphQL APIs enables clients to request specific data sets, reducing over-fetching compared to traditional REST APIs, which return fixed data structures with unnecessary fields. Unlike REST APIs that require multiple endpoints and round trips to gather related data, GraphQL provides a single endpoint. This enables clients to fetch exactly what they need in one request, improving […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/building-a-graphql-api-with-aws-appsync-using-direct-lambda-resolvers-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to read C&#43;&#43; compiler errors: Not a legal base class</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A colleague was trying to create a Windows Runtime delegate with WRL. Here&#39;s a simplified version of what they wrote. namespace ABI { using namespace ABI::Windows::UI::ViewManagement; } struct MyClass : Microsoft::WRL::RuntimeClass&amp;lt;⟦...⟧&amp;gt; { HRESULT OnInputPaneShowing(ABI::InputPane* sender,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250919-00/?p=111612 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Component Updates &amp; Redesigned Update Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 13:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following on from our previous initiative to improve how Docker Desktop delivers updates, we are excited to announce another major improvement to how Docker Desktop keeps your development tools up to date. Starting with Docker Desktop 4.46, we&#39;re introducing automatic component updates and a completely redesigned update experience that puts your productivity first. Why We&#39;re...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-silent-component-updates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Containers: llama.cpp Now Pulls GGUF Models Directly from Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The world of local AI is moving at an incredible pace, and at the heart of this revolution is llama.cpp—the powerhouse C++ inference engine that brings Large Language Models (LLMs) to everyday hardware (and it’s also the inference engine that powers Docker Model Runner). Developers love llama.cpp for its performance and simplicity. And we at...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/llama-cpp-pulls-gguf-models-from-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – September Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you remember, dancin’ in September? 🎶 This September, let JetBrains keep the rhythm of your studies strong with free JetBrains IDEs and tools for study, a brand-new collaboration between AWS and JetBrains Academy, exclusive opportunities for school students, and more. Ready to groove into learning?
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/09/19/jetbrains-academy-september/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 09:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.2 has arrived with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates included in this version: To find out more details about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/intellij-idea-2025-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale visual production using Stability AI Image Services in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was written with Alex Gnibus of Stability AI. Stability AI Image Services are now available in Amazon Bedrock, offering ready-to-use media editing capabilities delivered through the Amazon Bedrock API. These image editing tools expand on the capabilities of Stability AI’s Stable Diffusion 3.5 models (SD3.5) and Stable Image Core and Ultra models, which […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-visual-production-using-stability-ai-image-services-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompting for precision with Stability AI Image Services in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock now offers Stability AI Image Services: 9 tools that improve how businesses create and modify images. The technology extends Stable Diffusion and Stable Image models to give you precise control over image creation and editing. Clear prompts are critical—they provide art direction to the AI system. Strong prompts control specific elements like tone, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/prompting-for-precision-with-stability-ai-image-services-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Assisted Development powered by Local Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers have long struggled with concerns about data privacy, restrictive cloud dependencies, and limited control over their AI tools—especially when working on sensitive projects or within regulated industries. Now, with the excitement surrounding local models, you can harness AI directly on your device, ensuring your data stays private
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/ai-assisted-development-powered-by-local-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A free, online event for the .NET community. JetBrains .NET Days Online returns for two focused days of practical talks, live demos, and real-world tips from community speakers and the JetBrains .NET team. Register now → Event basics Registration: https://lp.jetbrains.com/dotnet-days-2025 Agenda highlights Here’s a preview of what we’ve got in store for you: How to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/18/announcing-jetbrains-net-days-online-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Wolverine 5 and CritterWatch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re targeting October 1st for the release of Wolverine 5.0. At this point, I think I’d like to say that we’re not going to be adding any new features to Wolverine 4.* except for JasperFx Software client needs. And also, not that I have any pride about this, I don’t think we’re going to address … Continue reading Update on Wolverine 5 and CritterWatch →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/18/update-on-wolverine-5-and-critterwatch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new GitHub app for Teams: from conversation to code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Meet the reimagined GitHub app for Teams: an AI-powered app to collaborate with GitHub Copilot right inside your Teams conversations. This initial release focuses on the Copilot coding agent, which was built to translate conversations into code and pull requests. This is the first step toward bringing the full power
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/copilot-powered-github-app-for-teams-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and Distribute AI Agents and Workflows with cagent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            cagent is a new open-source project from Docker that makes it simple to build, run, and share AI agents, without writing a single line of code. Instead of writing code and wrangling Python versions and dependencies when creating AI agents, you define your agent&#39;s behavior, tools, and persona in a single YAML file, making it...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/cagent-build-and-distribute-ai-agents-and-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker and CNCF: Partnering to Power the Future of Open Source</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Docker, open source is not just something we support; it&#39;s a core part of our culture. It’s part of our DNA. From foundational projects like Docker Compose (35.5k stars, 5.4k forks) and Moby (69.8k stars, 18.8k forks) to our continued code contributions, we remain committed to strengthening the open-source ecosystem. Today, we are announcing...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-cncf-partnership/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Amazon Bedrock batch inference using Amazon CloudWatch metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to monitor and manage Amazon Bedrock batch inference jobs using Amazon CloudWatch metrics, alarms, and dashboards to optimize performance, cost, and operational efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/monitor-amazon-bedrock-batch-inference-using-amazon-cloudwatch-metrics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use AWS Deep Learning Containers with Amazon SageMaker AI managed MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to integrate AWS DLCs with MLflow to create a solution that balances infrastructure control with robust ML governance. We walk through a functional setup that your team can use to meet your specialized requirements while significantly reducing the time and resources needed for ML lifecycle management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-aws-deep-learning-containers-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-managed-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Updates and Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of updates and bug fixes for the 2025.2 release of ReSharper and Rider has just been made public. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.2.2 To make your transition to Visual Studio 2026 seamless, ReSharper now installs a lightweight migration extension bundled with the product. This extension will be carried over automatically by […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/18/resharper-rider-2025-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can I close a duplicate handle while I&#39;m waiting on the original?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our study of the case of the invalid handle error when a handle is closed while a thread is waiting on it, Frederic Benoit
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250918-00/?p=111608 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner General Availability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share that Docker Model Runner is now generally available (GA)! In April 2025, Docker introduced the first Beta release of Docker Model Runner, making it easy to manage, run, and distribute local AI models (specifically LLMs). Though only a short time has passed since then, the product has evolved rapidly, with continuous...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-docker-model-runner-ga/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Enrichment in Marten Projections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 21:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So here’s a common scenario when building a system using Event Sourcing with Marten: As an example, let’s say that your application has some reference information about system users saved in this document type (from the Marten testing suite): And you also have events for some kind of UserTask aggregate that manages the workflow of … Continue reading Event Enrichment in Marten Projections →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/17/event-enrichment-in-marten-projections/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your organization’s productivity with the Amazon Q Business browser extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showed how to use the Amazon Q Business browser extension to give your team seamless access to AI-driven insights and assistance. The browser extension is now available in US East (N. Virginia) and US West (Oregon) AWS Regions for Mozilla, Google Chrome, and Microsoft Edge as part of the Lite Subscription.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/supercharge-your-organizations-productivity-with-the-amazon-q-business-browser-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Agentic Workflows with OpenAI GPT OSS on Amazon SageMaker AI and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to deploy gpt-oss-20b model to SageMaker managed endpoints and demonstrate a practical stock analyzer agent assistant example with LangGraph, a powerful graph-based framework that handles state management, coordinated workflows, and persistent memory systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-agentic-workflows-with-openai-gpt-oss-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I get my shell thumbnail extractors to run in the same process?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We learned that Explorer uses the COM Surrogate as a sacrificial process when hosting thumbnail extraction plug-ins. A customer had a thumbnail extraction plug-in for which prepar
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250917-29/?p=111604 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Common DevOps Problems And How to Solve Them With GoLand</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most popular posts on the /devops subreddit says, “After 24 years in IT, I’m done. I don’t want to debug another YAML file. This is not how I foresee spending my life.” DevOps can be frustrating, and the 3,000+ people who upvoted that post clearly agree. It doesn’t have to be this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/09/17/8-common-devops-problems-and-how-to-solve-them-with-goland/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Record Scanner for vinyl collectors cuts costs with Azure Cosmos DB vector search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            by Artur Drozdz, Founder of Record Scanner (recordscanner.com) If you’re like me, there’s at least one room in your home with an entire cabinet dedicated to your growing vinyl collection. At this point, you’ve probably heard that vinyl is making a comeback, it’s not just vintage anymo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/record-scanner-for-vinyl-collectors-cuts-costs-with-azure-cosmos-db-vector-search 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the most out of MCP in Visual Studio with Prompts, Resources, and Sampling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce that Visual Studio now supports MCP prompts, resources, and sampling (with even more coming soon!) to enhance your Copilot experience by bringing in more context from your engineering stack. These powerful new features unlock deeper integrations with your favorite tools and services, making your development workflow m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/mcp-prompts-resources-sampling 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt Files and Instructions Files Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot is transforming the way developers write code by acting as an intelligent coding agent directly in your editor. Whether you’re building ASP.NET web applications, working with C#, or reviewing code with your team, Copilot can help automate repetitive tasks, suggest entire functions, and streamline code reviews. In this guide, w
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/prompt-files-and-instructions-files-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server 2025 RC1: faster DiskANN and FP16 support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce major improvements to DiskANN in SQL Server 2025 RC1, making vector search faster, more scalable, and more storage-efficient than ever before. ⚡ Significantly Faster Index Builds Building DiskANN indexes is now considerably faster, thanks to
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/sql-server-2025-rc1-faster-diskann-and-fp16-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: Fabric Integration and GitHub Copilot Slash Commands (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code continues to evolve, delivering features that make SQL development more integrated, more consistent, and more developer-friendly. In version v1.36.0, we’re announci
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-fabric-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Secure AI Coding Agents with Cerebras and Docker Compose</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the recent article, Building Isolated AI Code Environments with Cerebras and Docker Compose, our friends at Cerebras showcased how one can build a coding agent to use worlds fastest Cerebras’ AI inference API, Docker Compose, ADK-Python, and MCP servers. In this post, we’ll dive deeper into the underlying technologies and show how the pieces...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/cerebras-docker-compose-secure-ai-coding-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Debugger: ApplicationContext at Your Fingertips</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA has great support for debugging Java and Kotlin applications. But if you are building Spring Boot applications, you may want to access Spring components along with their metadata. That’s where the Spring Debugger plugin comes in. It makes life easier by letting you explore and use the entire Spring ApplicationContext right from your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/spring-debugger-applicationcontext-at-your-fingertips/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.3 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to kick off the Early Access Program (EAP) for Rider 2025.3! With the first preview build now available, you can try out the new features we’ve been working on and let us know what you think. Your feedback plays a vital role in shaping the final release. If you haven’t joined an EAP […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/17/the-early-access-program-for-rider-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.3 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that the Early Access Program (EAP) has started for both ReSharper and .NET Tools 2025.3. The first preview build is now available, giving you an early opportunity to explore what’s coming in the next major release. Your feedback is essential in helping us polish these updates, so we’d love to hear […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/17/the-early-access-program-for-resharper-and-net-tools-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ground Your Agents Faster with Native Azure AI Search Indexing in Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 08:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Azure AI Foundry now lets you ingest data directly from Azure Blob Storage, ADLS Gen2, or Microsoft OneLake and create an Azure AI Search index in just one click. When you create an agent in Azure AI Foundry one of the most powerf
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/ground-your-agents-faster-native-azure-ai-search-indexing-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting and reducing scheming in AI models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Apollo Research and OpenAI developed evaluations for hidden misalignment (“scheming”) and found behaviors consistent with scheming in controlled tests across frontier models. The team shared concrete examples and stress tests of an early method to reduce scheming.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/detecting-and-reducing-scheming-in-ai-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET STS releases supported for 24 months</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are increasing the length of support offered for .NET Standard Term Support (STS) releases from 18 months to 24 months. This change is effective starting with .NET 9, which means .NET 9 will now reach end of support on November 10, 2026. There is no change for Long Term Support (LTS) releases, which will continue to be supported for three y
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-sts-releases-supported-for-24-months 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Farewell to Consoles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting from the 2025.3 release, DataGrip and other JetBrains IDEs with database support will stop using the term query console. From now on, we’ll use query file – because consoles were essentially files all along, and it’s time the UI reflected that. We’ve made the workflow simpler, more discoverable, and more consistent. A bit of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/09/16/a-farewell-to-consoles/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline access to ISO-rating content changes with Verisk rating insights and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into how Verisk Rating Insights, powered by Amazon Bedrock, large language models (LLM), and Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), is transforming the way customers interact with and access ISO ERC changes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-access-to-iso-rating-content-changes-with-verisk-rating-insights-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unified multimodal access layer for Quora’s Poe using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center and Quora collaborated to build a unified wrapper API framework that dramatically accelerates the deployment of Amazon Bedrock FMs on Quora’s Poe system. We detail the technical architecture that bridges Poe’s event-driven ServerSentEvents protocol with Amazon Bedrock REST-based APIs, demonstrate how a template-based configuration system reduced deployment time from days to 15 minutes, and share implementation patterns for protocol translation, error handling, and multi-modal capabilities.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🚀 Introducing the New VS Code Extension for Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share that the Azure Databases extension for Visual Studio Code is now officially rebranded as the Azure Cosmos DB extension!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-the-new-vs-code-extension-for-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ: New AI Quotas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We hear you. And you’re right – the new quotas are a reduction from what you experienced. When we launched, we had little usage data for agentic experiences and no top‑up feature existed, so we set quotas much higher than the real cost of AI usage (tokens from providers) as a temporary measure. That felt […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/faq-new-ai-quota/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Computer Use tool (Preview) in Azure AI Foundry Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview We are excited to announce Computer Use
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/announcing-computer-use-tool-preview-in-azure-ai-foundry-agent-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-based T-SQL Refactoring: an automatic intelligent code optimization with Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Guest Post&amp;quot;]Saverio Lorenzini is a Senior Cloud Solution Architect with over 25 years of expertise in SQL Server. He specializes in migrations, performance tuning, and optimization. This fantastic work that shows a very practical use of AI to help
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/ai-based-t-sql-refactoring-an-automatic-intelligent-code-optimization-with-azure-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Stargate UK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI, NVIDIA, and Nscale launch Stargate UK, a sovereign AI infrastructure partnership delivering up to 50,000 GPUs and the UK’s largest supercomputer to power national AI innovation, public services, and economic growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-stargate-uk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating the &lt;CODE&gt;STATUS_&lt;WBR&gt;STACK_&lt;WBR&gt;BUFFER_&lt;WBR&gt;OVERRUN&lt;/CODE&gt; status code into customer-ready text</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer had a major client that was encountering this error message: INFOPATH.EXE The system detected an overrun of a stack-based buffer in this application. The overrun could potentially allow a malicious user to gain control of this application. (Note: Not actually
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250916-00/?p=111602 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Security: A Developer’s Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since its release by Anthropic in November 2024, Model Context Protocol (MCP) has gained massive adoption and is quickly becoming the connective tissue between AI agents and the tools, APIs, and data they act on. With just a few lines of configuration, an agent can search code, open tickets, query SaaS systems, or even deploy...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-security-explained/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the next development cycle and inviting you to join it. The Early Access Program (EAP) for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 is now open, offering an early look at the new features and improvements we’re working on. By evaluating new features and sharing constructive feedback, you help us provide you with powerful, reliable tooling […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/intellij-idea-2025-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards integration with GitHub Copilot (Private Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Several months ago, GitHub introduced the public preview of its Copilot coding agent, a powerful new capability that allows you to assign GitHub Issues directly to Copilot. From there, the agent works independently in the background, much like a human develo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-boards-integration-with-github-copilot-private-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 25 LTS and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Java release cadence means we get a new Java version every six months. Java 25 was released on September 16, 2025. At JetBrains, we are committed to supporting new technologies in IntelliJ IDEA and adding useful enhancements for both stable and preview features. In this blog post, we will give you an overview of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/09/java-25-lts-and-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting platform-specific .NET tools on old .NET SDKs: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at the advantages, trade-offs, and implications of the new platform-specific .NET tool feature added in .NET 10, and how to support old SDKs
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-8-supporting-platform-specific-dotnet-tools-on-old-sdks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying async void in C#: Why It&amp;#x27;s Dangerous and When It&amp;#x27;s Okay</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 09:42:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Async operations are an integral part of any application. In C#, mostly asynchronous methods return Task or Task, but there&#39;s also the odd case of async void. We know void is for synchronous operations, so why does C# even allow async void? I will dissect
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/demystifying-async-void-in-c-why-its-dangerous-and-when-its-okay/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building towards age prediction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI is building age prediction and parental controls in ChatGPT to create safer, age-appropriate experiences for teens while supporting families with new tools.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/building-towards-age-prediction 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teen safety, freedom, and privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore OpenAI’s approach to balancing teen safety, freedom, and privacy in AI use.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/teen-safety-freedom-and-privacy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
