<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 22:06:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (August 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 22:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.08.23 release, 2024-08-01 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout August. This month’s release includes several notable changes as well as bug fixes and documentation improvements. The most notable changes were: The shell function used to run vcpkg […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build powerful RAG pipelines with LlamaIndex and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 21:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use LlamaIndex with Amazon Bedrock to build robust and sophisticated RAG pipelines that unlock the full potential of LLMs for knowledge-intensive tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-powerful-rag-pipelines-with-llamaindex-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating prompts at scale with Prompt Management and Prompt Flows for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 20:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to implement an automated prompt evaluation system using Amazon Bedrock so you can streamline your prompt development process and improve the overall quality of your AI-generated content.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluating-prompts-at-scale-with-prompt-management-and-prompt-flows-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Vision Buddy – Empowering the Visually Impaired with AI and .NET Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 19:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re featuring a guest author, Jonathan David. He’s written an article we’re sharing below, focused on how to create Vision Buddy to empower visually impaired individuals using .NET and Semantic Kernel. We’ll turn it over to Jonathan to share more! Discover how this proof-of-concept leverages AI using .NET Semantic Kernel to provide visually impaired users […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-vision-buddy-empowering-the-visually-impaired-with-ai-and-net-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Vector Search with DiskANN Part 1: Full Space Search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vector Search with Azure Cosmos DB Azure Cosmos DB NoSQL features advanced vector indexing and search capabilities powered by DiskANN, a suite of highly scalable, accurate, and cost-effective approximate nearest neighbor (ANN) algorithms for low-latency vector search at any scale. Azure Cosmos DB features key capabilities important for building Modern AI applications: A mission critical […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-vector-search-with-diskann-part-1-full-space-search 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 16:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the September release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd). Including remote container build support, multiple hooks per event, deployment stack support, promoting resource group scoped deployments to the Beta feature stage, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-september-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing and Licensing Changes in RustRover and the Rust Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RustRover was initially released without support for web frontend technologies and databases. This decision was primarily based on EAP usage statistics and early research. It also allowed us to price RustRover more competitively. However, after the release, we received a large number of requests from our community asking us to support these technologies. Another piece […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/09/05/pricing-and-licensing-changes-in-rustrover-and-the-rust-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the .NET Migration Trenches - Turning Off the Lights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Posts in this series:IntroCatalogingEmpty ProxyShared LibraryOur First ControllerMigrating Initial Business LogicOur First ViewsSession StateHangfireAuthenticationMiddlewareTurning Off the LightsIn the last post, we looked at migrating our middleware, which we tackle in an as-needed basis. When a controller needs
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/tales-from-the-net-migration-trenches-turning-off-the-lights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Vulnerability scanning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Microsoft 365 Certification validates vulnerability scanning for your application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-vulnerability-scanning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel Trends 2024: The Latest Market Insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we move through 2024, Laravel continues to solidify its position as one of the most popular PHP frameworks, powering a multitude of web applications across the globe. In this blog post, we’ll analyze the recently published State of Laravel 2024 survey results, highlighting key takeaways and what they mean for developers, companies, and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/09/laravel-trends-2024-the-latest-market-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the image that came out horribly slanted: Taking the pitch into account</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Getting the pieces to line up.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240905-00/?p=110224 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily dock and float tool windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 10:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’re in the middle of a debugging session, attempting to chase down that one issue that is causing you trouble. In the heat of the moment, you grab a tool window and drag it out of its docked position – purely by accident. You didn’t mean to drag it, but sometimes when you move the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/easily-dock-and-float-tool-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! This edition is packed with the latest news on Java, Kotlin, and other influential technologies in the IT world. Don’t miss out on exploring IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2, staying up to date with Java 23, grabbing your tickets for KotlinConf 2025, and learning about the newest developments […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/java-annotated-monthly-september-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Testing ASP.NET Core Web API With JMeter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 05:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2024/05_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to load test an ASP.NET Core Web API with JMeter. So let’s get going. Introduction to JMeter Load testing is crucial for ensuring that web applications perform well under heavy traffic. JMeter is a popular and robust open-source tool for measuring the performance and functionality of web applications. When […] The post Load Testing ASP.NET Core Web API With JMeter appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Amazon SageMaker pipelines using AWS Controllers for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 22:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how ML engineers familiar with Jupyter notebooks and SageMaker environments can efficiently work with DevOps engineers familiar with Kubernetes and related tools to design and maintain an ML pipeline with the right infrastructure for their organization. This enables DevOps engineers to manage all the steps of the ML lifecycle with the same set of tools and environment they are used to.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-amazon-sagemaker-pipelines-using-aws-controllers-for-kubernetes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectively manage foundation models for generative AI applications with Amazon SageMaker Model Registry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 22:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the new features of Model Registry that streamline foundation model (FM) management: you can now register unzipped model artifacts and pass an End User License Agreement (EULA) acceptance flag without needing users to intervene.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/effectively-manage-foundation-models-for-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-sagemaker-model-registry/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an ecommerce product recommendation chatbot with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 21:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to build an ecommerce product recommendation chatbot using Amazon Bedrock Agents and foundation models (FMs) available in Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ecommerce-product-recommendation-chatbot-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Thomson Reuters Labs achieved AI/ML innovation at pace with AWS MLOps services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 20:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Thomson Reuters Labs (TR Labs) was able to develop an efficient, flexible, and powerful MLOps process by adopting a standardized MLOps framework that uses AWS SageMaker, SageMaker Experiments, SageMaker Model Registry, and SageMaker Pipelines. The goal being to accelerate how quickly teams can experiment and innovate using AI and machine learning (ML)—whether using natural language processing (NLP), generative AI, or other techniques. We discuss how this has helped decrease the time to market for fresh ideas and helped build a cost-efficient machine learning lifecycle.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover .NET at DEVintersection Las Vegas 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us at DEVintersection Las Vegas from September 9-12, 2024, for an in-person event featuring the latest in .NET and Azure technologies. Connect with experts, dive into new advancements, and get your questions answered by the people who build the tools you use every day.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/discover-dotnet-at-dev-intersection-las-vegas-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Bring your AI Copilots to the edge with Phi-3 and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 18:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bring your AI Copilots to the edge with Phi-3 and Semantic Kernel Today we’re featuring a guest author, Arafat Tehsin, who’s a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for AI. He’s written an article we’re sharing below, focused on how to Bring your AI Copilots to the edge with Phi-3 and Semantic Kernel. We’ll turn it […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-bring-your-ai-copilots-to-the-edge-with-phi-3-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSVC Backend Updates in Visual Studio 2022 version 17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 17.11 brings new optimizations, intrinsics, features, and improvements to the MSVC backend. Check out the highlights below: Performance improvements and additional functionality for all architectures: The SLP vectorizer can now recognize when vectors need to be permuted and when elements of a vector are defined by different operations. Updated corruption handling in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/msvc-backend-updates-in-visual-studio-2022-version-17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘JEP Explained’ – a series of interviews on Java 23 features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The release of Java 23 is around the corner, September 17, 2024, to be precise. What’s new in this Java version and why should you care about it? If you want to know more than just the syntax of these new features – the bigger picture, behind the scenes stories, and real life experiences of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/jep-explained-a-series-of-interviews-on-java-23-features/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporate GitHub Copilot into your daily flow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 16:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Streamlining Workflow with GitHub Copilot Have you ever received code completions that are too large to manage or ones that need slight tweaks, but you must accept all the code to make those changes? To address these pain points, in Visual Studio 17.11 we’ve introduced a new feature that allows you to refine your completions […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/incorporate-github-copilot-into-your-daily-flow 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Nested App Authentication: An improved authentication protocol for your Teams app</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 16:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Nested App Authentication simplifies the authentication process and enables single sign-on across supported Microsoft first-party applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-nested-app-authentication-an-improved-authentication-protocol-for-your-teams-app 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the image that came out horribly slanted: Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imperfect pitch.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240904-00/?p=110216 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine’s New Message Batching</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2024/04_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, did you know that JasperFx Software offers both consulting services and support plans for the “Critter Stack” tools? The new feature shown in this post was done at the behest of a JasperFx support customer. And of course, we’re also more than happy to help you with any kind of .NET backend development:) Wolverine‘s … Continue reading Wolverine’s New Message Batching →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/03/wolverines-new-message-batching/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your Cloud Development Skills at ‘Azure Developers – .NET Aspire Day 2024’</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us at the Azure Developers - .NET Aspire Day 2024, a virtual event happening on September 18, 2024
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/enhance-your-cloud-development-skills-at-azure-developers-dotnet-aspire-day-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI image description application with Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock and AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 21:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we delve into the process of building and deploying a sample application capable of generating multilingual descriptions for multiple images with a Streamlit UI, AWS Lambda powered with the Amazon Bedrock SDK, and AWS AppSync driven by the open source Generative AI CDK Constructs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-generative-ai-image-description-application-with-anthropics-claude-3-5-sonnet-on-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use LangChain with PySpark to process documents at massive scale with Amazon SageMaker Studio and Amazon EMR Serverless</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 19:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a scalable and efficient Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) system using the new EMR Serverless integration, Spark’s distributed processing, and an Amazon OpenSearch Service vector database powered by the LangChain orchestration framework. This solution enables you to process massive volumes of textual data, generate relevant embeddings, and store them in a powerful vector database for seamless retrieval and generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-langchain-with-pyspark-to-process-documents-at-massive-scale-with-amazon-sagemaker-studio-and-amazon-emr-serverless/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load optimization in Azure Fluid Relay using Managed Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 16:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how Azure Fluid Relay leverages Prometheus metrics in determining cluster load and can restrict the cluster from taking in additional traffic once it reaches certain thresholds.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/load-optimization-in-azure-fluid-relay-using-managed-prometheus 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | September 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? In C#, you can use a feature called caller info attributes to obtain information about the caller of a method. This can be incredibly useful for logging, debugging, or tracing. The attributes CallerMemberName, CallerFilePath, and CallerLineNumber provide information such as the name of the calling method, the path to the source file […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/03/dotinsights-september-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing your Visual Studio authentication experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The current cyber security climate demands that applications not only provide outstanding features but also prioritize the security of user data. Applications like Visual Studio rely on token-based authentication to access resources on your behalf. While effective, token-based authentication can be susceptible to attacks if not properly protected. Today, we are happy to announce that […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/enhancing-your-visual-studio-authentication-experience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Docker Desktop Enterprise Admin Features: MSI Installer and Login Enforcement Alternative</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to launch the general availability for two significant updates: the Docker Desktop MSI installer and a new sign-in enforcement alternative. These updates aim to streamline administration, improve security, and ensure users can take full advantage of Docker Business subscription features.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-msi-installer-login-enforcement-alternatives/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.34: MSI Installer GA, Upgraded Host Networking, and Powerful Enhancements for Boosted Productivity &amp; Administration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover Docker Desktop 4.34&#39;s enhancements that boost security, scalability, and productivity for developers. This release includes a readily available MSI installer for simpler Windows deployment, improved authentication processes, smart storage compaction for WSL2, and seamless NVIDIA AI Workbench integration for streamlined model training and local development.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-34/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did Windows 95 use blue screen error messages instead of hard error messages?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You may not able to get there from here.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240903-00/?p=110205 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in September</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 10:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new academic season brings fresh opportunities, and at JetBrains Academy, we’re ready to help you make the most of them. With a new compelling project, and fresh educational topics, this September is packed with everything you need to proceed on your coding journey. Let’s take a closer look at these updates. Python 🆕 Project: […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/09/03/jetbrains-academy-new-in-september/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with tar files in .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to create, extract, and list tar files using the built-in tar support introduced in .NET 7, and discuss some of the limitations
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/working-with-tar-files-in-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Calisthenics #4: Implementations explanations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 08:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The application of code rules is often conveyed as unidirectional and one-size-fits-all. In other words, when we learn to develop, we tend to read that there is only one way to produce quality code, and only one way to implement rules or patterns.With this series of articles, we aim
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/object-calisthenics-9-rules-clean-code-explanations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Calisthenics #3: Bringing Order to Chaos by Yoan</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 07:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Object Calisthenics, a set of programming exercises designed to improve code quality and object-oriented design, can be a powerful tool when refactoring existing codebases. To see how they work, Pierre and I decided to do the exercise on our own, without influencing each other.If you haven&#39;t read
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/object-calisthenics-9-rules-clean-code-implementation-yoan/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Calisthenics #2: Bringing Order to Chaos by Pierre</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 07:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Object Calisthenics, a set of programming exercises designed to improve code quality and object-oriented design, can be a powerful tool when refactoring existing codebases. To see how they work, Yoan and I decided to do the exercise on our own, without influencing each other.If you haven&#39;t read
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/object-calisthenics-9-rules-clean-code-implementation-pierre/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time is a Flat Circle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 17:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This conceptual idea is apparently known to philosophers as “Eternal return” or “eternal recurrence.” Funny story for me, I worked with a business analyst one time who was a former philosopher. To purposely antagonize him, I gave a super amateurish explanation of Descartes writings and how I thought they applied to engineering in principle where … Continue reading Time is a Flat Circle →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/02/time-is-a-flat-circle/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Proxy 3 Library for Dynamic Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 14:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Next Generation Polymorphism in C++
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/announcing-the-proxy-3-library-for-dynamic-polymorphism 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Co­Initialize­Security function demands an absolute security descriptor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Even though you usually have a self-relative one in hand.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240902-00/?p=110201 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us for JetBrains .NET Days Online 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 10:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains .NET Days Online 2024 is back for its sixth edition! This year’s Call for Speakers had so many great submissions from the .NET folks that we couldn’t fit all of the talks we wanted in just one day. Tune in live on September 25–26 for two days of demo-rich sessions and insightful discussions with .NET enthusiasts, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/02/dotnet-days-online-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StringValues in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 06:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When developing web applications using ASP.NET Core, we frequently encounter scenarios where we need to manage collections of strings. These collections can originate from various sources, such as HTTP headers, query strings, form data, and configuration settings. Efficiently handling these collections is crucial for maintaining the performance and scalability of our web applications. That’s where […] The post StringValues in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement ASP.NET Core OpenID Connect OAuth PAR client with Keycloak using .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 04:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2024/02_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to implement an ASP.NET Core application which uses OpenID Connect and OAuth PAR for authentication. The client application uses Keycloak as the identity provider. The Keycloak application is hosted in a docker container. The applications are run locally using .NET Aspire. This makes it really easy to develop using containers. Code: […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/09/02/implement-asp-net-core-openid-connect-oauth-par-client-with-keycloak-using-net-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I use for interacting with Git</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2024/01_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 19:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2024/01_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A friend of mine asked me at lunch this week what I was using to interact or manipulate Git, and I think he might have been disappointed with my lack of sophistication. At this point, I’m not willing to cast aspersions on whatever folks use as long as they’re being effective in their own environment, … Continue reading What I use for interacting with Git →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/01/what-i-use-for-interacting-with-git/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surviving and Thriving in Tech: Timeless Advice from Three Decades in Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2024/01_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_09_2024/01_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, a seasoned software engineer shares insights gained from three decades in the industry. He emphasizes continuous learning, staying marketable, developing soft skills, engaging in the local programming community, and working on personal projects. He also warns against companies that discourage community involvement and invites beginners to comment on future article topics.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/09/01/surviving-and-thriving-in-tech-timeless-advice-from-three-decades-in-software-engineering/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Biggest Fear In My Software Engineering Career – Dev Leader Weekly 59</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2024/31_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2024/31_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post My Biggest Fear In My Software Engineering Career – Dev Leader Weekly 59 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the importance of working in areas you&#39;re uncomfortable in to gain more experience. The post My Biggest Fear In My Software Engineering Career – Dev Leader Weekly 59 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/08/31/my-biggest-fear-in-my-software-engineering-career-dev-leader-weekly-59/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Event Sourcing for .NET Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2024/31_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_08_2024/31_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover event sourcing in .NET through a beginner&#39;s eyes. Explore core concepts, benefits, and real-world challenges.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/introduction-to-event-sourcing-for-net-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for prompt engineering with Meta Llama 3 for Text-to-SQL use cases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 20:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a solution that uses the vector engine ChromaDB and Meta Llama 3, a publicly available foundation model hosted on SageMaker JumpStart, for a Text-to-SQL use case. We shared a brief history of Meta Llama 3, best practices for prompt engineering with Meta Llama 3 models, and an architecture pattern using few-shot prompting and RAG to extract the relevant schemas stored as vectors in ChromaDB.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing advanced prompt engineering with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 20:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide insights and practical examples to help balance and optimize the prompt engineering workflow. We focus on advanced prompt techniques and best practices for the models provided in Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models from leading AI companies such as Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Mistral AI, Stability AI, and Amazon through a single API. With these prompting techniques, developers and researchers can harness the full capabilities of Amazon Bedrock, providing clear and concise communication while mitigating potential risks or undesirable outputs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure AI Inference Connector for Azure AI Studio Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 16:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction With the latest launch of the Azure AI Inference SDK for Azure AI Studio Models Catalog, we are happy to announce that we have also made available our dedicated Azure AI Inference Semantic Kernel Connector. This connector is specially designed on top of the published Azure AI Inference SDK and is targeted to allow easy access to a comprehensive suite of AI models in the Azure AI Model Catalog for inferencing for use in your Semantic Kernel projects.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Graph APIs for Teams webinar registration now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 14:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how to use Microsoft Graph APIs to programmatically schedule online meetings with the appropriate meeting options.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-graph-apis-for-teams-webinar-registration-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Windows kernel, what is a LUID, and what makes it loo-ey?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s a locally-unique ID, for a specific definition of &amp;quot;local&amp;quot;.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240830-00/?p=110198 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – August Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 13:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the new academic year approaching, the JetBrains Academy team is excited to bring you fresh updates! Discover new programs and courses designed to advance your tech career. And for computer science tutors we have curated a playlist of videos packed with fun teaching ideas. Dive in now!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/08/30/jetbrains-academy-july-digest-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing ASP.NET Core OData 9 Official Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that ASP.NET Core OData 9 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.AspNetCore.OData 9.0.0 The major highlight of this release is the update of the OData .NET dependencies to the 8.x major version. By updating the dependencies,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-asp-net-core-odata-9-official-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>使用 MSTest.Analyzers 增强您的测试体验</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 06:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_08_2024/30_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Jakub Jareš的Supercharge your testing experience with MSTest.Analyzers – .NET Blog (microsoft.com) MSTest 附带一组分析器，用于检查您的测试代码并指出常见的错误和陷阱。这些错误可能很微妙，并导致测试框架完全忽略您的测试。 我们从 3.2.0 版本就开始提供这些分析器了，但在最新的 3.5.1 版本中，我们添加了一些我们认为您不应错过的分析器。 遗漏的测试 一个常见问题是当您忘记在类上添加 [TestClass] 时。MSTest 将无法知道类中有测试，也不会运行它们： public class MyTests { [TestMethod] public async Task TestMethod1() { Assert.Fail(); } } 如果没有 MSTest.Analyzers，此代码在构建时不会出现警告或信息提示。运行测试时也不会出现测试失败的情况。由于类上没有 [TestClass] 属性，MSTest 会出于性能原因跳过整个类，并且您的测试将永远不会被找到。 但是使用分析器时您会在构建过程中收到一条信息提示： 我们建议将此信息提示升级为警告，甚至是构建错误。可以通过在 .editorconfig 文件中添加以下这行代码来实现 [*.cs] # MSTEST0030: Type containing &#39;[TestMethod]&#39; should be marked with &#39;[TestClass]&#39; dotnet_diagnostic.MSTEST0030.severity = warning 为什么默认情况下这不是警告？ 您可能会问为什么 MSTEST0030 默认是一条信息提示而不是默认的警告。原因是我们不能在 MSTest v3 中引入重大变更，而上述代码是一个常见的模式，用于从基类重用测试。 public class MyTestsBase { [TestMethod] public async Task CommonTestMethod() { } } [TestClass] public class MyTests : MyTestsBase { [TestMethod] public async Task TestMethod1() { Assert.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
