<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 22:24:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are Applied Skills Replacing Microsoft Certifications?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 22:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Learn Applied Skills credentials are not replacing Microsoft Certifications. Microsoft is expanding their credentialing portfolio to cater better to learners and customers, allowing validation of specific skill sets with this new offering. Microsoft Certifications are continuing to be role-based, and still assess a broad range of skills essential for success in key roles within […] The article Are Applied Skills Replacing Microsoft Certifications? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step by Step guide to develop AI Multi-Agent system using Microsoft Semantic Kernel and GPT-4o</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we want to highlight a recent Medium article published here: Step by Step guide to develop AI Multi-Agent system using Microsoft Semantic Kernel and GPT-4o | by Akshay Kokane | Jun, 2024 | Medium We’ve included a few excerpts below,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/step-by-step-guide-to-develop-ai-multi-agent-system-using-microsoft-semantic-kernel-and-gpt-4o 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Twilio used Amazon SageMaker MLOps pipelines with PrestoDB to enable frequent model retraining and optimized batch transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Shamik Ray, Srivyshnav K S, Jagmohan Dhiman and Soumya Kundu from Twilio. Today’s leading companies trust Twilio’s Customer Engagement Platform (CEP) to build direct, personalized relationships with their customers everywhere in the world. Twilio enables companies to use communications and data to add intelligence and security to every step of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-twilio-used-amazon-sagemaker-mlops-pipelines-with-prestodb-to-enable-frequent-model-retraining-and-optimized-batch-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactor your code with default lambda parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore opportunities to refactor your C# code with default lambda parameters, a new feature in C# 12.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/refactor-your-code-with-default-lambda-parameters 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Teams webinar integration with HubSpot marketing automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn why the integration of HubSpot with Microsoft Teams represents a significant new advancement for Teams webinar customers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-teams-webinar-integration-with-hubspot-marketing-automation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate deep learning training and simplify orchestration with AWS Trainium and AWS Batch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In large language model (LLM) training, effective orchestration and compute resource management poses a significant challenge. Automation of resource provisioning, scaling, and workflow management is vital for optimizing resource usage and streamlining complex workflows, thereby achieving efficient deep learning training processes. Simplified orchestration enables researchers and practitioners to focus more on model experimentation, hyperparameter tuning, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-deep-learning-training-and-simplify-orchestration-with-aws-trainium-and-aws-batch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosch widely adopts Visual Studio for their C&#43;&#43; remote Linux projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Bosch security camera team was seeking a unified development setup for their team and recently re-evaluated Visual Studio as a solution for their C++ projects and remote Linux development needs. Their experience with Visual Studio 2022 featured notable improvements relevant to their workflows such as seamless GDB integration and CMake/WSL integrations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/bosch-widely-adopts-visual-studio-for-their-c-remote-linux-projects 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 EAP 3: Improved GDB Performance and Enhancements for Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 15:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.2 EAP build (242.16677.29) is now out! It’s available from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 EAP Here are the highlights: The full release notes are available here. Find out more about our plans for this release in the CLion 2024.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/06/2024-2-eap-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I view the list of symbols available in a library?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A tool hiding inside another tool.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240617-00/?p=109905 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venerable Used Datalore to Reduce Eight-Hour Excel Analysis to Two Minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 09:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Caught in a spiderweb of spreadsheets Like many financial organizations, Venerable faced hurdles due to its dependence on Excel. Changes in a single spreadsheet often triggered a chain reaction of adjustments across countless others, leading to mistakes and a lot of manual work. This setup resulted in a time-consuming, error-prone process that was amplified when […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/06/17/venerable-used-datalore-to-reduce-eight-hour-excel-analysis-to-two-minutes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flattening Nested Collections in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 05:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore flattening nested collections in C#. We’ll examine different approaches for handling from simple to complex data structures, offering practical guidance to effectively flatten nested collections within our C# applications. Let’s get started. Importance of Flattening Nested Collections Nested collections can introduce unnecessary complexity, making it challenging to work with the […] The post Flattening Nested Collections in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Introducing FrozenSet in .NET 8: Benefits and Benchmark PerformanceCollection Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2024/16_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2024/16_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET version 8 introduced the FrozenSet type, offering immutable and hashable set collection with benefits including improved performance, memory efficiency, and thread safety. Benchmarks show comparable performance to List, outperforming HashSet and ImmutableHashSet. However, it is slightly slower than the latter in lookups. FrozenSet offers significant advantages for concurrent applications and memory optimization.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/16/collection-performance-introducing-frozenset-in-net-8-benefits-and-benchmark-performancecollection-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Do’s and Don’ts For Developers  – Dev Leader Weekly 48</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post AI Do’s and Don’ts For Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 48 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss ways you can leverage AI as a developer and things to avoid too! The post AI Do’s and Don’ts For Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 48 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/06/15/ai-dos-and-donts-for-developers-dev-leader-weekly-48/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Properly Set Connection Strings in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 06:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will delve into connection strings providing insights into their functionality, and best practices for safeguarding sensitive data. Let’s dive in! Purpose and Components of Connection Strings Connection strings are the backbone of a connection between our application and a database, encapsulating important information such as server address, database name, and authentication […] The post How to Properly Set Connection Strings in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Transaction Scripts to Domain Models: A Refactoring Journey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_06_2024/15_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transaction Scripts organizes business logic by procedures where each procedure handles a single request from the presentation.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/from-transaction-scripts-to-domain-models-a-refactoring-journey 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 EAP 3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 20:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest installment in the Rider 2024.2 Early Access Program has just been released! Let’s take a look at the changes. Bundled .NET Watch Run Configuration plugin dotnet-watch is a .NET global tool specifically designed to monitor file changes during development and promptly reload or restart the target command. One of the standout features of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/14/rider-2024-2-eap-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lock-free reference-counting a TLS slot using atomics, part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Keeping track of two things at once.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240614-00/?p=109902 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugger Upskill: Debug Without Breakpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 11:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a typical debugging scenario, you would set breakpoints to tell the debugger when to suspend your program. A breakpoint usually corresponds to the moment that marks the starting point for further investigation. Deciding where to set a breakpoint can be challenging. There might be situations where the exact line is unclear, or you might […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/debugger-upskill-debug-without-breakpoints/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C#12新功能合集三：使用任意类型别名重构C#代码</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 08:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译于David Pine的这篇文章: Refactor your code using alias any type。 这篇文章是四篇系列文章中的第三篇，主要探讨C# 12的各种功能。在这篇文章中，我们将深入探讨“别名任何类型”功能，该功能允许您使用 using 指令为任何类型创建别名。这个系列已经初具规模： 使用主构造函数重构 C# 代码 使用集合表达式重构 C# 代码 使用任意类型别名重构 C# 代码（本篇文章） 重构 C# 代码以使用默认 lambda 参数 所有这些功能都将继续我们的旅程，使我们的代码更具可读性和可维护性，这些被认为是开发人员应该知道的“日常 C#”功能。让我们深入了解吧！ 别名任意类型*️⃣ C# 12 引入了使用 using 指令为任意类型添加别名的功能。此功能允许您指定映射到其他类型的别名。这包括元组类型、指针类型、数组类型，甚至非开放泛型类型，所有这些类型都可以在您的代码中使用。此功能在以下场景特别有用： 当使用长或复杂的类型名称时。 当消除类型歧义并解决潜在的命名冲突时。 当定义要在程序集中共享的值元组类型时。 当希望通过使用更具描述性的名称来增加代码的清晰度时。 官方 C# 文档提供了很多有关如何使用此功能的示例，但我并不想在此重复这些示例，而是决定编写一个演示应用程序来示范该功能的各个方面。 可空引用类型 此功能支持大多数类型，但可空引用类型除外。也就是说，您无法为可空引用类型设置别名， C# 编译器会报告错误 CS9132：使用的别名不能是可空引用类型。以下内容摘自功能说明，以帮助澄清这一点： // This is not legal.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/c12%e6%96%b0%e5%8a%9f%e8%83%bd%e5%90%88%e9%9b%86%e4%b8%89%ef%bc%9a%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8%e4%bb%bb%e6%84%8f%e7%b1%bb%e5%9e%8b%e7%9a%84%e5%88%ab%e5%90%8d%e9%87%8d%e6%9e%84c%e4%bb%a3%e7%a0%81 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Boilerplate: An Inside Look Into Our .Net Clean Architecture Repo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will take an inner look at the clean architecture boilerplate and how it helps kickstart our projects rapidly.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/next-level-clean-architecture-boilerplate 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Differences Between Collections With the LINQ Except Method in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 06:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_06_2024/14_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with collections in C#, we sometimes need to manipulate them by performing operations such as comparisons, mergers, or finding set differences between them. The LINQ Except method comes in handy when we want to find the set difference between two sequences, as it returns a new sequence containing elements in the first sequence […] The post Find Differences Between Collections With the LINQ Except Method in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye, long procedural code! Fix it with workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 20:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve all written long procedural code with many logic branches that must handle failures because it tries to execute a long business process with many actions. Better alternatives exist than writing a rat’s nest of complex procedural code. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video… Read More »Goodbye, long procedural code! Fix it with workflows The post Goodbye, long procedural code!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the public preview of the Microsoft AI Chat Protocol library for JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 19:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post details the public preview release of the AI Chat Protocol library, allowing users to build robust, streamed AI frontends in JavaScript.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/announcing-the-public-preview-of-the-microsoft-ai-chat-protocol-library-for-javascript 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The present and future of Copilot extensibility: Top 10 takeaways from Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 18:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dive into our key announcements from Build to discover new pathways to extend, customize, and amplify Copilot capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/the-present-and-future-of-copilot-extensibility-top-10-takeaways-from-build-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Generative AI apps with .NET 8 and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 18:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today’s we’d like to share a blog post from two members of the .NET team, Jordan Matthiesen and Luis Quintanilla, focused on Building Generative AI apps with .NET 8 – .NET Blog (microsoft.com). The future of AI is here, and .NET is ready for it!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/building-generative-ai-apps-with-net-8-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC vs. Docker: Which One Should You Use?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 18:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the key differences between Docker and LXC, including use cases and technical requirements, to determine which containerization technology best suits your project needs.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/lxc-vs-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 5: Jakarta Data Support, Extended JPA Support, Streamlined Cron Expressions Handling, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 17:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 5 is now available! It brings a range of exciting updates to the IDE’s integrations with popular frameworks such as Spring, Quarkus, and Micronaut, along with Jakarta Data specification support, and more. To try them out today, download the IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 5 build from our website, update directly from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PostgreSQL with .NET and Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Getting started with .NET and PostgreSQL, and using Entra ID to secure your app.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-postgre-sql-with-dotnet-and-entra-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lock-free reference-counting a TLS slot using atomics, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Getting it is easy. Getting rid of it is hard.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240613-00/?p=109892 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between Span and Memory in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 05:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll briefly explain the Span and Memory .NET types and mention their primary usage. Furthermore, we will explore the differences between Span and Memory in C# in depth and conclude with some general tips on when to use one type over another. What Is Span? The Span type is a value type […] The post Differences Between Span and Memory in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “Critter Stack” Just Leveled Up on Modular Monolith Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 02:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2024/13_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The goal for the “Critter Stack” tools is to be the absolute best set of tools for building server side .NET applications, and especially for any usage of Event Driven Architecture approaches. To go even farther, I would like there to be a day where organizations purposely choose the .NET ecosystem just because of the … Continue reading The “Critter Stack” Just Leveled Up on Modular Monolith Support →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI On Your Data with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 18:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, everyone! In the fast-paced world of technology, using artificial intelligence to get more out of your data is becoming essential. Azure OpenAI on Your Data is a feature that helps businesses do just that. It combines the advanced AI models from OpenAI with the strong data management tools of Azure,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/azure-openai-on-your-data-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The .NET MAUI Extension for Visual Studio Code is now Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Start developing .NET MAUI apps with the GA Visual Studio Code extension today!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/the-dotnet-maui-extension-for-visual-studio-code-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft.AspNetCore.OData 9 Preview Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 17:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the forthcoming major release of Microsoft.AspNetCore.OData, scheduled for June. In preparation for this significant update, we have made preview versions of the library available to gather early feedback from our community. The following preview release is now available on NuGet: Microsoft.AspNetCore.OData 9.0.0-preview.2 Key Update The primary change in this release is the update of the OData core libraries dependencies to the recently released OData Core 8.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a custom UI for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 16:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q is a new generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered assistant designed for work that can be tailored to your business. Amazon Q can help you get fast, relevant answers to pressing questions, solve problems, generate content, and take actions using the data and expertise found in your company’s information repositories and enterprise systems. When you […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-custom-ui-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 16:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-driven business landscape, the ability to efficiently extract and process information from a wide range of documents is crucial for informed decision-making and maintaining a competitive edge. However, traditional document processing workflows often involve complex and time-consuming manual tasks, hindering productivity and scalability. In this post, we discuss an approach that uses the […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scalable-intelligent-document-processing-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces Free Writing Assistance, Powered by JetBrains AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 16:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing assistance powered by JetBrains AI is now included in YouTrack 2024.2. All cloud and server customers with active subscriptions can use it for free to automatically check grammar, spelling, and punctuation and add precision and flair to their writing. We’ve also added improvements based on the most popular requests from teams using various parts […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/06/youtrack-introduces-free-writing-assistance-powered-by-jetbrains-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use weather data to improve forecasts with Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 15:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Photo by Zbynek Burival on Unsplash Time series forecasting is a specific machine learning (ML) discipline that enables organizations to make informed planning decisions. The main idea is to supply historic data to an ML algorithm that can identify patterns from the past and then use those patterns to estimate likely values about unseen periods […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-weather-data-to-improve-forecasts-with-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lock-free reference-counting a TLS slot using atomics, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            First, we do it with locks.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240612-00/?p=109887 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Education: Tailoring Tools and Techniques for Rust</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disclaimer: This article was created using JetBrains Grazie, an AI-based writing and communication companion. With its help, the core topics of this rich and nuanced livestream were conveniently distilled into a compact blog post format. In the world of programming languages, the ability to learn and understand a language is a critical factor for developers. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/06/12/programming-education-tailoring-tools-and-techniques-for-rust/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2024.2 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 12:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post marks the start of the Early Access Program for DataSpell 2024.2. The DataSpell 2024.2 EAP 1 build is now accessible for download, providing an early glimpse into the exciting updates on the horizon.You can download the new version from our website, update directly from inside the IDE or via the free Toolbox […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2024/06/2024-2-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch up on the latest Git tooling features in 17.10 GA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 07:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We believe that boosting the productivity of your development and team collaboration helps you produce better software solutions. That’s why the Visual Studio Version Control team has delivered new features, streamlining your inner loop and code review experiences. You’ll get AI support writing commit messages,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/catch-up-on-the-latest-git-tooling-features-in-17-10-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Custom Header Parameter to All API Endpoints in Swagger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 05:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Within the .NET ecosystem, Swagger stands out as an essential tool, enabling developers to produce interactive and comprehensive API documentation. Header parameters play a crucial role in carrying important metadata in HTTP requests. Specifically, this metadata includes information like authentication tokens and custom configurations, shaping how clients and services interact. In this article, we explore […] The post Adding a Custom Header Parameter to All API Endpoints in Swagger appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Unit Testable Code with Maintainable Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2024/12_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing maintainable code should be a goal in most software engineering projects. Although definitions and especially hard measurements of…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/comparing-unit-testable-code-with-maintainable-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Course Registration Project with Azure SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 20:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This semester long project was completed by Master’s students at Cornell University with mentorship from the Azure SQL database product team at Microsoft. Project Mission The purpose of this project is to design a high-fidelity university course registration system utilizing Microsoft Azure cloud services.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/course-registration-project-with-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2022 – 17.10 Performance Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 19:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the latest update of Visual Studio 2022, which brings you a range of performance enhancements across various areas of the IDE. In this blog post, we will highlight some of the most notable improvements that you can experience in version 17.10,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2022-17-10-performance-enhancements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 17:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month, we are releasing fixes that impact our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. The following version of the product has been patched. Azure DevOps Server 2022.1 Patch 4 If you have Azure DevOps Server 2022.1, you should install Azure DevOps Server 2022.1 Patch 4.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/june-patches-for-azure-devops-server-3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build engaging apps for Microsoft Teams meetings with new content sharing capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 17:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce new features that will make it easy for you to enable delightful collaboration experiences for your Microsoft Teams app&#39;s users with minimal code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-engaging-apps-for-microsoft-teams-meetings-with-new-content-sharing-capabilities 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Generative AI apps with .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn the latest news and announcements about the state of generative AI development with .NET 8.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/build-gen-ai-with-dotnet-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining software development with the Amazon Q Developer Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 16:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Developer uses generative artificial intelligence (AI) to deliver state-of-the-art accuracy for all developers, taking first place on the leaderboard for SWE-bench, a dataset that tests a system’s ability to automatically resolve GitHub issues. This post describes how to get started with the software development agent, gives an overview of how the agent works, and discusses its performance on public benchmarks. We also delve into the process of getting started with the Amazon Q Developer Agent and give an overview of the underlying mechanisms that make it a state-of-the-art feature development agent.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI Applications with ease using Semantic Kernel and .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 16:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, everyone! Today, we are featuring a guest author from another team at Microsoft on our blog. Today’s topic will explore how we can build AI applications with ease using the Semantic Kernel and .NET Aspire. So, if you’re excited about creating intelligent,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/build-ai-applications-with-ease-using-semantic-kernel-and-net-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next steps: how to rapidly reach the potential of AUKUS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “… the story of AI’s industrialisation is intimately tied to Cloud infrastructure …”1 The United States (US) has long recognised the imperative to apply innovative commercial technologies like artificial intelligence (AI) to national security.2 Transformative developments of AI will impact many areas of society,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/next-steps-how-to-rapidly-reach-the-potential-of-aukus 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started quickly with AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia using AWS Neuron DLAMI and AWS Neuron DLC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with the AWS Neuron 2.18 release, you can now launch Neuron DLAMIs (AWS Deep Learning AMIs) and Neuron DLCs (AWS Deep Learning Containers) with the latest released Neuron packages on the same day as the Neuron SDK release. When a Neuron SDK is released, you’ll now be notified of the support for Neuron DLAMIs […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-started-quickly-with-aws-trainium-and-aws-inferentia-using-aws-neuron-dlami-and-aws-neuron-dlc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sprinklr improves performance by 20% and reduces cost by 25% for machine learning inference on AWS Graviton3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with Ratnesh Jamidar and Vinayak Trivedi from Sprinklr. Sprinklr’s mission is to unify silos, technology, and teams across large, complex companies. To achieve this, we provide four product suites, Sprinklr Service, Sprinklr Insights, Sprinklr Marketing, and Sprinklr Social, as well as several self-serve offerings. Each of these products are […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/sprinklr-improves-performance-by-20-and-reduces-cost-by-25-for-machine-learning-inference-on-aws-graviton3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Wiz is empowering organizations to remediate security risks faster with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wiz is a cloud security platform that enables organizations to secure everything they build and run in the cloud by rapidly identifying and removing critical risks. Over 40% of the Fortune 100 trust Wiz’s purpose-built cloud security platform to gain full-stack visibility, accurate risk prioritization, and enhanced business agility. Organizations can connect Wiz in minutes […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-wiz-is-empowering-organizations-to-remediate-security-risks-faster-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin story of the Windows 3D Pipes screen saver</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking for a place to show off.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240611-00/?p=109881 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.31: Air-Gapped Containers, Accelerated Builds, and Beta Releases of Docker Desktop on Windows on Arm, Compose File Viewer, and GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 13:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Docker Desktop 4.31 release offers new features to empower developers, including: air-gapped containers, accelerated builds, and beta releases of Docker Desktop on Windows on Arm (WoA) and Compose File Viewer.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-31/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Launches 2024 State of Application Development Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 13:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Docker 2024 State of Application Development Report offers insight into developers&#39; processes and tools, industry trends, Docker usage, and more.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-2024-state-of-application-development-report/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.36 Is Here, With Improved Syntax Highlighting for PHP, C/C&#43;&#43;, and Svelte, Better Remote Development With SSH, and Other Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.36 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this latest version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at this update’s highlights. Download Fleet 1.36 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/06/fleet-1-36-is-here-with-improved-syntax-highlighting-for-php-c-c-and-svelte-better-remote-development-with-ssh-and-other-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape The Future Of Embedded Development with CLion!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we believe in constantly evolving to meet the needs of our users. Embedded development is no exception, and we are looking for your feedback. Your experience and insights are essential to the continuous improvement of CLion, a JetBrains IDE. That’s why we’d like to invite you to participate in our survey, designed to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/06/shape-the-future-of-embedded-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stopping Using Exception Use Result Monad Instead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 10:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Error handling is an inevitable part of software development. Traditionally, exceptions are the primary method for signaling that something has gone awry. However, the exception mechanism is fraught with issues: unpredictable control flow, performance bottlenecks, and challenges in debugging. Imagine a world where error handling is graceful, predictable, and
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/stopping_using_exception_use_monad/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing collection expressions in C#12: Behind the scenes of collection expressions - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I introduce C#12 collection expressions, discuss the benefits of the unified syntax for refactoring, and show how to use the spread element
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/behind-the-scenes-of-collection-expressions-part-1-introducing-collection-expressions-in-csharp12/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sonar Webinar, end to end security of a web application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 06:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I did a Webinar on application security with Denis Troller and Sonar. I would like to thank Sonar for this opportunity, I really enjoyed it and found doing this together with you really professional, pleasant and fun to do. Here’s the recording: Link to the Sonar Q&amp;amp;A: https://community.sonarsource.com/t/webinar-end-to-end-security-in-a-web-application/115405 Link to the repository: https://github.com/damienbod/EndToEndSecurity
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/06/11/sonar-webinar-end-to-end-security-of-a-web-application/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weak Events in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 06:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We use weak events in C# to avoid memory leaks in event-based applications. Let’s learn more about weak events, why they’re needed, and how to implement them. Let’s get started. What Are Strong and Weak Events? A strong event is the default implementation of an event in C#. It enables an object to notify other […] The post Weak Events in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Build 2024：引领AI与云原生应用开发的新篇章</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 01:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自.NET Team的.NET Announcements and Updates from Microsoft Build 2024 – .NET Blog。 在 Microsoft Build 2024 上，我们很高兴推出一系列旨在使 .NET 开发更快、更容易的新功能和工具。 探索 Microsoft Build 2024 上的 .NET 会议，了解新功能的实际效果，或者通过下载 .NET 9 Preview 4 亲自尝试。 以下是我们的更新和公告： 人工智能：用于构建AI应用的端到端方案、拥抱AI生态、与云服务深度集成。 .NET Aspire：用于构建云原生分布式应用程序，今天发布。 C# 13：加强了许多深受喜爱的 C# 功能，使它们更适合您。 性能：通过关键基准测试减少内存和执行时间。 .NET 库和框架的加强，包括 ASP.NET Core、Blazor、.NET MAUI 等。 让我们从如何使用 .NET 为开发人员改进 AI 开发开始。 .NET 与人工智能 .NET 为您提供了使用 AI 创建功能强大的应用程序的工具。您可以使用Semantic Kernel来编排 AI 插件，从而将 AI 功能无缝集成到您的应用程序中。您可以使用最先进的库（例如 OpenAI、Qdrant 和 Milvus）来增强应用程序的功能。您还可以使用 .NET Aspire 将应用程序部署到云端，确保最佳性能和可扩展性。 让我们更深入地了解这些内容。 AI基础知识 我们引入了一种新的 Tensor
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneak Peek of Strong Typed Identifiers in Marten</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 20:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you really need to have strong typed identifier support in Marten right now, here’s the long standing workaround. Some kind of support for “strong typed identifiers” has long been a feature request for Marten from our community. I’ve even been told by a few folks that they wouldn’t consider using Marten until it did … Continue reading Sneak Peek of Strong Typed Identifiers in Marten →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Performance of TLS 1.3 in Java JDK 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 20:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transport Layer Security (TLS) 1.3 is the latest version of the TLS protocol, built on the foundation of its predecessors, with significant improvements in terms of security, performance, and simplicity. TLS 1.3 is widely considered one of the most secure network protocols currently available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/improved-performance-of-tls-1-3-in-java-jdk-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Years Since Kubernetes Launched at DockerCon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 17:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reflecting on the monumental announcement of Kubernetes at DockerCon on June 10th, 2014, Docker CEO Scott Johnston celebrates its transformative impact on container orchestration and modern application development over the past decade, highlighting Docker&#39;s role in this pivotal industry shift.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/10-years-since-kubernetes-launched-at-dockercon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with UI testing .NET MAUI apps using Appium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A proven way to test your (mobile) apps is through UI testing. In this post we will learn how to get setup with UI testing for .NET MAUI apps using Appium.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-maui-ui-testing-appium 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosch widely adopts Visual Studio 2022 after experiencing performance improvements for C&#43;&#43; Linux cross-compilation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The Bosch security camera team had been evaluating Visual Studio as a unified development setup for their team’s C++ development, which includes remote Linux C++ development for cross-compiling. While evaluating Visual Studio 2022, the team had a positive experience of using Visual Studio for their C++ development due to notable improvements over the years.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/bosch-widely-adopts-visual-studio-2022-after-experiencing-performance-improvements-for-c-linux-cross-compilation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code generation using Code Llama 70B and Mixtral 8x7B on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 14:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of machine learning and artificial intelligence (AI), large language models (LLMs) have emerged as powerful tools for a wide range of natural language processing (NLP) tasks, including code generation. Among these cutting-edge models, Code Llama 70B stands out as a true heavyweight, boasting an impressive 70 billion parameters. Developed by Meta […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/code-generation-using-code-llama-70b-and-mixtral-8x7b-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Azure Cosmos DB: A Comprehensive Guide from Prototype to Production</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 14:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past couple of years, we have collaborated with numerous customers to tackle performance, scaling, and cost issues that arise when transitioning their Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL API based applications to production. In many cases, these challenges stem from a lack of understanding of key Azure Cosmos DB concepts.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/mastering-azure-cosmos-db-a-comprehensive-guide-from-prototype-to-production 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I get the name of a SID, and what does it mean when the conversion fails?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most places will do it for you, or at least try.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240610-00/?p=109872 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing the Renovate configuration across multiple projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Renovate is a tool that helps you to keep your dependencies up-to-date. You can configure Renovate using a configuration file at the root of the repository. In this post, I describe how to share the Renovate configuration across multiple projects. Developers don&#39;t like to maintain the same configuration in multiple repositories. It&#39;s error-prone and time-consuming. By sharing the configuration, you can…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/sharing-the-renovate-configuration-across-multiple-projects.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allow your AI Agent to call Microsoft Graph APIs securely with Microsoft Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover an exciting new plugin in the Chat Copilot sample app from the Semantic Kernel team. This plugin lets an AI Agent call Microsoft Graph APIs secured by Microsoft Entra ID using the On-Behalf-Of (OBO) flow.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/ai-agent-graph-api 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test &amp; Feedback Extension in Manifest V3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 06:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce a new update to the Azure DevOps Test and Feedback extension! This update brings essential implementation changes, upgrading from manifest version 2 to version 3. Following Google’s announcement of their Manifest V2 deprecation schedule, we have been actively working on our implementation of Manifest V3.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/test-feedback-extension-v3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrying Failed HttpClient Requests in .NET Using Polly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 02:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore the different approaches to retrying failed HttpClient requests using Polly. We will also discuss the advantages and disadvantages of each retry strategy, from simplest to most sophisticated. Let’s start. Reasons for HttpClient Request Failures We like to think of the Internet as a reliable data transmission medium. Sadly, this […] The post Retrying Failed HttpClient Requests in .NET Using Polly appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
