<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB EF Core Provider: What’s New?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest updates to the MongoDB EF Core Provider brings updates to change tracking, index creation, complex queries, and transactions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mongodb-ef-core-provider-whats-new 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 EAP 5: Support for the Call Hierarchy in CLion Nova and the New Project Status Widget</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new CLion 2024.3 EAP build, 243.20847.43, is out. You can download it for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 EAP This build introduces two major features: support for function call hierarchy in CLion Nova and a new project status […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/10/clion-2024-3-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Gap Between the Classic and New UIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 15:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Any significant update to the UI and UX of a professional tool is likely to pose challenges for its users. We recognize that the new UI of JetBrains IDEs represents a major change and understand how unsettling it can be when the software you rely on for productivity is significantly reworked. However, in order for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/bridging-the-gap-between-the-classic-and-new-uis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to Azure Cosmos DB’s Portal Networking Settings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 14:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to share with you an update to the Azure Cosmos DB networking configuration options within the Azure Portal. This update introduces a split in the IP address list, now presented as two distinct categories: user IP addresses and Portal Middleware IPs. Managing IP access control policies is essential for maintaining a secure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/updates-to-azure-cosmos-dbs-portal-networking-settings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Docker AI Tools for Devs to Provide Context for Better Code Fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to map your codebase in order to provide context for creating better AI-generated code fixes.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/using-docker-ai-tools-for-devs-to-provide-context-for-better-code-fixes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 6: Updated Structure Tool Window, Streamlined GraalVM Native Image Debugging, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP build is here, bringing new features and improvements for you to explore! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 6 In this update, we’ve […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement security headers for an ASP.NET Core API supporting OpenAPI Swagger UI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 07:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article shows how to implement security headers for an application supporting an API and a swagger UI created from a open API in .NET 9. The security headers are implemented using the NetEscapades.AspNetCore.SecurityHeaders Nuget packages from Andrew Lock. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/WebApiOpenApi Deploying a web application which supports both an API and a UI have different […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/10/21/implement-security-headers-for-an-api-supporting-openapi-swagger-ui/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entity Framework Core Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 04:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core (EF Core) is an object-relational mapper (ORM), enabling us to work with a database using .NET objects, eliminating much of the data-access code we usually need to write. EF Core supports many databases, including SQL Server, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and more, making it highly versatile. While EF Core provides many conveniences, following […] The post Entity Framework Core Best Practices appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing IBM Granite AI Models Now Available on Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IBM&#39;s Granite AI models, optimized for business applications, are now available on Docker Hub, making it easier for developers to deploy, scale, and customize AI-powered apps.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-ibm-granite-ai-models-now-available-on-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combo HTTP Endpoint and Message Handler with Wolverine 3.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 01:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Wolverine 3.0 last week, we snuck in a small feature at the last minute that was a request from a JasperFx Software customer. Specifically, they had a couple instances of a logical message type that needed to be handled both from Wolverine’s Rabbit MQ message transport, and also from the request … Continue reading Combo HTTP Endpoint and Message Handler with Wolverine 3.0 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Dictionary Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2024/20_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2024/20_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, offering enhanced functionality for IDictionary collection types. The provided extension methods improve performance and reliability in projects. Community involvement and feedback are encouraged for further enhancements. Detailed benchmark results are available on GitHub. Contact dotnetdave@live.com for contributions and inquiries.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/20/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-dictionary-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Lessons From Building a SaaS – Dev Leader Weekly 66</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_10_2024/19_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_10_2024/19_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post 4 Lessons From Building a SaaS – Dev Leader Weekly 66 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the lessons I&#39;ve learned while building a SaaS The post 4 Lessons From Building a SaaS – Dev Leader Weekly 66 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/10/19/4-lessons-from-building-a-saas-dev-leader-weekly-66/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Details for ASP.NET Core APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_10_2024/19_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_10_2024/19_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how to leverage Problem Details in ASP.NET Core to create consistent, informative API error responses that enhance developer experience and comply with RFC 9457. This comprehensive guide explores the latest features in .NET 8 and 9, demonstrating how to implement custom exception handlers, utilize IProblemDetailsService, and apply best practices for robust error handling in your APIs.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/problem-details-for-aspnetcore-apis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train, optimize, and deploy models on edge devices using Amazon SageMaker and Qualcomm AI Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_10_2024/18_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 20:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_10_2024/18_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we introduce an innovative solution for end-to-end model customization and deployment at the edge using Amazon SageMaker and Qualcomm AI Hub.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/train-optimize-and-deploy-models-on-edge-devices-using-amazon-sagemaker-and-qualcomm-ai-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Conf 2024 Student Zone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_10_2024/18_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_10_2024/18_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET Conf Student Zone is a beginner-friendly, virtual event where experts will teach you how to build amazing projects - all using C# and .NET!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnetconf-2024-student-zone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating tail call elimination in the face of return address protection, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_10_2024/18_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_10_2024/18_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rewriting the activation frame.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241018-00/?p=110385 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Breakpoint Expressions for C&#43;&#43; Debugging in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 22:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Conditional Breakpoints Performance Improvement Debugging C++ code can be a time-consuming process, especially when dealing with complex scenarios. As a developer, it’s frustrating to go through extensive setup and wait for a specific conditional breakpoint to trigger so you can analyze your application in a specific state. In Visual Studio 2022 version 17.10, we optimized […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/enhanced-breakpoint-expressions-for-c-debugging-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an ASP.Net application with External ID using Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Integrate Microsoft Entra External ID into your ASP.NET application using Visual Studio. Learn how External ID simplifies user authentication, improves your security posture, and reduces vulnerabilities. Whether you&#39;re new to identity management, or more experienced, this tutorial equips you with the guidance to enhance security and efficiency in your applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/integrating-ext-id-using-vs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon Q Business with AWS HealthScribe to gain insights from patient consultations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how you can use AWS HealthScribe with Amazon Q Business to create a chatbot to quickly gain insights into patient clinician conversations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-amazon-q-business-with-aws-healthscribe-to-gain-insights-from-patient-consultations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains at the ICPC World Finals 2024 Astana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 18:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year’s ICPC World Finals Astana was remarkable, and we were thrilled to be a part of it. The event brought together the world’s brightest young minds in competitive programming. Engaging with students, coaches, and the community was a valuable experience that reinforced our commitment to supporting emerging talent. The Opening Ceremony held at the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/17/jetbrains-icpc-world-finals-2024-astana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon SageMaker Studio with a custom file system in Amazon EFS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore three scenarios demonstrating the versatility of integrating Amazon EFS with SageMaker Studio. These scenarios highlight how Amazon EFS can provide a scalable, secure, and collaborative data storage solution for data science teams.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-sagemaker-studio-with-a-custom-file-system-in-amazon-efs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summarize call transcriptions securely with Amazon Transcribe and Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use Amazon Transcribe to get near real-time transcriptions of calls sent to Amazon Bedrock for summarization and sensitive data redaction. We’ll walk through an architecture that uses AWS Step Functions to orchestrate the process, providing seamless integration and efficient processing
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/summarize-call-transcriptions-securely-with-amazon-transcribe-and-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Code-First Infrastructure Deployments with HashiCorp Terraform and Azure Bicep</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re a Site Reliability Engineer (SRE), Cloud Engineer, or IT Admin, you will be required to spin up, configure, and manage all sorts of cloud resources. A code-first infrastructure approach to deploying and managing cloud resources will offer you and your team many benefits over the long term when it comes to infrastructure automation, […] The article Benefits of Code-First Infrastructure Deployments with HashiCorp Terraform and Azure Bicep was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating tail call elimination in the face of return address protection, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reusing the activation frame.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241017-00/?p=110380 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Docker Terraform Provider: Automate, Secure, and Scale with Ease</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the launch of the Docker Terraform Provider, designed to help users and organizations automate and securely manage their Docker-hosted resources.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-terraform-provider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Exciting News &#43; Special Announcement!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 12:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, it’s Kodee here, your favorite Kotlin mascot. I thought, who would be better to bring you all the exciting news from the Kotlin ecosystem than the cutest member of the team – me. So, without further ado, let’s jump right in!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/kodee-s-kotlin-roundup-exciting-news-special-announcement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1.7 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 09:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released a minor version for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.1 – 2024.1.7. You can update to this version from inside the IDE or via the Toolbox App. This version brings the following fix: For details, refer to the release notes. If you encounter any issues or would like to make a suggestion or a feature […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-1-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>加入 .NET 智能组件生态系统</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 08:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于首席产品经理 Daniel Roth 的Join the .NET Smart Components ecosystem – .NET Blog (microsoft.com) .NET 智能组件是一组示例嵌入式 UI 组件，使得在应用中轻松添加 AI 启用的功能变得更加简单，例如从剪贴板数据自动填写表单、智能文本补全以及语义搜索等场景。.NET 智能组件演示了如何将基于 AI 的功能预先打包成可重用的组件，从而更容易将这些功能集成到现有应用程序中。我们将 .NET 智能组件源代码作为参考示例实现提供，以帮助启动一个充满活力的可重用 .NET AI 驱动组件生态系统。 现已开源 .NET 智能组件在 GitHub 上的 dotnet/smartcomponents repo 中有了新家，其中包含实现源代码、文档和示例应用程序。库作者可以使用示例组件来获得灵感，并将其作为如何打包 AI 驱动功能以方便使用的参考实现。如果您对如何改进 .NET 智能组件有想法，或者对希望添加的新 AI 组件有想法，请通过在 GitHub 上提出问题与我们分享。 使用语义内核的局部嵌入 .NET 智能组件包含用于在您的服务器上本地计算嵌入 (LocalEmbeddings)的示例便捷 API。这些API可用于比较文本的语义相似性。这些 API 现已更新，以将基于 ONNX 的嵌入支持包装在语义内核中，然后演示如何在其基础上构建更多功能，例如自动模型获取、简化的语义搜索和替代嵌入表示。如果您发现这些附加功能有用，则可以将它们包含在您自己的应用程序和库中。否则，您可以直接使用语义内核 API。 来自流行组件供应商的智能组件 一些流行的组件供应商已经开始投资构建自己的智能组件，以 .NET 智能组件中的理念为基础，并添加自己独特的创新和功能。让我们来看看他们正在研究的几个例子。 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e5%8a%a0%e5%85%a5-net-%e6%99%ba%e8%83%bd%e7%bb%84%e4%bb%b6%e7%94%9f%e6%80%81%e7%b3%bb%e7%bb%9f 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>推出适用于 .NET 的官方OpenAI库的稳定版本</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 07:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于.NET 团队的Announcing the stable release of the official OpenAI library for .NET – .NET Blog (microsoft.com) 早在 6 月份，我们就推出了适用于 .NET 的OpenAI 库的第一个测试版，使开发人员能够将高级 AI 模型集成到他们的应用程序中。今天，我们很高兴地宣布，适用于.NET 的官方 OpenAI 库的稳定版本现已上线。此版本可确保开发人员在其 .NET 应用程序中使用 OpenAI 和 Azure OpenAI 服务时获得顺畅可靠的集成体验。 主要特点 适用于.NET 的官方 OpenAI 库提供了强大的工具，可简化将 OpenAI 的高级模型集成到 .NET 应用程序中的过程，从而为开发人员提供简洁流畅的体验： 全面支持OpenAI REST API：包括 Assistants v2 和 Chat Completions，可实现灵活和先进的交互。 支持最新模型：OpenAI 的最新旗舰模型，包括 GPT-4o、GPT-4o mini、o1-preview […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e6%8e%a8%e5%87%ba%e9%80%82%e7%94%a8%e4%ba%8e-net-%e7%9a%84%e5%ae%98%e6%96%b9openai%e5%ba%93%e7%9a%84%e7%a8%b3%e5%ae%9a%e7%89%88%e6%9c%ac 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine 3.0 is Live!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just as the title says, Wolverine 3.0 is live and published to Nuget! I believe that this release addresses some of Wolverine’s prior weaknesses and adds some powerful new features requested by our users. The journey for Wolverine right now is to be the singular most effective set of tooling for building robust, maintainable, and … Continue reading Wolverine 3.0 is Live! →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/10/16/wolverine-3-0-is-live/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Pull Request Annotation for CodeQL and Dependency Scanning in GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of software development, security is paramount. As developers, we strive to write clean, efficient, and most importantly, secure code. GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps has always been at the forefront of providing tools that make it easier to build and release high-quality software. Today, we’re excited to announce a new feature […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/introducing-pull-request-annotation-for-codeql-and-dependency-scanning-in-github-advanced-security-for-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Error Messages for a GOOD Developer Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 21:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debugging and troubleshooting are a big part of a developer’s day-to-day. Because of this, when designing your APIs, provide good API error messages as well as guide developers down a path of success and makes it easier for them to understand issues when they need to troubleshoot. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all… Read More »API Error Messages for a GOOD Developer Experience The post API Error Messages for a GOOD Developer Experience appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How DPG Media uses Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Transcribe to enhance video metadata with AI-powered pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how DPG Media is introducing AI-powered processes using Amazon Bedrock into its video publication pipelines. This solution is helping accelerate audio metadata extraction, create a more engaging user experience, and save time.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-dpg-media-uses-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-transcribe-to-enhance-video-metadata-with-ai-powered-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How SailPoint uses Anthropic’s Claude on Amazon Bedrock to automatically generate TypeScript code for SaaS connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we highlight how the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center collaborated with SailPoint Technologies to build a generative AI-based coding assistant that uses Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock to help accelerate the development of software as a service (SaaS) connectors.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-sailpoint-uses-anthropics-claude-on-amazon-bedrock-to-automatically-generate-typescript-code-for-saas-connectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map Earth’s vegetation in under 20 minutes with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the power of SageMaker geospatial capabilities by mapping the world’s vegetation in under 20 minutes. This example not only highlights the efficiency of SageMaker, but also its impact how geospatial ML can be used to monitor the environment for sustainability and conservation purposes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/map-earths-vegetation-in-under-20-minutes-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve your debugger game with editable expressions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you ever wish you could quickly test different queries on your collections or datasets while debugging? Do you want to save time and avoid writing code just to inspect your data? If you answered yes, then you will love the new editable expression feature in the Visual Studio debugger. This feature allows you to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/improve-your-debugger-game-with-editable-expressions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking insights and enhancing customer service: Intact’s transformative AI journey with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 17:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Intact&#39;s Call Quality solution used Amazon Transcribe and other AWS services to improve critical KPIs with AI-powered contact center call auditing and analytics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-insights-and-enhancing-customer-service-intacts-transformative-ai-journey-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we build GitHub Copilot into Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out how Visual Studio integrates GitHub Copilot, architectural detail, .NET implementation, and the importance of the indexing service for providing context-aware AI code suggestions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/building-github-copilot-into-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 control spotlight: Information security risk management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 16:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how Microsoft 365 Certification verifies information security risk management.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-control-spotlight-information-security-risk-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Best Practices: Using ARG and ENV in Your Dockerfiles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 14:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the ARG and ENV instructions and explore how to use them in your Dockerfiles to make your images more configurable and easier to maintain.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-best-practices-using-arg-and-env-in-your-dockerfiles/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of classic return address tricks on hardware-assisted return address protection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Return address manipulations that are possibly even more impermissible than they already were.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241016-00/?p=110378 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Docker IT Streamlined Docker Desktop Deployment Across the Global Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 13:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker IT deployed Docker Desktop to hundreds of macOS and Windows devices in 24 hours. Here&#39;s how they did it.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-docker-it-streamlined-docker-desktop-deployment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider Reveal Livestream: Big News for .NET and Game Devs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 12:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on October 24 for a special livestream where our Developer Advocates will reveal exciting news about JetBrains Rider. You won’t want to miss this! Set a reminder on YouTube and subscribe to our JetBrains channel to get notified when the livestream is about to start. We would appreciate it if you could spread […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/10/16/rider-reveal-livestream-big-news-for-dotnet-and-game-devs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Analysis for Your Projects With IntelliJ IDEA and Qodana</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we spend more time maintaining existing code than we do writing new code. Any tools that can help make this easier can save us a lot of time. In this blog post series, we’ll look at several ways that code analysis in IntelliJ IDEA can help you find and fix problems in your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/code-analysis-for-your-projects-with-intellij-idea-and-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.7.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 10:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Multiplatform is a declarative UI framework built by JetBrains that allows developers to share UI implementations across different platforms. The 1.7.0 release brings more components to common code, support for type-safe navigation, significant performance improvements on iOS, and changes from the latest Jetpack Compose update. Here are the highlights of this release: For the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/compose-multiplatform-1-7-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate migration portfolio assessment using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 22:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will harness the power of generative AI and Amazon Bedrock to help organizations simplify, accelerate, and scale migration assessments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-migration-portfolio-assessment-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve public speaking skills using a generative AI-based virtual assistant with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 20:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present an Amazon Bedrock powered virtual assistant that can transcribe presentation audio and examine it for language use, grammatical errors, filler words, and repetition of words and sentences to provide recommendations as well as suggest a curated version of the speech to elevate the presentation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-public-speaking-skills-using-a-generative-ai-based-virtual-assistant-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bria 2.3, Bria 2.2 HD, and Bria 2.3 Fast are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 20:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss Bria’s family of models, explain the Amazon SageMaker platform, and walk through how to discover, deploy, and run inference on a Bria 2.3 model using SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bria-2-3-bria-2-2-hd-and-bria-2-3-fast-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing SageMaker Core: A new object-oriented Python SDK for Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how the SageMaker Core SDK simplifies the developer experience while providing API for seamlessly executing various steps in a general ML lifecycle. We also discuss the main benefits of using this SDK along with sharing relevant resources to learn more about this SDK.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-sagemaker-core-a-new-object-oriented-python-sdk-for-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Organization Access Tokens</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker organization access tokens let customers manage access that each token has, instead of managing users and their placement within the organization.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-organization-access-tokens/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a data labeling project with Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth Plus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth is a powerful data labeling service offered by AWS that provides a comprehensive and scalable platform for labeling various types of data, including text, images, videos, and 3D point clouds, using a diverse workforce of human annotators. In addition to traditional custom-tailored deep learning models, SageMaker Ground Truth also supports generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-data-labeling-project-with-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-plus/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating industry-wide innovations in datacenter infrastructure and security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft drives innovation and contributes to the broader AI and datacenter community, benefitting the entire industry. The post Accelerating industry-wide innovations in datacenter infrastructure and security appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/accelerating-industry-wide-innovations-in-datacenter-infrastructure-and-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in System.Text.Json in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An overview of all new .NET 9 features in System.Text.Json for developers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/system-text-json-in-dotnet-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick introduction to return address protection technologies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Detecting attempts to manipulate the return address.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241015-00/?p=110374 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety and simplicity with LINQ: Working with the result pattern - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to clean up unreadable Switch()-based result pattern code using LINQ query syntax, giving both readability and safety
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/working-with-the-result-pattern-part-2-safety-and-simplicity-with-linq/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging .NET Collections with Span and MemoryExtensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article discusses optimizing code efficiency in .NET using Span and MemoryExtensions for collection operations. It highlights significant performance improvements in common tasks such as finding, sorting, and reversing collections, demonstrating that these tools minimize memory allocations and enhance speed. Benchmark results underscore substantial advantages in performance and efficiency.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/15/supercharging-net-collections-with-span-and-memoryextensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#x27;s new in .NET 9: Cryptography improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 08:38:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 9 is releasing in mid-November 2024. Like every .NET version, this introduces several important features and enhancements aligning developers with an ever-changing development ecosystem. In this blog series, I will explore critical updates in different areas of .NET. For today&#39;s post, I&#39;ll present some improvements asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/whats-new-in-net-9-cryptography-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Tip: IEnumerable vs ICollection, and why it matters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with Lists in C#, you are working on a data structure that implements both ICollection and IEnumerable. What’s the difference between ICollection and IEnumerable? Why should you care about them, especially when exposing functionalities to external clients?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/ienumerable-vs-icollection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – October 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 19:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the October release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd), including configurable api-version for ACA.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-october-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a multimodal chatbot tailored to your unique dataset with Amazon Bedrock FMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to create a multimodal chat assistant on Amazon Web Services (AWS) using Amazon Bedrock models, where users can submit images and questions, and text responses will be sourced from a closed set of proprietary documents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-multimodal-chatbot-tailored-to-your-unique-dataset-with-amazon-bedrock-fms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design secure generative AI application workflows with Amazon Verified Permissions and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to design fine-grained access controls using Verified Permissions for a generative AI application that uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to answer questions about insurance claims that exist in a claims review system using textual prompts as inputs and outputs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/design-secure-generative-ai-application-workflows-with-amazon-verified-permissions-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch the highlights from Azure Developers – .NET Aspire Day 2024!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Watch the top sessions on demand for insights and practical guidance on building distributed applications with .NET Aspire!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/azure-developers-dotnet-aspire-day-recap 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ultimate chatbot?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 15:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RAG – Retrieval Augmented Generation – is by far one of the most common patterns today as it enables the creation of chatbots that can chat on your own data, as I described in my previous “Retrieval Augmented Generation with Azure SQL” blog post. As soon as you start to use it excitement grows, as […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/the-ultimate-chatbot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On naming things: The tension between naming something for what it is, what it does, or how it is used</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You are guaranteed to make someone upset.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241014-00/?p=110368 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding OverloadResolutionPriority attribute in C# 13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# 13 adds support for a new attribute: [OverloadResolutionPriority]. This attribute is niche, so most of you won&#39;t use it. However, it&#39;s a nice addition to the language, and it&#39;s worth knowing about it if you are writing libraries. Let&#39;s consider this simple example: Sample.Test(); // Print: Test 1 static class Sample { public static void Test() =&amp;gt; Console.WriteLine(&amp;quot;Test 1&amp;quot;); } Now, you want to update…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/understanding-overloadresolutionpriority-attribute-in-csharp-13.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Prevent Concurrent Execution of a Hangfire Job</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 05:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will see how we can prevent the concurrent execution of a Hangfire job. Hangfire is a wonderful tool for scheduling recurring background jobs. But, if we are not careful, we can encounter strange or intermittent errors caused by concurrent execution of a given job. We will first discuss potential problems related […] The post How to Prevent Concurrent Execution of a Hangfire Job appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
