<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:29:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code in Rust: Winners and Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you to everyone who joined Advent of Code 2025 in Rust! It was inspiring to see many Rustaceans solving algorithmic puzzles, and celebrating the holiday coding season with the community. Before the Advent began, Vitaly Bragilevsky published a blog post on how to use AI in Advent of Code challenge responsibly and effectively. This […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/12/22/advent-of-code-in-rust-winners-and-highlights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Beyond Chain-of-Thought with Chain-of-Draft on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores Chain-of-Draft (CoD), an innovative prompting technique introduced in a Zoom AI Research paper Chain of Draft: Thinking Faster by Writing Less, that revolutionizes how models approach reasoning tasks. While Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has been the go-to method for enhancing model reasoning, CoD offers a more efficient alternative that mirrors human problem-solving patterns—using concise, high-signal thinking steps rather than verbose explanations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/move-beyond-chain-of-thought-with-chain-of-draft-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Mistral AI’s Voxtral on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate hosting Voxtral models on Amazon SageMaker AI endpoints using vLLM and the Bring Your Own Container (BYOC) approach. vLLM is a high-performance library for serving large language models (LLMs) that features paged attention for improved memory management and tensor parallelism for distributing models across multiple GPUs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-mistral-ais-voxtral-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance document analytics with Strands AI Agents for the GenAI IDP Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To address the need for businesses to quickly analyze information and unlock actionable insights, we are announcing Analytics Agent, a new feature that is seamlessly integrated into the GenAI IDP Accelerator. With this feature, users can perform advanced searches and complex analyses using natural language queries without SQL or data analysis expertise. In this post, we discuss how non-technical users can use this tool to analyze and understand the documents they have processed at scale with natural language.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a multimodal generative AI assistant for root cause diagnosis in predictive maintenance using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to implement a predictive maintenance solution using Foundation Models (FMs) on Amazon Bedrock, with a case study of Amazon&#39;s manufacturing equipment within their fulfillment centers. The solution is highly adaptable and can be customized for other industries, including oil and gas, logistics, manufacturing, and healthcare.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-multimodal-generative-ai-assistant-for-root-cause-diagnosis-in-predictive-maintenance-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AI fixed my procrastination</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I struggled to get started. For ages, I kept putting off building this website, creating a new programming language for Visual Studio, and coming up with fresh color themes. Each project looked overwhelming, and I couldn’t find the time or motivation to jump in. It all just felt like too much at once. But when a national holiday gave me a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-ai-fixed-my-procrastination 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the other cool languages have &lt;code&gt;try&lt;/code&gt;...&lt;code&gt;finally&lt;/code&gt;. C&#43;&#43; says &#34;We have &lt;code&gt;try&lt;/code&gt;...&lt;code&gt;finally&lt;/code&gt; at home.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many languages¹ that have exceptions also have a finally clause, so you can write try { ⟦ stuff ⟧ } finally { always(); } A quick checks shows that this control structure exists in Java, C#, Python, JavaScript, but not C++. C++ says, &amp;quot;We have try...finally at home.&amp;quot;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251222-00/?p=111890 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Test Run Hub is Going Generally Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Delivering high-quality software requires clarity, speed, and collaboration. That’s why we introduced the New Test Run Hub in Azure Test Plans. A modern, streamlined experience designed to make test execution and analysis fast and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/the-new-test-run-hub-is-going-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Managing Mark of the Web in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is Mark of the Web? Mark of the Web (MOTW) is a Windows security feature that protects users from potentially unsafe files downloaded from the internet. When you download a file, Windows automatically adds a special metadata tag indicating the file originated from an untrusted source and may contain harmful content. Windows components such as Microsoft Edge and Windows Explorer use MOTW to determine…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/understanding-and-managing-mark-of-the-web-in-dotnet.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuously hardening ChatGPT Atlas against prompt injection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is strengthening ChatGPT Atlas against prompt injection attacks using automated red teaming trained with reinforcement learning. This proactive discover-and-patch loop helps identify novel exploits early and harden the browser agent’s defenses as AI becomes more agentic.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/hardening-atlas-against-prompt-injection 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One in a million: celebrating the customers shaping AI’s future</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_12_2025/22_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            More than one million customers around the world now use OpenAI to empower their teams and unlock new opportunities. This post highlights how companies like PayPal, Virgin Atlantic, BBVA, Cisco, Moderna, and Canva are transforming the way work gets done with AI.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/one-in-a-million-customers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Book: Build and Deploy Apps using Azure Developer CLI by Chris Pietschmann</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2025/21_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2025/21_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am excited to announce the release of my new book, Build and Deploy Apps using Azure Developer CLI, a practical, hands-on guide for developers and teams who want to streamline cloud-native application deployments on Microsoft Azure using the Azure Developer CLI (azd). Modern application delivery often gets slowed down by inconsistent environments, manual portal steps, […] The article New Book: Build and Deploy Apps using Azure Developer CLI by Chris Pietschmann was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Anyway You Want: Initializing Reference Type Static Fields Inline for Enhanced Code Readability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2025/21_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2025/21_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft advises initializing reference type static fields inline to enhance code readability and prevent issues from uninitialized fields. Two patterns are shown: inline initialization and using a static constructor. While both methods do not allocate memory, using a static constructor may slightly improve performance. EditorConfig can check for adherence to this guideline.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/12/21/code-it-anyway-you-want-initializing-reference-type-static-fields-inline-for-enhanced-code-readability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does Taking Ownership ACTUALLY Mean? - Dev Leader Weekly 120</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2025/21_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_12_2025/21_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss what it means to take ownership in software engineering.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/21/what-does-taking-ownership-actually-mean-dev-leader-weekly-120 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-12-20</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 23:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/20/weekly-recap-20251220 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 Recap: The Year Software Development Changed Shape</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2025 was the year software teams stopped optimizing models and started optimizing systems. By December, a few truths were impossible to ignore. 1. Developer Productivity Became the Real Competitive Advantage By mid-year, every major AI lab had cleared the “good enough reasoning” bar. With model quality converging, the differentiator was no longer raw intelligence. It...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/2025-recap-the-year-software-development-changed-shape/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Authentication and Identity validation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 11:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at authentication and identity validation and describes what should be validated and some of the concepts. With the increasing push to move processes to a digital world and the new threat models, authentication and identity validation MUST be implemented in a professional way. Using standards like OpenID Connect, OAuth and OpenID VCs […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/12/20/digital-authentication-and-identity-validation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server-Sent Events in ASP.NET Core and .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ASP.NET Core 10 introduces native Server-Sent Events as a lightweight, HTTP-native alternative to SignalR for simple one-way real-time updates like dashboards and notifications.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/server-sent-events-in-aspnetcore-and-dotnet-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) Dec 2025 - Extensions Enhancements, Foundry Rebranding, and Azure Pipelines Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 19:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the December 2025 edition of the Azure Developer CLI (azd) release blog—our final release of the year! This post covers releases 1.22.0 through 1.22.5, wrapping up 2025. To share your feedback and questions, join the December release discussion on GitHub.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-december-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work item linking for Advanced Security alerts now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Security vulnerabilities don&#39;t fix themselves. Someone needs to track them, prioritize them, and actually ship the fix. If you&#39;ve ever tried to manage security alerts alongside your regular sprint work, though, you know the friction: you&#39;re looking at an alert in one tab, switching to your backlog in another, trying to remember which vulner
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/work-item-linking-for-advanced-security-alerts-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing SOCI indexing for Amazon SageMaker Studio: Faster container startup times for AI/ML workloads</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to introduce a new feature for SageMaker Studio: SOCI (Seekable Open Container Initiative) indexing. SOCI supports lazy loading of container images, where only the necessary parts of an image are downloaded initially rather than the entire container.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-soci-indexing-for-amazon-sagemaker-studio-faster-container-startup-times-for-ai-ml-workloads/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A shortcut gives me a weird path for a program shortcut that doesn&#39;t point to the executable, so what is it?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Say you have a shortcut file and you want to see what its target is. The natural thing to do is to call IShellLink::GetPath, which returns S_FALSE if the shortcut does not target a path, or returns S_OK and a path to the target. But for some shortcuts, it returns S_OK but produces a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251219-00/?p=111885 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Mobile Development Teams Use Kotlin in 2025: Insights From a Certified Trainer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the second guest post in a two-part series from José Luis González. José Luis has a PhD in software development and is a JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer, who works with developers and engineering teams to deepen their Kotlin skills and apply the language effectively in real projects. At Hyperskill, he runs Kotlin instructor-led training for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/how-mobile-development-teams-use-kotlin-in-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Qodana 2025.3 Release Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Qodana 2025.3 delivers important new capabilities that help teams standardize their development practices, improve compliance, make audits easier, and simplify large-scale code analysis. From introducing Global Project Configuration, a major step toward scalable, centralized policy management, to expanding license auditing for .NET and enhancing monorepository support for Java and Kotlin, Qodana 2025.3 makes it easier […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/12/top-3-qodana-2025-3-release-highlights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Captain’s Chair: Igor Aleksandrov</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Captains are leaders from the developer community that are both experts in their field and are passionate about sharing their Docker knowledge with others. “From the Captain’s Chair” is a blog series where we get a closer look at one Captain to learn more about them and their experiences. Today we are interviewing Igor...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/from-the-captains-chair-igor-aleksandrov/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Hardened Images: Security Independently Validated by SRLabs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this week, we took a major step forward for the industry. Docker Hardened Images (DHI) is now available at no cost, bringing secure-by-default development to every team, everywhere. Anyone can now start from a secure, minimal, production-ready foundation from the first pull, without a subscription. With that decision comes a responsibility: if Docker Hardened Images become...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hardened-images-security-independently-validated-by-srlabs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First-Class Docker Support: Building and Deploying Containers With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Kumar Harsh, draft.dev. Docker has changed the way we build and ship software. Instead of wrestling with “it works on my machine” issues, developers can now package applications and all their dependencies into a neat, portable container that runs anywhere. No wonder Docker has become the de facto […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/first-class-docker-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in Microsoft Foundry | October and November 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 04:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Move from prototype to production in hours, not weeks: The new Microsoft Agent Framework and Hosted Agents let you build, test, and deploy multi-agent AI systems with enterprise-grade security—no Kubernetes or container headaches. Orchestrate any model, anywhere: Model
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/whats-new-in-microsoft-foundry-oct-nov-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize ASP.NET Web Forms UI to Blazor with AWS Transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 19:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Transform is an agentic service that accelerates modernization, including .NET applications. With it, you can transform .NET Framework Windows applications to cross-platform .NET and reduce operating costs up to 40% by running on Linux. For ASP.NET web applications, AWS Transform can port the UI layer to ASP.NET Core. In this post, I’ll explain how […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-asp-net-web-forms-ui-to-blazor-with-aws-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Coding Agents and Domain-Specific Languages: Challenges and Practical Mitigation Strategies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Introduction AI coding agents/assistants such as GitHub Copilot have become common in modern software engineering workflows. Their strengths—rapid pattern completion, context-aware suggestions, and the ability to learn style from local code—stem from broad training on large corpora of public, general-purpose code. They perf Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/ai-coding-agents-domain-specific-languages 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.3.1 Released: Next Edit Suggestions and Other Important Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since the 2025.3 release, we’ve published several rapid-response updates (2025.3.0.1–2025.3.0.4) for ReSharper and Rider to address the most urgent issues as quickly as possible. The 2025.3.1 update brings all of those fixes together and includes additional improvements that required more time to implement. For Rider, it also delivers the data-sharing functionality we announced earlier this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/18/resharper-and-rider-2025-3-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and deploy scalable AI agents with NVIDIA NeMo, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use the powerful combination of Strands Agents, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and NVIDIA NeMo Agent Toolkit to build, evaluate, optimize, and deploy AI agents on Amazon Web Services (AWS) from initial development through production deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-and-deploy-scalable-ai-agents-with-nvidia-nemo-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-and-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bi-directional streaming for real-time agent interactions now available in Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn about bi-directional streaming on AgentCore Runtime and the prerequisites to create a WebSocket implementation. You will also learn how to use Strands Agents to implement a bi-directional streaming solution for voice agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bi-directional-streaming-for-real-time-agent-interactions-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Edit Suggestions: Now Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next edit suggestions feature is now enabled in all JetBrains IDEs for JetBrains AI Pro, AI Ultimate, and AI Enterprise subscribers. Yes, you read that right! JetBrains-native diff suggestions are available right in your editor. Global support for optimized latency. Out-of-the-box IDE actions for reliability. And the best part? It doesn’t consume your AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/next-edit-suggestions-now-generally-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring Your Own Key (BYOK) Is Now Live in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bring Your Own Key (BYOK) is now available in the AI chat inside JetBrains IDEs as well as for AI agents, including JetBrains’ Junie and Claude Agent. Whether you’re looking to use cutting-edge frontier models, cost-efficient small models, locally hosted private models, or experimental research previews, BYOK makes it easy to bring them all directly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/bring-your-own-key-byok-is-now-live-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3.1 is out with a number of useful fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. The latest update brings the following improvements: For a comprehensive overview of the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-2025-3-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Consoles Are Coming Back</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi DataGrip and Database Tools community, Shortly after the 2025.3 release, your feedback made it clear that the redesigned workflow for query files and query consoles introduced issues in several important scenarios, especially when working with global data sources. After reviewing the impact, we’ve decided that the best course of action is to revert this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/18/query-consoles-are-coming-back/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adopting Kotlin in a Java-centric company is not about flipping a switch or rewriting everything “the right way”. It’s about people, timing, risk, and trust. Over the last four weeks, we’ve published a series of blog posts by Urs Peter, covering all of these aspects of migrating to Kotlin. In this post, we’ll tie the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/the-ultimate-guide-to-successfully-adopting-kotlin-in-a-java-dominated-environment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concluding thoughts on our deep dive into Windows clipboard text conversion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the past few articles (starting with conversion between CF_OEM­TEXT and CF_TEXT), we&#39;ve been looking at how Windows performs text conversion
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251218-00/?p=111882 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating chain-of-thought monitorability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces a new framework and evaluation suite for chain-of-thought monitorability, covering 13 evaluations across 24 environments. Our findings show that monitoring a model’s internal reasoning is far more effective than monitoring outputs alone, offering a promising path toward scalable control as AI systems grow more capable.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/evaluating-chain-of-thought-monitorability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Programming Courses in 2025: New and Favorite Picks on JetBrains Academy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            “It’s tiiiiiiiiiiiime!”, and not just for Mariah Carey on the playlist. Here’s our annual roundup of JetBrains Academy courses – the favorites you loved this year and the new courses launched in 2025. If you’re trying to figure out where to start, what to learn next, or how to invest in your future skills, this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/18/best-programming-courses-in-2025-new-and-favorite-picks-on-jetbrains-academy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI literacy resources for teens and parents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI shares new AI literacy resources to help teens and parents use ChatGPT thoughtfully, safely, and with confidence. The guides include expert-vetted tips for responsible use, critical thinking, healthy boundaries, and supporting teens through emotional or sensitive topics.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/ai-literacy-resources-for-teens-and-parents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deepening our collaboration with the U.S. Department of Energy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and the U.S. Department of Energy have signed a memorandum of understanding to deepen collaboration on AI and advanced computing in support of scientific discovery. The agreement builds on ongoing work with national laboratories and helps establish a framework for applying AI to high-impact research across the DOE ecosystem.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/us-department-of-energy-collaboration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating our Model Spec with teen protections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is updating its Model Spec with new Under-18 Principles that define how ChatGPT should support teens with safe, age-appropriate guidance grounded in developmental science. The update strengthens guardrails, clarifies expected model behavior in higher-risk situations, and builds on our broader work to improve teen safety across ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/updating-model-spec-with-teen-protections 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Copilot Studio &#43; Azure AI Search Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction: The Challenge In the early days of Microsoft Copilot Studio, our team noticed a recurring pattern. Across customer engagements, organizations were consistently struggling to integrate copilots with Azure AI Search. Organizations were consistently struggling to integrate copilot with Azure AI Search - not because either
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/mcs-azure-ai-search-intro 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addendum to GPT-5.2 System Card: GPT-5.2-Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This system card outlines the comprehensive safety measures implemented for GPT‑5.2-Codex. It details both model-level mitigations, such as specialized safety training for harmful tasks and prompt injections, and product-level mitigations like agent sandboxing and configurable network access.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-2-codex-system-card 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5.2-Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_12_2025/18_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2-Codex is OpenAI’s most advanced coding model, offering long-horizon reasoning, large-scale code transformations, and enhanced cybersecurity capabilities.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-2-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the power of distributed graph databases with JanusGraph and Azure Apache Cassandra</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Connecting the Dots: How Graph Databases Drive Innova
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/janusgraph-azure-cassandra-graph-databases 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking and managing assets used in AI development with Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll explore the new capabilities and core concepts that help organizations track and manage models development and deployment lifecycles. We will show you how the features are configured to train models with automatic end-to-end lineage, from dataset upload and versioning to model fine-tuning, evaluation, and seamless endpoint deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/tracking-and-managing-assets-used-in-ai-development-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track machine learning experiments with MLflow on Amazon SageMaker using Snowflake integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to integrate Amazon SageMaker managed MLflow as a central repository to log these experiments and provide a unified system for monitoring their progress.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/track-machine-learning-experiments-with-mlflow-on-amazon-sagemaker-using-snowflake-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 10 Years of DirectX 12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DirectX12 shipped in 2015 with a simple goal: give developers more control so games run faster, look better, and scale across Windows PC and console. Over the last decade, DirectX 12 delivered on that promise. We added features and made it easier for developers to focus on gameplay &amp;amp; graphics by providing more flexibility and achievable pe
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/celebrating-10-years-of-directx-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire 13.1 - Our holiday gift to you</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aspire 13.1 - Our holiday gift to you 🎁 Before we head off for the holidays, we wanted to leave you with one more release. Aspire 13.1 is packed with improvements to make your AI coding assistants first-class citizens in your development workflow, along with CLI enhancements, dashboard refinements, and streamlined Azure deploym
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspire-13-1-holiday-gift 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deducing the consequences of Windows clipboard text formats on UTF-8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve been looking at how Windows performs automatic conversion between the three text formats CF_TEXT, CF_OEM­TEXT, and CF_UNICODE­TEXT. The use of UTF-8 as the 8-bit character set is growing in popularity, and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251217-00/?p=111880 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When AI Amplifies Your Bad (and Good) Habits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is more like a megaphone than a magic wand. It amplifies what is already there. Whatever habits you bring to your workflow, good or bad, AI will turn up the volume. Every untested component, undocumented design, and ill-specified feature, to name a few, becomes louder when AI enters the mix. Teams with a clear […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/when-ai-amplifies-your-bad-and-good-habits/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack Roadmap for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I normally write this out in January, but I’m feeling like now is a good time to get this out as some of it is in flight. So with plenty of feedback from the other Critter Stack Core team members and a lot of experience seeing where JasperFx Software clients have hit friction in the … Continue reading Critter Stack Roadmap for 2026 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/12/17/critter-stack-roadmap-for-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Safer Container Ecosystem with Docker: Free Docker Hardened Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Containers are the universal path to production for most developers, and Docker has always been the steward of the ecosystem. Docker Hub has over 20 billion monthly pulls, with nearly 90% of organizations now relying on containers in their software delivery workflows. That gives us a responsibility: to help secure the software supply chain for...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hardened-images-for-every-developer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.3 Has Been Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MPS 2025.3 introduces a major overhaul of the JavaDoc language, significant changes to generator plans, and a major update to the reflective editor. It also enables keyboard actions in the Logical view and allows TextIcon to offer visually distinct variants for light and dark themes. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 What’s new Check out all the available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/12/mps-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Leaders on the KotlinConf’25 Stage: What Global Brands Built With Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin ecosystem continues to grow among the world’s most recognized brands, including Meta, AWS, Duolingo, Uber, and others. At KotlinConf 2025, these companies took the stage to share practical, real-world engineering stories. KotlinConf is where developers can learn directly from the teams building products at global scale. Software engineers showcase how they are tackling […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/industry-leaders-on-the-kotlinconf25-stage/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock your email potential with Schema.org</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Email is a key part of how people get things done, whether it’s booking a reservation, confirming a package delivery, or managing a cab reservation. But as inboxes become increasingly cluttered, important transactional information often gets buried. Users are forced to open multip
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/unlock-your-email-potential-with-schema-org 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing OpenAI Academy for News Organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is launching the OpenAI Academy for News Organizations, a new learning hub built with the American Journalism Project and The Lenfest Institute to help newsrooms use AI effectively. The Academy offers training, practical use cases, and responsible-use guidance to support journalists, editors, and publishers as they adopt AI in their reporting and operations.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-academy-for-news-organizations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers can now submit apps to ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_12_2025/17_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers can now submit apps for review and publication in ChatGPT, with approved apps appearing in a new in-product directory for easy discovery. Updated tools, guidelines, and the Apps SDK help developers build powerful chat-native experiences that bring real-world actions into ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/developers-can-now-submit-apps-to-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize ASP.NET MVC Razor UI with AWS Transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Transform is an agentic service that accelerates modernization, including .NET applications. With it, you can transform .NET Framework Windows applications to cross-platform .NET and reduce operating costs up to 40% by running on Linux. For ASP.NET web applications, AWS Transform can port the UI layer to ASP.NET Core. In this post, I’ll explain how […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-asp-net-mvc-razor-ui-with-aws-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why “Microservices” Debates Miss the Point</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 22:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DHH had a take on microservices in small teams that is getting a lot of attention. And while I agree with what he’s pointing out, all of these types of conversations miss what actually matters. This is not about microservices or a monolith or small teams. Now what’s implied here is microservices is much more… Read More »Why “Microservices” Debates Miss the Point The post Why “Microservices” Debates Miss the Point appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance by design: The essential guide for successful AI scaling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 21:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picture this: Your enterprise has just deployed its first generative AI application. The initial results are promising, but as you plan to scale across departments, critical questions emerge. How will you enforce consistent security, prevent model bias, and maintain control as AI applications multiply?
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/governance-by-design-the-essential-guide-for-successful-ai-scaling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Ergonomics: How the Azure Command Launcher for Java Improves GC Stability and Throughput on Azure VMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog we introduced Azure Command Launcher for Java (jaz) —a safe, resource-aware way to launch the JVM without hand-tuning dozens of flags. This follow-up shares performance results, focusing on
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/beyond-ergonomics-how-the-azure-command-launcher-for-java-improves-gc-stability-and-throughput-on-azure-vms 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tata Power CoE built a scalable AI-powered solar panel inspection solution with Amazon SageMaker AI and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Tata Power CoE and Oneture Technologies use AWS services to automate the inspection process end-to-end.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-tata-power-coe-built-a-scalable-ai-powered-solar-panel-inspection-solution-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking video understanding with TwelveLabs Marengo on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll show how the TwelveLabs Marengo embedding model, available on Amazon Bedrock, enhances video understanding through multimodal AI. We&#39;ll build a video semantic search and analysis solution using embeddings from the Marengo model with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless as the vector database, for semantic search capabilities that go beyond simple metadata matching to deliver intelligent content discovery.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-video-understanding-with-twelvelabs-marengo-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip turns 10. Hidden gems of DataGrip.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking back Hello, friends! 10 years ago to this very day, DataGrip was born. That’s right, on December 16, 2016, the first-ever version of DataGrip was released! But the origins of DataGrip go back even further. We had already been working to create a database IDE for quite some time by then, and its codename […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/16/datagrip-turns-10-hidden-gems-of-datagrip/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; code editing tools for GitHub Copilot: now in Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In November, we introduced C++ code editing tools for GitHub Copilot as a Private Preview, focusing on partnering with customers to tackle one of the common, taxing challenges for C++ development: refactoring at s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-code-editing-tools-for-github-copilot-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft.Testing.Platform Now Fully Supported in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this year, we announced that all major .NET test frameworks now support Microsoft.Testing.Platform. The next logical step? Making sure it works seamlessly with your CI/CD pipelines. Today, we&#39;re announcing comprehensive Azure DevOps integration for Microsof
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/microsoft-testing-platform-azure-retry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.3.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.3.0 release is out! This version includes new language features, stable ones, and other features now enabled by default. This release also brings tooling updates, performance improvements for different platforms, and important fixes. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/kotlin-2-3-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging, but Without the Drama (A Visual Studio 2026 Story)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It starts the way these things always start. A red build.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2026-debugging-with-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is the Windows clipboard taking the scenic route when converting from &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; to &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;OEM­TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our investigation of why the CF_OEM­TEXT clipboard format is not being created from CF_TEXT via Ansi­To­Oem led us to the realization that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251216-00/?p=111873 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and deploy voice AI apps using Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Voice is the next frontier of conversational AI. It is the most natural modality for people to chat and interact with another intelligent being. However, the voice AI software stack is complex, with many moving parts. Docker has emerged as one of the most useful tools for AI agent deployment. In this article, we&#39;ll explore...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/develop-deploy-voice-ai-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards integration with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A few months ago we introduced the Azure Boards integration with GitHub Copilot in private preview. The goal was simple: allow teams to take a work item from Azure Boards and send it directly to GitHub Copilot so the coding agent
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/github-copilot-for-azure-boards 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner now included with the Universal Blue family</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running large language models (LLMs) and other generative AI models can be a complex, frustrating process of managing dependencies, drivers, and environments. At Docker, we believe this should be as simple as docker model run. That&#39;s why we built Docker Model Runner, and today, we’re thrilled to announce a new collaboration with Universal Blue. Thanks...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-universal-blue/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs C&#43;&#43;: competition or evolution in systems programming for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C and C++ are the backbone of modern software. Operating systems, databases, game engines, and compilers all trace their roots to these languages. They give developers low-level control over memory, hardware, and performance. It’s a level of control that has defined decades of software development. However, the landscape has shifted, and the Rust vs. C++ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/12/16/rust-vs-cpp-comparison-for-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents, Protocols, and Why We’re Not Playing Favorites</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past few weeks, after we announced ACP protocol support, I’ve gotten lots of messages asking something along these lines: “Microsoft just launched AgentHQ for GitHub and VS Code. So, does this mean JetBrains will drop ACP? Will you only support your own thing now?” The quick answer: We’re not picking sides. Here’s why – […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/agents-protocols-and-why-we-re-not-playing-favorites/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a .NET CLR profiler using C# and NativeAOT with Silhouette</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at how to create a simple .NET profiler. But instead of using C++, the profiler uses C# and NativeAOT with the Silhouette library
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-dotnet-profiler-using-csharp-with-silhouette/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating AI’s ability to perform scientific research tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces FrontierScience, a benchmark testing AI reasoning in physics, chemistry, and biology to measure progress toward real scientific research.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/frontierscience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring AI’s capability to accelerate biological research</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces a real-world evaluation framework to measure how AI can accelerate biological research in the wet lab. Using GPT-5 to optimize a molecular cloning protocol, the work explores both the promise and risks of AI-assisted experimentation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/accelerating-biological-research-in-the-wet-lab 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in .NET 10 and C# 14: Optimizations in log aggregation jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:55:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 is officially out, along with C# 14. Microsoft has released .NET 10 as Long-Term Support (LTS) as a successor to .NET 8. Like every version, it is not just an update but brings something new to the table. In this series, we will explore which aspects of software
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/new-in-net-10-and-c-14-optimizations-in-log-aggregation-jobs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt Noise Is Killing Your AI Accuracy: How to Optimize Context for Grounded Output</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 01:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The most common reason an AI system “hallucinates” in production isn’t that the model is dumb. It’s that we’re drowning it. In the last year, many teams have quietly adopted a pattern that looks sophisticated on paper: throw everything into the prompt. Policies, API schemas, examples, edge cases, brand voice, product specs, meeting notes, customer […] The article Prompt Noise Is Killing Your AI Accuracy: How to Optimize Context for Grounded Output was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[C# Tip] How to create and access custom C# Attributes by using Reflection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In C#, Attributes are a handy mechanism to attach metadata to your classes, methods, properties, etc. In this article, we will see how to create custom Attributes and access them at runtime using Reflection.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/custom-csharp-attributes-reflection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new ChatGPT Images is here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new ChatGPT Images is powered by our flagship image generation model, delivering more precise edits, consistent details, and image generation up to 4× faster. The upgraded model is rolling out to all ChatGPT users today and is also available in the API as GPT-Image-1.5.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/new-chatgpt-images-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
