<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 08:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Serializing Objects: Efficient Serialization and Deserialization of Collections with JsonSerializer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article demonstrates the ease of serializing and deserializing collections using JsonSerializer.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/03/serializing-objects-efficient-serialization-and-deserialization-of-collections-with-jsonserializer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedded Resources in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 06:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve covered resources in a couple of our previous articles. In Localization in ASP.NET Core, we delved into .NET localization, touching upon resources since XML files utilized for localization fall under .NET resources. We also discussed resources in our article, How to Read a String From a .resx (Resource) File in C#, where we explored […] The post Embedded Resources in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>加入 Microsoft Build 2024 的 .NET 团队！</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 03:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Mehul Harry的 Join the .NET Team at Microsoft Build 2024! 倒计时已经开始！ Microsoft Build 2024 即将到来，如果您是 .NET 爱好者，请准备好迎接一系列精彩的会议。 无论您是经验丰富的开发人员还是刚刚开始您的开发之旅，每个人都能找到适合自己的东西。 活动形式：混合体验 无论您是在西雅图还是在舒适的家中，都可以加入我们。 通过现场和在线会议的相结合，您不会错过任何精彩内容。 深入了解 .NET：不容错过的会议 请查看下面的会议，了解即将到来的活动。 如需了解更多详情并预订席位，请务必访问会议链接。 时间（太平洋夏令时间） 会议标题 格式 地点 链接 5 月 22 日下午 1:00 使用 .NET Aspire 揭秘云原生开发 分组讨论 西雅图 + 在线 查看会议 5 月 22 日下午 2:15 使用 Visual Studio 系列在任何操作系统上进行 .NET Aspire 开发 分组讨论 西雅图 + 在线 查看会议 5 月 23 日上午 8:30 C# 13 中的新增功能 分组讨论 西雅图 + 在线 查看会议 5 月 23 日上午 11:00 将 AI 融入您的 .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Print a 2D Array to the Console in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 05:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to print a 2D array to the console using C#. Whether we are handling complex data structures or simply organizing information efficiently, understanding how to manipulate 2D arrays is a valuable skill. Let’s begin. Understanding 2D Arrays First, let’s understand what 2D arrays are. A 2D or two-dimensional […] The post How to Print a 2D Array to the Console in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform IP Functions for Managing IP Addresses, CIDR Blocks, and Subnets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 03:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Terraform provides functions to manage and manipulate IP addresses and CIDR blocks. These functions are crucial for network automation and orchestration in cloud environments, enabling users to create, manage, and allocate network resources efficiently. This article shows how to use the Terraform IP functions, along with some practical examples to help you get the most […] The article Terraform IP Functions for Managing IP Addresses, CIDR Blocks, and Subnets was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter To Junior Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 46</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post A Letter To Junior Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 46 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss focus areas for junior developers to consider for becoming more effective. The post A Letter To Junior Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 46 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/06/01/a-letter-to-junior-developers-dev-leader-weekly-46/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With EasyCaching in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 05:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            EasyCaching is an open-source caching library that helps us manage caching more easily, and flexibly and it’s an alternative to ASP.NET Core’s out-of-the-box caching library. Caching is a prevalent and useful technique for improving the performance of web applications. By caching frequently accessed data, you can minimize the frequent use of SQL queries, API calls, […] The post Getting Started With EasyCaching in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Lookup Function – Usage and Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 03:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Terraform lookup() function provides a powerful feature that can be used to implement more flexible and easily configurable infrastructure configurations. The lookup() function is essential for retrieving values from maps dynamically. This article explains Terraform maps, in case you’re not familiar yet, and the explores the Terraform lookup() function with usage examples and a […] The article Terraform Lookup Function – Usage and Examples was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Slice Architecture: Structuring Vertical Slices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of organizing your project across layers? Vertical Slice Architecture is a compelling alternative to traditional layered architectures.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/vertical-slice-architecture-structuring-vertical-slices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (May 2024): Dedicated Pages for Each Package on vcpkg.io</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 19:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.05.24 release as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout May. This month’s update also includes individual pages for each package on the vcpkg website as well as several new documentation articles.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-may-2024-dedicated-pages-for-each-package-on-vcpkg-io 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluid Framework 2 generally available in June</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 16:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the exciting new features in Fluid Framework 2 including SharedTree DDS, SharePoint Embedded support, Fluid DevTools, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/fluid-framework-2-generally-available-in-june 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-training genomic language models using AWS HealthOmics and Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Genomic language models are a new and exciting field in the application of large language models to challenges in genomics. In this blog post and open source project, we show you how you can pre-train a genomics language model, HyenaDNA, using your genomic data in the AWS Cloud. Here, we use AWS HealthOmics storage as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pre-training-genomic-language-models-using-aws-healthomics-and-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falcon 2 11B is now available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 15:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the first model in the next generation Falcon 2 family, the Falcon 2 11B foundation model (FM) from Technology Innovation Institute (TII), is available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. Falcon 2 11B is a trained dense decoder model on a 5.5 trillion token dataset […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/falcon-2-11b-is-now-available-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock in support of GDPR (right to be forgotten) requests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 15:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) right to be forgotten, also known as the right to erasure, gives individuals the right to request the deletion of their personally identifiable information (PII) data held by organizations. This means that individuals can ask companies to erase their personal data from their systems and from the systems of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implementing-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-in-support-of-gdpr-right-to-be-forgotten-requests/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A graphical depiction of the steps in building a C&#43;&#43; executable, with XAML and packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleshing out the diagram.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240531-00/?p=109825 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set the Exit Code for a Console Application in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 05:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to set the exit code for a console application in .NET. Let’s dive in. What Are Exit Codes Exit codes are integer values we return after executing a process. A zero exit code usually indicates success, while a non-zero code indicates an error. For a complete list of […] The post How to Set the Exit Code for a Console Application in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell: Automate Terraform Install on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 03:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While HashiCorp Terraform is a single executable, it’s really useful to install it on the local machine so the terraform.exe executable can be run from anywhere. To do this, Terraform needs to be downloaded, placed somewhere on the local machine, and then that path must be added to the system PATH environment variable. I’ve done […] The article PowerShell: Automate Terraform Install on Windows was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bulkhead Pattern: How To Make Your System Fault-tolerant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 20:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Keep one small part of your system from taking down the entire system. Let’s look at the bulkhead pattern, the various ways you think about it, and how it applies to your architecture, which will help you with fault tolerance to keep your system running. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of… Read More »The Bulkhead Pattern: How To Make Your System Fault-tolerant The post The Bulkhead Pattern: How To Make Your System Fault-tolerant appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBRE and AWS perform natural language queries of structured data using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 19:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with CBRE. CBRE is the world’s largest commercial real estate services and investment firm, with 130,000 professionals serving clients in more than 100 countries. Services range from financing and investment to property management. CBRE is unlocking the potential of artificial intelligence (AI) to realize value across the entire commercial […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cbre-and-aws-perform-natural-language-queries-of-structured-data-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Refactoring tools in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 19:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code refactoring is the process of restructuring existing code, while its outward functionality remains unchanged. By refactoring, you can simplify complex code structures, reduce code redundancy, and enhance code reusability. Visual Studio offers many tools to help refactor your C++ code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-refactoring-tools-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic video content moderation and policy evaluation using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations across media and entertainment, advertising, social media, education, and other sectors require efficient solutions to extract information from videos and apply flexible evaluations based on their policies. Generative artificial intelligence (AI) has unlocked fresh opportunities for these use cases. In this post, we introduce the Media Analysis and Policy Evaluation solution, which uses AWS […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dynamic-video-content-moderation-and-policy-evaluation-using-aws-generative-ai-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitech uses Amazon Bedrock to revolutionize information access with AI-powered chatbot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Murthy Palla and Madesh Subbanna from Vitech. Vitech is a global provider of cloud-centered benefit and investment administration software. Vitech helps group insurance, pension fund administration, and investment clients expand their offerings and capabilities, streamline their operations, and gain analytical insights. To serve their customers, Vitech maintains a repository of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/vitech-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-revolutionize-information-access-with-ai-powered-chatbot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Microsoft Build: Docker’s Innovations with AI and Windows on Arm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 17:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows is back! Docker CTO Justin Cormack talks about this and other takeaways from Microsoft Build 2024, including recently announced (and long-awaited) Docker Desktop support for Windows on Arm.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/highlights-from-microsoft-build/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch Up on Microsoft Build 2024: Essential Sessions for .NET Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get up to date on all of the .NET sessions from Microsoft Build 2024 covering .NET 9, .NET Aspire, .NET MAUI, ASP.NET Core, EF Core, and so much more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/catching-up-on-microsoft-build-2024-essential-sessions-for-dotnet-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in the Windows Subsystem for Linux in May 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 16:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For this year’s Microsoft BUILD conference, we are thrilled to announce significant updates to WSL. This blog post will provide an overview of these enhancements and the recent developments in WSL. Memory, storage and networking improvements WSL Settings GUI application coming soon WSL Zero Trust Manage WSL in Dev Home,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/whats-new-in-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux-in-may-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Loop transforms the way developer teams work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 15:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Microsoft Loop provides a central and flexible place for your work to help you stay in sync and on track.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-loop-transforms-the-way-developer-teams-work 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A graphical depiction of the steps in building a C&#43;&#43; executable, enhanced for classic Win32</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adding in Microsoft-specific tools.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240530-00/?p=109823 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VBScript deprecation: Timelines and next steps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 11:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scripting options for web development and task automation are modernizing. To provide you with the most modern and efficient options, we are replacing VBScript with more advanced alternatives such as JavaScript and PowerShell. Find out what VBScript deprecation means for you and how you can get ready.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/vbscript-deprecation-timelines-and-next-steps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Comparing Key Search Methods in Dictionaries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article compares two key search methods in dictionaries: using Contains() on the Keys collection and ContainsKey() method directly on the dictionary. It demonstrates examples for both approaches, highlighting Microsoft&#39;s recommendation of using ContainsKey(). The article suggests further examination of the performance aspect of these methods.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/30/code-it-any-way-you-want-comparing-key-search-methods-in-dictionaries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.18 with reporters, better CI support, and improved Azure API Center integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to share the launch of Dev Proxy v0.18 to help you to build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-18-with-reporters-better-ci-support-and-improved-azure-api-center-integration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lookup in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 05:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we build our .NET applications, we commonly use dictionaries to store data as key-value pairs. However, dictionaries do not allow us to map multiple values to a single key. In this article, let’s explore the Lookup class in C# and discuss how we can use it to handle this challenge. Without further ado, let’s […] The post Lookup in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.com/csharp-lookup/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.1.2: What’s New!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 18:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.1.2 is here with features designed to enhance your productivity and streamline your development workflow. This update includes support for DRF viewsets and routers in the Endpoints tool window, code assistance for TypedDict and Unpack, and improved debugger performance when handling large collections. You can download the latest version from our download page or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/05/pycharm-2024-1-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do more in Microsoft Mesh with data and AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 18:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how you can get started leveraging AI to elevate your custom Microsoft Mesh experience with the Mesh Toolkit.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/do-more-in-microsoft-mesh-with-data-and-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F# developer stories: how we’ve finally fixed a 9-year-old performance issue</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some bugs carry exciting narratives — attempting to resolve them lets you trace the history of the repository and the community.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/fsharp-developer-stories-how-weve-finally-fixed-a-9yearold-performance-issue 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DirectSR Preview Available Now</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 17:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the evolving landscape of Super Resolution (SR), GPU hardware vendors have set the stage with their respective technologies – AMD FidelityFX™ Super Resolution, Intel XeSS, and NVIDIA DLSS Super Resolution. These cutting-edge solutions elevate the gaming experience by boosting frame rates while maintaining exceptional visual quality.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directsr-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance image search experiences with Amazon Personalize, Amazon OpenSearch Service, and Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 16:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A variety of different techniques have been used for returning images relevant to search queries. Historically, the idea of creating a joint embedding space to facilitate image captioning or text-to-image search has been of interest to machine learning (ML) practitioners and businesses for quite a while. Contrastive Language–Image Pre-training (CLIP) and Bootstrapping Language-Image Pre-training (BLIP) […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-image-search-experiences-with-amazon-personalize-amazon-opensearch-service-and-amazon-titan-multimodal-embeddings-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-end LLM training on instance clusters with over 100 nodes using AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to accelerate the full pre-training of LLM models by scaling up to 128 trn1.32xlarge nodes, using a Llama 2-7B model as an example. We share best practices for training LLMs on AWS Trainium, scaling the training on a cluster with over 100 nodes, improving efficiency of recovery from system and hardware failures, improving training stability, and achieving convergence.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/end-to-end-llm-training-on-instance-clusters-with-over-100-nodes-using-aws-trainium/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune large multimodal models using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large multimodal models (LMMs) integrate multiple data types into a single model. By combining text data with images and other modalities during training, multimodal models such as Claude3, GPT-4V, and Gemini Pro Vision gain more comprehensive understanding and improved ability to process diverse data types. The multimodal approach allows models to handle a wider range […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-large-multimodal-models-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A graphical depiction of the steps in building a C&#43;&#43; executable, basics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 15:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A high-level overview.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240529-25/?p=109818 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A modern Extension Manager has arrived with Visual Studio 17.10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 14:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re bringing our updated Extension Manager to all users! Over the last year, we’ve made our updated Extension Manager available as an optional preview feature and have been asking you to let us know what you think. Based on your incredible feedback,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-extension-manager-17-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2024: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 14:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An overview of the latest updates in Microsoft Entra for May 2024. Discover how these new capabilities can be integrated into your projects for optimal performance and security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-may-24 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Major Bug-Fix Release for All Versions: Update Your Server Now</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Summary Details Earlier this year, several critical vulnerabilities were discovered in TeamCity. If abused, the flaws might have enabled an unauthenticated attacker with HTTP(S) access to a TeamCity server to bypass the authentication checks and gain administrative control of the TeamCity server. All versions of TeamCity On-Premises through 2023.11.3 were affected by these vulnerabilities. Customers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/05/teamcity-major-bug-fix-release-for-all-versions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Hackathon, Powered by Google</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’re passionate about new technology and always excited to share our latest in-house fun. This April, we kicked off our internal AI Hackathon in collaboration with Google and with the support of our internal JetBrains AI and AI Assistant team. It was designed to get our teammates to step out of their daily […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/05/jetbrains-ai-hackathon-powered-by-google/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAP: JetBrains Qodana Now Supports C and C&#43;&#43; for In-Depth Code Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Qodana was created to help teams improve code quality across multiple languages. In light of this, we’ve recently launched the EAP for Qodana’s C and C++ linter, a tool designed to run static code analysis and provide deep insights into your work. In this post, we’ll dive into the essential features of Qodana’s C and C++ linter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/05/new-release-in-eap-stage-jetbrains-qodana-s-c-and-c-linter-provides-in-depth-code-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perform Vector Database Similarity Search in .NET Apps using Build5Nines.SharpVector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ability to efficiently search and retrieve documents based on their semantic content has become increasingly important; especially when it comes to building Generative AI systems that implement the Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) design pattern. One powerful approach to achieving this is through the use of vector representations of text data, which enables similarity search […] The article Perform Vector Database Similarity Search in .NET Apps using Build5Nines.SharpVector was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 Things You Didn’t Know About JetBrains Rider’s NuGet Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 09:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing package managers into the modern development workflow has been nothing short of transformative. If you’ve been a .NET developer for a long time, you may remember when we shared .dll files on community sites and consumed them from a lib folder at the root of our solution. Thanks to NuGet, those dark days of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/29/9-things-you-didn-t-know-about-jetbrains-rider-s-nuget-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Exercise Caution When Employing ContainsKey() with Dictionary Types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article highlights the potential performance issues of using ContainsKey() with Dictionary types in Microsoft .NET, advocating for the adoption of TryGetValue() instead. By employing TryGetValue(), the double lookup process is avoided, resulting in improved efficiency and code readability, as demonstrated through benchmark results and recommendations for custom dictionary types.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/29/microsoft-net-code-analysis-exercise-caution-when-employing-containskey-with-dictionary-types/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular Monolith Architecture In .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 06:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss the concept of Modular Monolith Applications, and how they compare with traditional Monoliths and Microservices. We will also explain the different communication patterns we can implement between our modules. In the last decade, most enterprise businesses have switched from monolith applications to microservice applications because monolith applications have coupling […] The post Modular Monolith Architecture In .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding interactivity with Blazor?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week I was working on a client project when I ran into a requirement to show a checkbox as part of a form. Pretty straightforward right? However I hit a bit of a stumbling block when I realised I needed to tweak the appearance of the checkbox (to better match the style of the application). It turns out there are limits to how far you can tweak the default checkbox using HTML and CSS.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – Build 2024 Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 22:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces Azure Developer CLI (azd) support for AI Studio and the new templates to build and deploy AI applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-build-2024-recap 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Year of JasperFx Software</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 21:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After about 25 years or so in the software industry, I finally founded my own business named JasperFx Software last year at about this time with the general strategy of building a services and product company around the “Critter Stack” tools (Marten, Wolverine, Weasel, and soon to be some others) as well as any or … Continue reading One Year of JasperFx Software →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/28/one-year-of-jasperfx-software/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrator’s Introduction to Azure IoT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 20:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Internet of Things (IoT) industry has continued to grow and become more pervasive in people’s everyday lives these last few years. There are MANY useful applications for IoT devices and solutions in both the consumer and industrial space. Some of the solutions we’ve become accustomed to are smart speakers, cameras, Amazon Alexa, and many […] The article Administrator’s Introduction to Azure IoT appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 19:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month, we are releasing fixes that impact our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. The following version of the product has been patched. Azure DevOps Server 2019.1.2 Patch 9 If you have Azure DevOps Server 2019.1.2, you should install Azure DevOps Server 2019.1.2 Patch 9.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/may-patches-for-azure-devops-server-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build 2024: What’s new for Microsoft Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 18:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how you can expand the knowledge of Copilot for Microsoft 365 with Microsoft Graph connectors and build custom solutions leveraging the data and services in Microsoft Graph APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-2024-whats-new-for-microsoft-graph 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VisualStudio.Extensibility 17.10: Debug your extensions with the Diagnostics Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 18:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine creating extensions that run faster and smoother than ever before! If you haven’t been following along lately, we’ve been working on improving the VisualStudio.Extensibility SDK. VisualStudio.Extensibility helps you build extensions that run outside the main IDE process for improved performance and reliability.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visualstudio-extensibility-17-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build 2024 Recap: Bridging the chasm between your ML and app devs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 17:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week, Semantic Kernel had a huge milestone during Microsoft Build. Both its Python and Java libraries achieved V1.0 status, guaranteeing that neither of them would have breaking changes for non-experimental features moving forward. This is a big deal for our customers,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/build-2024-recap-bridging-the-chasm-between-your-ml-and-app-devs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DXC 1.8.2405 Available Now, Including HLSL 202x</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The HLSL team is excited to announce DXC 1.8.2405 which is a packed release! In addition to a healthy assortment of bug fixes and quality of life improvements, this release features two things we’re really excited about. First this is the first DXC release to contain Windows binaries built with Clang alongside the binaries built with MSVC,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/dxc-1-8-2405-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code CMake Tools Extension 1.18 Update: Quick Start with CMake and more…</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 16:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The May release of CMake Tools in VS Code is now available. With this release, we have some new updates to the extension to improve CMake integrations with the extension’s support. Some major highlights include improvements to the CMake: Quick Start command and support for CMake presets v7 and v8.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-code-cmake-tools-extension-1-18-update-quick-start-with-cmake-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Windows Containers Support for BuildKit Released in v0.13.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are introducing experimental support for Windows Containers in BuildKit, with the aim of making this available soon in your standard Docker Build.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/experimental-windows-containers-support-for-buildkit-released-in-v0-13-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I force a DLL to register itself if it won’t respond to regsvr32?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can&#39;t force something that isn&#39;t there.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240528-00/?p=109815 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with YAML in Terraform using the `yamldecode` and `yamlencode` Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The functions built into and supported by HashiCorp Terraform include the yamldecode and yamlencode functions for working with YAML data. These functions enable seamless integration and manipulation of YAML within Terraform configurations, enhancing the flexibility and manageability of infrastructure setups. This article explains their usage, and provides some practical applications. Decoding YAML with yamldecode Function […] The article Working with YAML in Terraform using the yamldecode and yamlencode Functions appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking primary constructor member capture using a Roslyn Analyzer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe a Rosyln analyzer you can use to enforce that primary constructors are only used for initialization and never to capture as fields
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/blocking-primary-constructor-member-capture-using-an-analyzer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.2 EAP Digest #1: Better Tools Configuration Support, Svelte 5, Git Enhancements, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 08:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve kicked off WebStorm 2024.2 with a new Early Access Program (EAP). Please check out this blog post, where we explain the benefits of the program. If you haven’t already seen what to expect in WebStorm 2024.2, take a moment to explore our roadmap. The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the EAP […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/05/webstorm-2024-2-eap1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Azure DevOps Copilot using .NET 8, Semantic Kernel and Azure OpenAI GPT-4o</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 09:35:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to create an Azure DevOps Copilot that utilizes a small subset of the Azure DevOps REST API. To achieve this, we will be using Semantic Kernel along with .NET 8 and Azure OpenAI.
Link to article: https://www.mytechramblings.com/posts/building-an-azure-devops-copilot-using-semantic-kernel-and-azure-openai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fastest Ways to Perform Base 10 Conversions in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 05:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2024/28_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Performing base 10 conversions is fundamental when learning basic computer science and mathematical concepts. Since we know computer systems understand binary, such conversions can help us form different number representations that we can use for various applications such as encoding and cryptography. In this article, we will explore the fastest way to convert a base […] The post Fastest Ways to Perform Base 10 Conversions in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing links to source code for .NET API Docs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET API reference docs now link directly to the source code! Learn how the links are generated, and some of ideas for future improvements.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-docs-link-to-source-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there any difference between String­From­IID and String­From­CLSID?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not really.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240527-00/?p=109812 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to test a Roslyn analyzer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you write a Roslyn analyzer, you should also write tests for it. The Roslyn SDK provides a set of NuGet packages that you can use to test your analyzers. In this post, I describe how to test a Roslyn analyzer using the Roslyn SDK NuGet packages. First, Roslyn SDK NuGet packages are not available on NuGet.org. You need to add the following package source to your project file:…
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Microsoft Copilot for Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot for Azure is an AI-powered tool designed to enhance your efficiency and productivity when working with Azure. Leveraging advanced Large Language Models (LLMs) and the Azure control plane, Copilot for Azure provides deep insights and simplifies the management of Azure services and resources. It aims to streamline operations across both cloud and edge […] The article Introducing Microsoft Copilot for Azure appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Collection Examination: A Comparative Analysis of Predicate Methods in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores four methods for examining items in a collection using predicates, with a focus on performance. A Twitter poll revealed that over 50% of developers favored the LINQ Any() method, prompting the author to verify its efficiency in comparison to other options like Count() and Exists().
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/27/optimizing-collection-examination-a-comparative-analysis-of-predicate-methods-in-c/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C#12 引入主构造函数：简化代码重构</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 07:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译于David Pine的这篇文章：Refactor your C# code with primary constructors 作为 .NET 8 一部分的 C# 12 引入了一组引人注目的新功能！ 在这篇文章中，我们将探讨其中一个功能，特别是主构造函数，解释其用法和相关性。 然后，我们将演示一个重构示例，以展示如何将其应用到您的代码中，并讨论其好处和潜在的缺陷。 这将帮助您了解这一更改的影响并有助于您决定是否采用该功能。 主构造函数1️⃣ 主构造函数被认为是一项“C#日常”的开发人员功能。 它们允许您在一个简洁的声明中定义类或结构及其构造函数。 这可以帮助您减少需要编写的样板代码量。 如果您一直在关注 C# 版本，您可能熟悉记录类型，其中包括主构造函数的第一个示例。 与记录类型的区别 记录类型作为类或结构的类型修饰符引入，这简化了构建简单类（如数据容器）的语法。 记录可以包括主构造函数。 该构造函数不仅生成一个支持字段，而且还为每个参数公开一个公共属性。 与传统的类或结构类型不同，在传统的类或结构类型中，主构造函数参数可以在整个类定义中访问，而记录被设计为透明的数据容器。 他们本质上支持基于值的相等，这与他们作为数据持有者的预期角色相一致。 因此，它们的主构造函数参数可以作为属性访问是合乎逻辑的。 重构示例✨ .NET 提供了许多模板，如果您曾经创建过Worker Service，您可能见过以下Worker类模板代码： namespace Example.Worker.Service { public class Worker : BackgroundService { private readonly ILogger
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/c12-%e5%bc%95%e5%85%a5%e4%b8%bb%e6%9e%84%e9%80%a0%e5%87%bd%e6%95%b0%ef%bc%9a%e7%ae%80%e5%8c%96%e4%bb%a3%e7%a0%81%e9%87%8d%e6%9e%84 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a Microsoft Entra ID external authentication method using ASP.NET Core and OpenIddict</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 05:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article shows how to implement a Microsoft Entra ID external authentication method (EAM) using ASP.NET Core, OpenIddict and FIDO2/passkeys. The application using ASP.NET Core Identity to manage the accounts and the passkeys. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/MfaServer The following flow diagram from the Microsoft docs explains how EAM works. Refer to the documentation for a full explanation. […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/05/27/implement-a-microsoft-entra-id-external-authentication-method-using-asp-net-core-and-openiddict/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Compare Two Dictionaries in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 05:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2024/27_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will first explore several ways to compare two dictionaries in C#. Then, we will compare and rank the performance of these approaches using the BenchmarkDotNet library. When we work with Dictionary objects in C#, checking their equality is a common task we’re likely to encounter. Without further ado, let’s get started. […] The post How to Compare Two Dictionaries in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
