<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 22:45:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s new for Office Add-ins at Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 22:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog, the Office Platform team announces the new capabilities and features announced at Build 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/whats-new-for-office-add-ins-at-build-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Release of Semantic Kernel Python 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 19:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the release of the long-awaited Semantic Kernel Python SDK 1.0.0! This milestone version brings a plethora of enhancements and new features designed to empower AI and app developers with more robust and versatile tools. Exciting New Feature: Shared Prompts Across Languages One of the groundbreaking features of this release is the ability to share prompts across different programming languages.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-python-1-0-0-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating fashion product descriptions by fine-tuning a vision-language model with SageMaker and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 19:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to predict domain-specific product attributes from product images by fine-tuning a VLM on a fashion dataset using Amazon SageMaker, and then using Amazon Bedrock to generate product descriptions using the predicted attributes as input. So you can follow along, we’re sharing the code in a GitHub repository.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generating-fashion-product-descriptions-by-fine-tuning-a-vision-language-model-with-sagemaker-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New for C&#43;&#43; Developers in Visual Studio 2022 17.10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 18:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that Visual Studio 2022 version 17.10 is now generally available! This post summarizes the new features you can find in this release for C++. You can download Visual Studio 2022 from the Visual Studio downloads page or upgrade your existing installation by following the Update Visual Studio Learn page.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-for-cpp-developers-in-visual-studio-2022-17-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of Semantic Kernel Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 17:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last year we published the initial release of Semantic Kernel for Java. It has been nearly a year of work building and shaping this SDK to help developers quickly and idiomatically build intelligent Java apps with OpenAI. Throughout this time, all teams behind Semantic Kernel SDKs (for Python,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-the-general-availability-of-semantic-kernel-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you have to create a Windows Runtime Vector from C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, do it as late as possible</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stay with the std::vector until you really need the Window Runtime Vector.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240522-00/?p=109795 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Documentation Gets an AI-Powered Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 13:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the Docker Docs AI, a documentation assistant designed to provide instant, accurate answers directly from the Docker docs pages. Features include language options, answers from multiple sources, and contextual and debugging help.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-documentation-ai-powered-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Strategic Imperative of AI in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 13:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We examine the incredible growth of AI and explore its potential power to transform industries and help enterprises accelerate innovation.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/the-strategic-imperative-of-ai-in-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Output URL to Azure Portal for Azure Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp Terraform is an extremely powerful IaC tool for managing Microsoft Azure infrastructure through code, from the command-line, and from CI/CD tools like GitHub Actions or Terraform Cloud. Terraform is great for managing and deploying the configurations for Microsoft Azure resources, but tools like the Azure Portal are still needed to view the real Azure […] The article Terraform: Output URL to Azure Portal for Azure Resources appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Functions Flex Consumption Support for Java on Azure Developer Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 10:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Functions Flex Consumption has just been announced during Microsoft Build 2024 (Full details on this blog), we are excited to share that Flex Consumption is now also supported on Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ and Maven plugins for Azure Functions. With this support,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/announcing-flex-consumption-support-for-java-on-azure-developer-tools 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First preview of Visual Studio 2022 v17.11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 10:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the release of Visual Studio 2022 v17.11 Preview 1, the first preview of our next update for Visual Studio 2022. This preview focuses on quality-of-life improvements for all developers and workloads. See the release notes for full list of features.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/first-preview-of-visual-studio-2022-v17-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance: Exploring the Performance Impact of the ‘in’ Keyword in C# 7.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the impact of the &#39;in&#39; keyword in C# 7.2 on method parameters, ensuring reference treatment for enhanced performance. Explore a practical example and insights in our latest article.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/22/general-performance-exploring-the-performance-impact-of-the-in-keyword-in-c-7-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Global Default JSON Serialization Options in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 05:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JSON serialization is the process of transforming .NET objects into JSON format, which ensures data exchange within applications. Implementing global default JSON serialization settings in ASP.NET Core Web API maintains uniformity across applications. In this article, we’ll explore the various methods for setting global default JSON serialization options in the ASP.NET Core Web API. Before […] The post How to Set Global Default JSON Serialization Options in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announced at Build 2024: DiskANN-powered vector database, cross-region replication in vCore, and a new era of databases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 04:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Build 2024 kicked off this week aiming to answer the question “How will AI shape your future?” You’ll find the answer in the incredible lineup of sessions at this year’s event – featuring talks on generative AI, building copilots, cloud platforms,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/build2024-cosmos-roundup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing EAP for Vector Support in Azure SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 19:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are super excited to announce the Early Adopter Preview of Native Vector Support in Azure SQL Database and are currently accepting requests from customers who wish to participate. SQL beyond RDBMS Vector databases have gained a lot of prominence lately.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/announcing-eap-native-vector-support-in-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing NuGet 6.10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 18:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NuGet 6.10 is included in Visual Studio 2022 and .NET 8.0 out of the box. You can also download NuGet 6.10 for Windows, macOS, and Linux as a standalone executable. In NuGet 6.10, we introduce some exciting new features and bug fixes,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/nuget/announcing-nuget-6-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s a Vector Anyway?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 17:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s a bit of an understatement to say that Artificial Intelligence (AI), and specifically Generative AI, is at the top of every announcement, news feed, article and discussion lately. Not just in technology, but everywhere. There are a lot of things you to learn to understand not just how to use AI,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/whats-a-vector-anyway 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Announcements &amp; Updates from Microsoft Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our latest updates and announcements from Microsoft Build including .NET Aspire, .NET 9 Preview 4, C# 13, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-build-2024-announcements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a multimodal assistant with advanced RAG and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 16:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a new approach named multimodal RAG (mmRAG) to tackle those existing limitations in greater detail. The solution intends to address these limitations for practical generative artificial intelligence (AI) assistant use cases. Additionally, we examine potential solutions to enhance the capabilities of large language models (LLMs) and visual language models (VLMs) with advanced LangChain capabilities, enabling them to generate more comprehensive, coherent, and accurate outputs while effectively handling multimodal data
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How 20 Minutes empowers journalists and boosts audience engagement with generative AI on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 16:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Aurélien Capdecomme and Bertrand d’Aure from 20 Minutes. With 19 million monthly readers, 20 Minutes is a major player in the French media landscape. The media organization delivers useful, relevant, and accessible information to an audience that consists primarily of young and active urban readers. Every month, nearly 8.3 million 25–49-year-olds choose […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-20-minutes-empowers-journalists-and-boosts-audience-engagement-with-generative-ai-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel Time Plugin with Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 16:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to showcase a Semantic Kernel sample across all 3 languages: .NET, Python and Java! Today we’re going to dive into the Python version of the TimePlugin sample which is featured here. Prerequisites for the Azure OpenAI key or OpenAI key: As covered in our Python README.md or DEV_SETUP.md,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-time-plugin-with-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancements in the Kafka Connector for Azure Cosmos DB: A New Era of Scalability and Flexibility</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 16:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure Fabric team announced Azure Cosmos DB CDC source to an event stream in preview at BUILD 2024. This capability uses a brand new major version of The Azure Cosmos DB Kafka Connector behind the scenes, and we are also excited to introduce version 2.0 in beta preview!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/enhancements-in-the-kafka-connector-for-azure-cosmos-db-a-new-era-of-scalability-and-flexibility 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing joy and minimizing toil with great developer experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 15:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The future always starts with developers. They determine the speed of innovation, and never has that been more true than today, in the era of Generative AI. We’re already seeing GenAI have a profound impact on the way that we build applications and collaborate with our colleagues.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/maximizing-joy-and-minimizing-toil-with-great-developer-experiences 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Availability of .NET Aspire: Simplifying .NET Cloud-Native Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 15:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Aspire, the stack that streamlines development of .NET cloud-native services, is now generally available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-aspire-general-availability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Semantic Kernel to create a Restaurant Bookings Sample with Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 15:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, We’re looking forward to highlight a Python sample today focused on a Restaurant Bookings sample here. Booking Restaurant – Demo Application This sample provides a practical demonstration of how to leverage features from the Semantic Kernel to build a console application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/use-semantic-kernel-to-create-a-restaurant-bookings-sample-with-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WinGet.CommandNotFound</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 15:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce the release of WinGet.CommandNotFound! This PowerShell module is a feedback provider plugin for PowerShell that leverages the Windows Package Manager to provide suggestions for packages to install when a native command cannot be found. The command-line predictor feature in PowerShell enables this module to display WinGet packages as predictive suggestions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/winget-commandnotfound 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“@docker can you help me…”: An Early Look at the Docker Extension for GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 15:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the Docker extension for GitHub Copilot (@docker), a plugin that extends GitHub Copilot&#39;s technology to assist developers in working with Docker.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/preview-docker-extension-for-github-copilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and cost-effective multi-tenant LoRA serving with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 15:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a solution that addresses these challenges head-on using LoRA serving with Amazon SageMaker. By using the new performance optimizations of LoRA techniques in SageMaker large model inference (LMI) containers along with inference components, we demonstrate how organizations can efficiently manage and serve their growing portfolio of fine-tuned models, while optimizing costs and providing seamless performance for their customers. The latest SageMaker LMI container offers unmerged-LoRA inference, sped up with our LMI-Dist inference engine and OpenAI style chat schema.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust Security Principles for Generative AI &amp; LLMs in the Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s rapidly evolving digital landscape, enterprises face a constant barrage of cybersecurity threats. As organizations increasingly turn to cutting-edge technologies like Generative Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Large Language Models (LLMs) to drive innovation and efficiency, it’s crucial to ensure that robust security measures are in place. By applying the principles of Zero Trust, enterprises […] The article Zero Trust Security Principles for Generative AI &amp;amp; LLMs in the Enterprise appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts about primary constructors: 3 pros and 5 cons</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe some of the ways I like to use primary constructors and some of the things I don&#39;t like about them
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/thoughts-about-primary-constructors-3-pros-and-5-cons/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Expression-Bodied Methods vs. Traditional Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses the use of expression-bodied methods in .NET as an alternative to traditional methods for creating simple functions. It presents a comparison between the two methods in terms of syntax and performance. Despite the syntactical differences, benchmark results show that both methods demonstrate similar performance characteristics.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/21/code-it-any-way-you-want-expression-bodied-methods-vs-traditional-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the Best Immutable Dictionary for Your C# Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 08:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Make informed decisions when it comes to selecting the right immutable dictionary for your C# projects. Compare the performance and features of ReadOnlyDictionary, ImmutableDictionary, and FrozenDictionary
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/choosing-best-immutable-dictionary-csharp-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Error 500.19 - Internal Server Error</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 08:12:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was just asked how to troubleshoot an HTTP Error 500.19 - Internal Server Error when trying to launch an ASP.NET Core website on IIS. I have seen this error too many times for both ASP.NET and ASP.NET Core so decided to write a blog post asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/http-error-500-19-internal-server-error/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time .NET Error Reporting With Exceptionless</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 05:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2024/21_05_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to cover the Exceptionless library and see how to use it in an ASP.NET Core application. So let’s get started. What Is Exceptionless? Exceptionless is an open-source error and event reporting service. Once integrated into our applications, it helps us monitor and fix the exceptions that happen inside it. […] The post Real-Time .NET Error Reporting With Exceptionless appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing public preview of Bicep templates support for Microsoft Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 22:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the public preview of Bicep templates for Microsoft Graph resources. These templates introduce declarative infrastructure-as-code (IaC) capabilities for Microsoft Graph resources, initially targeting core Microsoft Entra ID resources. Define and deploy your tenant infrastructure, such as Entra ID groups or applications, using a Bicep file throughout the development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/bicep-templates-for-microsoft-graph-resources 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals Certification (AZ-900 Exam)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 17:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals certification with the AZ-900 exam tests and validates a candidates foundational knowledge of the cloud and Microsoft Azure. This exam is ideal for individuals from both technical and non-technical backgrounds who want to demonstrate their understanding of cloud concepts, Azure services, and Azure management and governance. Why You Should Earn […] The article Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals Certification (AZ-900 Exam) appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Tenancy: Marten’s “Conjoined” Model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 17:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is continuing a series about multi-tenancy with Marten, Wolverine, and ASP.Net Core: Let’s say that you definitely have the need for multi-tenanted storage in your system, but don’t expect enough data to justify splitting the tenant data over multiple databases, or maybe you just really don’t want to mess with all the extra overhead … Continue reading Multi-Tenancy: Marten’s “Conjoined” Model →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/20/multi-tenancy-martens-conjoined-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipating the future of physical systems design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rising complexity, IP intensity and need for security of physical systems products requires a transformation in how to develop, manufacture and operate these systems. To meet time-to-market demands, software developers and hardware producers alike need optimized cloud + AI solutions that can provide higher levels of collaboration,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/anticipating-the-future-of-physical-systems-design 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Semantic Kernel to create a Restaurant Bookings Sample with .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 15:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, With Microsoft Build approaching, we wanted to share some walk throughs and samples of Semantic Kernel. Today we’re going to dive into a Restaurant booking sample to showcase multiple features of Semantic Kernel. This sample provides a practical demonstration of how to leverage features from the Semantic Kernel to build a console application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/use-semantic-kernel-to-create-a-restaurant-bookings-sample-with-net 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you know what interface you want, just pass it directly to CoCreateInstance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Avoiding a second round trip.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240520-00/?p=109782 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline the Development of Real-Time AI Applications with MindsDB Docker Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With MindsDB, you can build AI-powered applications easily, even with no AI/ML experience. Follow along to learn how to set up MindsDB in Docker Desktop.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mindsdb-docker-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Check Your Docker Installation: Docker Desktop vs. Docker Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 13:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn the difference between Docker Desktop vs. Docker Engine, how to check your Docker version, and more.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/blog-how-to-check-docker-version/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dapper And Strongly Typed IDs – How To Dynamically Register Mappings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Dapper And Strongly Typed IDs – How To Dynamically Register Mappings appeared first on Dev Leader.How can we use Dapper and strongly typed IDs from the StronglyTypedId package? Let&#39;s see if we can generalize the guidance from the original author! The post Dapper And Strongly Typed IDs – How To Dynamically Register Mappings appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/05/20/dapper-and-strongly-typed-ids-how-to-dynamically-register-mappings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roslyn analyzers: How to</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post contains a collection of samples for writing Roslyn analyzers. It&#39;s a living document that I will update over time. Find an IMethodSymbol from a compilation var type = compilation.GetTypeByMetadataName(&amp;quot;System.Threading.Tasks.Task&amp;quot;) var methods = type.GetMembers(&amp;quot;GetAwaiter&amp;quot;).OfType(); If you want a specific method when there are multiple overloads, you can use the…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/roslyn-analyzers-how-to.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Certifications – Prove Your Expertise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 11:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Keeping up with GitHub requires lots of skill mastery. GitHub is a platform used by over 100 million developers worldwide and offers a suite of certifications designed to elevate your development prowess and demonstrate your mastery of its powerful tools. Whether you’re a software developer, DevOps Engineer, SRE, security specialist, or IT professional, GitHub’s certifications […] The article GitHub Certifications – Prove Your Expertise appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance Tip: Retrieving the Nullable Value from a Reference Type</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses two methods for retrieving nullable values from reference types in C#, showcasing examples using the ternary conditional expression and the null coalesce approach. Benchmark results indicate that the null coalesce approach demonstrates 1.12 times higher efficiency in performance compared to the ternary conditional expression.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/20/general-performance-tip-retrieving-the-nullable-value-from-a-reference-type/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Filter a List Based on Another List In C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 05:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2024/20_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Lists in C# are one of the most ubiquitous data structures. We perform all kinds of operations on them, such as appending, inserting, removing, sorting, and filtering. In this article, we’ll focus on the latter – filtering. In particular, we’ll see how to use a list to filter other lists. We can achieve it in […] The post How to Filter a List Based on Another List In C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Tenancy: What is it and why do you care?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 21:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m always on the lookout for ideas about how to endlessly promote both Marten &amp;amp; Wolverine. Since I’ve been fielding a lot of questions, issues, and client requests around multi-tenancy support in both tools the past couple weeks, now seems to be a good time for a new series exploring the existing foundation in both … Continue reading Multi-Tenancy: What is it and why do you care? →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Must-Know AI Terms for Developers, SREs, and DevOps Engineers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 11:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is all the buzz today! But, what does LLM, SLM, Copilot, GPT, ML, NLP and all the other acronyms and terms in the AI space really mean? AI tools are quickly becoming an integral part of every Developers, DevOps Engineers, and Site Reliability Engineers (SREs) daily workflow. AI literacy and understanding key […] The article Top 10 Must-Know AI Terms for Developers, SREs, and DevOps Engineers appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Visual Basic to Visual Studio: A Journey Through Microsoft’s IDE Evolution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author shares their journey from Visual Basic 2 in 1992 to the latest tools like Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code (VS Code). They emphasize the evolution of Microsoft&#39;s IDEs for software, web, and database development. They advocate for a hybrid approach of using IDEs for efficiency and familiarizing with CLI commands for flexibility.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/19/from-visual-basic-to-visual-studio-a-journey-through-microsofts-ide-evolution/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View-Based Authorization in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 06:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2024/19_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            View-based authorization is an authorization strategy that enables us to manage UI elements’ visibility based on the user’s identity. In this article, we’ll take a look at how we can achieve view-based authorization in an ASP.NET core application. Let’s begin. What Is Authorization? Before we dive deeper into the implementation of view-based authorization, let’s take […] The post View-Based Authorization in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Generative AI App in C# with Phi-3-mini LLM and ONNX</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft recently released the new Phi-3-mini SLM (small language model), and I previously wrote about running Phi3 locally using Ollama. I’ve been exploring the world of hosting AI models in code lately, and this stuff is getting really interested. It turns out that among the tools to run AI models locally, there are developer tools […] The article Build a Generative AI App in C# with Phi-3-mini LLM and ONNX appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Burnout – Dev Leader Weekly 44</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Developer Burnout – Dev Leader Weekly 44 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss developer burnout and what you can do about it in your career! The post Developer Burnout – Dev Leader Weekly 44 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/05/18/developer-burnout-dev-leader-weekly-44/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a Cookie to an HttpClient Request/Response in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 04:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What are cookies? Websites send small pieces of text, known as internet cookies, to our browsers whenever we visit them. They help us have a personalized experience on that particular website and remember it for the next time we visit it. Our goal today is how to make that happen in ASP.NET Core. In this […] The post Add a Cookie to an HttpClient Request/Response in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EF Core Migrations: A Detailed Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_05_2024/18_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this newsletter, we&#39;ll break down the essentials of EF Migrations. We&#39;ll explore creating migrations, SQL scripts, applying migrations, migration tooling, and more.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/efcore-migrations-a-detailed-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Rocks The Bay.NET User Group</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 18:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The dotNetDave No Rest for the Wicked World Tour is holding a virtual session on code and app performance for Microsoft .NET, tailored to .NET 8, on June 20th. The session will cover optimizing code performance and minimizing memory footprint, with insights from the latest performance metrics outlined in the fourth edition of &amp;quot;Rock Your Code: Code &amp;amp; App Performance for Microsoft&amp;quot;. For more details, visit https://www.meetup.com/baynet/events/301041843.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Semantic Kernel to create a Restaurant Bookings Sample with Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re looking forward to highlight a Java sample today focused on a Restaurant Bookings sample here. Booking Restaurant – Demo Application This sample provides a practical demonstration of how to leverage features from the Semantic Kernel to build a console application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/use-semantic-kernel-to-create-a-restaurant-bookings-sample-with-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Semantic Kernel to create a Time Plugin with Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plugins are one of the most powerful features of Semantic Kernel and in this demo we show how you can easily use Plugins with the power of Auto Function Calling from AI Models with Java here. A Glimpse into the Demonstration Time Information Plugin In the demo we implement a simple class TimePlugin with one function to retrieve the UTC time in String format.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/using-semantic-kernel-to-create-a-time-plugin-with-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixtral 8x22B is now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 16:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the Mixtral-8x22B large language model (LLM), developed by Mistral AI, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy with one click for running inference. You can try out this model with SageMaker JumpStart, a machine learning (ML) hub that provides access to algorithms and models so you […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mixtral-8x22b-is-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Generative AI prompt chaining workflows with human in the loop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 15:51:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While Generative AI can create highly realistic content, including text, images, and videos, it can also generate outputs that appear plausible but are verifiably incorrect. Incorporating human judgment is crucial, especially in complex and high-risk decision-making scenarios. This involves building a human-in-the-loop process where humans play an active role in decision making alongside the AI system. In this blog post, you will learn about prompt chaining, how to break a complex task into multiple tasks to use prompt chaining with an LLM in a specific order, and how to involve a human to review the response generated by the LLM.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New capabilities for Microsoft Graph APIs for Teams meetings with external attendees</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn more about Microsoft Graph SMS notification and reminder APIs, now generally available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/new-capabilities-for-microsoft-graph-apis-for-teams-meetings-with-external-attendees 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can’t I find the injected name of a templated class’s templated base class?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The compiler needs help finding it because it&#39;s not findable at the time the template is parsed.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240517-00/?p=109774 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding at the Speed of Innovation: AI and more with Azure SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 13:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Build 2024 approaches, the Azure SQL Database team is preparing a great line-up of product announcements. Innovation continues to be a big theme as we prepare to showcase exciting experiences powered by SQL data and generative AI. The ideal starting point for the new generation of AI-ready SQL apps is Azure SQL Database,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/ai-and-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hub-and-Spoke Network Topology in Microsoft Azure using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A hub-and-spoke network topology is a popular design pattern used to manage and control network traffic when deploying enterprise workloads to Microsoft Azure. This article will guide you through deploying a hub-and-spoke network in Microsoft Azure using HashiCorp Terraform. We will cover the basic concepts, provide sample Terraform code, discuss security best practices to ensure […] The article Deploying Hub-and-Spoke Network Topology in Microsoft Azure using Terraform appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Exercise Caution When Using Take() with a Basic Count</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article advises caution when using the LINQ method Take() with a basic count, suggesting that a range might be recommended by code analyzers. However, benchmark results indicate that using Take() with a simple count is 1.63 times faster than employing a range in such cases.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/17/collection-performance-exercise-caution-when-using-take-with-a-basic-count/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplified State Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post advocates for a simplifying a complex network of states into simple states that correlate with user expectations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/simplified-state-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Source Generators to Validate IOptions in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 02:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look at how to use source generators to validate IOptions and ensure they meet the required configuration expectations. Let’s dive in! Why We Need to Validate IOptions In ASP.NET Core we have ample choice when it comes to configuration providers. This gives us freedom when choosing a way to set our […] The post Using Source Generators to Validate IOptions in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; at VS Code Day 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 21:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking to get caught up on new C++ features released in the last year? Check out the new YouTube video What’s New with C++ in VS Code posted for VS Code Day 2024. VS Code Day is an annual event hosted by the VS Code team which lets you elevate your development workflow with the latest and greatest features from Visual Studio Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/cpp-at-vs-code-day-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2405.15: Agility SDK 1.614 support and misc bug fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 21:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2405.15, which can be downloaded here. This release has a handful of bug fixes and also adds support for the Direct3D 12 Agility SDK version 1.614. Notably this SDK adds support for the 999e5 texture format.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2405-15 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLDR: Google I/O 2024 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 20:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Google I/O 2024 Keynote was a showcase of technological innovation, underscoring Google’s relentless pursuit of excellence in artificial intelligence (AI). With CEO Sundar Pichai, the event was a celebration of the significant strides made in the past year and a glimpse into the future of AI-driven advancements. Central to the keynote was the Gemini […] The article TLDR: Google I/O 2024 Keynote appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Permission Prompt API available for Office Add-ins on the web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 19:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft now requires Office Add-in developers to prompt users for permission to access their device capabilities. To do this, you can now implement the Device Permission API.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/device-permission-prompt-api-available-for-office-add-ins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine’s Test Support Diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 18:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m working on fixing a reported bug with Wolverine today and its event forwarding from Marten feature. I can’t say that I yet know why this should-be-very-straightforward-and-looks-exactly-like-the-currently-passing-tests bug is happening, but it’s a good time to demonstrate Wolverine’s automated testing support and even how it can help you to understand test failures. First off, and … Continue reading Wolverine’s Test Support Diagnostics →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/16/wolverines-test-support-diagnostics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility SDK 1.614.0: R9B9G9E5 support for Render Targets and UAVs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today the DirectX team is excited to announce the release of the Agility SDK 1.614.0 which includes full support for R9G9B9E5_SHAREDEXP (999E5) texture format for render targets and UAV read/writes! This new Agility SDK is also fully supported by PIX. To get the latest release head on over to our Agility SDK downloads page.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agility-sdk-1-614-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How LotteON built a personalized recommendation system using Amazon SageMaker and MLOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with HyeKyung Yang, Jieun Lim, and SeungBum Shim from LotteON. LotteON aims to be a platform that not only sells products, but also provides a personalized recommendation experience tailored to your preferred lifestyle. LotteON operates various specialty stores, including fashion, beauty, luxury, and kids, and strives to provide a personalized shopping […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-lotteon-built-a-personalized-recommendation-system-using-amazon-sagemaker-and-mlops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – May 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 15:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the May release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd), which includes a new demo mode, various .NET Aspire enhancements, and bug fixes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-may-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 14:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new season of our Early Access Program has officially started! The first EAP build for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 is now available for download, offering a sneak peek at some of the exciting updates in the pipeline. You can download the new version from our website, update directly from inside the IDE or via the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/05/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us at Build 2024: Get the latest on Azure Cosmos DB in Seattle or online!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 14:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you ready to dive into the future of AI and data innovation? Microsoft Build 2024 is just around the corner, taking place May 21–23 in Seattle and online. Azure Cosmos DB has lots in store at Build this year and you won’t want to miss it!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/join-us-at-build-2024-get-the-latest-on-azure-cosmos-db-in-seattle-or-online 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling a single item from a C&#43;&#43; parameter pack by its index</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Combining a few tools to make a new tool.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240516-00/?p=109771 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 13:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re glad to announce the opening of the RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program. In this blog post, we’ll share what you can expect in this release cycle. What’s coming in RubyMine 2024.2? In this update, our goal is to enhance your RubyMine experience by incorporating new AI features, improving remote work capabilities, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/05/rubymine-2024-2-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing with Accessibility in Mind at Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 13:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Celebrate the Global Accessibility Awareness Day GAAD by taking actionable and easy steps to build accessibility into your development life-cycle! Learn how tools like Accessibility Insights &amp;amp; Visual Studio can help find accessibility issues in development.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/developing-with-accessibility-in-mind-at-microsoft 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve your code quality with GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 12:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous post, we discussed GitHub Copilot’s Slash Commands, which allow you to trigger specific actions within Visual Studio with simple text-based inputs. Now, let’s explore the /optimize command and its potential to improve code quality in Visual Studio. Refactoring with /optimize In a recent exploration by Bruno Capuano,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/improve-your-code-quality-with-github-copilot-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload File from URL to Azure Blob Storage using Azure CLI with Bash and PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 11:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure CLI az storage blob upload command can be used to upload a local file into Azure Blob Storage. However, there are times when it would be easier to upload a file straight from the HTTP(S) URL into Azure Blob Storage. Unfortunately the Azure CLI does not have a command for this specific scenario, […] The article Upload File from URL to Azure Blob Storage using Azure CLI with Bash and PowerShell appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Performance Difference Between Static and Non-Static Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores the performance disparity between static and non-static methods, commonly recommended for efficiency by code analysis tools.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/16/code-it-any-way-you-want-performance-difference-between-static-and-non-static-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oren Eini – Building a Database Engine in C# and .NET – June 18th Livestream</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 05:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on June 18th, 2024, at 2:00 PM UTC on JetBrains TV for our latest livestream with our special guest, the prolific Oren Eini, when they give their presentation, “Building a Database Engine in C# and .NET”. Join Oren Eini, CEO of RavenDB, as he delves into the intricate process of constructing a database […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/16/oren-eini-building-a-database-engine-in-csharp-and-dotnet-june-18th-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Generate a Random Color Name in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 22:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to generate a random color name using the KnownColor enumeration. This enum is particularly useful in UI design and data visualization, as it provides a wide variety of preset colors. Let’s begin. Understanding the KnownColor Enumeration To understand why we would even need to generate a random color […] The post How to Generate a Random Color Name in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled Message Delivery with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 22:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine has the ability to schedule the delivery of messages for a later time. While Wolverine certainly isn’t trying to be Hangfire or Quartz.Net, the message scheduling in Wolverine today is valuable for “timeout” messages in sagas, or “retry this evening” type scenarios, or reminders of all sorts. If using the Azure Service Bus transport, … Continue reading Scheduled Message Delivery with Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/15/scheduled-message-delivery-with-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Looping Over a Collection Using Span and ReadOnlySpan</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores the performance benefits of utilizing Span and ReadOnlySpan for collection processing, highlighting advantages such as improved performance, reduced memory pressure, enhanced safety, and compatibility with modern API design. Span allows read-write access and efficient iteration with lightweight storage, while ReadOnlySpan provides read-only access to prevent accidental modifications, offering similar benefits for collection processing.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/15/collection-performance-looping-over-a-collection-using-span-and-readonlyspan/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Developers at Microsoft Build: Docker Unveils Integrations and Sessions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 18:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker&#39;s presence at Microsoft Build is more than just a showcase — it’s a portal to the future of application development. Visit our booth to interact with Docker experts, experience live demos, and explore the powerful capabilities of Docker Desktop and other Docker products.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-microsoft-build-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework May 2024 Servicing Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for May 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-may-2024-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless exam generator application from your own lecture content using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Crafting new questions for exams and quizzes can be tedious and time-consuming for educators. The time required varies based on factors like subject matter, question types, experience level, and class level. Multiple-choice questions require substantial time to generate quality distractors and ensure a single unambiguous answer, and composing effective true-false questions demands careful effort to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-exam-generator-application-from-your-own-lecture-content-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate NLP inference with ONNX Runtime on AWS Graviton processors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ONNX is an open source machine learning (ML) framework that provides interoperability across a wide range of frameworks, operating systems, and hardware platforms. ONNX Runtime is the runtime engine used for model inference and training with ONNX. AWS Graviton3 processors are optimized for ML workloads, including support for bfloat16, Scalable Vector Extension (SVE), and Matrix […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-nlp-inference-with-onnx-runtime-on-aws-graviton-processors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn how Amazon Ads created a generative AI-powered image generation capability using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Ads helps advertisers and brands achieve their business goals by developing innovative solutions that reach millions of Amazon customers at every stage of their journey. At Amazon Ads, we believe that what makes advertising effective is delivering relevant ads in the right context and at the right moment within the consumer buying journey. With that […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/learn-how-amazon-ads-created-a-generative-ai-powered-image-generation-capability-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing backward compatibility with Microsoft Graph PowerShell v2.19</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release introduces backward compatibility support to address the issues some of our users encountered with versions 2.17 and 2.18.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-backward-compatibility-with-microsoft-graph-powershell-v2-19 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data API builder becomes Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing Data API builder General Availability On May 15th, Data API builder becomes Generally Available. Data API builder for Azure SQL Databases – Generally Available It’s been a long road, getting from there to here. Nearly three years ago, Data API builder began as just a dream.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/data-api-builder-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready for Visual Studio at Build 2024: Join Thousands Online!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MICROSOFT BUILD 2024 Watch it Live! or On-Demand – Starting Next Tuesday! Next week, from May 21st, I’ll be diving into Microsoft Build 2024, and I invite you to come along for the ride—virtually! We’ll explore cutting-edge developments in Visual Studio,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-at-build-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get ready for Microsoft Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us at the upcoming Microsoft Build conference from May 21-23, 2024, online (for free) or in person in Seattle. Sit in on identity-focused breakout sessions and demos, while also exploring a broad range of talks on Microsoft’s latest developer tools and technologies. Network with industry leaders and like-minded professionals and create valuable connections at this dynamic event.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/get-ready-for-build-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Data API builder General Availability for Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            About Data API builder for Azure Databases Exciting news! The Data API Builder for Azure Cosmos DB is now officially available! Say goodbye to developer headaches when accessing databases for client applications. Requiring no code, the Data API Builder provides secure,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-data-api-builder-general-availability-for-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the most efficient device selector query that selects no devices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking for the most efficient way of rejecting everything.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240515-00/?p=109764 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Guide to Containerizing Llamafile with Docker for AI Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Walk through how to use Docker to containerize llamafile, an executable that brings together all the components needed to run an LLM chatbot with a single file.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/a-quick-guide-to-containerizing-llamafile-with-docker-for-ai-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering DevOps Engineers with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of technology, the role of DevOps Engineers is becoming increasingly complex and critical. As organizations strive for higher reliability and performance, increased automation workflows, and smoother release processes, the integration of generative AI technologies, such as those offered by Azure OpenAI, is revolutionizing the realm of DevOps. DevOps Engineers can now […] The article Empowering DevOps Engineers with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Default and per Request Timeout in HttpClient</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 03:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll demonstrate how to set a default request timeout for all requests and configure specific request timeout settings for individual requests using HttpClient. In modern software development, managing HTTP requests efficiently is vital for keeping our applications fast and reliable. The HttpClient enables us to effectively execute HTTP calls in .NET applications. […] The post Change Default and per Request Timeout in HttpClient appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
