<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 17:08:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Restricting PAT Creation in Azure DevOps Is Now in Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As organizations continue to strengthen their security posture, restricting usage of personal access tokens (PATs) has become a critical area of focus. With the latest public preview of the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/restricting-pat-creation-in-azure-devops-is-now-in-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and LangChain: Leading the Way in AI Security for Open Source on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 17:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For developers building in the field of AI, the industry moves so quickly that we often prioritise speed and execution over everything else. To keep up with the latest changes, many developers and enterpris
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//microsoft-and-langchain-leading-the-way-in-ai-security-for-open-source-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emit logs on-demand with log buffering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing logs in production environments involves tricky trade-offs. You want detailed logs when things go wrong, but you don&#39;t want to pay storage costs for logs that never get examined. While log sampling helps reduce log volume by emitting only a percentage of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/emit-logs-on-demand-with-log-buffering 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize and migrate on-premises fraud detection machine learning workflows to Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Radial is the largest 3PL fulfillment provider, also offering integrated payment, fraud detection, and omnichannel solutions to mid-market and enterprise brands. In this post, we share how Radial optimized the cost and performance of their fraud detection machine learning (ML) applications by modernizing their ML workflow using Amazon SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/modernize-and-migrate-on-premises-fraud-detection-machine-learning-workflows-to-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contextual retrieval in Anthropic using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Contextual retrieval enhances traditional RAG by adding chunk-specific explanatory context to each chunk before generating embeddings. This approach enriches the vector representation with relevant contextual information, enabling more accurate retrieval of semantically related content when responding to user queries. In this post, we demonstrate how to use contextual retrieval with Anthropic and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/contextual-retrieval-in-anthropic-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run small language models cost-efficiently with AWS Graviton and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy a small language model on SageMaker AI by extending our pre-built containers to be compatible with AWS Graviton instances. We first provide an overview of the solution, and then provide detailed implementation steps to help you get started. You can find the example notebook in the GitHub repo.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/run-small-language-models-cost-efficiently-with-aws-graviton-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Caching Done Right</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you need to scale your API, one of the first things developers often think about is, “Let’s just add a cache.” If API Caching were that simple. Adding caching introduces a whole new set of problems that you need to consider carefully to be successful with your caching strategy. In this article, I want… Read More »API Caching Done Right The post API Caching Done Right appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to filter C&#43;&#43; Build Insights by project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 15:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 version 17.14 comes with quality-of-life improvements to its C++ Build Insights integration that will make it easier for you to navigate large multi-project traces and handle long file names for your build inputs and artifacts.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-to-filter-c-build-insights-by-project 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Ceremony Railway Programming with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 15:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Railway Programming is an idea that came out of the F# community as a way to develop for “sad path” exception cases without having to resort to throwing .NET Exceptions as a way of doing flow control. Railway Programming works by chaining together functions with a standardized response in such a way that it’s relatively easy to abort … Continue reading Low Ceremony Railway Programming with Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do some Windows functions fail if I pass an unaligned Unicode string?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer found that if they passed Unicode strings (which in Windows means strings encoded as UTF-16LE using the two-byte data type wchar_t as code units) which are not on even addresses, then some—but not all—functions fail to accept those strings. Why isn&#39;t this documented? This is one of the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250605-00/?p=111250 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Plugin Metadata Management with SemanticPluginForge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of software development, flexibility and adaptability are key. Developers often face challenges when it comes to updating plugin metadata dynamically without disrupting services or requiring redeployment. This is where SemanticPluginForge, an open-source project, step
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/enhancing-plugin-metadata-management-with-semanticpluginforge 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarter SK Agents with Contextual Function Selection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 09:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Smarter SK Agents with Contextual Function Selection In today&#39;s fast-paced AI landscape, developers are constantly seeking ways to make AI interactions more efficient and relevant. The new Contextual Function Selection feature in the Semantic Kernel Agent Framework is here to address this need. By dynamically selecti
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/smarter-sk-agents-with-contextual-function-selection 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Waterfall Evaluation of Query Classification, Retrieval &amp; Generation in Multi-Agent LLM Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As organizations increasingly deploy multi-agent LLM systems to handle complex queries and workflows, the need for robust evaluation frameworks becomes crucial. Based on our recent work implementing hypothesis-driven experimentation for a large enterprise client, this post shares insights on building a hierarchical water
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/hierarchical-waterfall-evaluation-query-classification-rag-llm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.28 with LLM usage and costs tracking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 06:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce the release of Dev Proxy v0.28. This version introduces a new ability to help you understand language models’ usage and costs in your applications, alongside many improvements to mocking, TypeSpec generation, and plugin flexibility. In this version: New OpenAITelemetryPlugin to track language mode
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-28-with-llm-usage-and-costs-tracking 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disrupting malicious uses of AI: June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our June 2025 update, we outline how we’re disrupting malicious uses of AI—through safety tools that detect and counter abuse, support democratic values, and promote responsible AI deployment for the benefit of all.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/disrupting-malicious-uses-of-ai-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing GenAI Coding Risk Like an Investment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2025/05_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI tools have greatly improved in their ability to generate large amounts of code, quickly, to support software development tasks…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/genai-coding-investment-risk-strategy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impel enhances automotive dealership customer experience with fine-tuned LLMs on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 21:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Impel enhances the automotive dealership customer experience with fine-tuned LLMs on SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/impel-enhances-automotive-dealership-customer-experience-with-fine-tuned-llms-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch Up on Microsoft Build 2025: Essential Sessions for .NET Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Build 2025 is a wrap! We packed this year&#39;s conference with tons of cool stuff around AI-powered coding, cloud-native apps, and the future of .NET. If you missed the live event or just want to revisit the good parts, here&#39;s a roundup of can&#39;t-miss content you&#39;ll want to check out. [alert type=&amp;quot;note&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Note&amp;quot;]All sessions are now avail
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/catching-up-on-microsoft-build-2025-essential-sessions-for-dotnet-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How climate tech startups are building foundation models with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 16:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how climate tech startups are developing foundation models (FMs) that use extensive environmental datasets to tackle issues such as carbon capture, carbon-negative fuels, new materials design for microplastics destruction, and ecosystem preservation. These specialized models require advanced computational capabilities to process and analyze vast amounts of data effectively.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-climate-tech-startups-are-building-foundation-models-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your development with Claude Code and Amazon Bedrock prompt caching</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 16:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll explore how to combine Amazon Bedrock prompt caching with Claude Code—a coding agent released by Anthropic that is now generally available. This powerful combination transforms your development workflow by delivering lightning-fast responses from reducing inference response latency, as well as lowering input token costs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/supercharge-your-development-with-claude-code-and-amazon-bedrock-prompt-caching/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build like Microsoft: Developer agents in action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 15:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every day, developers tackle complex workflows involving planning, coding, reviewing, testing, securing, and releasing software. These tasks, often scattered across various tools and platforms, create friction that slows us down. At Microsoft, we believe AI can change that. This belief led us to create Athena, an AI-powered collaborative ag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-like-microsoft-developer-agents-in-action 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Management for Docker Desktop now generally available in the Admin Console</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 15:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce that Settings Management for Docker Desktop is now Generally Available! Settings Management can be configured in the Admin Console for customers with a Docker Business subscription. After a successful Early Access period, this powerful administrative solution has been enhanced with new compliance reporting capabilities, completing our vision for centralized Docker Desktop...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/settings-management-for-docker-desktop-now-generally-available-in-the-admin-console/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 14:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.2 has arrived with several valuable fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates included in this version: To find out more details about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/intellij-idea-2025-1-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riffing on a typo in the name of the opera &lt;i&gt;Turandot&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I turned on the radio in the car and heard what was identified by the Radio Data System information as a performance by the Metropolitan Opera of New York of Puccini&#39;s Turnadot. Whoever entered the information introduced a typo, because the correct spelling is Turan
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250604-01/?p=111247 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I programmatically find the network path by which a folder has been shared?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you right-click a folder in Explorer, select Properties, and go to the Sharing tab, there is a section titled &amp;quot;Network File and Folder Sharing&amp;quot;, and in there, it tells you the network path by which this folder has been shared. (Or &amp;quot;Not shared&amp;quot; if it hasn&#39;t been shared at all.) How can I obtain this path programmatically? There
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250604-00/?p=111245 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Truths About Developer Experience: Three Key Insights From Our Research</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 13:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developer experience (DevEx) and developer productivity (DP) are hot topics. Many companies are already working actively to measure and improve them, while others, if not already doing this, are at least aware of them. However, what we’re interested in is what’s really happening inside companies when it comes to DevEx and DP. To get a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/06/hidden-truths-about-developer-experience-three-key-insights-from-our-research/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Mastering Unit Testing with Spargine’s UnitTester Class</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The UnitTester class in the DotNetTips.Spargine.Tester assembly aids developers in logging unit test data efficiently. It features methods like PropertiesToString, PrintToDebug, and SaveToFile, which facilitate outputting results to the Debug panel or saving them to files. This tool enhances the debugging and reporting processes in .NET unit testing.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/04/boost-your-net-projects-mastering-unit-testing-with-spargines-unittester-class/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Conversational Agents with Azure AI Language Conversational Language Understanding and Custom Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 22:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we focus our work on empowering the agent design experience, a list of the new features in the we published earlier this week, including the intent triage agent and the exact question-answering agent, utilizing Conversational language understanding (CLU) and Custom question answering (CQA). We’re excited to share new enhancements to the customization experiences in CLU and CQA […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/enhancing-conversational-agents-with-azure-ai-language-conversational-language-understanding-and-custom-question-answering 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make an AI Chatbot from Scratch using Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 18:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’ll show you how to build a fully functional Generative AI chatbot using Docker Model Runner and powerful observability tools, including Prometheus, Grafana, and Jaeger. We’ll walk you through the common challenges developers face when building AI-powered applications, demonstrate how Docker Model Runner solves these pain points, and then guide you step-by-step through building...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-make-ai-chatbot-from-scratch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AI Foundry with .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using AI Foundry with .NET MAUI brings the power of LLMs to mobile and desktop applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-ai-foundry-with-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (May 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 16:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure SDK releases every month. In this post, you&#39;ll find this month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-may-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the power of Model Context Protocol (MCP) on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 16:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve witnessed remarkable advances in model capabilities as generative AI companies have invested in developing their offerings. Language models such as Anthropic’s Claude Opus 4 &amp;amp; Sonnet 4 and Amazon Nova on Amazon Bedrock can reason, write, and generate responses with increasing sophistication. But even as these models grow more powerful, they can only work […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-the-power-of-model-context-protocol-mcp-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a scalable AI assistant to help refugees using AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 15:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Danish humanitarian organization Bevar Ukraine has developed a comprehensive virtual generative AI-powered assistant called Victor, aimed at addressing the pressing needs of Ukrainian refugees integrating into Danish society. This post details our technical implementation using AWS services to create a scalable, multilingual AI assistant system that provides automated assistance while maintaining data security and GDPR compliance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-scalable-ai-assistant-to-help-refugees-using-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced diagnostics flow with LLM and Amazon Bedrock agent integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 15:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Noodoe uses AI and Amazon Bedrock to optimize EV charging operations. By integrating LLMs, Noodoe enhances station diagnostics, enables dynamic pricing, and delivers multilingual support. These innovations reduce downtime, maximize efficiency, and improve sustainability. Read on to discover how AI is transforming EV charging management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhanced-diagnostics-flow-with-llm-and-amazon-bedrock-agent-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Academy: Unlock Your Azure Skills and Accelerate Your Career</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we launched the Cloud Academy benefit for Visual Studio Professional and Enterprise subscribers back in March 2025, our goal was simple: give you the hands-on, practical learning experience you need to confidently master Azure and cloud technologies — without spending a dime beyond your subscription. Why? Because in today’s fast-changing tech world, knowing theory […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/cloud-academy-benefit-for-visual-studio-subscribers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The symbolism of the magnifying glass is not universal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just making things bigger?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250603-00/?p=111240 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 13:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The Original Name of .NET Was “Next Generation Windows Services (NGWS)“. Before Microsoft officially named it “.NET,” the platform was internally referred to as NGWS: Next Generation Windows Services. The name “.NET” was adopted in the late 1990s to emphasize the platform’s focus on web-based development and interoperability, as opposed to being […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/03/dotinsights-june-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling security with responsible disclosure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces its Outbound Coordinated Disclosure Policy to guide how it responsibly reports vulnerabilities in third-party software—emphasizing integrity, collaboration, and proactive security at scale.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/scaling-coordinated-vulnerability-disclosure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating your first sample game with MonoGame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I provide an introduction to MonoGame, looking at it&#39;s history, the requirements for building with MonoGame, and finally a first sample app.
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-your-first-sample-game-with-monogame/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: How Junie Uses TeamCity to Evaluate Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Junie is an intelligent coding agent developed by JetBrains. It automates the full development loop: reading project files, editing code, running tests, and applying fixes, going far beyond simple code generation. Similar to how developers use tools like ChatGPT to solve coding problems, Junie takes it a step further by automating the entire process. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/how-junie-uses-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! The RubyMine 2025.2 Early Access Program is already available! In this blog post, we’ll share the upcoming features and updates planned for this release cycle. What’s coming in RubyMine 2025.2? Debugger improvements We’re introducing a number of changes aimed at enhancing the debugger installation experience. The entire process will now take less time, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/what-s-next-for-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie and RubyMine: Your Winning Combo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Junie, a powerful AI coding agent from JetBrains, is available in RubyMine! Install the plugin and try it out now! Why Junie is a game-changer Unlike other AI coding agents, Junie leverages the robust power of JetBrains IDEs and reliable large language models (LLMs) to deliver exceptional results with high precision. According to SWE-bench Verified, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/06/junie-and-rubymine-your-winning-combo/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IEnumerable vs. IAsyncEnumerable in .NET: Streaming vs. Buffering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 08:31:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You&#39;ve likely used IEnumerable with EF Core while fetching data from a database. However, have you ever wondered how it loads data from your data set, and if IEnumerable will work fine when the application grows? To find answers, I will break down the core
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/ienumerable-vs-iasyncenumerable-in-net-streaming-vs-buffering/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Event Sourcing with Marten Go Faster</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 21:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’re about to start a new system with Event Sourcing using Marten, and you’re expecting your system to be hugely successful such that it’s going to handle a huge amount of data, but you’re already starting with pretty ambitious non-functional requirements for the system to be highly performant and all the screens or exposed APIs … Continue reading Making Event Sourcing with Marten Go Faster →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/06/02/making-event-sourcing-with-marten-go-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A story of collaborating agents: chatting with your database the right way</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 18:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, more and more customers are embracing AI with one clear goal in mind: they want to chat with their data. And by “data,” they mean all of it: structured tables, unstructured documents, images, audio, and more. This demand has given rise to hybrid approaches that blend semantic understanding with precise data retrieval. But here’s […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/a-story-of-collaborating-agents-chatting-with-your-database-the-right-way 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension Manager updates in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 18:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest updates in Visual Studio 2022 introduced features specifically designed to improve how you manage extensions. These updates offer tools that help you automate processes, provide detailed controls for configuration, and enhance the user interface to streamline your development workflows. Seamless auto updates Visual Studio now automatically triggers updates whenever you open the Extension […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/extension-manager-updates-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build GraphRAG applications using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Graph-based Retrieval-Augmented Generation (GraphRAG) in Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases to build intelligent applications. Unlike traditional vector search, which retrieves documents based on similarity scores, knowledge graphs encode relationships between entities, allowing large language models (LLMs) to retrieve information with context-aware reasoning.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-graphrag-applications-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline personalization development: How automated ML workflows accelerate Amazon Personalize implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post presents an MLOps solution that uses AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK) and services like AWS Step Functions, Amazon EventBridge and Amazon Personalize to automate provisioning resources for data preparation, model training, deployment, and monitoring for Amazon Personalize.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-personalization-development-how-automated-ml-workflows-accelerate-amazon-personalize-implementation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3D12 Cooperative Vector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the preview release for Cooperative Vector support in D3D12. This exposes powerful new hardware acceleration for vector and matrix operations, enabling developers to efficiently drive neural rendering techniques directly from individual shader threads in real-time graphics pipelines. In research and in industry, machine learning based approaches have made their way to mainstream, replacing/augmenting […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/cooperative-vector 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast-track SOP processing using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 16:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When a regulatory body like the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) introduces changes to regulations, organizations are required to evaluate the changes against their internal SOPs. When necessary, they must update their SOPs to align with the regulation changes and maintain compliance. In this post, we show different approaches using Amazon Bedrock to identify relationships between regulation changes and SOPs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fast-track-sop-processing-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Secret Protection and GitHub Code Security for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 14:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following the changes to GitHub Advanced Security on GitHub, we’re launching the standalone security products of GitHub Secret Protection and GitHub Code Security for Azure DevOps today. You can bring the protection of Advanced Security to your enterprise with the flexibility to enable the right level of protection for your repositories. GitHub Secret Protection for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/github-secret-protection-and-github-code-security-for-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stating the obvious about debugging an invalid parameter error when freeing memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing it down for posterity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250602-00/?p=111236 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context Collection Competition by JetBrains and Mistral AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Build smarter code completions and compete for a share of USD 12,000! In AI-enabled IDEs, code completion quality heavily depends on how well the IDE understands the surrounding code – the context. That context is everything, and we want your help to find the best way to collect it. Join JetBrains and Mistral AI at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/06/context-collection-competition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Null-Forgiving Operator Removal in C# Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Nullable Reference Types are a feature in C# that helps developers avoid null reference exceptions by providing compile-time checks for nullability. This feature was introduced in C# 8.0 and is designed to improve code quality and reduce runtime errors. When the compiler cannot handle all cases, so developers may need to use the null-forgiving operator ! to suppress warnings. This operator tells the…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/automating-null-forgiving-operator-removal-in-csharp-projects.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Predict the Future of AI in Software Development!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 11:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever wanted to share your ideas about AI and have a chance at winning prizes at the same time? As a company dedicated to creating the best possible solutions for software development, we at JetBrains want to know what you think about AI in software development. In this post, we tell you more about the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/06/predict-the-future-of-ai-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Container Apps vs AKS: Which Is Right for Your Enterprise Application?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When it comes to modernizing enterprise systems in Azure, containerization is the name of the game. But if you’re standing at the crossroads of Azure Container Apps and Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS), the decision isn’t always straightforward. Both options offer robust paths to scalable microservices—but they cater to different levels of control, complexity, and operational […] The article Azure Container Apps vs AKS: Which Is Right for Your Enterprise Application? was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Learning, Part 2: Get Unstuck With AI Hints in Python and Kotlin Tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 08:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous post, we introduced AI-powered machine translation and inline theory definitions to help make learning smoother and more accessible. Today, we’re excited to share the next big step in bringing intelligent assistance to your programming journey: AI hints. This feature is designed especially for beginners who may get stuck while solving coding tasks […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/06/02/ai-hints-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Answers to Your KMP Questions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            During the Closing Panel at KotlinConf 2025, we received many questions about Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP), but unfortunately didn’t have time to address them all live. So we’ve decided to answer the most popular ones in a follow-up blog post. Will IntelliJ IDEA and Android Studio support full Swift navigation, completion, etc., for iOS code, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/get-answers-to-your-kmp-questions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Says… Soft Skills at Conferences Matter—A Lot!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author reflects on two decades of speaking engagements, emphasizing the importance of soft skills in software engineering over mere technical knowledge. They argue that communication, empathy, and collaboration are crucial for career growth. While major conferences often overlook these topics, community-driven events showcase their value, urging attendees to advocate for more sessions on soft skills.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/02/dotnetdave-says-soft-skills-at-conferences-matter-a-lot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling OpenID Connect error events in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 04:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ASP.NET Core provides great extension points for handling OpenID Connect error events. This blog looks at implementing error handling in an ASP.NET Core application implemented using ASP.NET Core Identity. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/IdentityExternalErrorHandling Setup The application uses OpenID Connect to implement the authentication of the user identities. This implements a standard OpenID Connect flow and uses Microsoft […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/06/02/handling-openid-connect-error-events-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marten 8.0, Wolverine 4.0, and even Lamar 15.0 are out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 02:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s a pretty big “Critter Stack” community release day today, as: Before getting into the highlights, let me start by thanking the Critter Stack Core team for all their support, contributions to both the code and documentation, and for being a constant sounding board for me and source of ideas and advice: Next, I’d like … Continue reading Marten 8.0, Wolverine 4.0, and even Lamar 15.0 are out! →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Untapped Power of Veteran Engineers: Why Companies Are Overlooking Their Most Valuable Assets – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2025/01_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2025/01_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article emphasizes the critical value of veteran software engineers, highlighting their extensive experience, technical expertise, and leadership in innovation. It addresses age bias in the tech industry, advocating for the recognition and utilization of senior talent. Companies that embrace this perspective can significantly enhance their performance and resilience.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/01/the-untapped-power-of-veteran-engineers-why-companies-are-overlooking-their-most-valuable-assets-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Enhance Your Workflow with AssemblyHelper in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2025/01_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2025/01_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AssemblyHelper class from the DotNetTips.Spargine.Core assembly is an essential tool for .NET developers, offering numerous high-performance methods to manage assemblies efficiently. It simplifies tasks like loading, locating, and inspecting assemblies, enhancing productivity by reducing complexity in large projects. Incorporate AssemblyHelper into your toolkit for improved development processes.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/01/boost-your-net-projects-enhance-your-workflow-with-assemblyhelper-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Cost of Being the Team Hero - Dev Leader Weekly 96</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2025/31_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2025/31_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the trap of becoming a hero on the team and what you can do about it!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/31/the-hidden-cost-of-being-the-team-hero-dev-leader-weekly-96 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-05-30</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2025/31_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 07:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2025/31_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/05/31/weekly-recap-20250530 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YARP vs Nginx - A Quick Performance Comparison</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2025/31_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2025/31_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will compare the performance of YARP and Nginx, two popular reverse proxy solutions.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/yarp-vs-nginx-a-quick-performance-comparison 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering Real-Time Messaging at Scale with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Teams, Copilot, Azure Communication Services and many other product offerings from Microsoft, rely on a unified messaging platform that powers real-time communication and collaboration at an unprecedented scale. This messaging platform has become critical for enabling boundary-less collaboration, supporting hundreds of millions of users worldwide. To ensure global discovery, durable storage and performance needed […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/powering-real-time-messaging-at-scale-with-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Amazon SageMaker Projects with Terraform Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post you define, deploy, and provision a SageMaker Project custom template purely in Terraform. With no dependencies on other IaC tools, you can now enable SageMaker Projects strictly within your Terraform Enterprise infrastructure.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-amazon-sagemaker-projects-with-terraform-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How ZURU improved the accuracy of floor plan generation by 109% using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ZURU collaborated with AWS Generative AI Innovation Center and AWS Professional Services to implement a more accurate text-to-floor plan generator using generative AI. In this post, we show you why a solution using a large language model (LLM) was chosen. We explore how model selection, prompt engineering, and fine-tuning can be used to improve results.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-zuru-improved-the-accuracy-of-floor-plan-generation-by-109-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going beyond AI assistants: Examples from Amazon.com reinventing industries with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Non-conversational applications offer unique advantages such as higher latency tolerance, batch processing, and caching, but their autonomous nature requires stronger guardrails and exhaustive quality assurance compared to conversational applications, which benefit from real-time user feedback and supervision. This post examines four diverse Amazon.com examples of such generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/going-beyond-ai-assistants-examples-from-amazon-com-reinventing-industries-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architect a mature generative AI foundation on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we give an overview of a well-established generative AI foundation, dive into its components, and present an end-to-end perspective. We look at different operating models and explore how such a foundation can operate within those boundaries. Lastly, we present a maturity model that helps enterprises assess their evolution path.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/architect-a-mature-generative-ai-foundation-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3D12 Opacity Micromaps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DirectX Raytracing (DXR) now supports Opacity Micromaps (OMMs), enabling hardware to handle alpha tested geometry more efficiently than relying only on costly AnyHit shader invocations. At GDC 2025 DXR 1.2 was announced including OMMs, and you can see it discussed in this: GDC DirectX State Of The Union YouTube Recording. In the video, Remedy showed […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/omm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3D12 Shader Execution Reordering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Shader Execution Reordering (SER) is an addition to DirectX Raytracing that enables application shader code inform hardware how to find coherency across rays so they can be sorted to execute better in parallel. At GDC 2025 DXR 1.2 was announced including SER, and you can see it discussed in this: GDC DirectX State Of The […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/ser 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2505.30 and 2505.30-preview: support for DXR 1.2, Cooperative Vectors and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released two new versions of PIX, which can be downloaded here. These complement the new D3D12 Agility SDKs released today. The new versions of PIX are: PIX 2505.30 – supports the new retail D3D12 features released today in Agility SDK 1.616, including: Opacity Micromaps (OMMs) Tiled Resources Tier 4 PIX 2505.30-preview – supports the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2505-30-and-2505-30-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility SDK 1.717-preview and 1.616-retail</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 16:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce both a retail and preview Agility SDK release with several new features, available on Agility SDK Downloads today! As usual, the features in this release come with Day One PIX support. Please read the PIX blog post for more information. Agility SDK 1.717-preview features Cooperative Vectors unlocks powerful new hardware acceleration for vector […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agility-sdk-1-717-preview-and-1-616-retail 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon OpenSearch ML connector APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 15:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenSearch offers a wide range of third-party machine learning (ML) connectors to support this augmentation. This post highlights two of these third-party ML connectors. The first connector we demonstrate is the Amazon Comprehend connector. In this post, we show you how to use this connector to invoke the LangDetect API to detect the languages of ingested documents. The second connector we demonstrate is the Amazon Bedrock connector to invoke the Amazon Titan Text Embeddings v2 model so that you can create embeddings from ingested documents and perform semantic search.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the gap between development and production: Seamless model lifecycle management with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 15:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Model Copy and Model Share features provide a powerful option for managing the lifecycle of an AI application from development to production. In this comprehensive blog post, we&#39;ll dive deep into the Model Share and Model Copy features, exploring their functionalities, benefits, and practical applications in a typical development-to-production scenario.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bridging-the-gap-between-development-and-production-seamless-model-lifecycle-management-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 15:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the May edition of PHP Annotated! It’s been a minute since the last edition. Turns out time flies when you’re deep in foundation work, and the occasional existential debugging session. But we are back. Here’s everything you might’ve missed in the PHP world, we dug through the noise so you can just enjoy […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/05/php-annotated-may-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using an oracle to see where your code is producing the wrong output</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If there is a reference implementation, then use it as a check.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250530-00/?p=111232 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Verifier and API Compatibility Maintenance: Livestream Recording &amp; Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 13:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a recent session, IntelliJ Platform Developer Advocate Róbert Novotný walked through the Plugin Verifier—one of the most important tools for maintaining plugin compatibility across JetBrains IDEs. The session focused on spotting breaking API changes, avoiding internal APIs, and verifying plugin behavior across IDE versions. If you couldn’t join us live, the full recording is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/05/plugin-verifier-and-api-compatibility-maintenance-livestream-recording-amp-key-takeaways/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Semantic Kernel: A Commitment to Innovation and Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 13:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Semantic Kernel is Microsoft’s core framework for enterprise AI orchestration, remaining secure, stable, and rapidly evolving with unified multi-agent support and deep Azure integration, backed by ongoing investment and a clear long-term roadmap.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/semantic-kernel-commitment-ai-innovation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Ground Truth Generation for Search Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article discusses the challenges and methodologies for creating a reliable groundtruth dataset for search evaluation. It highlights the use of TREC Pooling and GPT-4o assisted ranking to overcome the labor-intensive process of manual labeling, ensuring high-quality search evaluations even with limited data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/efficient-ground-truth-generation-search-evaluation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing earth observation with geospatial foundation models on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 21:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how a leading GeoFM (Clay Foundation’s Clay foundation model available on Hugging Face) can be deployed for large-scale inference and fine-tuning on Amazon SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-earth-observation-with-geospatial-foundation-models-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go from prompt to playback with Sora from Azure OpenAI in the video playground in Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 20:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The video playground in Azure AI Foundry is a high-fidelity testbed for prototyping with cutting-edge video generation models like Sora from Azure OpenAI. It offers a controlled environment for developers to experiment with prompt structures, evaluate model consistency, and optimize outputs for industry use cases.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/sora-in-video-playground 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an agentic RAG application for advanced knowledge discovery with LlamaIndex, and Mistral in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 20:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate an example of building an agentic RAG application using the LlamaIndex framework. LlamaIndex is a framework that connects FMs with external data sources. It helps ingest, structure, and retrieve information from databases, APIs, PDFs, and more, enabling the agent and RAG for AI applications. This application serves as a research tool, using the Mistral Large 2 FM on Amazon Bedrock generate responses for the agent flow.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SQL Cryptozoology AI Embeddings Lab Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 19:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Missed out on MS Build 2025? No worries! Our lab is now available for your exploration. Dive into a unique cryptozoology experience using Azure SQL and Azure AI to uncover intriguing (and true) connections among cryptids worldwide. Curious about who would reign supreme in a battle royal or which regions of the world hold the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/azure-sql-cryptozoology-ai-embeddings-lab-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text-to-image basics with Amazon Nova Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 19:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus on the Amazon Nova Canvas image generation model. We then provide an overview of the image generation process (diffusion) and dive deep into the input parameters for text-to-image generation with Amazon Nova Canvas.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/text-to-image-basics-with-amazon-nova-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-world applications of Amazon Nova Canvas for interior design and product photography</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 19:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Nova Canvas can solve real-world business challenges through advanced image generation techniques. We focus on two specific use cases that demonstrate the power and flexibility of this technology: interior design and product photography.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/real-world-applications-of-amazon-nova-canvas-for-interior-design-and-product-photography/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic DevOps in action: Reimagining every phase of the developer lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 19:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What if your dev tools could take the first pass at a feature, file a bug report, propose a fix—and deploy it? With Agentic DevOps and GitHub Copilot, they can. Here&#39;s how agents will reshape every step of the software development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/reimagining-every-phase-of-the-developer-lifecycle 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector Support Public Preview now extended to Azure SQL MI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 17:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce that Azure SQL Managed Instance now supports Vector type and functions in public preview. This builds on the momentum from Azure SQL Database, where vector support has been in public preview since December. Check out the detailed announcement 💡 Why Choose Azure SQL Managed Instance for AI-Driven Modernization? Effortless Cloud […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/4561-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune the volume of logs your app produces</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explores the new log sampling feature
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/finetune-the-volume-of-logs-your-app-produces 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Innovation: HashiCorp Terraform Revolutionized Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 15:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the current cloud-first world, where agility, automation, and scalability are required, there are few tools that have left as profound a mark on infrastructure management as HashiCorp Terraform. Widely regarded as a cornerstone of modern DevOps practices, Terraform helped usher in a new era of Infrastructure as Code (IaC) that is defined by declarative […] The article Software Innovation: HashiCorp Terraform Revolutionized Infrastructure as Code (IaC) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Live Watches in CLion’s Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest CLion 2025.2 EAP build, 252.18003.25, includes one of the most requested features for embedded development: live watches. It allows you to monitor global variables in real time without stopping the debugger or the program’s execution. This feature is particularly useful for embedded developers working with time-sensitive protocols, such as Bluetooth, or with physical […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/05/introducing-live-watches/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Multi-Agent AI Apps in Java with Spring AI and Azure Cosmos DB!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 14:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI-driven apps become more sophisticated, there’s an increasing need for them to mimic collaborative problem solving – like a team of domain experts working together. Multi-agent apps offer exactly that: collections of specialized agents that cooperate to handle complex tasks. But to make them production-grade, you need more than just clever prompts – you […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/building-multi-agent-ai-apps-in-java-with-spring-ai-and-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of creating new instances when you wanted to use the same one</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C++ language backward compatibility makes legal what you had hoped wasn&#39;t.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250529-00/?p=111228 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating websites in minutes with AI Website Builder</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wix’s AI Website Builder, powered by OpenAI, lets anyone create a full website in minutes—just by describing their idea in a conversation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/wix 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
