<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:17:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Microsoft Graph callRecords API capabilities in GCCH and DoD</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read about the new capabilities for the Microsoft Graph callRecords API coming to GCCH and DOD environments in December.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/new-microsoft-graph-callrecords-api-capabilities-in-gcch-and-dod 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribe, translate, and summarize live streams in your browser with AWS AI and generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the approach behind building an AWS AI-powered Chrome extension that aims to revolutionize the live streaming experience by providing real-time transcription, translation, and summarization capabilities directly within your browser.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transcribe-translate-and-summarize-live-streams-in-your-browser-with-aws-ai-and-generative-ai-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s Vision for 2025 and Beyond: Copilot, Responsible AI, Security and Multicloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Ignite 2024 conference kicks off next week and I’ve analyzed the full session list to gleam insights into the company’s strategic roadmap for 2025 and beyond. This years conference has an unmistakable emphasis on artificial intelligence, security, and multicloud innovation. The 1,846 sessions hosted at the conference spanning a vast array of tech […] The article Microsoft’s Vision for 2025 and Beyond: Copilot, Responsible AI, Security and Multicloud was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: Suntory and Reliability in AI with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Suntory Global Spirits is the spirits division of Suntory Holdings, a multinational beverage and food company based in Japan. Suntory is renowned for its high-quality alcoholic beverages, including premium Japanese whisky, gin, vodka, and other spirits. We’ll turn it over to Urko Benito from Suntory to dive into their AI journey with Semantic Kernel. The […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-suntory-and-reliability-in-ai-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your financial statement analysis with Amazon Bedrock and generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy a generative AI application that can accelerate your financial statement analysis on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-your-financial-statement-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock-and-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual content processing using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon A2I</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post outlines a custom multilingual document extraction and content assessment framework using a combination of Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock and Amazon A2I to incorporate human-in-the-loop capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multilingual-content-processing-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-a2i/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a reverse image search engine with Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings in Amazon Bedrock and AWS managed services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to extract key objects from image queries using Amazon Rekognition and build a reverse image search engine using Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings from Amazon Bedrock in combination with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless Service.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-reverse-image-search-engine-with-amazon-titan-multimodal-embeddings-in-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-managed-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datalore On-Premises or Cloud: Which Suits You Best?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In an era where data is the new currency, the ability to quickly gain actionable insights can be a game-changer for businesses and research institutions alike. Shortening the feedback loop between data scientists, analysts, and business intelligence teams can lead to more agile and responsive strategies, ultimately speeding up innovation and optimizing operations. JetBrains has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/11/13/datalore-on-premises-or-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an Azure OpenAI app with Python using External ID authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 16:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to securely integrate Azure’s OpenAI services with External ID authentication, using Python, Azure CLI, and Bicep templates. This guide walks you through setting up a secure AI-driven application with streamlined access management on Azure.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/azure-openai-app-with-python-and-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scala 3 support Transparent inline methods (experimental) Transparent inline methods in Scala 3 allow the compiler to reinterpret the method being inlined in the context of information known already at the compile time. Our support of this feature is still experimental and requires more work, but what we offer in this release already covers the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/11/13/intellij-scala-plugin-2024-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share Your Insights on Using Rider and Win a Prize!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to invite you to participate in our research study, which will be an informal interview. In it, we’ll ask you about your workflows, your experiences with Rider, the challenges you typically encounter, and your aspirations, as this will help us tailor our solutions to better meet the needs of developers like you. The […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/share-your-insights-on-using-rider-and-win-a-prize/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3, our final major release of the year, is here! This update brings a range of new features and enhancements across the IDE to improve your daily development workflows. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/intellij-idea-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next major CLion release is approaching, and the v2024.3 Release Candidate (RC) is already available. You can download build 243.21565.198 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. You need an active subscription or a trial license to use the CLion 2024.3 RC. DOWNLOAD CLION […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/11/2024-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First preview of Visual Studio 2022 v17.13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the availability of Visual Studio 2022 v17.13 Preview 1 – the first preview of our next update to Visual Studio. This update focuses on providing fantastic developer experiences across the board, with a focus on stability &amp;amp; security, and AI &amp;amp; productivity. Download the preview and see the full list of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/first-preview-of-visual-studio-2022-v17-13 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn How to Optimize Docker Hub Costs With Our Usage Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customers can now manage their resource usage effectively by tracking their consumption with new metering tools. By gaining a clearer understanding of their usage, customers can identify patterns and trends, helping them maximize the value of their Docker Hub experience.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hubdashboards/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2024.3: Rails 8 Support, Inline AI Prompts, Integration With RBS Collection, Ruby 3.4 Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2024.3 is now available! The latest version of JetBrains’ IDE for Ruby and Ruby on Rails comes with Rails 8 support, including Kamal 2 code completion, nilability annotations from schema.rb for type support, and Solid Queue and Solid Cache code insights. Enhanced by JetBrains AI Assistant, RubyMine now offers faster and more contextually aware […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/11/rubymine-2024-3-rails-8-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant 2024.3: Refine Your AI Experience With Model Selection, Enhanced Code Completion, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant 2024.3 is here! A highlight of this release is the flexibility to choose your preferred chat model. Select between Google Gemini, OpenAI, or local models to tailor interactions for a more customized experience. This update also brings advanced code completion for all major programming languages, improved context management, and the ability to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/11/jetbrains-ai-assistant-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2024.3: Day-One C# 13 Support, Streamlined Code Cleanup, and Enhanced C&#43;&#43; Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce the release of ReSharper 2024.3! This release marks an important step toward a new approach to our product updates. With version 2024.3, we’re working to align ReSharper’s releases with major .NET SDK updates, aiming to bring you the latest C# capabilities as early as possible. While we can’t guarantee this timing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/resharper-2024-3-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotCover, dotMemory, dotPeek, and dotTrace 2024.3 Have Been Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dotCover 2024.3, dotMemory 2024.3, dotPeek 2024.3, and dotTrace 2024.3 have been released and are ready for download! Let’s take a look at what’s new with these .NET tools. dotMemory 2024.3 dotTrace 2024.3 dotCover 2024.3 dotPeek 2024.3 If you’re also interested in learning more about ReSharper 2024.3 or Rider 2024.3, please visit:
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/dotnet-tools-243-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.3: Same-Day Support for .NET 9 SDK and C# 13, Console Debugging for Game Dev, AI Enhancements, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that Rider 2024.3 is here. This release marks a major change to our team’s development process. Starting with version 2024.3, we’re aiming to align updates to JetBrains Rider and ReSharper with major .NET SDK releases. While this isn’t a guaranteed timeline for every release, our goal is to minimize the wait […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/rider-2024-3-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Development in Rider 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 07:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Remote development has long held promise for developers seeking flexibility. However, only in recent years has it become an indispensable part of modern development workflows that prioritize collaboration and scalability. Nowadays, developer teams often need to work from different locations while leveraging high-performance, shared environments that feel as reliable as their local setups. With JetBrains […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/13/remote-development-in-rider-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 improves JavaScript module importing for Blazor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So you’ve set out to build your shiny new web app using Blazor. Blazor’s component model is more than up to the task and you spend a few weeks happily building out UI to meet your requirements. But then you run into a requirement to integrate with a JavaScript library. Curse it! Now you have to figure out how to make calls to a JavaScript library from your Blazor app. This is exactly the kind of requirement that can get complicated, pretty quickly.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI for agriculture: How Agmatix is improving agriculture with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes how Agmatix, a pioneering Agtech company powering R&amp;amp;D for input companies and digital agronomic solutions, uses Amazon Bedrock and AWS fully featured services to enhance the research process and development of higher-yielding seeds and sustainable molecules for global agriculture.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generative-ai-for-agriculture-how-agmatix-is-improving-agriculture-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate financial industry-specific insights using generative AI and in-context fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we demonstrate prompt engineering techniques to generate accurate and relevant analysis of tabular data using industry-specific language. This is done by providing large language models (LLMs) in-context sample data with features and labels in the prompt. The results are similar to fine-tuning LLMs without the complexities of fine-tuning models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-financial-industry-specific-insights-using-generative-ai-and-in-context-fine-tuning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliver personalized marketing with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Bedrock Developer Experience, and Amazon Personalize that allow marketers to save time and deliver efficient personalized advertising using a generative AI enhanced solution. Our solution is a marketing agent that shows how Amazon Personalize can effectively segment target customers based on relevant characteristics and behaviors. Additionally, by using Amazon Bedrock Agents and foundation models (FMs), our tool generates personalized creative content specifically tailored to each purpose.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.3: Built-In Database Tools and SQL Support, Better AI-driven Code Completion, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our third major release of 2024 is here! In this version, you’ll find built-in database tools and SQL support, various quality enhancements, better code completion with AI Assistant, and a whole lot more. DOWNLOAD WEBSTORM 2024.3 If you only have a few minutes to explore the highlights of WebStorm 2024.3, check out our quick review […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/11/webstorm-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Language Support in ReSharper and Rider 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our upcoming 2024.3 release marks a huge milestone for our development process but especially for our users. ReSharper and Rider 2024.3 will be simshipped along with .NET 9 and C# 13! Yes, you heard right—no more waiting an extra few weeks or using our EAP builds to take advantage of the latest and greatest C# […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/12/csharp-language-support-in-resharper-and-rider-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Together: Understanding the Difference Between Sign-In Enforcement and SSO</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker Desktop’s sign-in enforcement and single sign-on (SSO) features work together to enhance security and streamline user management, ensuring proper authentication and access control while unlocking Docker’s full suite of tools.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/sign-in-enforcement-and-sso/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Flyway for Database Migrations in Spring Boot Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most software applications use SQL databases on account of their reliability, consistency, and maturity when it comes to handling structured data. The database schema evolves over time as business requirements change to add new features or update existing ones. Object-relational mapping (ORM) frameworks like JPA/Hibernate provide an easy way to generate a database schema based […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/how-to-use-flyway-for-database-migrations-in-spring-boot-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating AI Development with the Docker AI Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker&#39;s AI Catalog simplifies AI development by offering a curated platform that helps developers and publishers easily integrate AI capabilities into applications.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/accelerating-ai-development-with-the-docker-ai-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s ComputerInfo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, developed for use in production. The ComputerInfo class offers methods to retrieve essential system information for logging.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/12/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-computerinfo/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring C# Records and Their Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 09:05:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In C#, classes historically define types like in any other Object-Oriented Language. Classes define models, encapsulate data and behavior, and organize code. A new block organizer came into play with the launch of C# 9—Record. This article will explore C# records with practical code examples. I will also dive
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/exploring-c-records-and-their-use-cases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Meta Llama 3.2 text generation models for generative AI inference using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 17:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to fine-tune Meta’s latest Llama 3.2 text generation models, Llama 3.2 1B and 3B, using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart for domain-specific applications. By using the pre-built solutions available in SageMaker JumpStart and the customizable Meta Llama 3.2 models, you can unlock the models’ enhanced reasoning, code generation, and instruction-following capabilities to tailor them for your unique use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-meta-llama-3-2-text-generation-models-for-generative-ai-inference-using-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights with the Amazon Q Business Microsoft Teams connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 17:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Teams is an enterprise collaboration tool that allows you to build a unified workspace for real-time collaboration and communication, meetings, and file and application sharing. You can exchange and store valuable organizational knowledge within Microsoft Teams. Microsoft Teams data is often siloed across different teams, channels, and chats, making it difficult to get a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-with-the-amazon-q-business-microsoft-teams-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Docs With Code Samples? Try Out the New Writerside EAP Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 15:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Each Early Access release is designed to make writing documentation easier and more enjoyable. This update is based on your feedback and focuses on improving code blocks, but there is more! Thank you all for sharing your ideas. It’s a pleasure to keep improving our product for you. Code samples in documentation: Stick to the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/11/writing-docs-with-code-samples-try-out-the-new-writerside-eap-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Your Coding Projects With JetBrains AI Assistant: My Journey to Build a Flask Web App</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: In this post, I walk through the process of enhancing a chatbot project from Hyperskill by adding a web interface with Flask, JavaScript, and HTML. I tried out JetBrains AI Assistant and documented how it helped me with common coding tasks like installing frameworks, debugging, and generating code snippets, streamlining my development workflow. From […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/11/boosting-your-coding-projects-with-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop using diagnostic verbosity in MSBuild</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On CI, some projects use the msbuild diagnostic verbosity to get more information about the build. This is useful to troubleshoot build issues. However, this verbosity level has some drawbacks. In this post, I describe how to use the binary log feature of MSBuild to get the same information in a more efficient way. Diagnostic verbosity vs binary log The msbuild diagnostic verbosity is the most verbose…
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Pointers in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 07:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll introduce pointers in C#, exploring their syntax, usage in unsafe code blocks, and practical applications with direct memory manipulation. We’ll also discuss considerations involved in using pointers in a managed language. Let’s start! What Is a Pointer in C#? A pointer is simply a variable that holds the memory address of […] The post How to Use Pointers in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make sure users get the latest version of your stylesheet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever made a change to your Blazor app’s CSS only to find, when you publish your app, it seems to be stuck using the old styles? Modern browsers love to cache static assets like stylesheets. It speeds up performance and saves re-fetching the same thing multiple times from the server. The problem comes when you make changes to the stylesheet and push out a new version. Unless you change the filename of the stylesheet, the browser sees that your site is requesting a file it’s already cached and diligently serves the contents from the cache.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s List Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2024/10_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2024/10_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source collection of .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages developed for enhancing List collections in .NET. It features various performance-optimized methods for List manipulation, including adding, converting, and checking items.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/10/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-list-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Network Security Best Practices to Protect Your Cloud Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2024/09_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 15:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2024/09_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Securing network environments in Microsoft Azure is paramount when organizations migrate their infrastructure and applications to the cloud. Azure, as one of the leading cloud service providers, offers a broad spectrum of security tools and best practices designed to protect resources against a multitude of network threats. Azure network security plays a critical role in […] The article Azure Network Security Best Practices to Protect Your Cloud Infrastructure was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot Tip: Interactive Debugging with GitHub Copilot Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2024/09_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 05:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2024/09_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello developers! Continuing our series on GitHub Copilot tips, here’s another valuable insight to enhance your coding experience: Debugging is an essential part of the development process, but it can often be time-consuming and frustrating. GitHub Copilot Chat transforms this experience by providing an interactive and intelligent debugging assistant right within your IDE. Here’s how […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/github-copilot-tip-interactive-debugging-with-github-copilot-chat 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming in C#: The Practical Parts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2024/09_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2024/09_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Functional programming patterns can make your C# code safer and more maintainable, without getting lost in academic theory. Learn practical patterns you can use today to write better code.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/functional-programming-in-csharp-the-practical-parts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which compilation target should I pick for my Arm64 music apps, ASIO components, and plugins?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 21:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Windows music creation community today is centered around Intel/AMD x64 (x86-64) because that is what most Windows PCs run for some time now. The introduction of Arm64 Copilot+ PCs has provided new opportunities with efficient and powerful devices with great battery life and NPUs. But because we continue to support both the AMD/Intel x86-64 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/which-compilation-target-should-i-pick-for-my-arm64-music-apps-asio-components-and-plugins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.7 RC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 21:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the availability of the release candidate of TypeScript 5.7. To get started using the RC, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@rc Let’s take a look at what’s new in TypeScript 5.7! Checks for Never-Initialized Variables For a long time, TypeScript has been able […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-7-rc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Blogs home page layout simplified</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Dev Blogs community! What we heard – part 2 In my previous post about the grid and list layout choices I shared the feedback we received after launching a Dev Blogs refresh. I also shared how we improved and provided options for the layout of posts. Today, I will address the other major feedback […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devblogs-news/dev-blogs-home-page-layout-simplified 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of a program that crashed on its first instruction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Didn&#39;t even make it out of the gate.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241108-00/?p=110490 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Default Bundled Plugins in Fleet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recently, we announced the public rollout of the Fleet Plugins SDK – a step that finally allows plugins to be created and shared among the Fleet community at large. Believe it or not, this did not mark the very beginning of extensibility in Fleet. Fleet has always featured a variety of bundled plugins (currently upwards […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/11/default-bundled-plugins-in-fleet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Ways to Simplify CI/CD Pipelines on GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post focuses on three ways to simplify CI/CD pipelines deploying to Azure with GitHub Actions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/three-ways-to-simplify-cicd-pipelines-on-github-actions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI: The New Frontier for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 07:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AJ Enns reflects on his journey as a new developer and the impact of AI as an integrated, coding assistant for improving developer velocity. The year is 2024, and AI has been around for a while. ChatGPT broke onto the scene and changed the world forever. As soon as I heard about it, the first […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/ai-the-new-frontier-for-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Release Candidate is here! You can download the latest build from our website, from the free Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. To use this build, you need to have an active IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate subscription. With the big release day approaching fast, our team is putting the finishing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/intellij-idea-2024-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Prompt Management is now available in GA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 22:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Prompt Management, with new features that provide enhanced options for configuring your prompts and enabling seamless integration for invoking them in your generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-prompt-management-is-now-available-in-ga/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready for .NET Conf 2024!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The biggest .NET event of the year is almost here, its all free, all online, and you&#39;re invited!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/get-ready-for-dotnet-conf-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Zalando optimized large-scale inference and streamlined ML operations on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is cowritten with Mones Raslan, Ravi Sharma and Adele Gouttes from Zalando. Zalando SE is one of Europe’s largest ecommerce fashion retailers with around 50 million active customers. Zalando faces the challenge of regular (weekly or daily) discount steering for more than 1 million products, also referred to as markdown pricing. Markdown pricing is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-zalando-optimized-large-scale-inference-and-streamlined-ml-operations-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing Stability AI’s most advanced text-to-image models for media, marketing and advertising: Revolutionizing creative workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To stay competitive, media, advertising, and entertainment enterprises need to stay abreast of recent dramatic technological developments. Generative AI has emerged as a game-changer, offering unprecedented opportunities for creative professionals to push boundaries and unlock new realms of possibility. At the forefront of this revolution is Stability AI’s family of cutting-edge text-to-image AI models. These […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleashing-stability-ais-most-advanced-text-to-image-models-for-media-marketing-and-advertising-revolutionizing-creative-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a multi-tenant generative AI environment for your enterprise on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While organizations continue to discover the powerful applications of generative AI, adoption is often slowed down by team silos and bespoke workflows. To move faster, enterprises need robust operating models and a holistic approach that simplifies the generative AI lifecycle. In the first part of the series, we showed how AI administrators can build a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-multi-tenant-generative-ai-environment-for-your-enterprise-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance customer support with Amazon Bedrock Agents by integrating enterprise data APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has transformed customer support, offering businesses the ability to respond faster, more accurately, and with greater personalization. AI agents, powered by large language models (LLMs), can analyze complex customer inquiries, access multiple data sources, and deliver relevant, detailed responses. In this post, we guide you through integrating Amazon Bedrock Agents with enterprise data […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-customer-support-with-amazon-bedrock-agents-by-integrating-enterprise-data-apis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next big release for Rider is just around the corner! If you’re eager to get a sneak peek, you can download the Release Candidate version of Rider 2024.3 from our website right now. Here are the feature highlights of the Rider 2024.3 RC build: If you encounter any issues when using the Rider 2024.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/07/the-rider-2024-3-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2024.3 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get a preview of all the latest features and improvements set to be shipped with the next major ReSharper and .NET tools releases by downloading the Release Candidate builds that have just landed. Here are the lists of major improvements in each of the new builds: The ReSharper 2024.3 Release Candidate The ReSharper C++ 2024.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/07/rsrp-net-tools-2024-3-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I observe reads from a memory-mapped file when writing large blocks?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CPU doesn&#39;t see the entire write at once.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241107-00/?p=110486 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave’s Faster or Not!: Exploring Early Return in .NET Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post introduces a series called &amp;quot;dotNetDave&#39;s Faster or Not!&amp;quot; which aims to explore performance claims in .NET. It discusses method return patterns, comparing early returns and single-exit methods. Despite minor performance differences favoring early returns, the author advocates for their use due to improved readability and reduced complexity in coding.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/07/dotnetdaves-faster-or-not-exploring-early-return-in-net-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging a managed identity connection to Azure SQL in Azure App Service using containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 07:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dominique St-Amand explores how to debug a managed identity connection from a container-based App Service to Azure SQL. So you’ve been eager to deploy your containerized web application that you’ve been working on for a while, to Azure App Service. You follow the best security practices which means you’ve setup your connection to your Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/debugging-a-managed-identity-connection-to-azure-sql-in-azure-app-service-using-containers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (October 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 06:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.10.21 registry release, 2024-10-18 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout October. This release adds support for Azure universal packages as a binary caching provider and other minor improvements. CppCon Talk on Managing C++ Dependencies I also gave […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-october-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAG with SQL Vector Store: A Low-Code/No-Code Approach using Azure Logic Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 05:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data is at the heart of every AI application, and efficient data ingestion is critical for success. With over 1,400 enterprise connectors, Logic Apps offers unmatched access to a diverse range of systems, applications, and databases, whether hosted in the cloud or on-premises. These connectors give businesses the flexibility to keep their data where it […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/sql-vector-store-data-ingestion-and-retrieval-using-azure-logic-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Customers Don’t Care About JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 22:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your customers do not care about the technology behind your app. What programming language, frameworks, libraries, or whatever tooling you’re using, they don’t care. They care about it providing them value and that it has certain characteristics. They want it to work. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my… Read More »Your Customers Don’t Care About JavaScript The post Your Customers Don’t Care About JavaScript appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleash the power of generative AI with Amazon Q Business: How CCoEs can scale cloud governance best practices and drive innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 21:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Hearst, one of the nation’s largest global, diversified information, services, and media companies, overcame these challenges by creating a self-service generative AI conversational assistant for business units seeking guidance from their CCoE.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleash-the-power-of-generative-ai-with-amazon-q-business-how-ccoes-can-scale-cloud-governance-best-practices-and-drive-innovation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 Goes Beta With Enhanced CLion Nova, Debug Servers, and OpenCV Image Viewer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of CLion 2024.3 is now available with key improvements and changes announced for the upcoming release. You can download build 243.21565.87 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 BETA Read the full release notes on YouTrack. Below is a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/11/clion-2024-3-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate foundation models into your code with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 17:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The rise of large language models (LLMs) and foundation models (FMs) has revolutionized the field of natural language processing (NLP) and artificial intelligence (AI). These powerful models, trained on vast amounts of data, can generate human-like text, answer questions, and even engage in creative writing tasks. However, training and deploying such models from scratch is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-foundation-models-into-your-code-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciting Announcement: Public Preview of Native Vector Support in Azure SQL Database!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Public Preview of Native Vector Support in Azure SQL Database We are excited to share that the dedicated vector data type in Azure SQL Database, which was previously available through the Early Adopter Preview, is now transitioning to Public Preview! As of today, the Vector data type and its associated functions are accessible to everyone, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/exciting-announcement-public-preview-of-native-vector-support-in-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a new, more conversational way to chat with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the fast-evolving world of software development, intuitive AI-driven interactions are becoming essential to unlocking new levels of productivity. Today, we’re excited to share our latest innovation – a guided chat experience within GitHub Copilot that reshapes how developers interact with AI. This guided chat experience is available in Visual Studio 2022 17.12 Preview 3 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/conversational-way-to-chat-with-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and deploy a UI for your generative AI applications with AWS and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS provides a powerful set of tools and services that simplify the process of building and deploying generative AI applications, even for those with limited experience in frontend and backend development. In this post, we explore a practical solution that uses Streamlit, a Python library for building interactive data applications, and AWS services like Amazon Elastic Container Service (Amazon ECS), Amazon Cognito, and the AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK) to create a user-friendly generative AI application with authentication and deployment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unearth insights from audio transcripts generated by Amazon Transcribe using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we examine how to create business value through speech analytics with some examples focused on the following: 1) automatically summarizing, categorizing, and analyzing marketing content such as podcasts, recorded interviews, or videos, and creating new marketing materials based on those assets, 2) automatically extracting key points, summaries, and sentiment from a recorded meeting (such as an earnings call), and 3) transcribing and analyzing contact center calls to improve customer experience.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to subscribe for GitHub copilot business without GitHub Enterprise: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know that now you can subscribe to GitHub Copilot Business without GitHub Enterprise (GHE), which means you can get GitHub Copilot Business as a standalone capability, while having the normal GitHub Enterprise features (repositories, actions, etc.) disabled. This post is a screenshot-based step-by-step guide on how to configure a new GitHub Copilot Business […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-subscribe-for-github-copilot-business-without-github-enterprise 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I declare an operator overload for my Windows Runtime class?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That&#39;s not something expressible in the Windows Runtime.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241106-00/?p=110478 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on Unreal Engine Support in TeamCity: UGS Integration and Open-Sourcing the Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve got a few exciting updates about the Unreal Engine plugin announced in the previous blog post. TL;DR – we’re adding Unreal Game Sync (UGS) integration and open-sourcing the plugin. These updates are all about making the CI/CD experience smoother for Unreal Engine devs and getting the community more involved. UGS Before diving in, let’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/11/unreal-engine-plugin-ugs-integration-and-open-sourcing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Your Setup with the Microsoft Dev Box Pre-Requisites Page</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Dev Box team has been working hard to streamline the onboarding process for Dev Box administrators when first trying out the service, especially for situations when you’re unsure of all the necessary steps. In this blog, we are introducing a solution to make this process smoother and more efficient. Introducing the Microsoft Dev Box […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/streamline-setup-with-microsoft-dev-box-pre-requisites 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
