<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Architecture with Needlr in .NET: Building Modular Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2026/15_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2026/15_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to build modular .NET applications using Needlr&#39;s plugin system, including IServiceCollectionPlugin, IWebApplicationPlugin, and automatic plugin discovery.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/15/plugin-architecture-with-needlr-in-net-building-modular-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects with Spargine: Centralized Time Handling with the Clock Type</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2026/15_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_02_2026/15_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Clock type in the DotNetTips.Spargine.Core assembly and NuGet package centralizes time-related functions to enhance application consistency and reduce fragmentation. It provides a comprehensive and reliable abstraction for developers, ensuring efficient time handling while minimizing bugs. By streamlining time operations, Clock fosters cleaner, more predictable code across applications.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/02/15/boost-your-net-projects-with-spargine-centralized-time-handling-with-the-clock-type/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Weeks of Claude Code for Me</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2026/14_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2026/14_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m busy all the time with the Critter Stack tools, answering questions on Slack or Discord, and trying like hell to make JasperFx Software go. I’ve admittedly had my head in the sand a bit about the AI tools for coding, thinking that what I do being relatively novel for the most part and that … Continue reading 2 Weeks of Claude Code for Me →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2026/02/14/2-weeks-of-claude-code-for-me/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Implement Abstract Factory Pattern in C#: Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2026/14_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2026/14_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement Abstract Factory pattern in C# with a complete step-by-step guide. Includes code examples, best practices, and common pitfalls to avoid.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/14/how-to-implement-abstract-factory-pattern-in-c-stepbystep-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Extract Structured Data From Images Using Ollama in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2026/14_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_02_2026/14_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vision models can do more than describe images. I used Ollama and Microsoft.Extensions.AI to extract structured receipt data into strongly typed C# objects, all running locally.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/how-to-extract-structured-data-from-images-using-ollama-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DPO Fine-Tuning Using Microsoft Foundry SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 23:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the rapidly evolving landscape of large language models (LLMs), achieving precise control over model behavior while maintaining quality has become a critical challenge. While models like GPT-4 demonstrate impressive capabilities, ensuring their outputs align with human preferences—whether for safety, helpfulness, or style—requires sophi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/dpo-fine-tuning-using-microsoft-foundry-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize AI agent browsing with proxies, profiles, and extensions in Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are announcing three new capabilities that address these requirements: proxy configuration, browser profiles, and browser extensions. Together, these features give you fine-grained control over how your AI agents interact with the web. This post will walk through each capability with configuration examples and practical use cases to help you get started.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/customize-ai-agent-browsing-with-proxies-profiles-and-extensions-in-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-browser/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize WPF Desktop applications to ASP.NET Core MVC with Amazon Q Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction A medical imaging customer recently approached our team with a need to modernize their legacy Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) Framework desktop applications into ASP.NET Core MVC Web applications. They wanted to use an agentic approach to speed up their modernization to achieve the up to 4x speed that other customers have realized with Amazon […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-wpf-desktop-applications-to-asp-net-core-mvc-with-amazon-q-developer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.26.0-1 Microsoft build now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-26-0-1-microsoft-build-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Llms Need Mark as Answer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:20:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Today’s LLMs have already ingested basically all of the publicly available information they can to build their models. In order to improve further, they’re going to need to seek out additional sources of information. One obvious such source is the countless interactions they have with their users, and while privacy concerns are certainly relevant here, for the purposes of this article I want to focus on another issue: quality signals.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I distinguish between the numeric keypad 0 and the top-row 0 in the &lt;CODE&gt;WM_&lt;WBR&gt;CHAR&lt;/CODE&gt; message?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we looked at how to distinguish the numeric keypad 0 and the top-row 0 in the WM_KEY­DOWN message. We may as well look at th
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260213-00/?p=112062 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to solve the context size issues with context packing with Docker Model Runner and Agentic Compose</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve worked with local language models, you’ve probably run into the context window limit, especially when using smaller models on less powerful machines. While it’s an unavoidable constraint, techniques like context packing make it surprisingly manageable. Hello, I’m Philippe, and I am a Principal Solutions Architect helping customers with their usage of Docker. In...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/context-packing-context-window/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say Goodbye to “It Works on My Machine”: A Look at TeamCity’s Pretested Commits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Adeyinka Adegbenro, draft.dev. Developers know the frustration well. Code works perfectly on their laptop, then breaks the moment it hits staging or production. It’s easy to overlook slight environmental differences that hide latent bugs like race conditions, platform-specific library loading failures, data inconsistencies (large data sets can expose […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/02/say-goodbye-to-works-on-my-machine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Your Codebase to Go 1.26 With GoLand Syntax Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Working on an existing Go project rarely starts with a plan to modernize it. More often, you open a file to make a small change, add a field, or adjust some logic. The code compiles, tests pass, and everything looks fine, but the language has moved forward, and your code hasn’t kept up. As you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2026/02/13/moving-your-codebase-to-go-1-26-with-goland-syntax-updates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Modular Monoliths With Kotlin and Spring</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial was written by an external contributor. Over a decade ago, Netflix became one of the early adopters of microservice architecture, showcasing its potential at a large scale. Since then, many companies have jumped on the microservices bandwagon, building their backends this way from day one. While microservices offer isolation and independent scaling, their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/02/building-modular-monoliths-with-kotlin-and-spring/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core with Needlr: Simplified Web Application Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to set up ASP.NET Core web applications with Needlr for dependency injection, including ForWebApplication, minimal APIs, and middleware configuration.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/13/aspnet-core-with-needlr-simplified-web-application-setup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5.2 derives a new result in theoretical physics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new preprint shows GPT-5.2 proposing a new formula for a gluon amplitude, later formally proved and verified by OpenAI and academic collaborators.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/new-result-theoretical-physics 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Lockdown Mode and Elevated Risk labels in ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing Lockdown Mode and Elevated Risk labels in ChatGPT to help organizations defend against prompt injection and AI-driven data exfiltration.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-lockdown-mode-and-elevated-risk-labels-in-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond rate limits: scaling access to Codex and Sora</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How OpenAI built a real-time access system combining rate limits, usage tracking, and credits to power continuous access to Sora and Codex.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/beyond-rate-limits 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling social science research</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GABRIEL is a new open-source toolkit from OpenAI that uses GPT to turn qualitative text and images into quantitative data, helping social scientists analyze research at scale.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/scaling-social-science-research 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – February Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi there 👋 February is in full swing, and we’ve packed this digest with things you don’t want to miss.Inside: upcoming events, hands-on learning, competitions, scholarships, and fresh updates to keep you moving forward in 2026 🚀
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2026/02/12/jetbrains-academy-february-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft at DevNexus 2026: Practical AI for Real-World Java Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Java developers face a tough trifecta: keeping mission-critical systems running, modernizing legacy apps, and weaving AI into real engineering workflows, all without increasing risk. At DevNexus 2026, the Microsoft Java team is tackling these challenges head-on.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/microsoft-at-devnexus-2026-practical-ai-for-real-world-java-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI meets HR: Transforming talent acquisition with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to create an AI-powered recruitment system using Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, AWS Lambda, and other AWS services to enhance job description creation, candidate communication, and interview preparation while maintaining human oversight.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-meets-hr-transforming-talent-acquisition-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build long-running MCP servers on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore with Strands Agents integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide you with a comprehensive approach to achieve this. First, we introduce a context message strategy that maintains continuous communication between servers and clients during extended operations. Next, we develop an asynchronous task management framework that allows your AI agents to initiate long-running processes without blocking other operations. Finally, we demonstrate how to bring these strategies together with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Strands Agents to build production-ready AI agents that can handle complex, time-intensive operations reliably.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Legacy User Settings in SharePoint Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The SharePoint Framework (SPFx) has undergone some important changes in how it handles Entra ID app registration and security models. Here you can find additional details about what w
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/handling-legacy-user-settings-in-sharepoint-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Intelligent Apps with SQL: Join the SQL &#43; AI Datathon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            T
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-intelligent-apps-with-sql-join-the-sql-ai-datathon 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I distinguish between the numeric keypad 0 and the top-row 0 in the &lt;CODE&gt;WM_&lt;WBR&gt;KEY­DOWN&lt;/CODE&gt; message?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to know how to distinguish between the numeric keypad 0 and the top-row 0 in the WM_KEY­DOWN message. And while we&#39;re at it, let&#39;s also distinguish between the numeric keypad 0 and the Ins key. We start with this table of what you get in the WM_KEY­DOWN message w
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260212-00/?p=112059 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Factory Pattern Real-World Example in C#: Complete Implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            See Abstract Factory pattern in action with a complete real-world C# example. Step-by-step implementation of a furniture shop system demonstrating families of related objects.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/12/abstract-factory-pattern-realworld-example-in-c-complete-implementation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Having the Wrong AI Dreams?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            (This opinion piece by JetBrains’ Team Lead in AI Development Experience reflects on key takeaways from NeurIPS 2025, a major AI research conference. It explains why these insights matter and considers related signals emerging from other recent research.) Mass layoffs, robots taking control of the planet, a post-truth world. Which of these comes to mind […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/02/are-we-having-the-wrong-ai-dreams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5.3-Codex-Spark</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing GPT-5.3-Codex-Spark—our first real-time coding model. 15x faster generation, 128k context, now in research preview for ChatGPT Pro users.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-3-codex-spark 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Nemotron 3 Nano 30B MoE model is now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to announce that the NVIDIA Nemotron 3 Nano 30B model with 3B active parameters is now generally available in the Amazon SageMaker JumpStart model catalog. You can accelerate innovation and deliver tangible business value with Nemotron 3 Nano on Amazon Web Services (AWS) without having to manage model deployment complexities. You can power your generative AI applications with Nemotron capabilities using the managed deployment capabilities offered by SageMaker JumpStart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 6.0 Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the beta release of TypeScript 6.0! To get started using the beta, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@beta TypeScript 6.0 is a unique release in that we intend f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-6-0-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot Testing for .NET Brings AI-powered Unit Tests to Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot testing for .NET makes it dramatically faster and more convenient to generate high-quality unit tests without leaving your code. Today, we’re excited to announce that this capability is now generally available in Visual Studio 2026 v18.3. This release brings
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/github-copilot-testing-for-dotnet-available-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Prompt - Why and How to Fine-tune Your Own Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large Language Models (LLMs) have reached a point where general intelligence is no longer the bottleneck. The real challenge in enterprise AI systems behavioral alignment ensuring models that produce consistent, reliable, policy-compliant outputs on a scale. Prompt engineering and Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) are powerful but they do n
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/beyond-the-prompt-why-and-how-to-fine-tune-your-own-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Unplugged on PyTV – A Free Online Python Conference for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The PyCharm team loves being part of the global Python community. From PyCon US to EuroPython to every PyCon in between, we enjoy the atmosphere at conferences, as well as meeting people who are as passionate about Python as we are. This includes everyone: professional Python developers, data scientists, Python hobbyists and students. However, we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2026/02/python-unplugged-on-pytv/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Amazon Bedrock throttling and service availability: A comprehensive guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to implement robust error handling strategies that can help improve application reliability and user experience when using Amazon Bedrock. We&#39;ll dive deep into strategies for optimizing performances for the application with these errors. Whether this is for a fairly new application or matured AI application, in this post you will be able to find the practical guidelines to operate with on these errors.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swann provides Generative AI to millions of IoT Devices using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to implement intelligent notification filtering using Amazon Bedrock and its gen-AI capabilities. You&#39;ll learn model selection strategies, cost optimization techniques, and architectural patterns for deploying gen-AI at IoT scale, based on Swann Communications deployment across millions of devices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/swann-provides-generative-ai-to-millions-of-iot-devices-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How LinqAlpha assesses investment theses using Devil’s Advocate on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LinqAlpha is a Boston-based multi-agent AI system built specifically for institutional investors. The system supports and streamlines agentic workflows across company screening, primer generation, stock price catalyst mapping, and now, pressure-testing investment ideas through a new AI agent called Devil’s Advocate. In this post, we share how LinqAlpha uses Amazon Bedrock to build and scale Devil’s Advocate.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-linqalpha-assesses-investment-theses-using-devils-advocate-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock language-specific rich symbol context using new find_symbol tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Refactoring at scale is a time-consuming and error-prone process for developers. In large codebases, developers have relied on manual searches and incremental edits across multiple files to accomplish these tasks. Modern development workflows depend on fast and accurate code navigation to avoid these pitfalls. When developers refactor exist
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/unlock-language-specific-rich-symbol-context-using-new-find_symbol-tool 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I suppress the hover effects when I put a Win32 common controls ListView in single-click mode?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer had a Win32 common controls ListView in single-click mode. This has a side effect of enabling hover effects: When the mouse hovers over an item, the cursor changes to a hand, and the item gets highlighted in the hot-track color. How can they suppress these hover effects while still having single-click activation? When the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260211-00/?p=112057 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy to Azure App Service deployment slots with azd</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deploy to Azure App Service slots with azd deploy Missed deploying to an App Service slot? Now you can—without workarounds or manual scripts. What&#39;s new? Before, azd deploy could only deploy to the default production slot. Now, azd understands the slots you define in Bicep a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azd-app-service-slot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Azure Cosmos DB Performance with Azure Advisor Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the first post of this series, we introduced how Azure Advisor helps Azure Cosmos DB users uncover opportunities to optimize efficiency and make smarter decisions. This follow-up dives deeper into one
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/maximize-azure-cosmos-db-performance-with-azure-advisor-recommendations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Syringe Class: Needlr&#39;s Fluent API Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deep dive into Needlr&#39;s Syringe class and its fluent API for configuring dependency injection, discovery strategies, and type registration in C#.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/11/the-syringe-class-needlrs-fluent-api-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Rust 2025: Popularity, Trends, and Future</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Based on findings from the JetBrains Developer Ecosystem Survey Report 2025, The State of Rust 2025 offers a detailed look at how the Rust ecosystem is evolving – how developers use Rust today, which tools they use, how much they rely on AI tools in their workflows, and where the language is gaining momentum. With […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2026/02/11/state-of-rust-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best AI Models for Coding: Accuracy, Integration, and Developer Fit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI models and coding assistants have become essential tools for developers. Today, developers rely on large language models (LLMs) to accelerate coding, improve code quality, and reduce repetitive work across the entire development lifecycle. From intelligent code completion to refactoring, debugging, and documentation, AI-powered tools are now embedded directly into daily workflows. Drawing on insights […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/02/the-best-ai-models-for-coding-accuracy-integration-and-developer-fit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harness engineering: leveraging Codex in an agent-first world</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By Ryan Lopopolo, Member of the Technical Staff
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/harness-engineering 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft .NET Code Analysis: Efficient String Prefix Checks — StartsWith() vs. IndexOf()</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using IndexOf() for checking if a string starts with a specific value in .NET is inefficient and unclear. This approach performs unnecessary work and obscures intent.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/02/11/microsoft-net-code-analysis-efficient-string-prefix-checks-startswith-vs-indexof/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects with Spargine: Modern Password Hashing Using PasswordHasher</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure password hashing is vital for application security. The PasswordHasher class in Spargine for .NET 10 consolidates previous hashing implementations into a single solution that supports various modern algorithms. This enhances flexibility and ensures robust security while simplifying usage, making it essential for developers aiming to protect user credentials effectively.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/02/11/boost-your-net-projects-with-spargine-modern-password-hashing-using-passwordhasher/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 11 Preview 1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 22:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the first preview release of .NET 11! We just shipped our first preview release, adding to some major enhancements across the .NET Runtime, SDK, libraries, C#, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more. Check out the full release notes linked below and get started today. [cta-button align=&amp;quot;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-11-preview-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 20:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are releasing patches for our self‑hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly recommend that all customers stay on the latest, most secure version of Azure DevOps Server. The latest release, Azure DevOps Server, is available from the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/february-patches-for-azure-devops-server-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework February 2026 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for February 2026. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of February 10, 2026. This update contains secu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-february-2026-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon uses Amazon Nova models to automate operational readiness testing for new fulfillment centers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock can be used to implement an AI-powered image recognition solution that automates the detection and validation of module components, significantly reducing manual verification efforts and improving accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-uses-amazon-nova-models-to-automate-operational-readiness-testing-for-new-fulfillment-centers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iberdrola enhances IT operations using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Iberdrola, one of the world’s largest utility companies, has embraced cutting-edge AI technology to revolutionize its IT operations in ServiceNow. Through its partnership with AWS, Iberdrola implemented different agentic architectures using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, targeting three key areas: optimizing change request validation in the draft phase, enriching incident management with contextual intelligence, and simplifying change model selection using conversational AI. These innovations reduce bottlenecks, help teams accelerate ticket resolution, and deliver consistent and high-quality data handling throughout the organization.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building real-time voice assistants with Amazon Nova Sonic compared to cascading architectures</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Nova Sonic delivers real-time, human-like voice conversations through the bidirectional streaming interface. In this post, you learn how Amazon Nova Sonic can solve some of the challenges faced by cascaded approaches, simplify building voice AI agents, and provide natural conversational capabilities. We also provide guidance on when to choose each approach to help you make informed decisions for your voice AI projects.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-real-time-voice-assistants-with-amazon-nova-sonic-compared-to-cascading-architectures/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI-Powered Apps with Azure Cosmos DB and the Vercel AI SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Vercel AI SDK is an open-source TypeScript toolkit that provides the core building blocks for integrating AI into any JavaScript application. It works with 20+ AI providers out of the box—including OpenAI, Azure OpenAI, Anthropic, Google, Mistral, and more—so you can write your code once and switch pro
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/building-ai-powered-apps-azure-cosmos-db-vercel-ai-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standardizing HLSL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The HLSL team is excited to announce the formation of Ecma Technical Committee 57; a committee to standardize the High Level Shading Language. The formation of this committee marks an important milestone in HLSL&#39;s development and strengthens Microsoft&#39;s commitment to HLSL
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/standardizing-hlsl 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can high-temperature superconductors transform the power infrastructure of datacenters?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the demand for AI and data-intensive computing is on the rise, the need for efficient and reliable power delivery is critical. The post Can high-temperature superconductors transform the power infrastructure of datacenters? appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/can-high-temperature-superconductors-transform-the-power-infrastructure-of-datacenters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did Windows 95 get permission to put the Weezer video &lt;i&gt;Buddy Holly&lt;/i&gt; on the CD?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I noted that the Windows 95 CD contained a variety of multimedia extras, partly because they were fun, and partly to show off Windows 95&#39;s multimedia capabilities. One of those multime
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260210-00/?p=112052 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | February 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? C# allows digit separators (_) in numeric literals to make large numbers more readable, e.g., int num = 1_000_000; is valid and equals one million. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 🔗 Links Here’s the latest from the developer community. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/02/10/dotinsights-february-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardened Images Are Free. Now What?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Hardened Images are now free, covering Alpine, Debian, and over 1,000 images including databases, runtimes, and message buses. For security teams, this changes the economics of container vulnerability management. DHI includes security fixes from Docker’s security team, which simplifies security response. Platform teams can pull the patched base image and redeploy quickly. But free...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hardened-images-free-now-what/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Databao: The JetBrains Tool That Lets You Talk to Your Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we build tools that help teams work with complex systems in a more productive and enjoyable way. As AI becomes part of everyday workflows, a new challenge is emerging for data teams: How can you enable AI-assisted analytics without sacrificing accuracy, transparency, or control over data? Today, we’re introducing Databao, a new data […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/databao/2026/02/introducing-databao/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[New Livestream] Go 1.26 Release Party</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for the Go 1.26 Release Party, where we’ll celebrate the latest Go release together with the community. In this livestream, Go experts will walk through what’s new in Go 1.26, why the changes matter, and how they impact real-world Go development. Date: February 19, 2026 Time: 4:00 – 5:30 pm UTC The celebration […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2026/02/10/new-livestream-go-1-26-release-party/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to Use Abstract Factory Pattern in C#: Decision Guide with Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn when to use Abstract Factory pattern in C# with clear decision criteria, code examples, and scenarios. Understand the signs that indicate Abstract Factory is the right choice.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/10/when-to-use-abstract-factory-pattern-in-c-decision-guide-with-examples 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Local Models to Agent Workflows: Building a Deep Research Solution with Microsoft Agent Framework on Microsoft Foundry Local</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction: A New Paradigm for AI Application Development In enterprise AI application development, we often face this dilemma: while cloud-based large language models are powerful
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/from-local-models-to-agent-workflows-building-a-deep-research-solution-with-microsoft-agent-framework-on-microsoft-foundry-local 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Scholarships from the JetBrains Foundation – Applications Are Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The JetBrains Foundation is offering up to 40 full scholarships for the Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence BSc program at Neapolis University Pafos starting this year. Find the complete program details here. What’s New for 2026 These scholarships are comprehensive, covering tuition, accommodation, medical insurance, visa fees, and a monthly stipend (€300). Graduates of programs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2026/02/10/full-scholarships-from-the-jetbrains-foundation-applications-are-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing strongly-typed IDs in .NET for safer domain models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:44:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we know that user requests can be unpredictable. When they request data, it is either successfully returned or not found. However, a &amp;quot;not found&amp;quot; result usually happens in two ways. First, the user might request a record, such as a basketball player, by passing an ID
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/pimplementing-strongly-typed-ids-in-net-for-safer-domain-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: .NET Projects and the Tools Behind Them</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 07:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference – the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the people […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2026/02/10/open-source-in-focus-dotnet-projects-and-the-tools-behind-them/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot reference implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post dives deeper into the implementation architecture for the Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automated-reasoning-checks-rewriting-chatbot-reference-implementation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Travel in Azure SQL with Temporal Tables</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications often need to know what data looked like before. Who changed it, when it changed, and what the previous values were. Rebuilding that history in application code is tedious and error prone. This is especially valuable when exposing a database to an AI agent through MCP servers like SQL MCP Server, where information discovery mat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/time-travel-in-azure-sql-with-temporal-tables 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale LLM fine-tuning with Hugging Face and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how this integrated approach transforms enterprise LLM fine-tuning from a complex, resource-intensive challenge into a streamlined, scalable solution for achieving better model performance in domain-specific applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-llm-fine-tuning-with-hugging-face-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Relic transforms productivity with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Working with the Generative AI Innovation Center, New Relic NOVA (New Relic Omnipresence Virtual Assistant) evolved from a knowledge assistant into a comprehensive productivity engine. We explore the technical architecture, development journey, and key lessons learned in building an enterprise-grade AI solution that delivers measurable productivity gains at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-relic-transforms-productivity-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate agentic application development with a full-stack starter template for Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to deploy Fullstack AgentCore Solution Template (FAST) to your Amazon Web Services (AWS) account, understand its architecture, and see how to extend it for your requirements. You will learn how to build your own agent while FAST handles authentication, infrastructure as code (IaC), deployment pipelines, and service integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-agentic-application-development-with-a-full-stack-starter-template-for-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent-to-agent collaboration: Using Amazon Nova 2 Lite and Amazon Nova Act for multi-agent systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how agent-to-agent collaboration on Amazon Bedrock works in practice, using Amazon Nova 2 Lite for planning and Amazon Nova Act for browser interaction, to turn a fragile single-agent setup into a predictable multi-agent system.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/agent-to-agent-collaboration-using-amazon-nova-2-lite-and-amazon-nova-act-for-multi-agent-systems/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should I do if a wait call reports &lt;CODE&gt;WAIT_&lt;WBR&gt;ABANDONED&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you call a wait function like Wait­For­Single­Object and receive the code WAIT_ABANDONED, what does it mean and what should you do? The documentation says that WAIT_ABANDONED means that you successfully claimed a mutex, but the thread that previously owned the mutex failed t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260209-00/?p=112049 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:34:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Better late than never, as I’m writing this in early February 2026… First, here are a few links to past years in review:
My 2017 Year in Review My 2018 Year in Review My 2019 Year in Review My 2020 Year in Review My 2021 Year in Review My 2022 Year in Review My 2023 Year in Review My 2024 Year in Review My Year in Review Post Checklist
Now on to the various categories…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Service Discovery in C# with Needlr: How It Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Needlr&#39;s automatic service discovery works in C# with convention-based registration, type scanning, and the DoNotAutoRegister attribute for .NET applications.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/09/automatic-service-discovery-in-c-with-needlr-how-it-works 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting more information in MSBuild binlogs with property tracking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSBuild binary logs (binlogs) are a powerful tool for diagnosing build issues. If you&#39;re not familiar with binlogs, check out my post Exploring a MSBuild binary log using the binary log viewer to get started, or Stop using diagnostic verbosity in MSBuild to understand why binlogs are better than diagnostic verbosity. By default, binlogs capture a lot of information, but you can get even more details about…
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing ChatGPT to GenAI.mil</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI for Government announces the deployment of a custom ChatGPT on GenAI.mil, bringing secure, safety-forward AI to U.S. defense teams.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bringing-chatgpt-to-genaimil 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing ads in ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI begins testing ads in ChatGPT to support free access, with clear labeling, answer independence, strong privacy protections, and user control.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/testing-ads-in-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolate the swiyu Public Beta management APIs using YARP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at hardening the security for the swiyu public beta infrastructure. The generic containers provide both management APIs and wallet APIs which support the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations 1.0 specification. The management APIs require both network protection and application security. This post looks at implementing the network isolation. Code: https://github.com/swiss-ssi-group/swiyu-passkeys-idp-loi-loa Blogs in this […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2026/02/09/isolate-the-swiyu-public-beta-management-apis-using-yarp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
