<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:55:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update, October 2025 – Compose Hot Reload and UX Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.8.0 is out, with Compose Hot Reload, a customizable Kotlin compiler version, new JavaScript and Wasm platforms, and many other improvements to both the IDE and CLI experience. Read on for all of the details, and see the release notes for the full list of changes and bug fixes. To get support for Amper’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/10/amper-update-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Lab to Live: A Blueprint for a Voice-Powered AI Sales Coach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Until recently, building real-time voice AI for production was challenging. Developers faced hurdles such as managing audio streams and ensuring low-latency performance. That landscape is changing. The
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/from-lab-to-live-a-blueprint-for-a-voice-powered-ai-sales-coach 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance agentic workflows with enterprise search using Kore.ai and Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how organizations can enhance their employee productivity by integrating Kore.ai’s AI for Work platform with Amazon Q Business. We show how to configure AI for Work as a data accessor for Amazon Q index for independent software vendors (ISVs), so employees can search enterprise knowledge and execute end-to-end agentic workflows involving search, reasoning, actions, and content generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-agentic-workflows-with-enterprise-search-using-kore-ai-and-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate development with the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore MCP server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Model Context Protocol (MCP) Server. With built-in support for runtime, gateway integration, identity management, and agent memory, the AgentCore MCP Server is purpose-built to speed up creation of components compatible with Bedrock AgentCore. You can use the AgentCore MCP server for rapid prototyping, production AI solutions, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-development-with-the-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-mcpserver/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 – v2025.2.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/10/intellij-idea-2025-2-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Live! Orlando – Your Ultimate Learning Adventure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine swapping stories with fellow developers over dinner as the Florida sun sets, then beginning the next morning with a stroll past the resort’s palm-lined walkways before catching your first session across
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-live-orlando-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (September 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-september-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog × A2A: Building Connected AI Agents in Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever tried building a system of multiple AI agents, you’ve probably run into the problem. It starts simple enough: You’ve got one agent writing blog posts, another proofreading them, and maybe a third suggesting or generating images. Individually, they’re effective. But getting them to work together? That’s where things might start falling apart. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/10/koog-a2a-building-connected-ai-agents-in-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AXA Belgium’s Journey to Running .NET Web APIs on AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Among others, the insurance industry is embracing the benefits of cloud-focused serverless computing services to run code without the overhead of provisioning or managing servers. Moving on-premises .NET Web APIs to such destinations come with a broad range of considerations. This blog post provides a return of experience from AXA Belgium’s engineering team and their […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/axa-belgiums-journey-to-running-net-web-apis-on-aws-lambda/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem with inferring from a function call operator is that there may be more than one</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I wrote briefly on writing a helper class for generating a particular category of C callback wrappers around C++ methods. This particular
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251002-00/?p=111647 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Visual Studio 2026: Day-One Compatibility, Migration Steps, and Performance Gains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here, and the next major VS update is on the horizon. As with any new Visual Studio version, one of the first questions developers ask is: “Will my extensions work after updating – especially ReSharper?”. The short answer is a resounding “yes”. But there’s more to the story, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/02/resharper-and-visual-studio-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Shell Scripts to Science Agents: How AI Agents Are Transforming Research Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s 2 AM in a lab somewhere. A researcher has three terminals open, a half-written Jupyter notebook on one screen, an Excel sheet filled with sample IDs on another, and a half-eaten snack next to shell commands. They’re juggling scripts to run a protein folding model, parsing CSVs from the last experiment, searching for literature,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-science-agents-research-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning Local Models with Docker Offload and Unsloth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve been experimenting with local models for a while now, and the progress in making them accessible has been exciting. Initial experiences are often fantastic, many models, like Gemma 3 270M, are lightweight enough to run on common hardware. This potential for broad deployment is a major draw. However, as I&#39;ve tried to build meaningful,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/fine-tuning-models-with-offload-and-unsloth/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With GPT-5, Wrtn builds lifestyle AI for millions in Korea</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wrtn scaled AI apps to 6.5M users in Korea with GPT-5, creating ‘Lifestyle AI’ that blends productivity, creativity, and learning—now expanding across East Asia.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/wrtn 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving PHP open source forward</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we want the PHP community to shine. First and foremost, we do this by building PhpStorm, the best IDE for PHP development; but we also support and help drive the PHP Foundation; have just organised PHPverse, accessible for everyone worldwide; and recently we made the Laravel Idea plugin free for all. On top […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/10/moving-php-open-source-forward/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Fabric Eventhouse to Store Great Expectations Validation Results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a previous post, we explored how to perform data validations with Great Expectations (GX) in Microsoft Fabric. We walked through how to set up the validation framework and ensure your data meets the quality standards expected. Now, in thi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/leveraging-fabric-eventhouse-to-store-great-expectations-validation-results 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (September 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 05:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.09.17 registry release, the 2025-08-29 and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-september-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI announces strategic collaboration with Japan’s Digital Agency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Japan’s Digital Agency partner to advance generative AI in public services, support international AI governance, and promote safe, trustworthy AI adoption worldwide.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/strategic-collaboration-with-japan-digital-agency 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Hapag-Lloyd improved schedule reliability with ML-powered vessel schedule predictions using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Hapag-Lloyd developed and implemented a machine learning (ML)-powered assistant predicting vessel arrival and departure times that revolutionizes their schedule planning. By using Amazon SageMaker AI and implementing robust MLOps practices, Hapag-Lloyd has enhanced its schedule reliability—a key performance indicator in the industry and quality promise to their customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-hapag-lloyd-improved-schedule-reliability-with-ml-powered-vessel-schedule-predictions-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rox accelerates sales productivity with AI agents powered by Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that Rox is generally available, with Rox infrastructure built on AWS and delivered across web, Slack, macOS, and iOS. In this post, we share how Rox accelerates sales productivity with AI agents powered by Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/rox-accelerates-sales-productivity-with-ai-agents-powered-by-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways I Use Background Coding Agents Every Day</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Coding agents are different from in-editor chat and agent modes for AI assisted programming. They run asynchronously—often in the cloud—tackling tasks while you focus locally. I rely heavily on the GitHub Copilot coding agent and its VS Code integration to spin up multiple parallel workflows. Below
Link to article: https://montemagno.com/5-ways-i-use-background-coding-agents-every-day/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The $150 Secret Hiding in Plain Sight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picture this: I’m standing in front of 400+ developers at Visual Studio Live! Redmond, right here on the Microsoft campus in Building 33, about to reveal what I call the hidden value of a Visual Studio subscription. I pull up a simple question on the screen:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/unlock-vss-benefits-myvisualstudio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip Is Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a change in our licensing model that we believe will benefit the developer community – DataGrip is now free for non-commercial use! With this change, DataGrip joins JetBrains RustRover, CLion, Rider, WebStorm, and RubyMine, which are already free for non-commercial use. Read on to learn more about the change and why […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/10/01/datagrip-is-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Microsoft Agent Framework (Preview): Making AI Agents Simple for Every Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI agents shouldn&#39;t be rocket science. Yet many developers find themselves wrestling with complex orchestration logic, struggling to connect multiple AI models, or spending weeks building hosting infrastructure just to get a simple agent into production. What if building an AI agent could be as straightforward as creating a web API
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-microsoft-agent-framework-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I convert a &lt;code&gt;FILETIME&lt;/code&gt; to a C&#43;&#43; clock like &lt;code&gt;std::system_clock&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;winrt::clock&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The traditional Win32 data structure for holding a date/time is the FILETIME. How do you interoperate between this and the C++ clocks like std::system_clock and winrt::clock? When C++ introduced the concept of clocks in C++11, it did not require clocks to have any particular epoch. In C++20, th
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251001-00/?p=111643 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Microsoft Agent Framework: The Open-Source Engine for Agentic AI Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why agents need a new foundation Over the last year, developers have been experimenting with AI agents in every imaginable form. Agents are not just chatbots or copilots — they are autonomous software components that can reason about goals, call tools and APIs, collaborate with other agents, and adapt dynamically.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/introducing-microsoft-agent-framework-the-open-source-engine-for-agentic-ai-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock Your Code: Coding Standards for Microsoft .NET (20th Anniversary Edition)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 20th Anniversary Edition of Rock Your Code: Coding Standards for Microsoft .NET, authored by David McCarter, is now available on Amazon. This comprehensive guide offers updated standards for .NET 10, best practices, and expert insights, making it essential for software engineers aiming for improved code quality and performance over two decades.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/10/01/rock-your-code-coding-standards-for-microsoft-net-20th-anniversary-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Array Performance in .NET: Getting the Most from ArrayPool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ArrayPool optimizes memory usage by providing a thread-safe pool of reusable arrays, significantly reducing allocations and garbage collection pressure, especially in high-performance scenarios. It&#39;s effective for I/O, serialization, and media processing. Best practices include tight scope management, clearing sensitive data on return, and careful tracking of logical array lengths.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/10/01/optimizing-array-performance-in-net-getting-the-most-from-arraypool/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samsung and SK join OpenAI’s Stargate initiative to advance global AI infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Samsung and SK join OpenAI’s Stargate initiative to expand global AI infrastructure, scaling advanced memory chip production and building next-gen data centers in Korea.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/samsung-and-sk-join-stargate 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Marten’s 10th Birthday!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 20:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To the best of my recollection and internet sleuthing today, development on Marten started in October of 2015 after my then colleague Corey Kaylor had kicked around an idea the previous summer to utilize the new JSONB feature in PostgreSQL 9.4 as a way to replace our then problematic usage of a third party NoSQL … Continue reading Celebrating Marten’s 10th Birthday! →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/30/celebrating-martens-10th-birthday/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize fraud prevention: GraphStorm v0.5 for real-time inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 20:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to implement real-time fraud prevention using GraphStorm v0.5&#39;s new capabilities for deploying graph neural network (GNN) models through Amazon SageMaker. We show how to transition from model training to production-ready inference endpoints with minimal operational overhead, enabling sub-second fraud detection on transaction graphs with billions of nodes and edges.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/modernize-fraud-prevention-graphstorm-v0-5-for-real-time-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Recognized in the 2025 Magic Quadrant™ for AI Code Assistants</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, JetBrains’s AI (including both AI Assistant and Junie) was recognized in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for AI Code Assistants, an industry that we believe is innovating and changing faster than almost any other. Using AI is now a fundamental part of software development. Developers are increasingly able to automate mundane tasks like […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/30/jetbrains-recognized-in-the-2025-magic-quadrant-for-ai-code-assistants/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript 7 native preview in Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In March of this year Anders Hejlsberg announced TypeScript 7 native preview and in May Daniel posted Announcing TypeScript Native Previews. Visual Studio 2026 Insiders n
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/typescript-7-native-preview-in-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: Convicted</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you do something with conviction, you do so with full confidence that you are correct. But what is the verb that means &amp;quot;To be fully confident that one is correct&amp;quot;? At Microsoft, it is often backformed into the verb convict (stress on second syllable). This backformation typically happens in speech,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250930-00/?p=111639 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio September Update - profiler agent, app modernization, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The September 2025 update for Visual Studio 2022 (v17.14) is now available. In this month, we are bringing you a fully integrated and game-changing agentic AI experience, from code generation to modernization, profiling, and code reviews.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-september-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better AI Depends on Better Data: We Need Your Help</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Over the past few years, AI has made remarkable progress, but it doesn’t always deliver what professional developers need. One key reason is that most models are trained on public datasets that don’t reflect the complex, real-world scenarios faced by professional developers every day. Without such real-world data, our AI tools will fall short. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/30/detailed-data-sharing-for-better-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing NuGet packages from GitHub actions the easy way with Trusted Publishing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how you can use nuget.org&#39;s new Trusted Publishing feature to publish NuGet packages from a GitHub Actions workflow
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/easily-publishing-nuget-packages-from-github-actions-with-trusted-publishing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sora feed philosophy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the Sora feed philosophy—built to spark creativity, foster connections, and keep experiences safe with personalized recommendations, parental controls, and strong guardrails.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/sora-feed-philosophy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to TeamCity On-Premises Renewal Pricing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re committed to continuously improving TeamCity and providing high-quality support. To reflect that ongoing investment, we’re updating our renewal pricing and grace period policies, effective November 3, 2025. At the same time, we’re ensuring that all existing licenses purchased before November 3, 2025, will continue to benefit from the current renewal discounts. What’s changing? Next […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/09/updates-to-teamcity-on-premises-renewal-pricing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Costs of Boxing in C#: How to Detect and Avoid Them</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:53:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# Boxing and Unboxing are vital players in the performance of an application. However, they are often overlooked. They involve heap allocations that bring a penalty due to their accessing mechanism. In today&#39;s post, we will unfold Boxing and Unboxing in detail, study how they are costly to
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/hidden-costs-of-boxing-in-c-how-to-detect-and-avoid-them/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s OpenJDK builds now ready for Java 25</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK binaries are now available for Java 25. As always, our builds aim to provide a high-quality, production-ready build of OpenJDK, with binaries tested across plat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/microsofts-openjdk-builds-now-ready-for-java-25 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching Sora responsibly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To address the novel safety challenges posed by a state-of-the-art video model as well as a new social creation platform, we’ve built Sora 2 and the Sora app with safety at the foundation. Our approach is anchored in concrete protections.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/launching-sora-responsibly 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sora 2 is here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our latest video generation model is more physically accurate, realistic, and controllable than prior systems. It also features synchronized dialogue and sound effects. Create with it in the new Sora app.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/sora-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sora 2 System Card</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sora 2 is our new state of the art video and audio generation model. Building on the foundation of Sora, this new model introduces capabilities that have been difficult for prior video models to achieve– such as more accurate physics, sharper realism, synchronized audio, enhanced steerability, and an expanded stylistic range.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/sora-2-system-card 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Docker Hardened Images: Secure Helm Charts for Deployments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Development teams are under growing pressure to secure their software supply chains. Teams need trusted images, streamlined deployments, and compliance-ready tooling from partners they can rely on long term. Our customers have made it clear that they’re not just looking for one-off vendors. They’re looking for true security partners across development and deployment. That’s why...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hardened-images-helm-charts-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leader Election and Virtual Actors in Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A JasperFx Software client was asking recently about the features for software controlled load balancing and “sticky” agents I’m describing in this post. Since these features are both critical for Wolverine functionality and maybe not perfectly documented already, it’s a great topic for a new blog post! Both because it’s helpful to understand what’s going … Continue reading Leader Election and Virtual Actors in Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/29/leader-election-and-virtual-actors-in-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data API builder 1.6: Advanced Behaviors with Special HTTP Headers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data API builder (DAB) provides REST and GraphQL endpoints over SQL Server, Azure Cosmos DB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and SQL Data Warehouse. REST endpoints support several HTTP headers that let you control how requests behave. These headers give you precision over updates, caching, and discovering new resources.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/data-api-builder-16-http-headers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Claude Agent in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: The new Claude Agent is now seamlessly integrated into JetBrains IDEs via the AI chat and included in the JetBrains AI subscription. No extra plugins, no extra subscriptions – just advanced AI coding assistance built on Anthropic’s Agent SDK, which powers Claude Code, right inside your IDE. The new agent leverages Anthropic models, including […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/introducing-claude-agent-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Overload Resolution For Parameter Arrays in C&#43;&#43;/CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In the below discussion, .NET Framework refers to the older version of the Microsoft Common Language Runtime, also known as &amp;quot;Desktop Framework&amp;quot; (versions 4.0 through 4.8.x) while .NET refers t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/fixing-overload-resolution-for-parameter-arrays-in-c-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I enumerate the overflow icons in the Notification Area without showing them?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I demonstrated enumerating notification icons via UI Automation. Part of the exercise was enumerating the icons in the overflow area. This was done by finding the button that expands the over
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250929-00/?p=111637 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building OpenAI with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At OpenAI, we rely on our own technology to help streamline work, scale expertise, and drive outcomes. In our new series, OpenAI on OpenAI, we share lessons to help other organizations do the same.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/building-openai-with-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting inbound leads into customers at OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI used AI to deliver personalized answers at scale, converting inbound leads into customers.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-inbound-sales-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving sales productivity and customer success at OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI boosts sales productivity by automating prep, centralizing knowledge, and scaling top-selling practices.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-gtm-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering teams to unlock insights faster at OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s research assistant helps teams analyze millions of support tickets, surface insights faster, and scale curiosity across the company.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-research-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving support with every interaction at OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI uses AI to enhance support, cutting response times, improving quality, and scaling to meet hypergrowth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-support-model 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning contracts into searchable data at OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI built a system to extract contract data quickly, cutting turnaround times and making it easier for teams to access the details they need.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-contract-data-agent 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker MCP Toolkit: MCP Servers That Just Work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we want to highlight Docker MCP Toolkit, a free feature in Docker Desktop that gives you access to more than 200 MCP servers. It’s the easiest and most secure way to run MCP servers locally for your AI agents and workflows. The MCP toolkit allows you to isolate MCP servers in containers, securely configure...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-toolkit-mcp-servers-that-just-work/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I tried out JetBrains’ code analysis tool Qodana”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the English version of the Japanese article first published by Jan Maki on Qiita. This post was not commissioned by Qodana and was written independently. For more information please reach out to them in the comments or via their link tree. Qodana is JetBrains’ code analysis platform for quality and aspects of code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/09/i-tried-out-jetbrains-code-analysis-tool-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Git insteadOf to Automatically Replace HTTPS URLs with SSH</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with Git repositories, you often encounter URLs in HTTPS format, especially when cloning from GitHub, GitLab, or other hosting services. However, if you prefer using SSH for authentication (which is often more convenient with key-based auth), manually changing URLs can be tedious. Also, it can be even harder when dealing with submodules. Git&#39;s insteadOf configuration option provides an…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/using-git-insteadof-to-automatically-replace-https-urls-with-ssh.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combating online child sexual exploitation &amp; abuse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how OpenAI combats online child sexual exploitation and abuse with strict usage policies, advanced detection tools, and industry collaboration to block, report, and prevent AI misuse.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/combating-online-child-sexual-exploitation-abuse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing parental controls</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re rolling out parental controls and a new parent resource page to help families guide how ChatGPT works in their homes.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-parental-controls 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buy it in ChatGPT: Instant Checkout and the Agentic Commerce Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re taking first steps toward agentic commerce in ChatGPT with new ways for people, AI agents, and businesses to shop together.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/buy-it-in-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Sprint to Wolverine 5.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Little update since the last check in on Wolverine 5.0. I think right now that Wolverine 5.0 hits by next Monday (October 6th). To be honest, besides documentation updates, the biggest work is just pushing more on the CritterWatch backend this week to see if that forces any breaking changes in the Wolverine internals. What’s … Continue reading Last Sprint to Wolverine 5.0 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/28/last-sprint-to-wolverine-5-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify Unique Key Generation with KeyGenerator in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The KeyGenerator in Spargine is an efficient tool for generating unique keys using GUIDs, ideal for object IDs and database records. It offers methods for creating keys with or without prefixes. This utility simplifies the process of generating unique keys, enhancing workflow in .NET projects, alongside the UlidGenerator for ULIDs.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/09/28/boost-your-net-projects-simplify-unique-key-generation-with-keygenerator-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ardalis Fall 2025 Speaking Tour</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2025/27_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2025/27_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I may have gone a bit overboard this year... I&#39;ve scheduled myself for 5 developer conferences in 4 weeks during October 2025! If you&#39;re…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/ardalis-fall-2025-speaking-tour/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Secure APIs with Role-Based Access Control in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2025/27_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2025/27_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) in ASP.NET Core with custom authorization handlers, permission-based policies, and clean extension methods for both Minimal APIs and MVC controllers.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/building-secure-apis-with-role-based-access-control-in-aspnetcore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Hotkey Typer — type long prompts with a hotkey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 22:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I&#39;m recording demos or making videos I often need to reproduce long prompts or blocks of text on-screen. Manually retyping them every time is slow and error-prone, and pasting from the clipboard can feel jerky and reveal private content. I wanted a tiny, reliable app that would
Link to article: https://montemagno.com/announcing-hotkey-typer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing Your .NET MAUI Apps for Google Play&#39;s 16 KB Page Size Requirement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you&#39;re a .NET MAUI developer publishing apps to Google Play, there&#39;s an important requirement coming your way. Starting November 1st, 2025, Google Play will require all new apps and updates targeting Android 15+ to support 16 KB page sizes on 64-bit devices. What is the 16 KB Page Size Requirement? Androi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/maui-google-play-16-kb-page-size-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building health care agents using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this solution, we demonstrate how the user (a parent) can interact with a Strands or LangGraph agent in conversational style and get information about the immunization history and schedule of their child, inquire about the available slots, and book appointments. With some changes, AI agents can be made event-driven so that they can automatically send reminders, book appointments, and so on.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-health-care-agents-using-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build multi-agent site reliability engineering assistants with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a multi-agent SRE assistant using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, LangGraph, and the Model Context Protocol (MCP). This system deploys specialized AI agents that collaborate to provide the deep, contextual intelligence that modern SRE teams need for effective incident response and infrastructure management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-multi-agent-site-reliability-engineering-assistants-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why didn&#39;t Windows 95 setup install a miniature Windows 95 so that it could be written as a 32-bit program?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I noted some time ago that Windows 95 Setup was actually three programs running under three different operating systems. The first part was an MS-DOS program, which was used if you installed Windows 9
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250926-00/?p=111629 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trust Paradox: When Your AI Gets Catfished</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The fundamental challenge with MCP-enabled attacks isn&#39;t technical sophistication. It&#39;s that hackers have figured out how to catfish your AI. These attacks work because they exploit the same trust relationships that make your development team actually functional. When your designers expect Figma files from agencies they&#39;ve worked with for years, when your DevOps folks trust...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-prompt-injection-trust-paradox/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Resource Management in mssql-python through Context Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reviewed by: Sumit Sarabhai
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/simplifying-resource-management-in-mssql-python-through-context-manager 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking MCP in JetBrains: How Copilot Uses Sampling, Prompts, Resources, and Elicitation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 07:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the enhanced capability of the MCP on JetBrains, you can now bring prompts, resources, and even interac
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/unlocking-mcp-in-jetbrains-how-copilot-uses-sampling-prompts-resources-and-elicitation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Java Open-Source Projects Use IntelliJ IDEA: Real-World Examples – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 07:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of this series, we introduced some of the Java community’s most recognized open-source projects. Now, we’re back with more standouts: projects that speed up builds, strengthen testing, and simplify working with modern web stacks. And as always, IntelliJ IDEA helps maintainers move faster, confidently, and with a focus on quality. 🌿 jsoup […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/26/how-java-open-source-projects-use-intellij-idea-real-world-examples-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partnering with AARP to help keep older adults safe online</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and AARP are partnering to help older adults stay safe online with new AI training, scam-spotting tools, and nationwide programs through OpenAI Academy and OATS’s Senior Planet initiative.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/aarp-partnership-older-adults-online-safety 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
