<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 20:16:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Unified Development Environment is GA!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 20:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview We are proud to announce that the Unified Developer Experience for Finance and Operations apps (colloquially known as UDE) is now generally availablity for all customers. As you may know, UDE is both the next step in the app development experience for Finance and Operations,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/the-unified-development-environment-is-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the official OpenAI library for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The initial beta release of the official OpenAI library for .NET is now available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/openai-dotnet-library 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware! Anti-patterns in Event-Driven Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 18:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Event-driven architecture has patterns and common practices that are solutions for various problems. The issue arises when you apply these patterns when you don’t have the problem they solve, or you can avoid having the problem in the first place. Here are some patterns and why the might become anti-patterns in a given context. YouTube… Read More »Beware! Anti-patterns in Event-Driven Architecture The post Beware! Anti-patterns in Event-Driven Architecture appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build RAG applications using Jina Embeddings v2 on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the Jina Embeddings v2 model, developed by Jina AI, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy with one click for running model inference. This state-of-the-art model supports an impressive 8,192-tokens context length. You can deploy this model with SageMaker JumpStart, a machine learning (ML) hub […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-rag-applications-using-jina-embeddings-v2-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Super Resolution: The First OS-Integrated AI-Based Super Resolution for Gaming</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the latest innovation in gaming graphics with Automatic super resolution (Auto SR)—the first OS-integrated AI super resolution (SR) technique where your games not only play smoother, but look stunning too! Ready for a quick visual challenge? Take a glance at these side-by-side images of Borderlands 3 played natively at 1440p versus one rendered at 720p but enhanced by AI-based Auto SR.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/autosr 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – June 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The June 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include an experimental Python REPL with Intellisense and syntax highlighting, and pytest improvements on the testing rewrite. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-june-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Your Own AI-Driven Code Analysis Chatbot for Developers with the GenAI Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We dive into a winning Docker AI/ML Hackathon submission, Code Explorer, which might spark project ideas for you.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-your-own-ai-driven-code-analysis-chatbot-genai-stack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification validates app compliance through annual pen testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn more about the Microsoft 365 Certification and how pen testing can help verify your app’s underlying security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-validates-app-compliance-through-annual-pen-testing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can INI files be Unicode? Yes, they can, but it has to be your idea</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;ll only be Unicode if it&#39;s already Unicode.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240606-00/?p=109861 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop Kubernetes Operators in Java without Breaking a Sweat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 13:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover testing possibilities that let developers consider Java as the language of choice for Kubernetes-related projects.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/develop-kubernetes-operators-in-java-without-breaking-a-sweat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream – An Authentic Voice in Young Professionals: Why and How Educators Should Foster It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 12:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, June 18, at 3:00 pm UTC for the third livestream in the JetBrains Academy series for educators, An Authentic Voice in Young Professionals: Why and How Educators Should Foster It with Andrew Paul. Andrew has extensive teaching experience at various academic levels. He started his journey in education with Kainos, Queen’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/06/06/an-authentic-voice-in-young-professionals-why-and-how-educators-should-foster-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 10:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? A commonly used sorting algorithm known as Bogosort is also referred to as the ‘slow sort’. Because the algorithm works by generating all permutations of its input until it finds one that is sorted, makes it significantly inefficient and impractical for large data sets. Despite its impracticality, it’s often mentioned in computer […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/06/dotinsights-june-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Trial Periods Now Available for Plugins on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 10:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Selling your plugins on JetBrains Marketplace comes with numerous benefits. The platform handles licensing and billing, eliminating the need for a custom solution and simplifying the checkout process by taking care of payment processing and sales-related communications. JetBrains Marketplace allows you to fine-tune your offering, including volume and community discounts, as well as coupons with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/06/flexible-trial-periods-now-available-for-plugins-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Code Analysis for Spring: Run Analysis, Fix Critical Errors, Hit the Beach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fun fact: 72% of our JVM users use Spring in their applications, especially in industries like manufacturing and finance. Why? Spring makes programming with Java and Kotlin quicker, easier, and safer for everybody – but it also comes with unique challenges. Why is it so tricky to manage code quality in Spring? Spring has a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/06/static-code-analysis-for-spring-run-analysis-fix-critical-errors-hit-the-beach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bouncy Castle Cryptography Library for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 05:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cryptography remains an ever-important topic in building modern security-minded applications. Bouncy Castle is a cryptography library for .NET that allows users to build robust cryptography features. In this article, we will cover just a few important capabilities Bouncy Castle offers us and how to implement them. Let’s get started! What is Bouncy Castle? Bouncy Castle […] The post Bouncy Castle Cryptography Library for .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New LinkedIn Learning Course on Semantic Kernel Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 20:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today’s topic will cover a new LinkedIn Learning Course here: If you can code in .NET, you are an AI developer | LinkedIn Learning focused on Semantic Kernel Fundamentals. We are excited to welcome back José Luis Latorre Millás, an MVP for Microsoft focused on AI who worked on this to dive in further.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/new-linkedin-learning-course-on-semantic-kernel-fundamentals 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect email phishing attempts using Amazon Comprehend</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 19:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Phishing is the process of attempting to acquire sensitive information such as usernames, passwords and credit card details by masquerading as a trustworthy entity using email, telephone or text messages. There are many types of phishing based on the mode of communication and targeted victims. In an Email phishing attempt, an email is sent as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/detect-email-phishing-attempts-using-amazon-comprehend/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combat impersonation using Face Check with Microsoft Entra Verified ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 18:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post highlights the need for better identity verification methods to prevent fraud and impersonation. Microsoft Entra Verified ID&#39;s Face Check, showcased at Microsoft Build 2024, enhances security by comparing live selfies with trusted photos, effectively preventing unauthorized access and detecting spoofing techniques.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/verified-id-face-check 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSTest 3.4 is here with WinUI support and new analyzers!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSTest 3.4 is available. Learn all about the highlighted features and fixes that will make your testing experience always better.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-mstest-34 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating C&#43;&#43; header units into Office using MSVC (3/n)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 16:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview Recap: Where we were, what we’re doing now. Changes adopted in Word: Composing headers for reuse. Testing Details: The setup of the performance experiment. Opportunity for Improvement: Identifying a potential performance bottleneck. Upcoming Improvements to MSVC. What’s next for Office?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/integrating-c-header-units-into-office-using-msvc-3-n 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Skyflow creates technical content in days using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 15:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guest post is co-written with Manny Silva, Head of Documentation at Skyflow, Inc. Startups move quickly, and engineering is often prioritized over documentation. Unfortunately, this prioritization leads to release cycles that don’t match, where features release but documentation lags behind. This leads to increased support calls and unhappy customers. Skyflow is a data privacy […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-skyflow-creates-technical-content-in-days-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writerside’s First AI EAP Release is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 14:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The first Writerside build with AI-powered features is now available as part of its Early Access Program. Read on the full story, or jump straight to the new features. No longer a threat, AI is a writer’s friend Just one year ago, tech writers felt threatened by the AI breakthrough and were worried their jobs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/06/writerside-s-first-ai-eap-release-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving our Azure marketplace images a makeover</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We previously announced the addition of new, optimized Azure VM image offers to help you create and test your applications faster and more easily on Azure VMs and the Microsoft Dev Box service. As we continue to evolve and optimize our offers,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/giving-our-visual-studio-azure-marketplace-images-a-makeover 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How 16-bit Windows cached INI files for performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Taking advantage of co-operative multitasking.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240605-00/?p=109852 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the first Rider 2024.2 Early Access Program (EAP) build just around the corner, we thought we’d give you an idea of what we’re working on for the next major update. The following is a list of our priorities for the next release. Note that these are the features we’re working on, however some might […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/05/rider-2024-2-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 08:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly is here! This month, we’re thrilled to welcome Tom Cools to share some of the interesting things he’s found of late in our Featured Content section. As always, we bring you the latest Java news, highlighting the key JEPs set to be available in Java 23. You’ll also […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/java-annotated-monthly-june-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and downloading a PDF or DOCX in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post shows how a PDF can be created from data in an ASP.NET Core backend and downloaded using an API. The data could be loaded from different locations and exported then as a PDF or a docx or whatever you require. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/AspNetCoreCreatePdf Why GemBox? There are many different tools to generate PDF all […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/06/05/creating-and-downloading-a-pdf-or-docx-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing ExecuteAsync() and StartAsync() Methods from the BackgroundService Class in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 05:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Due to the emerging significance of running background tasks, .NET Core has given us new ways of achieving it. BackgroundService is another tool in our toolbox with methods ExecuteAsync() and StartAsync() being the central components. In this article, we will compare these methods and demonstrate when and how to use them. We will first introduce […] The post Comparing ExecuteAsync() and StartAsync() Methods from the BackgroundService Class in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the Potential of Generative AI in Azure SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI is not just a technological advancement; it’s a paradigm shift that is redefining the landscape of customer interaction. Azure SQL Database stands at the forefront of this revolution, offering unparalleled opportunities to harness the power of “your data” in crafting state-of-the-art applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/unleashing-the-potential-of-generative-ai-in-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating One Billion MSAL.NET Downloads</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 22:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Celebrating the first billion downloads of the Microsoft Authentication Library for .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/msal-net-one-billion 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[security] Go 1.22.4-1 and 1.21.11-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 22:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft builds of the Go security patches released today, June 4, are now available for download. The new versions are: 1.22.4-1 1.21.11-1 For more information about the changes included in this release, take a look at the upstream Go announcement: [security] Go 1.22.4 and Go 1.21.11 are released.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/security-go-1-22-4-1-and-1-21-11-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline custom model creation and deployment for Amazon Bedrock with Provisioned Throughput using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 17:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As customers seek to incorporate their corpus of knowledge into their generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications, or to build domain-specific models, their data science teams often want to conduct A/B testing and have repeatable experiments. In this post, we discuss a solution that uses infrastructure as code (IaC) to define the process of retrieving and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-custom-model-creation-and-deployment-for-amazon-bedrock-with-provisioned-throughput-using-terraform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A beginner’s guide to mapping arrays in EF Core 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            EF Core 8 introduces support for mapping typed arrays of simple values to database columns so the semantics of the mapping can be used in the SQL generated from LINQ queries.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/array-mapping-in-ef-core-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost productivity with video conferencing transcripts and summaries with the Amazon Chime SDK Meeting Summarizer solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 16:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Businesses today heavily rely on video conferencing platforms for effective communication, collaboration, and decision-making. However, despite the convenience these platforms offer, there are persistent challenges in seamlessly integrating them into existing workflows. One of the major pain points is the lack of comprehensive tools to automate the process of joining meetings, recording discussions, and extracting […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-productivity-with-video-conferencing-transcripts-and-summaries-with-the-amazon-chime-sdk-meeting-summarizer-solution/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing UNISTR and || operator in Azure SQL Database – preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that the UNISTR intrinsic function and ANSI SQL concatenation operator (||) are now available in public preview in Azure SQL Database. The UNISTR function allows you to escape Unicode characters, making it easier to work with international text.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/announcing-unistr-and-ansi-sql-concatenation-operator-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize ASP.NET Web Forms applications in-place using DotVVM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 15:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was co-authored by Alok Bhatnagar, Technical Account Manager, AWS, and Tomáš Herceg, founder of DotVVM, an open-source framework that simplifies creating line-of-business web applications for .NET developers. Since the genesis of the .NET Framework, ASP.NET Web Forms has been a popular choice for building websites. Even to this day, there are thousands of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-asp-net-web-forms-applications-in-place-using-dotvvm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Fluid DevTools to debug your web app</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 15:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A guide to using the Fluid DevTools browser extension to inspect and manipulate Fluid data structures and containers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/use-fluid-devtools-to-debug-your-web-app 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Get Current Branch Name for Git Repo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 14:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to get the current branch name in GitHub Actions can be useful for workflows that trigger off of multiple branches of a GitHub repository. The reason this can be useful is that the branch name may be important to mark or tag the code release in some way (i.e. tag a docker image), or […] The article GitHub Actions: Get Current Branch Name for Git Repo was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Global­Lock max out at 255 locks?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Because that&#39;s how many bits were available for reporting the lock count.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240604-00/?p=109847 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Announces SOC 2 Type 2 Attestation &amp; ISO 27001 Certification</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 13:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker demonstrates commitment to security by achieving SOC 2 Type 2 attestation and ISO 27001 certification.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-announces-soc-2-type-2-attestation-iso-27001-certification/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Hands-On with Visual Studio and Azure: Live at Microsoft HQ this August!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio LIVE! Microsoft HQ 2024 August 5-9 | Microsoft Conference Center, Redmond, WA Join the Ultimate Developer Celebration! Who’s ready to connect with fellow developers and Visual Studio Product Managers this August at the Microsoft Campus in Redmond? Visual Studio Live!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/get-hands-on-with-visual-studio-and-azure-live-at-microsoft-hq-this-august 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #2: Drag, Drop, Deploy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 10:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you could click your way through a pipeline configuration. How much easier would that be? Guess what: Now you can define dependencies between jobs in TeamCity Pipelines with a simple drag and drop. Just click on the job that you’d like to connect with another one – and voilà! In case you prefer the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/06/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditionally skipping a trigger job in GitLab based on a previous job</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe the approaches I explored to conditionally skip a trigger job in GitLab based on a previous job using dynamic pipelines
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/conditionally-skipping-a-trigger-job-in-gitlab-based-on-a-previous-job/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tarsier Studios Brings Little Nightmares to Life With JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 08:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we have Tristan Louet and Meghan Corso from Tarsier Studios with us. Meghan is actively involved in advancing Unreal Engine support in JetBrains Rider and ReSharper C++, while Tristan leads the core technology team, focusing on plugins, reusable solutions, infrastructure, and methodologies. This special interview will give you a firsthand insight into their experiences […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/04/how-tarsier-studios-brings-little-nightmares-to-life-with-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Testing Processes with Contract Testing and Pact in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Optimize your .NET development workflow with contract testing and Pact. Explore the transformative impact of contract testing on testing cycles, reliability, and integration. Unlock the potential of seamless software development.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/contract-testing-net-software-development-pact/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Exception.HResult property in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 08:24:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since launching support for showing parsed HRESULT on the elmah.io UI, we have received a few questions about HRESULTs in general. While I understand that HRESULTs is probably not on everyone&#39;s radar, I think a general understanding will help with debugging. In this post, I&#39;ll asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-the-exception-hresult-property-in-c/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Mock IConfiguration.GetValue in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 05:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll take a closer look at how we can mock IConfiguration.GetValue when writing unit tests in ASP.NET Core. Let’s start! Mock IConfiguration.GetValue in ASP.NET Core Before we start mocking, we need a class that utilizes IConfiguration: public class FinanceService(IConfiguration configuration) : IFinanceService { public double CalculateTotalAmount(double hours) { var hourlyRate = configuration.GetValue(&amp;quot;FinanceSettings:HourlyRate&amp;quot;); […] The post How to Mock IConfiguration.GetValue in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>256 Seconds with dotNetDave: Handling Exceptions Part 1 – Reusable Assemblies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 20:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This content discusses exception handling in Microsoft .NET, focusing on application layer and reusable assemblies. It offers insights on preventing exceptions and notifying calling code, and references a related book. The principles are noted to be applicable to other programming languages.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/03/256-seconds-with-dotnetdave-handling-exceptions-part-1-in-reusable-assemblies/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Tenancy: Database per Tenant with Marten</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 18:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is continuing a series about multi-tenancy with Marten, Wolverine, and ASP.Net Core: In the previous post we learned how to keep all the document or event data for each tenant in the same database, but using Marten’s “conjoined multi-tenancy” model to keep the data separated. This time out, let’s go for a much higher … Continue reading Multi-Tenancy: Database per Tenant with Marten →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/06/03/multi-tenancy-database-per-tenant-with-marten/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement serverless semantic search of image and live video with Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-driven world, industries across various sectors are accumulating massive amounts of video data through cameras installed in their warehouses, clinics, roads, metro stations, stores, factories, or even private facilities. This video data holds immense potential for analysis and monitoring of incidents that may occur in these locations. From fire hazards to broken equipment, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-serverless-semantic-search-of-image-and-live-video-with-amazon-titan-multimodal-embeddings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prioritizing employee well-being: An innovative approach with generative AI and Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced corporate landscape, employee mental health has become a crucial aspect that organizations can no longer overlook. Many companies recognize that their greatest asset lies in their dedicated workforce, and each employee plays a vital role in collective success. As such, promoting employee well-being by creating a safe, inclusive, and supportive environment is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/prioritizing-employee-well-being-an-innovative-approach-with-generative-ai-and-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Download File and Commit to Repository</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A few times I’ve found the need to setup a GitHub Actions workflow that downloads a file and commits that file back to the repository. I had a need to pull in a JSON file and update it periodically to a GitHub repository. There are other scenarios where this may be needed. This article will […] The article GitHub Actions: Download File and Commit to Repository was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build intelligent apps for Microsoft 365 with Teams Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how Teams Toolkit can help you build your own custom copilot.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-intelligent-apps-for-microsoft-365-with-teams-toolkit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactor your code using alias any type</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the &amp;quot;alias any type&amp;quot; C# 12 feature through a complete demo application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/refactor-your-code-using-alias-any-type 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Revamped Visual Studio Resource Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 16:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the recent revamp of Visual Studio’s Resource Explorer, developers are in for a treat! We’re thrilled to unveil the reimagined Visual Studio Resource Explorer, and trust us, it’s a game-changer. Developers who manage resources in Visual Studio will be delighted to learn that we have finally updated our out-of-the-box resource management experience to better accommodate the needs of the modern .NET developer.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-the-revamped-visual-studio-resource-explorer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on harmful overuse of std::move</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Could we expand copy elision to cover the harmful cases?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240603-00/?p=109842 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Django 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 12:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you curious to discover the latest trends in Django development? In collaboration with the Django Foundation, PyCharm surveyed more than 4,000 Django developers from around the globe and analyzed the trends in framework usage based on their answers. In this blog post, we share the following key findings with you: Dive in to learn […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/06/the-state-of-django/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a multi-arch Docker image for a .NET application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are in a transition period where x64 architectures are not the only architectures available. Apple has switched to ARM with the M1 chip, and Microsoft is also pushing for ARM now. If you want to run your application on ARM64 and x64 architectures, you need to create a Docker image for each architecture. Docker supports multi-arch images, which allow you to create a single image that can run on multiple…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code Update – May 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 09:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the May update for Visual Studio Code for Java! In this blog we are going to share an exciting new AI related feature for Java developers on Visual Studio Code. In addition, there will be several important Spring updates,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-visual-studio-code-update-may-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code的更新 – 2024年5月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 09:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎来到 Visual Studio Code 的 Java 五月更新！在本篇博客中，我们将分享一个令人兴奋的与AI相关的新功能，专门Visual Studio Code上的Java开发者准备。另外，还会有几个重要的Spring的重要更新，让我们开始吧！ 基于Github Copilot优化并重构Java代码 当我们的代码更新迭代，我们的业务逻辑会不断变复杂。与此同时，Java的版本也在不同地升级。我们一些旧的代码通常可以用一些更好的新的代码去替代，不仅可以提升它们的效率，也可以使代码更美观和简洁。这些事情之前可能都需要我们人为去做，而随着AI的普及，慢慢很多任务都可以用AI相关工具去处理，而伴随Build大会2024的各种AI产品的发布，我们也想给广大在Visual Studio Code上的Java开发者带来一个好消息，我们已在Java插件中的Insider(Pre-release)版本中发布了一项重要的新功能: “Rewrite with new Java syntax“，允许开发者一键优化自己的Java代码！该功能与GitHub Copilot相互集成，因此开发者需要有GitHub Copilot的许可。 以下是该功能的工作流程：在您的Java类上，将会在类名上方出现一个新的CodeLens文本：“Rewrite with new Java syntax”。用户点击此文本后，将会触发对当前Java类的检查。检查完成后，Visual Studio Code将显示改进建议，并指示用户代码改进建议的位置。演示如下： 对于每个建议，会出现附加的CodeLens，显示具体改进建议的内容。用户可以直接点击CodeLens文本，这样将直接调出弹出GitHub Copilot的聊天对话框。用户可以直接查看潜在的代码修改建议，并会被提供“接受(Accept)”或“放弃(Discard)”的选择。如果用户接受建议，那么原有代码将被覆盖。让我们看看第一个示例，其中for循环可以用IntStream重构。 再来看另一个示例，我们的功能建议将多重的if和else-if逻辑直接重写为switch表达式。通过点击CodeLens文本，代码可以直接重写为改进后的代码。 检查部分代码 有时我们可能不想检查整个类，因为有些代码可能过于复杂。我们的功也支持检查部分代码。我们只需选择要检查的代码，然后点击左侧的灯泡，选择“Rewrite with new Java syntax”。这是一个示例： 通过这种方式，开发人员可以更灵活地检查代码。 此功能旨在利用AI为Java开发人员提供有用的建议和方便的重构。我们希望这可以大大提高开发人员的生产力。目前该功能主要聚焦在用更新的Java语法替换当前的代码，如果您对此功能有任何反馈，请在我们的GitHub repo上提交问题！ 要使用此功能，开发人员需要安装Insider（Pre-release）版本的Java插件包和GitHub Copilot插件。（需拥有GitHub Copilot许可证） Spring相关更新 JPQL 语法高亮 Spring Boot Tools插件现在为JPQL查询字符串提供语法高亮显示。语法高亮显示适用于Java源文件中的@Query注释以及命名查询属性文件。这使得阅读这些查询字符串更加容易。 以下是一个演示截图： 从pom.xml 直接添加Spring Boot Starter 我们在Spring Boot项目的pom.xml文件的依赖部分添加了一个可点击的提示。这个可点击的提示直接调用支持添加额外的Spring Boot starter模块。这提高了该功能的可发现性和可用性，使其非常容易找到和使用。 Spring Boot Dashboard 可以显示当前激活的Profile Spring Boot Dashboard现在在运行的Spring Boot应用程序的端口旁边直接显示活动的配置文件。这在预发布(Pre-release)版本中可用。 自动将application property转换为YAML及其反向转换 Spring Boot Tools现在提供操作，自动将application.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serializing Objects: Efficient Serialization and Deserialization of Collections with JsonSerializer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article demonstrates the ease of serializing and deserializing collections using JsonSerializer.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/03/serializing-objects-efficient-serialization-and-deserialization-of-collections-with-jsonserializer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedded Resources in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 06:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve covered resources in a couple of our previous articles. In Localization in ASP.NET Core, we delved into .NET localization, touching upon resources since XML files utilized for localization fall under .NET resources. We also discussed resources in our article, How to Read a String From a .resx (Resource) File in C#, where we explored […] The post Embedded Resources in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>加入 Microsoft Build 2024 的 .NET 团队！</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 03:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Mehul Harry的 Join the .NET Team at Microsoft Build 2024! 倒计时已经开始！ Microsoft Build 2024 即将到来，如果您是 .NET 爱好者，请准备好迎接一系列精彩的会议。 无论您是经验丰富的开发人员还是刚刚开始您的开发之旅，每个人都能找到适合自己的东西。 活动形式：混合体验 无论您是在西雅图还是在舒适的家中，都可以加入我们。 通过现场和在线会议的相结合，您不会错过任何精彩内容。 深入了解 .NET：不容错过的会议 请查看下面的会议，了解即将到来的活动。 如需了解更多详情并预订席位，请务必访问会议链接。 时间（太平洋夏令时间） 会议标题 格式 地点 链接 5 月 22 日下午 1:00 使用 .NET Aspire 揭秘云原生开发 分组讨论 西雅图 + 在线 查看会议 5 月 22 日下午 2:15 使用 Visual Studio 系列在任何操作系统上进行 .NET Aspire 开发 分组讨论 西雅图 + 在线 查看会议 5 月 23 日上午 8:30 C# 13 中的新增功能 分组讨论 西雅图 + 在线 查看会议 5 月 23 日上午 11:00 将 AI 融入您的 .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Print a 2D Array to the Console in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 05:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to print a 2D array to the console using C#. Whether we are handling complex data structures or simply organizing information efficiently, understanding how to manipulate 2D arrays is a valuable skill. Let’s begin. Understanding 2D Arrays First, let’s understand what 2D arrays are. A 2D or two-dimensional […] The post How to Print a 2D Array to the Console in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform IP Functions for Managing IP Addresses, CIDR Blocks, and Subnets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 03:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2024/02_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Terraform provides functions to manage and manipulate IP addresses and CIDR blocks. These functions are crucial for network automation and orchestration in cloud environments, enabling users to create, manage, and allocate network resources efficiently. This article shows how to use the Terraform IP functions, along with some practical examples to help you get the most […] The article Terraform IP Functions for Managing IP Addresses, CIDR Blocks, and Subnets was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter To Junior Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 46</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post A Letter To Junior Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 46 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss focus areas for junior developers to consider for becoming more effective. The post A Letter To Junior Developers – Dev Leader Weekly 46 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/06/01/a-letter-to-junior-developers-dev-leader-weekly-46/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With EasyCaching in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 05:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            EasyCaching is an open-source caching library that helps us manage caching more easily, and flexibly and it’s an alternative to ASP.NET Core’s out-of-the-box caching library. Caching is a prevalent and useful technique for improving the performance of web applications. By caching frequently accessed data, you can minimize the frequent use of SQL queries, API calls, […] The post Getting Started With EasyCaching in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Lookup Function – Usage and Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 03:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Terraform lookup() function provides a powerful feature that can be used to implement more flexible and easily configurable infrastructure configurations. The lookup() function is essential for retrieving values from maps dynamically. This article explains Terraform maps, in case you’re not familiar yet, and the explores the Terraform lookup() function with usage examples and a […] The article Terraform Lookup Function – Usage and Examples was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Slice Architecture: Structuring Vertical Slices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2024/01_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of organizing your project across layers? Vertical Slice Architecture is a compelling alternative to traditional layered architectures.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/vertical-slice-architecture-structuring-vertical-slices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (May 2024): Dedicated Pages for Each Package on vcpkg.io</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 19:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.05.24 release as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout May. This month’s update also includes individual pages for each package on the vcpkg website as well as several new documentation articles.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-may-2024-dedicated-pages-for-each-package-on-vcpkg-io 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluid Framework 2 generally available in June</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 16:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the exciting new features in Fluid Framework 2 including SharedTree DDS, SharePoint Embedded support, Fluid DevTools, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/fluid-framework-2-generally-available-in-june 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-training genomic language models using AWS HealthOmics and Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Genomic language models are a new and exciting field in the application of large language models to challenges in genomics. In this blog post and open source project, we show you how you can pre-train a genomics language model, HyenaDNA, using your genomic data in the AWS Cloud. Here, we use AWS HealthOmics storage as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pre-training-genomic-language-models-using-aws-healthomics-and-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falcon 2 11B is now available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 15:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the first model in the next generation Falcon 2 family, the Falcon 2 11B foundation model (FM) from Technology Innovation Institute (TII), is available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. Falcon 2 11B is a trained dense decoder model on a 5.5 trillion token dataset […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/falcon-2-11b-is-now-available-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock in support of GDPR (right to be forgotten) requests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 15:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) right to be forgotten, also known as the right to erasure, gives individuals the right to request the deletion of their personally identifiable information (PII) data held by organizations. This means that individuals can ask companies to erase their personal data from their systems and from the systems of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implementing-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-in-support-of-gdpr-right-to-be-forgotten-requests/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A graphical depiction of the steps in building a C&#43;&#43; executable, with XAML and packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleshing out the diagram.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240531-00/?p=109825 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set the Exit Code for a Console Application in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 05:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to set the exit code for a console application in .NET. Let’s dive in. What Are Exit Codes Exit codes are integer values we return after executing a process. A zero exit code usually indicates success, while a non-zero code indicates an error. For a complete list of […] The post How to Set the Exit Code for a Console Application in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell: Automate Terraform Install on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 03:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While HashiCorp Terraform is a single executable, it’s really useful to install it on the local machine so the terraform.exe executable can be run from anywhere. To do this, Terraform needs to be downloaded, placed somewhere on the local machine, and then that path must be added to the system PATH environment variable. I’ve done […] The article PowerShell: Automate Terraform Install on Windows was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bulkhead Pattern: How To Make Your System Fault-tolerant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 20:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Keep one small part of your system from taking down the entire system. Let’s look at the bulkhead pattern, the various ways you think about it, and how it applies to your architecture, which will help you with fault tolerance to keep your system running. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of… Read More »The Bulkhead Pattern: How To Make Your System Fault-tolerant The post The Bulkhead Pattern: How To Make Your System Fault-tolerant appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBRE and AWS perform natural language queries of structured data using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 19:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with CBRE. CBRE is the world’s largest commercial real estate services and investment firm, with 130,000 professionals serving clients in more than 100 countries. Services range from financing and investment to property management. CBRE is unlocking the potential of artificial intelligence (AI) to realize value across the entire commercial […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cbre-and-aws-perform-natural-language-queries-of-structured-data-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Refactoring tools in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 19:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code refactoring is the process of restructuring existing code, while its outward functionality remains unchanged. By refactoring, you can simplify complex code structures, reduce code redundancy, and enhance code reusability. Visual Studio offers many tools to help refactor your C++ code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-refactoring-tools-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic video content moderation and policy evaluation using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations across media and entertainment, advertising, social media, education, and other sectors require efficient solutions to extract information from videos and apply flexible evaluations based on their policies. Generative artificial intelligence (AI) has unlocked fresh opportunities for these use cases. In this post, we introduce the Media Analysis and Policy Evaluation solution, which uses AWS […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dynamic-video-content-moderation-and-policy-evaluation-using-aws-generative-ai-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitech uses Amazon Bedrock to revolutionize information access with AI-powered chatbot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Murthy Palla and Madesh Subbanna from Vitech. Vitech is a global provider of cloud-centered benefit and investment administration software. Vitech helps group insurance, pension fund administration, and investment clients expand their offerings and capabilities, streamline their operations, and gain analytical insights. To serve their customers, Vitech maintains a repository of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/vitech-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-revolutionize-information-access-with-ai-powered-chatbot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Microsoft Build: Docker’s Innovations with AI and Windows on Arm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 17:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows is back! Docker CTO Justin Cormack talks about this and other takeaways from Microsoft Build 2024, including recently announced (and long-awaited) Docker Desktop support for Windows on Arm.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/highlights-from-microsoft-build/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch Up on Microsoft Build 2024: Essential Sessions for .NET Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get up to date on all of the .NET sessions from Microsoft Build 2024 covering .NET 9, .NET Aspire, .NET MAUI, ASP.NET Core, EF Core, and so much more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/catching-up-on-microsoft-build-2024-essential-sessions-for-dotnet-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in the Windows Subsystem for Linux in May 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 16:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For this year’s Microsoft BUILD conference, we are thrilled to announce significant updates to WSL. This blog post will provide an overview of these enhancements and the recent developments in WSL. Memory, storage and networking improvements WSL Settings GUI application coming soon WSL Zero Trust Manage WSL in Dev Home,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/whats-new-in-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux-in-may-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Loop transforms the way developer teams work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 15:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Microsoft Loop provides a central and flexible place for your work to help you stay in sync and on track.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-loop-transforms-the-way-developer-teams-work 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A graphical depiction of the steps in building a C&#43;&#43; executable, enhanced for classic Win32</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adding in Microsoft-specific tools.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240530-00/?p=109823 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VBScript deprecation: Timelines and next steps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 11:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scripting options for web development and task automation are modernizing. To provide you with the most modern and efficient options, we are replacing VBScript with more advanced alternatives such as JavaScript and PowerShell. Find out what VBScript deprecation means for you and how you can get ready.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/vbscript-deprecation-timelines-and-next-steps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Comparing Key Search Methods in Dictionaries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article compares two key search methods in dictionaries: using Contains() on the Keys collection and ContainsKey() method directly on the dictionary. It demonstrates examples for both approaches, highlighting Microsoft&#39;s recommendation of using ContainsKey(). The article suggests further examination of the performance aspect of these methods.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/30/code-it-any-way-you-want-comparing-key-search-methods-in-dictionaries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.18 with reporters, better CI support, and improved Azure API Center integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to share the launch of Dev Proxy v0.18 to help you to build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-18-with-reporters-better-ci-support-and-improved-azure-api-center-integration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lookup in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 05:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we build our .NET applications, we commonly use dictionaries to store data as key-value pairs. However, dictionaries do not allow us to map multiple values to a single key. In this article, let’s explore the Lookup class in C# and discuss how we can use it to handle this challenge. Without further ado, let’s […] The post Lookup in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.com/csharp-lookup/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
