<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 19:12:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Weather Company enhances MLOps with Amazon SageMaker, AWS CloudFormation, and Amazon CloudWatch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 19:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share the story of how The Weather Company (TWCo) enhanced its MLOps platform using services such as Amazon SageMaker, AWS CloudFormation, and Amazon CloudWatch. TWCo data scientists and ML engineers took advantage of automation, detailed experiment tracking, integrated training, and deployment pipelines to help scale MLOps effectively. TWCo reduced infrastructure management time by 90% while also reducing model deployment time by 20%.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-weather-company-enhances-mlops-with-amazon-sagemaker-aws-cloudformation-and-amazon-cloudwatch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eviden scales AWS DeepRacer Global League using AWS DeepRacer Event Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 18:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Eviden is a next-gen technology leader in data-driven, trusted, and sustainable digital transformation. With a strong portfolio of patented technologies and worldwide leading positions in advanced computing, security, AI, cloud, and digital platforms, Eviden provides deep expertise for a multitude of industries in more than 47 countries. Eviden is an AWS Premier partner, bringing together […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/eviden-scales-aws-deepracer-global-league-using-aws-deepracer-event-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate unique images by fine-tuning Stable Diffusion XL with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 18:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stable Diffusion XL by Stability AI is a high-quality text-to-image deep learning model that allows you to generate professional-looking images in various styles. Managed versions of Stable Diffusion XL are already available to you on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart (see Use Stable Diffusion XL with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart in Amazon SageMaker Studio) and Amazon Bedrock (see […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-unique-images-by-fine-tuning-stable-diffusion-xl-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Round Trips are Evil</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 18:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Houston gets drenched by Hurricane Beryl as I write this, I’m reminded of a formative set of continuing education courses I took when I was living in Houston in the late 90’s and plotting my formal move into software development. Whatever we learned about VB6 in those MSDN classes is long, long since obsolete, … Continue reading Network Round Trips are Evil →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/07/08/network-round-trips-are-evil/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wayland Support Preview In 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 15:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are delighted to announce that, starting with the 2024.2 Early Access Program (EAP), IntelliJ-based IDEs will offer preliminary support for the Wayland display server protocol on Linux, including Windows Subsystem for Linux a.k.a. WSLg. How To Opt In On Linux, IntelliJ-based IDEs were using exclusively the X11 protocol and an X server to show […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/wayland-support-preview-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New UI Becomes the Default in 2024.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 14:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that we will enable the new UI for all JetBrains IDE users in the upcoming 2024.2 version. We designed the new UI to reduce visual clutter, ensuring easy access to essential features while gradually revealing more advanced functionality as needed. The new UI is clean and modern, providing bigger, easier-to-use […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/07/08/the-new-ui-becomes-the-default-in-2024-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the point of std::monostate? You can’t do anything with it!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not doing anything with it is exactly the point.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240708-00/?p=109959 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2024: A look at the latest Microsoft Entra key feature releases, announcements, and updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 13:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An overview of the latest updates in Microsoft Entra for Jul 2024. Discover how these new capabilities can be integrated into your projects for optimal performance and security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/eng-connect-jul-24 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 EAP 5: Zephyr West Support and Full Line Code Completion for C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 13:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.2 EAP 5 build (242.19890.26) is now out! It’s available from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 EAP Zephyr West support In this EAP build, we introduce a new project model supported by CLion – it’s called the West project model. As we previously mentioned […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/07/2024-2-eap-5-zephyr-west-support-full-line-code-completion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy to Elastic Beanstalk with GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 11:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Elastic Beanstalk makes deploying, managing, and scaling .NET web applications on Amazon Web Services easy. This powerful service is available to anyone developing or hosting .NET apps on IIS. In this post, I’ll demonstrate how to set up a continuous deployment pipeline to Elastic Beanstalk directly from GitHub using GitHub Actions. With just a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/deploy-to-elastic-beanstalk-environment-with-github-actions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystify history with GitHub Copilot commit explanations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 07:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever struggled to understand what a commit was doing or why it was made? Do you wish you had more clarity and context when reviewing or collaborating on code changes? If you answered yes, then you’ll love what GitHub Copilot can do for you: generate commit explanations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/demystify-history-with-github-copilot-commit-explanations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find All the Positions of a Substring in Another String in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 05:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to learn how to find all the positions of a substring in another string. So we are trying to find, for example, all the occurrences of the word ‘the’ in a sentence: “Some consider the occurrences to be the unconscious mind’s attempts to communicate to the conscious mind.” Searching Substrings to Find All the Positions […] The post How to Find All the Positions of a Substring in Another String in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Strong Foundations: The Crucial Role of Data in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2024/07_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2024/07_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Creating beloved software demands collective effort from various teams. Data plays a pivotal role, analogous to a building&#39;s foundation. Neglecting the data infrastructure can lead to persistent issues and eventual failure. Companies should prioritize specialized data professionals and seamless collaboration to ensure software longevity. Siloed teams hamper progress, prompting engineers and customers to flee.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/07/07/building-strong-foundations-the-crucial-role-of-data-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding long-running HTTP API requests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 15:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How do you handle long-running HTTP requests that take long to complete? For example, how would you design an HTTP API that needs to generate a transcript for a specific video (by ID)? Deeper into that question, you can assume that won’t be a fast request/response, so how can we better manage this? Using asynchronous… Read More »Avoiding long-running HTTP API requests The post Avoiding long-running HTTP API requests appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build vs Buy: The Age-old Dev Debate – Dev Leader Weekly 51</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Build vs Buy: The Age-old Dev Debate – Dev Leader Weekly 51 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss different scenarios where I built my own vs when companies decide to build vs buy. The post Build vs Buy: The Age-old Dev Debate – Dev Leader Weekly 51 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/07/06/build-vs-buy-the-age-old-dev-debate-dev-leader-weekly-51/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Discovery in Microservices With .NET and Consul</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_07_2024/06_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Service discovery is a pattern that allows developers to use logical names to refer to external services, instead of physical IP addresses and ports. In this week&#39;s issue, we&#39;ll see how to implement service discovery in your .NET microservices with Consul.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/service-discovery-in-microservices-with-net-and-consul 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the June edition of PHP Annotated! We’ll recap the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, featuring handpicked news, articles, tools, and videos. Highlights PHP 8.1.29, PHP 8.2.20, and PHP 8.3.8 released ❗️These security updates fix CVE-2024-4577, CVE-2024-5458, CVE-2024-5585, and vulnerability in openssl_private_decrypt() function known as the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/07/php-annotated-june-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Turbo in your Rails apps with RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 14:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! The RubyMine team is constantly striving to provide support for new technologies for Ruby and Rails. One of the most exciting recent additions to Rails is undoubtedly Hotwire, so we’ve prepared an overview of this suite of frameworks and a tutorial on how to use the most important Turbo and Stimulus features in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/07/how-to-use-turbo-in-your-rails-apps-with-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I produce a Windows Runtime asynchronous activity from C&#43;&#43;/WinRT?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Somebody that deals with them natively.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240705-00/?p=109957 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Data Science Platform Downtime – neXDos Says It’s Real With Datalore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JupyterHub Hosting Hurdles neXDos heavily relies on diverse data sources – from stock market APIs to in-house PostgreSQL data – to inform their bespoke investment strategies. Previously, neXDos prototyped, backtested, and future-proofed their trading algorithms by hosting JupyterLab and JupyterHub. But this approach was problematic due to complexity in many areas, including managing the server […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/05/zero-data-science-platform-downtime-nexdos-says-it-s-real-with-datalore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Per-Minute macOS Sonoma M2 Agents in TeamCity Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 08:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently introduced per-minute macOS agents in TeamCity Cloud. Now, we’re switching the macOS agents to macOS Sonoma M2, offering you more power efficiency and greater performance when running your builds on TeamCity. We’re offering a 50% discount on the new per-minute macOS build agents in TeamCity Cloud until January 1, 2025. Enjoy the power […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/07/macos-sonoma-agents-teamcity-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Fear to Triumph: My 30-Year Journey in Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This content chronicles my 30-year journey in public speaking, from an unexpected start to embracing challenges and speaking at major conferences. Overcoming fears, I found career success and enriched personal connections. I encourage aspiring speakers to refine their craft and seize opportunities for growth and impact in both professional and personal spheres.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/07/05/from-fear-to-triumph-my-30-year-journey-in-public-speaking/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot Studio – Prompt Response Times</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tahir Naveed walks through how to measure prompt response times with Microsoft Copilot Studio and explores considerations that factor into the overall performance of these requests. Building custom copilots (GenAI chatbots) in Microsoft Copilot Studio is amazing. Especially with the new functionalities which were released in Microsoft Build 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/copilot-studio-prompt-response-times 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – July 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the July edition of Java Annotated Monthly! We’re excited to feature insights from the ever-brilliant Trisha Gee, who’s been busy curating some top-class content over the past month. This edition is packed with Java news and tips, including a spotlight on the upcoming Java 23. You’ll also find articles on Kotlin, Spring, AI, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/java-annotated-monthly-july-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure IoT Operations Data Processor Pipelines: Unlocking Efficiency in the Industrial Metaverse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we explore the implementation of Azure IoT Operations Data Processor pipelines in a manufacturing context, focusing on data processing at the edge.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/aio-data-processor-pipelines-unlocking-efficiency-industrial-metaverse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | July 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 06:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_07_2024/05_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The BinaryFormatter class was traditionally used in .NET for serializing and deserializing objects into a binary format. However, it has been deprecated in 2020 due to serious security vulnerabilities that can allow for remote code execution when deserializing untrusted data. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/05/dotinsights-july-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I produce a Windows Runtime asynchronous activity from C#?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AsyncInfo helper class converts Tasks to Windows Runtime asynchronous activities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240704-00/?p=109955 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polars vs. pandas: What’s the Difference?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 13:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve been keeping up with the advances in Python dataframes in the past year, you couldn’t help hearing about Polars, the powerful dataframe library designed for working with large datasets. Unlike other libraries for working with large datasets, such as Spark, Dask, and Ray, Polars is designed to be used on a single machine, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/07/polars-vs-pandas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science with GenAI is Revolutionizing Investment Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 09:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is the formula for success in the investment management industry? Behind every successful firm is a unique combination of domain expertise, cutting-edge technology, relationship management, rapid adaptability, and competition. While data science driven by generative AI (genAI) cannot turn your employees into domain experts overnight, nor can it single-handedly eliminate the competition, it can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2024/07/04/data-science-with-genai-is-revolutionizing-investment-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read appsettings.json in a .NET Console Application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 06:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to read appsettings.json in a .NET console application. Explanation Of appsettings.json The appsettings.json file in .NET applications serves as a centralized repository for configuration settings, utilizing the JSON format for its simplicity and readability. It includes various hierarchically organized sections, such as logging levels, connection strings, and custom application […] The post How to Read appsettings.json in a .NET Console Application appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: preezie’s AI Journey with Microsoft Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_07_2024/04_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re thrilled to feature the preezie team on the Semantic Kernel blog. The preezie team will discuss their AI journey, how they’ve integrated the Semantic Kernel SDK to build out their AI solutions and advice they’d give to other customers getting started on their AI journeys.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-prezzies-ai-journey-with-microsoft-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build your multilingual personal calendar assistant with Amazon Bedrock and AWS Step Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to apply AWS services such as Amazon Bedrock, AWS Step Functions, and Amazon Simple Email Service (Amazon SES) to build a fully-automated multilingual calendar artificial intelligence (AI) assistant. It understands the incoming messages, translates them to the preferred language, and automatically sets up calendar reminders.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-your-multilingual-personal-calendar-assistant-with-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-step-functions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical content creation in the age of generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI and transformer-based large language models (LLMs) have been in the top headlines recently. These models demonstrate impressive performance in question answering, text summarization, code, and text generation. Today, LLMs are being used in real settings by companies, including the heavily-regulated healthcare and life sciences industry (HCLS). The use cases can range from medical […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/medical-content-creation-in-the-age-of-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing guardrails in Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed capability that helps you securely connect foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock to your company data using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). This feature streamlines the entire RAG workflow, from ingestion to retrieval and prompt augmentation, eliminating the need for custom data source integrations and data flow […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-guardrails-in-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt engineering techniques and best practices: Learn by doing with Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You have likely already had the opportunity to interact with generative artificial intelligence (AI) tools (such as virtual assistants and chatbot applications) and noticed that you don’t always get the answer you are looking for, and that achieving it may not be straightforward. Large language models (LLMs), the models behind the generative AI revolution, receive […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/prompt-engineering-techniques-and-best-practices-learn-by-doing-with-anthropics-claude-3-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Instant GraphQL APIs with Hasura Data Connector for Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to partner with Hasura to launch a new Hasura native data connector that generates instant GraphQL APIs on Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL. Hasura DDN makes data access easy by enabling backend teams to effortlessly deliver a unified API on all your data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-instant-graphql-apis-with-hasuras-data-connector-for-azure-cosmos-db-nosql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of Office 365 connectors within Microsoft Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting August 15, 2024 we will be retiring the Office 365 connectors feature from Microsoft Teams and recommend Power Automate workflows as the solution to relay information into and out of Teams in a scalable, flexible, and secure way.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/retirement-of-office-365-connectors-within-microsoft-teams 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 8: Faster Time to Code, Language-Aware Sticky Lines, and Tags in The Version Control Widget</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 14:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 8 is now live! You can download the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 8 The Early Access Program for v2024.2 is nearing its end, but there’s still time to participate and preview the latest improvements for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-8/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Online Migration Capability for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB  in Azure Data Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce a significant enhancement to the Azure Cosmos DB Migration for MongoDB extension! Now, you can seamlessly migrate your MongoDB workloads to vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB with the added convenience of online migration capability. Let’s dive into the details.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-online-migration-capability-for-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-in-azure-data-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I produce a Windows Runtime asynchronous activity from C&#43;&#43;/CX?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Parallel Patterns Library has special support for C++/CX.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240703-00/?p=109953 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.37 Is Out! Introducing AI Code Completion for Java, Folding Imports by Default, Soft Wraps for Markdown and Asciidoc, and Other Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.37 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this latest version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at this update’s highlights. Download Fleet 1.37 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/07/fleet-1-37-is-out-introducing-ai-code-completion-java-folding-imports-by-default-soft-wraps-markdown-asciidoc-other-enhancements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Coding Workshop on Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Struggling to get started with Python? Join us on our Discord server for a free beginner-friendly online workshop, tailored to those with no or basic programming experience. In this live interactive session, you’ll see Python in action. We’ll cover essential concepts from our most popular course, Introduction to Python, and provide hands-on experience using integrated […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/03/online-coding-workshop-on-python/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Self-Hosted Is Out – Get 40% OFF This Static Code Analysis Team Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 09:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most developers use IDEs and code editors for local code quality analysis, but only 33% of developers use external static code analysis tools for every CI pipeline commit. Another 33% occasionally use automated analysis technology. As reported by our customers, the low adoption of static code analysis tools among developers poses a problem for companies, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/07/qodana-self-hosted-is-out-get-40-off-this-static-code-analysis-team-tool/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve productivity when processing scanned PDFs using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a generative AI-powered assistant that can answer questions, provide summaries, generate content, and extract insights directly from the content in digital as well as scanned PDF documents in your enterprise data sources without needing to extract the text first. Customers across industries such as finance, insurance, healthcare life sciences, and more need […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-productivity-when-processing-scanned-pdfs-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.21.12-1 and 1.22.5-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 23:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft builds of the Go security patches released today, are now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-21-12-1-and-1-22-5-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Amazon Bedrock in your .NET applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 20:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recent developments in generative Artificial Intelligence (generative AI) have made it easier and affordable to create applications and experiences that improve the way we live and work. Generative AI is helping businesses improve customer experiences through assistants and conversational analytics and boost employee productivity through automated generation of content, reports, and code. In this blog […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/getting-started-with-amazon-bedrock-in-net-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated PyTorch inference with torch.compile on AWS Graviton processors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 17:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Originally PyTorch used an eager mode where each PyTorch operation that forms the model is run independently as soon as it’s reached. PyTorch 2.0 introduced torch.compile to speed up PyTorch code over the default eager mode. In contrast to eager mode, the torch.compile pre-compiles the entire model into a single graph in a manner that’s optimal for […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerated-pytorch-inference-with-torch-compile-on-aws-graviton-processors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a CI/CD Pipeline for Android Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 17:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest article by Kumar Harsh, draft.dev. If you ship Android app releases frequently, you probably already understand the value of well-defined build, test, and deployment workflows. Without resilient, automated DevOps workflows in place, it can be difficult to maintain a high release velocity. Automating these through continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/07/cicd-for-android/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access control for vector stores using metadata filtering with Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 17:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In November 2023, we announced Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock as generally available. Knowledge bases allow Amazon Bedrock users to unlock the full potential of Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) by seamlessly integrating their company data into the language model’s generation process. This feature allows organizations to harness the power of large language models (LLMs) while […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/access-control-for-vector-stores-using-metadata-filtering-with-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accenture creates a custom memory-persistent conversational user experience using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Traditionally, finding relevant information from documents has been a time-consuming and often frustrating process. Manually sifting through pages upon pages of text, searching for specific details, and synthesizing the information into coherent summaries can be a daunting task. This inefficiency not only hinders productivity but also increases the risk of overlooking critical insights buried within […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accenture-creates-a-custom-memory-persistent-conversational-user-experience-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an end-to-end serverless digital assistant for semantic search with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the rise of generative artificial intelligence (AI), an increasing number of organizations use digital assistants to have their end-users ask domain-specific questions, using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) over their enterprise data sources. As organizations transition from proofs of concept to production workloads, they establish objectives to run and scale their workloads with minimal operational […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-an-end-to-end-serverless-digital-assistant-for-semantic-search-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbox App 2.4 Gets a Refreshed UI Theme, Right-Click Context Menu, and Other Updates.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Toolbox App 2.4 comes with a reworked UI theme, a new way to open the context menu for tools, and other updates. If you’re using Gitee, check out the JetBrains Toolbox browser extension update as well. New UI theme Toolbox App 2.4 got a facelift! The navigation remains the same, but we’ve reworked the interface […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/toolbox-app/2024/07/toolbox-app-2-4-gets-a-refreshed-ui-theme-right-click-context-menu-and-other-updates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dive into native Windows development with new WinUI workload and template improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At //Build 2024, the WinUI team announced a renewed focus on WinUI as one of the premier app development frameworks we recommend for native Windows app development. To make it as seamless and easy as possible to get into coding, we created a new Windows Dev Center page,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/dive-into-native-windows-development-with-new-winui-workload-and-template-improvements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now use role-based access control in Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer is a web-based tool that allows you to interact with your data, run queries, and visualize results in Azure Cosmos DB. It is available in the Azure Portal and as a standalone web app. RBAC allows you to use Microsoft Entra ID identities to control data access in Data Explorer,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-use-role-based-access-control-in-azure-cosmos-db-data-explorer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The history of Alt&#43;number sequences, and why Alt&#43;9731 sometimes gives you a heart and sometimes a snowman</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code pages and custom keyboard handling.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240702-00/?p=109951 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast and compliant routing in Azure Fluid Relay</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 13:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how about the optimal placement of the geographically distributed Azure Fluid Relay (AFR) servers and how we route the traffic to these servers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/fast-and-compliant-routing-in-azure-fluid-relay 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use the Tasks View in JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 13:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Task Parallel Library (TPL) is foundational to all .NET applications, as it allows frameworks to write and execute multithreaded and parallel code. Additionally, developers looking to get the most out of their resources may want to write custom code, taking advantage of the types found in System.Threading and System.Threading.Tasks. You must understand concurrency and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/02/how-to-use-the-tasks-view-in-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 EAP 4: Improvements for Remote Toolchain, a Fix for Settings Persistence in Nova, and Enhanced GDB Pretty Printers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 09:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.2 EAP 4 build (242.19533.43) is now out! It’s available from our website, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 EAP Highlights: Your CLion teamJetBrainsThe Drive to Develop
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/07/2024-2-eap-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the generated code: the spread element: Behind the scenes of collection expressions - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show what the compiler generates when you use collection expressions with the spread element and how it depends on the collections used
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/behind-the-scenes-of-collection-expressions-part-4-the-spread-element/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned after migrating Azure Functions to Isolated Functions on .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 08:25:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The In-process model of running Azure Functions is being retired in favor of the Isolated model in two years. A lot of components on elmah.io are running on Azure Functions. To ensure we are running on the most modern and supported platform (also in two years), we have spent asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/lessons-learned-after-migrating-azure-functions-to-isolated-functions-on-net-8/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 05:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to talk about a structural design pattern, the Bridge Pattern. We will discuss what problem this pattern solves and how to implement it in C#. If you want to read more about design patterns in C#, you can inspect our C# Design Patterns page. Let’s start. What is The Bridge Design […] The post Bridge Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davide&#39;s Code and Architecture Notes - Arc42 Documentation, for a comprehensive description of your project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How is your project structured? What are the driving forces? If you don’t know how to express this info, you should try the Arc42 template to create a strong foundation for your documentation.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/arc42-documentation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a self-service digital assistant using Amazon Lex and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations strive to implement efficient, scalable, cost-effective, and automated customer support solutions without compromising the customer experience. Generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered chatbots play a crucial role in delivering human-like interactions by providing responses from a knowledge base without the involvement of live agents. These chatbots can be efficiently utilized for handling generic inquiries, freeing up […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-self-service-digital-assistant-using-amazon-lex-and-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify idle endpoints in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker is a machine learning (ML) platform designed to simplify the process of building, training, deploying, and managing ML models at scale. With a comprehensive suite of tools and services, SageMaker offers developers and data scientists the resources they need to accelerate the development and deployment of ML solutions. In today’s fast-paced technological landscape, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/identify-idle-endpoints-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian language RAG with Cohere multilingual embeddings and Anthropic Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Media and entertainment companies serve multilingual audiences with a wide range of content catering to diverse audience segments. These enterprises have access to massive amounts of data collected over their many years of operations. Much of this data is unstructured text and images. Conventional approaches to analyzing unstructured data for generating new content rely on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/indian-language-rag-with-cohere-multilingual-embeddings-and-anthropic-claude-3-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2024.2 EAP 5: An Important Milestone and Other Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest installment in the Early Access Program for ReSharper 2024.2 has just been released! This preview build marks an important milestone – it is the first one to feature asynchronous typing, an important design change for ReSharper on its way to out-of-process operation. In addition to that, the update also brings several updates across […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/01/resharper-2024-2-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 EAP 5: Reader Mode, Monitoring for Game Dev, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2024.2 EAP 5 has just landed! This build brings a variety of new features and improvements to enhance your development experience. As always, your feedback is invaluable in helping us refine these updates, so we encourage you to try out the new build and share your thoughts. UX/UI Reader mode Reader mode is now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/07/01/rider-2024-2-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone! We’re back with an update on the state of the RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program. In preparation for the release, we’ve been working on improving AI Assistant, as well as providing support for Rails 8 features, Stimulus, and more.You can download the latest EAP build from our website, via the free Toolbox App, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/07/rubymine-2024-2-early-access-program-update/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Guided Projects in JetBrains Academy Plugin 2024.6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that Framework lessons have been renamed as Guided Projects. In this release, we’ve streamlined the process for educators to edit and synchronize changes within Guided Projects, addressing common issues faced when updating course content. To explore the latest improvements, install the JetBrains Academy plugin or update to the latest version from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/01/jetbrains-academy-plugin-2023-4-is-available-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2024.2 EAP Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we’ll explore the most significant features available in the latest EAP. You can try them by downloading and installing the EAP build side by side with a stable version of PhpStorm. Don’t forget to share your experience with us in the comments section below. Support for log files The PhpStorm 2024.2 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/07/phpstorm-2024-2-eap-highlights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If I register the same shell extension as both a context menu extension and a drag/drop extension, how do I know which one the system is using?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Who forced you to register the same shell extension for both?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240701-00/?p=109947 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Generative AI to Create Runnable Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the innovative realm of AI developer tools with Docker&#39;s GenAI Docker Labs series. Join us as we dive deep into the potential of AI. Discover how generative AI can assist with documentation, project-specific tasks, and more throughout the software lifecycle. Stay updated and get involved with Docker&#39;s latest projects and tools.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/using-generative-ai-to-create-runnable-markdown/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to output a SARIF file from a .NET project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SARIF (Static Analysis Results Interchange Format) is an OASIS Standard that defines an output file format. The SARIF standard is used to streamline how static analysis tools share their results. SARIF is a JSON-based format that is easy to parse. Lots of tools support it, including Visual studio Code or Visual Studio. GitHub also supports this file format to report static analysis results. You can upload…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/how-to-output-a-sarif-file-from-a-dotnet-project.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP 7: Improved Code Completion in AI Assistant, String Variable Data Visualizers in the Debugger, And More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 10:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP build brings some exciting new features and improvements. AI Assistant’s code completion, both single- and multi-line, has been upgraded for more accurate suggestions and a streamlined user experience. The IDE now offers convenient debugging visualizers to help you better comprehend data stored in JSON, HTML, XML, and other data […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating hashes in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 08:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article looks at different ways to create hashes in .NET Core. Hashes are useful for one way encryption which can be used for password storage, JWT validation and some other security use cases. When storing hashes in a database, extra care must be taken and the recommended approach from Microsoft should be used when […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/07/01/creating-hashes-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let GitHub Copilot draft of your pull request description</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 07:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing good pull request descriptions is essential for effective code reviews and collaboration. But it’s time-consuming and tedious, especially when you have multiple commits or complex changes. That’s why we’re highlighting a feature that will make your life better with the help of GitHub Copilot: generated pull request descriptions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/let-github-copilot-draft-of-your-pull-request-description 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Functions vs Lambda Expressions in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 05:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll discuss the differences between local functions and lambda expressions in C#. Let’s start. Lambda Expressions Lambda expressions are anonymous functions. They are short blocks of code that accept parameters and return a value. We can assign the lambda expression to a variable or pass it as a parameter. We define lambda […] The post Local Functions vs Lambda Expressions in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
