<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:03:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automating Secure and Scalable AI Deployments on Azure with HashiCorp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While the promise of AI continues to generate momentum, many organizations face a familiar challenge: getting AI projects beyond the prototype phase. According to Gartner, only 30% of AI initiatives make it into production, and RAND reports that up to 80% fail to deliver expected outcomes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/automating-secure-and-scalable-ai-deployments-on-azure-with-hashicorp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Practices for Building, Testing, and Packaging MCP Servers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently launched a new, reimagined Docker MCP Catalog with improved discovery and a new submission process. Containerized MCP servers offer a secure way to run and scale agentic applications and minimize risks tied to host access and secret management. Developers can submit servers in two ways: Docker-built servers, which include our full security suite...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-server-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.43: Expanded Model Runner, Reimagined MCP Catalog, MCP Server Submissions, and Smarter Gordon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.43 just rolled out a set of powerful updates that simplify how developers run, manage, and secure AI models and MCP tools. Model Runner now includes better model management, expanded OpenAI API compatibility, and fine-grained controls over runtime behavior. The improved MCP Catalog makes it easier to discover and use MCP servers, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-43/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming network operations with AI: How Swisscom built a network assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Swisscom developed their Network Assistant. We discuss the initial challenges and how they implemented a solution that delivers measurable benefits. We examine the technical architecture, discuss key learnings, and look at future enhancements that can further transform network operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transforming-network-operations-with-ai-how-swisscom-built-a-network-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End model training and deployment with Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we guide you through the stages of customizing large language models (LLMs) with SageMaker Unified Studio and SageMaker AI, covering the end-to-end process starting from data discovery to fine-tuning FMs with SageMaker AI distributed training, tracking metrics using MLflow, and then deploying models using SageMaker AI inference for real-time inference. We also discuss best practices to choose the right instance size and share some debugging best practices while working with JupyterLab notebooks in SageMaker Unified Studio.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>German language cheat sheet: On changing quantities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Somehow, I must have missed out on learning phrases of changes in quantity in German, so I need a cheat sheet. Trend
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250703-01/?p=111337 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If the &lt;code&gt;Format­Message&lt;/code&gt; function fails, and I requested that it allocate a buffer, do I have to free the buffer?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer called the Format­Message function with the FORMAT_MESSAGE_ALLOCATE_BUFFER flag, and they weren&#39;t sure what to do if the function fails (by returning 0). Do they have to free the buffer by calling Local­Free? No, you don&#39;t have to free the buffer. In fact, on f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250703-00/?p=111335 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: A Carefully Curated June Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 13:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s time for another edition of Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup! If June flew by while you were deep in development, don’t worry – I’ve gathered all the ecosystem highlights for you in one handy digest. Here’s what you might have missed. Kotlin YouTube highlights That’s all for June! While you’re rewatching conference talks or experimenting with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/kodees-kotlin-roundup-june-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Why Kakao Pay Chose Kotlin for Backend Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 05:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is a JetBrains translation of the original post by katfun.joy, a backend developer at Kakao Pay. Kakao Pay leverages Kotlin with Spring for backend development across various services, including its insurance offerings. Check out Kakao Pay’s story to see how Kotlin helps it address the complex requirements of the insurance industry and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/case-study-why-kakao-pay-chose-kotlin-for-backend-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize RAG in production environments using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart and Amazon OpenSearch Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 20:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to use Amazon OpenSearch Service as a vector store to build an efficient RAG application.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimize-rag-in-production-environments-using-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-and-amazon-opensearch-service/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local AI &#43; .NET = AltText Magic in One C# Script</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Need to generate image descriptions fast? In this post, we’ll show how to combine .NET 10’s new capabilities with local AI models to create smart AltText — all in one simple C# file. It’s a fun way to explore what AI can do beyond chat. AltText Generation with Local AI Models and dotnet run app.cs ✨ I
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/alttext-generator-csharp-local-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing AI agent governance with Boomi and AWS: A unified approach to observability and compliance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Boomi partnered with AWS to help enterprises accelerate and scale AI adoption with confidence using Agent Control Tower.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advancing-ai-agent-governance-with-boomi-and-aws-a-unified-approach-to-observability-and-compliance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Gordon to Containerize Your Apps and Work with Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 18:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These days, almost every tech company is looking for ways to integrate AI into their apps and workflows, and Docker is no exception. They&#39;ve been rolling out some impressive AI capabilities across their products. This is my first post as a Docker Captain and in this post, I want to shine a spotlight on a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/containerize-your-apps-with-ask-gordon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Awesome GitHub Copilot Customizations repo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 17:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we&#39;re excited to announce the launch of the Awesome GitHub Copilot Customizations repo! The Awesome Copilot repo is a community-driven resource with custom instructions, reusable prompts, and custom chat modes that helps you get consisten
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//introducing-awesome-github-copilot-customizations-repo 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (June 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoMapper and MediatR Commercial Editions Launch Today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today I&#39;m excited to announce the official launch and release of the commercial editions of AutoMapper and MediatR. Both of these libraries have moved under their new corporate owner (me), Lucky Penny Software. I formed this company to house these projects separate from my consulting company, but it&amp;amp;
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/automapper-and-mediatr-commercial-editions-launch-today/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unintended yet somehow entirely expected consequences of marking a COM interface as local</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was adding an interface to their out-of-process COM server. They added their interface to the project&#39;s existing IDL file and recompiled the resulting proxy stub DLL. But when they tried to connect to the server, the connection failed with error 0x80040155, also known as REGDB_E_IID­NOT­REG
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250702-00/?p=111332 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker State of App Dev: Dev Ex &amp; Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Report: What’s helping devs thrive — and what’s still holding them back? A look at how culture, tooling, and habits are shaping the developer experience today, per Docker’s 2025 State of Application Development Survey. Great culture, better tools — but developers often still feel stuck. From pull requests stuck in review to tasks without clear...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-state-of-app-dev-dev-ex-productivity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Chronicles: The Office That Time Forgot – Why Microsoft Must Rethink User Experience Now</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/02/ux-chronicles-the-office-that-time-forgot-why-microsoft-must-rethink-user-experience-now/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement ASP.NET Core OpenID Connect with Keycloak to implement Level of Authentication (LoA) requirements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 04:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at implementing an OpenID Connect client in ASP.NET Core and require a level of authentication (LoA) implemented using Keycloak. The applications are hosted using Aspire. The LoA is requested in Keycloak using the arc_values claim. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/IdentityExternalErrorHandling Setup The applications are implemented using Aspire. An ASP.NET Core application uses an OpenID Connect […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/07/02/implement-asp-net-core-openid-connect-with-keykloak-to-implement-level-of-authentication-loa-requirements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us for MCP Dev Days - July 29-30</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 22:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get ready for two days of deep technical insight, community connection, and hands-on learning at MCP Dev Days, a virtual event dedicated to the Model Context Protocol (MCP) — the emerging standard that bridges AI models and the tools they rely on. [cta-button text=&amp;quot;➡️ Register for MCP Dev Days&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;h
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//join-us-for-mcp-dev-days-july-29-30 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio to build complex AI workflows using Amazon Bedrock Flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 20:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use SageMaker Unified Studio to create complex AI workflows using Amazon Bedrock Flows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio-to-build-complex-ai-workflows-using-amazon-bedrock-flows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating AI innovation: Scale MCP servers for enterprise workloads with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a centralized Model Context Protocol (MCP) server implementation using Amazon Bedrock that provides shared access to tools and resources for enterprise AI workloads. The solution enables organizations to accelerate AI innovation by standardizing access to resources and tools through MCP, while maintaining security and governance through a centralized approach.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-ai-innovation-scale-mcp-servers-for-enterprise-workloads-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the right approach for generative AI-powered structured data retrieval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore five different patterns for implementing LLM-powered structured data query capabilities in AWS, including direct conversational interfaces, BI tool enhancements, and custom text-to-SQL solutions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/choosing-the-right-approach-for-generative-ai-powered-structured-data-retrieval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing drug data analysis using Amazon Bedrock multimodal RAG capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock&#39;s multimodal RAG capabilities revolutionize drug data analysis by efficiently processing complex medical documentation containing text, images, graphs, and tables.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-drug-data-analysis-using-amazon-bedrock-multimodal-rag-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DirectStorage 1.3 is now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re releasing DirectStorage 1.3, this update includes a new API and several refinements based on developer feedback. The package is now available for download via NuGet
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directstorage-1-3-is-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Transform for .NET now supports chat about assessments and transformations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Transform for .NET accelerates large-scale modernization of .NET projects, including porting .NET Framework to cross-platform .NET as well as .NET upgrades. Today we are releasing a new feature that allows you to gain insights about transformation jobs using chat from the web console. This new chat capability lets you ask about repository assessments and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/aws-transform-for-net-now-supports-chat-about-assessments-and-transformations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building secure, scalable AI in the cloud with Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Forrester Research shows how Azure helps enterprises scale generative AI securely, overcoming infrastructure and compliance challenges to unlock real business value. The post Building secure, scalable AI in the cloud with Microsoft Azure appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/building-secure-scalable-ai-in-the-cloud-with-microsoft-azure/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sizzle reel that says things that nobody understands</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the end of project milestones, some organizations have a tradition of asking each team within the organization to produce a a &amp;quot;sizzle reel&amp;quot; highlighting the work that they have accomplished. These short videos are then gathered together and shown at the organizational group meeting so everybody can show off their work and receive appropr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250701-00/?p=111328 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Docker MCP Catalog: the Secure Way to Discover and Run MCP Servers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) ecosystem is exploding. In just weeks, our Docker MCP Catalog has surpassed 1 million pulls, validating that developers are hungry for a secure way to run MCP servers. Today, we&#39;re excited to share major updates to the Docker MCP Catalog, including enhanced discovery features and our new open submission process....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-catalog-secure-way-to-discover-and-run-mcp-servers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module Import Declarations: No More Import Hell</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you are proud of yourself for creating an amazing Java application, framework, or a library. You open one of its source files to make some changes and this is what you see: While looking at this long list of imports, are you wondering why you need to know the name of every single class […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/module-import-declarations-no-more-import-hell/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the features of dotnet run app.cs: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss the new single-file .NET run experience, in which you can run a C# file directly, without needing a csproj project file
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-1-exploring-the-dotnet-run-app.cs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No-code personal agents, powered by GPT-4.1 and Realtime API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Genspark built a $36M ARR AI product in 45 days—with no-code agents powered by GPT-4.1 and OpenAI Realtime API.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/genspark 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Remote Development Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 09:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The concept of remote development is deceptively simple: spin up your development environment somewhere that’s not your local machine. The perks range from freeing up local resources to not panicking when your laptop gets stolen. Yet, there are plenty of pitfalls, including flaky setups, poor visibility, and lousy monitoring. Let’s look at some best practices […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/07/10-remote-development-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davide&#39;s Code and Architecture Notes - Software Architecture vs Software Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Software Architecture and Software Design are terms that look similar but refer to two totally different aspects of software. Let’s find the differences and their purposes.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/software-architecture-vs-software-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and deploy AI inference workflows with new enhancements to the Amazon SageMaker Python SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 21:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide an overview of the user experience, detailing how to set up and deploy these workflows with multiple models using the SageMaker Python SDK. We walk through examples of building complex inference workflows, deploying them to SageMaker endpoints, and invoking them for real-time inference.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-and-deploy-ai-inference-workflows-with-new-enhancements-to-the-amazon-sagemaker-python-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New for Java Developers in Azure Cosmos DB (NoSQL)?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 18:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Java ecosystem around Azure Cosmos DB has quietly grown a lot stronger in the first half of 2024. And the updates are especially exciting if you’re working on scalable apps or exploring GenAI workloads. From new support for vector search and indexing, to better
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/whats-new-for-java-developers-in-azure-cosmos-db-nosql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring azd extensions: Enhance your Azure developer experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Exploring azd extensions: Enhance your Azure developer experience The Azure Developer CLI (azd) has a new feature called extensions that empowers developers to customize their workflow with azd. If you&#39;re a developer building on Azure, maybe you already have a &amp;quot;wish list&amp;quot; of CLI capabilities. If so, you might be able to create an ext
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azd-extension-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents at Work: Putting MSSQL MCP Server into Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How often have you wished you could just talk to your data? Imagine extracting crucial insights, updating records, or building complex reports without wrestling with intricate query languages or relying on a dedicated developer. For many professionals, the true power of their enterprise data remains locked behind technical barriers, h
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/mssql-mcp-server-in-action-susans-journey 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Leadership Series</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Progress Or Perfection? Staying Quality-Focused as a Team Under Pressure Everyone from growth-mindset gurus to Agile die-hards talk about ways in which we can iterate as developers. Release an MVP, build as you go, “minimize waste, maximize value” to stay lean, and do it all while prioritizing user feedback. But as much merit as these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/06/qodana-leadership-series-minaev/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New YouTrack Prices Starting from October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re introducing a few changes to YouTrack prices, which will take effect on October 1, 2025. What’s not changing What will be changing Read on to learn about the reasons for this change, how to prepare, and what it means for YouTrack Cloud and Server customers. Why are we making this change? Our current pricing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/06/new-youtrack-prices-starting-from-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in Azure AI Foundry | June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Key dev updates: Agent Service hits GA with Model Context Protocol (MCP) support—integrate any backend with standardized JSON-RPC calls, no more custom OpenAPI specs. New models include o3-pro for enterprise reasoning, Sora for video generation, and DeepSeek-R1 for open-source reasoning. Platform ch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/whats-new-in-azure-ai-foundry-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest NoSQL Java Ecosystem Updates: June 2024 - June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the latest roundup of key updates across the Azure Cosmos DB Java ecosystem! The largest external customers of Azure Cosmos DB API for NoSQL, running some of th
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/latest-nosql-java-ecosystem-updates-june-2024-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context extraction from image files in Amazon Q Business using LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we look at a step-by-step implementation for using the custom document enrichment (CDE) feature within an Amazon Q Business application to process standalone image files. We walk you through an AWS Lambda function configured within CDE to process various image file types, and showcase an example scenario of how this integration enhances Amazon Q Business&#39;s ability to provide comprehensive insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/context-extraction-from-image-files-in-amazon-q-business-using-llms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 mid-year link clearance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visualizing all the books of the world in ISBN space. What it says on the tin. Back in 2013, there was a series of promotional videos for the golf European Tour titled &amp;quot;Every Shot Imaginable&amp;quot;, in which golfers attempted silly tasks. P
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250630-01/?p=111323 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing the power of the empty set in API design: Requesting zero items</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A team was proposing a method that was at its essence a Read(n) that takes the maximum number of items to read. The reality was more complicated than that: The parameter n was really a configuration property on an operation, but it had the same meaning: It set the maximum number of items to return. The team s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250630-00/?p=111320 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AWS architecture diagrams using Amazon Q CLI and MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q Developer CLI with the AWS Diagram MCP and the AWS Documentation MCP servers to create sophisticated architecture diagrams that follow AWS best practices. We discuss techniques for basic diagrams and real-world diagrams, with detailed examples and step-by-step instructions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-aws-architecture-diagrams-using-amazon-q-cli-and-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool Calling with Local LLMs: A Practical Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Which local model should I use for tool calling? When building GenAI and agentic applications, one of the most pressing and persistent questions is: “Which local model should I use for tool calling?” We kept hearing again and again, from colleagues within Docker and the developer community, ever since we started working on Docker Model...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/local-llm-tool-calling-a-practical-evaluation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find Public Symbols That Can Be Internal Using Roslyn</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I got a question about how to find all public symbols in a solution that can be internal. This is a common scenario when you want to reduce the visibility of your code to improve encapsulation. You can use Roslyn as a library to analyze the code in a solution and find such symbols. I&#39;ve already written about how to use Roslyn as a library to analyze and rewrite code in a solution: .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.4: Another Set of Bug-fixes Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 08:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A fourth set of updates for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.4 comes with the following fixes For the full list of resolved issues, please refer to our issue tracker. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/30/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI in Australia—OpenAI’s Economic Blueprint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, OpenAI, in partnership with Mandala Partners, is sharing the OpenAI AI Economic Blueprint for Australia. At a time when boosting productivity has emerged as a national priority for Australia, the Blueprint provides a clear, actionable plan for how Australia can unlock the full economic and social potential of artificial intelligence.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/openais-australia-economic-blueprint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source AI Editor: First Milestone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are open sourcing the GitHub Copilot Chat extension. It’s the first milestone in making VS Code an open source AI editor. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/open-source-ai-editor:-first-milestone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Mastering Method Returns with Spargine’s SimpleResult Type</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2025/29_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2025/29_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET development community is increasingly favoring result types like SimpleResult over exceptions for routine error handling, enhancing reliability and performance. SimpleResult allows returning values alongside exceptions, supports multiple errors, and improves clarity in code. This utility promotes efficient error handling in various application contexts.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/29/boost-your-net-projects-mastering-method-returns-with-spargines-simpleresult-type/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back on 20&#43; Years of Programming - Dev Leader Weekly 100</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss my reflections looking back on 20 years of programming and building software.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/28/looking-back-on-20-years-of-programming-dev-leader-weekly-100 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-06-27</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 06:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/28/weekly-recap-20250627 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testcontainers Best Practices for .NET Integration Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Integration tests shouldn&#39;t rely on external infrastructure—but they also shouldn&#39;t mock everything away. In this post, we look at how to use Testcontainers in .NET to spin up real Postgres and Redis instances in your tests, how to manage container lifecycle using IAsyncLifetime, and how to structure your xUnit fixtures for speed and reliability
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/testcontainers-best-practices-dotnet-integration-testing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Model Context Protocol Support (preview) in Azure AI Foundry Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 22:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative-AI agents only become useful when they can do things—query systems of record, trigger workflows, or look up specialized knowledge. Until now that meant hand-rolling Azure Functions, managing OpenAPI specs, or writing custom pl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/announcing-model-context-protocol-support-preview-in-azure-ai-foundry-agent-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating C# Model Context Protocol servers with Amazon Q Developer CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 21:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to create your own Model Context Protocol (MCP) server with C# and .NET. You will use Amazon Q Developer Command-Line Interface (Amazon Q CLI) as an MCP client. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open standard that lets Artificial Intelligence (AI) models safely interact with external tools and resources. MCP enhances […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/integrating-c-model-context-protocol-servers-with-amazon-q-developer-cli/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs: Unlocking enterprise knowledge for AI with the Retrieval API — Now in Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 17:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Build 2025, we introduced the Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs. Developers now have an extensibility layer that empowers them to create intelligent, AI-driven experiences deeply integrated with the Microsoft 365 ecosystem. These API
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-copilot-apis-unlocking-enterprise-knowledge-for-ai-with-the-retrieval-api 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS costs estimation using Amazon Q CLI and AWS Cost Analysis MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q CLI with the AWS Cost Analysis MCP server to perform sophisticated cost analysis that follows AWS best practices. We discuss basic setup and advanced techniques, with detailed examples and step-by-step instructions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-costs-estimation-using-amazon-q-cli-and-aws-cost-analysis-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Easy Private AI Assistant with Goose and Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Goose is an innovative CLI assistant designed to automate development tasks using AI models. Docker Model Runner simplifies deploying AI models locally with Docker. Combining these technologies creates a powerful local environment with advanced AI assistance, ideal for coding and automation. Looking for a seamless way to run AI-powered development tasks locally without compromising on...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-an-ai-assistant-with-goose-and-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I get errors or warnings about some weird symbol called ?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform..., part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have been investigating why a project is getting an error about a weird C++/CX symbol, and we tracked it down to three things:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250627-00/?p=111316 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Extension Methods to Extension Members: Unlocking New Possibilities in .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article examines the significance of extension methods in .NET, emphasizing their role in enhancing existing types without altering source code. It also introduces Extension Members in .NET 10 (C# 14), allowing the addition of both methods and properties, thus expanding developers&#39; capabilities. While there are limitations, they improve code maintainability and flexibility.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/27/from-extension-methods-to-extension-members-unlocking-new-possibilities-in-net-10/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic Claude Sonnet 4 and Opus 4 Now Available in GitHub Copilot for JetBrains and Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 05:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anthropic Claude Sonnet 4 and Claude Opus 4 are now available in GitHub Copilot Chat for JetBrains IDEs and Eclipse. Model Availability✨
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/anthropic-claude-sonnet-4-and-opus-4-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot for Xcode Adds Support for Anthropic Claude Sonnet 4 and Opus 4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 02:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot for Xcode now supports Anthropic Claude Sonnet 4 and Claude Opus 4, bringing more powerful AI assistance to your Swift, Objective-C, and Apple platform development.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/copilot-for-xcode-adds-support-for-claude-sonnet-4-and-opus-4 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
