<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenTofu: Open Source Alternative to Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the world of cloud, hybrid, and on-premises Infrastructure as Code (IaC), where managing and provisioning infrastructure through code has become indispensable, tools like OpenTofu play a pivotal role. The evolutions of IaC tools continues with OpenTofu, as a fork of Terraform that offers a more open-source, community-driven alternative that is managed by the Linux […] The article OpenTofu: Open Source Alternative to Terraform appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Math Do You Need To Program? – Dev Leader Weekly 41</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How Much Math Do You Need To Program? – Dev Leader Weekly 41 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I answer the question of how much math do you need to program -- with help from Twitter. The post How Much Math Do You Need To Program? – Dev Leader Weekly 41 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 05:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about Server-Sent Events in ASP.NET Core. We will see what they are, their features, advantages, and implementation. So, let’s start. What Are Server-Sent Events The Server-Sent Events (SSE) protocol allows servers to send real-time, event-driven updates to clients over an HTTP connection without the client requesting these updates. It […] The post Using Server-Sent Events for Realtime Updates in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Response Messaging Pattern With MassTransit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_04_2024/27_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building distributed systems with .NET, direct calls between services can create tight coupling. The request-response messaging pattern can allow distributed services to communicate in a loosely coupled way.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/request-response-messaging-pattern-with-masstransit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databricks DBRX is now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 19:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the DBRX model, an open, general-purpose large language model (LLM) developed by Databricks, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy with one click for running inference. The DBRX LLM employs a fine-grained mixture-of-experts (MoE) architecture, pre-trained on 12 trillion tokens of carefully curated data and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/databricks-dbrx-is-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases in Amazon Bedrock now simplifies asking questions on a single document</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 19:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At AWS re:Invent 2023, we announced the general availability of Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock. With Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, you can securely connect foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock to your company data for fully managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). In previous posts, we covered new capabilities like hybrid search support, metadata filtering […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/knowledge-bases-in-amazon-bedrock-now-simplifies-asking-questions-on-a-single-document/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OData .NET 8 Preview Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We would like to announce that we are planning a new major release of OData .NET core libraries in June. Ahead of this release, we have released preview versions of the libraries to get some early feedback from the community. Specifically,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/odata-net-8-preview-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability Improvements in the Visual Studio Connection Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Visual Studio 2022 17.10 Preview 2, we’ve introduced some UX updates and usability improvements to the Connection Manager. With these updates we provide a more seamless experience when connecting to remote systems and/or debugging failed connections. Please install the latest Preview to try it out.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/usability-improvements-in-the-visual-studio-connection-manager 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking changes to Microsoft Graph presence and online meeting basic change notifications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The change removes data about the changed resource from the notifications and applies the established pattern for change notifications to presence and online meeting resources.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/breaking-changes-to-microsoft-graph-presence-and-online-meeting-basic-change-notifications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Dev Experience with Serverless Rust in RustRover</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 14:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Serverless computing and the Rust programming language together offer a promising path for developers to build efficient and scalable applications without the traditional barriers of infrastructure management. In our latest livestream session with James Eastham, a senior cloud architect at AWS, we explored the synergies between Rust and serverless architecture, particularly focusing on AWS Lambda. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/04/26/boosting-dev-experience-with-serverless-rust-in-rustrover/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Comparing the two algorithms.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240426-00/?p=109705 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.1.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WebStorm 2024.1.2, the second update for WebStorm 2024.1, is now available! It contains improvements for Angular and adds ESLint 9 support. You can update to v2024.1.2 by using the Toolbox App, installing it right from the IDE, or downloading it from our website. Angular improvements This update introduces new support for Angular 17.2 syntax output() […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/04/webstorm-2024-1-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Modules using Git Branch as Source</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp Terraform empowers DevOps Engineers and SREs to manage cloud resources efficiently. One of its standout features is the Terraform Modules support, allowing users to organize and reuse infrastructure code effectively as reusable modules. While Terraform’s native module registry serves as a central hub for sharing modules, sometimes you may prefer hosting modules in your […] The article Terraform: Modules using Git Branch as Source appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2022.2.3 Is Ready for Download</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For MPS users still on version 2022.2, we’ve prepared another bug-fix release with several fixes and improvements. Check them out and see how they can make your life easier. DOWNLOAD MPS 2022.2.3 Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/04/mps-2022-2-2-has-been-released-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Spotlight on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Marketplace is a thriving ecosystem where developers can discover plugins that enhance their coding experience and implement and share their plugins with others. While many users find plugins through targeted searches, some may not be aware of tools and integrations that extend beyond programming to general productivity. To draw attention to this trove of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/04/plugin-spotlight-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Maze Weekly #211</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 09:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Issue #211 of the Code Maze weekly. Check out what’s new this week and enjoy the read. .NET and C# Top Picks Unit testing BlobServiceClient with Azure blobs and NSubstitute [blog.elmah.io] If you rely on Azure Blob in your projects, here’s an excellent article by Thomas Ardal that can help you understand it better and […] The post Code Maze Weekly #211 appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Is LINQ Always the Most Performant Choice?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores the performance implications of using LINQ for collection queries, finding that a conventional foreach() loop outperforms LINQ by 1.75 times in identifying items matching a given query. The conclusion suggests benchmarking to determine the optimal approach based on the nature of the query and elements being sought.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/26/collection-performance-is-linq-always-the-most-performant-choice/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Containers Simplified</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post talks about the concept of development containers and how it can help us to solve the challenges we face when setting up our development environment or onboarding a new team member.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/dev-containers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Zip File in Memory In C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will look at how we create In-Memory Zip files in C#. Previously, we discussed how to create and read Zip files in .NET in our Working With Zip Files in C#/.NET article, so we recommend taking a look at that to familiarize yourself with working with Zip files. Let’s delve in. […] The post How to Create a Zip File in Memory In C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.5 Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the availability of TypeScript 5.5 Beta. To get started using the beta, you can get it through NuGet, or through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@beta Here’s a quick list of what’s new in TypeScript 5.5!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-5-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Semantic Kernel Hits 1,000,000 Downloads</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 20:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A million moments of innovation, a million instances of creative coding, a million downloads. Microsoft Semantic Kernel has proudly reached a significant milestone within the software development community. This achievement is not just a number—it’s a beacon of collective progress and the power of open-source collaboration.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/microsoft-semantic-kernel-hits-1000000-downloads 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio features for C&#43;&#43; Header Files and Modules</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 19:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the field of C++ programming, the management of header files and modules can often seem challenging. However, there are numerous tools and features available that can simplify this process, enhancing efficiency and reducing the likelihood of errors. Here’s a walkthrough for several tools that we provide for C++ headers and modules.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-features-for-c-header-files-and-modules 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.1.1 Bug-Fix Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CLion 2024.1.1 bug-fix update is here! The fixes included in this update are listed below. Download build 241.15989.121 from our website, through the Toolbox App, as a snap package for Ubuntu, or via a patch from inside the IDE. If you haven’t upgraded to v2024.1, now is a good time to do so. You […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/04/clion-2024-1-1-bug-fix-update/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new for .NET in Ubuntu 24.04</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ubuntu 24.04 is now available with .NET from day one in the official Ubuntu feeds! Thanks to the partnership between Canonical and Microsoft, you can start using .NET with Ubuntu 24.04 today!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/whats-new-for-dotnet-in-ubuntu-2404 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a Hugging Face (PyAnnote) speaker diarization model on Amazon SageMaker as an asynchronous endpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 17:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Speaker diarization, an essential process in audio analysis, segments an audio file based on speaker identity. This post delves into integrating Hugging Face’s PyAnnote for speaker diarization with Amazon SageMaker asynchronous endpoints. We provide a comprehensive guide on how to deploy speaker segmentation and clustering solutions using SageMaker on the AWS Cloud.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-a-hugging-face-pyannote-speaker-diarization-model-on-amazon-sagemaker-as-an-asynchronous-endpoint/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing API Manifest Plugins for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, Today we’re featuring a guest author from another team in Microsoft on our Semantic Kernel blog. We will turn it over to Mustafa Zengin to dive into Introducing API Manifest Plugins for Semantic Kernel. Semantic Kernel allows developers to import plugins from OpenAPI documents.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/introducing-api-manifest-plugins-for-semantic-kernel-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate the text summarization capabilities of LLMs for enhanced decision-making on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations across industries are using automatic text summarization to more efficiently handle vast amounts of information and make better decisions. In the financial sector, investment banks condense earnings reports down to key takeaways to rapidly analyze quarterly performance. Media companies use summarization to monitor news and social media so journalists can quickly write stories on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-the-text-summarization-capabilities-of-llms-for-enhanced-decision-making-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing IBM’s Acquisition of HashiCorp: A Game-Changer in Hybrid Cloud Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IBM has announced its acquisition of HashiCorp Inc., a leading multi-cloud infrastructure automation company, for $6.4 billion! This acquisition is poised to revolutionize the hybrid cloud landscape, offering enterprises a comprehensive end-to-end solution to navigate the complexities of today’s AI-driven application growth. Let’s look at the details of this cloud changing acquisition and its implications […] The article Analyzing IBM’s Acquisition of HashiCorp: A Game-Changer in Hybrid Cloud Management appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K2 Compiler Performance Benchmarks and How to Measure Them on Your Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 15:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the Kotlin 2.0.0 release drawing ever closer, the K2 compiler is now available for you to try! In this blog post, we explore the performance of the K2 compiler in various projects and give you the tools to collect your own performance statistics. The road to the Stable version of the K2 compiler has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/04/k2-compiler-performance-benchmarks-and-how-to-measure-them-on-your-projects/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Going free-threaded.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240425-00/?p=109702 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: How are Data Sources used?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In HashiCorp Terraform, data sources serve as a bridge between the Terraform configuration and external systems or information. Essentially, data sources allow Terraform to query external resources, such as cloud platforms, APIs, databases, or other systems, and use the retrieved information within the configuration. Unlike resources, which represent infrastructure components to be managed by Terraform, […] The article Terraform: How are Data Sources used? appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Comparison of Passing Parameters in Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article explores different methods of passing parameters into methods, including conventional, in operator, and ref readonly approaches, comparing their performance. Despite differences in syntax, benchmark results demonstrate similar performance among these methods.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/25/code-it-any-way-you-want-comparison-of-passing-parameters-in-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Show the Generated SQL Query in EF Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 06:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core has many useful features, and in this article, we will see how to use it to show a generated SQL query. EF Core is an open source Object-relational mapper that supports several databases like SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and also LINQ (Language Integrated Query). One key benefit to developers is the ability to […] The post How to Show the Generated SQL Query in EF Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing .NET MAUI Community Tookit v8: TouchBehavior support is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET MAUI Community Toolkit version 8.0 has been released with the highly anticipated TouchBehavior on board!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-maui-community-toolkit-touchbehavior 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance conversational AI with advanced routing techniques with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Conversational artificial intelligence (AI) assistants are engineered to provide precise, real-time responses through intelligent routing of queries to the most suitable AI functions. With AWS generative AI services like Amazon Bedrock, developers can create systems that expertly manage and respond to user requests. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-conversational-ai-with-advanced-routing-techniques-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve LLM performance with human and AI feedback on Amazon SageMaker for Amazon Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Amazon EU Design and Construction (Amazon D&amp;amp;C) team is the engineering team designing and constructing Amazon warehouses. The team navigates a large volume of documents and locates the right information to make sure the warehouse design meets the highest standards. In the post A generative AI-powered solution on Amazon SageMaker to help Amazon EU […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-llm-performance-with-human-and-ai-feedback-on-amazon-sagemaker-for-amazon-engineering/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Step-by-Step Guide to Performing Data Analysis With Kotlin DataFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This is the first in a series of tutorials on how to easily manipulate and visualize your data using the Kotlin DataFrame and Kandy libraries. The tutorials are aimed at regular Kotlin developers, so no previous experience of data analysis or similar frameworks (like pandas or Apache Spark) is necessary. You should, however, be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/04/a-step-by-step-guide-to-performing-data-analysis-with-kotlin-dataframe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve accuracy of Amazon Rekognition Face Search with user vectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In various industries, such as financial services, telecommunications, and healthcare, customers use a digital identity process, which usually involves several steps to verify end-users during online onboarding or step-up authentication. An example of one step that can be used is face search, which can help determine whether a new end-user’s face matches those associated with […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-accuracy-of-amazon-rekognition-face-search-with-user-vectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Promising Methodology for Testing GenAI Applications in Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Testing applications that incorporate AI can be difficult. In this article, we share a promising new methodology for testing GenAI applications in Java.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/testing-genai-applications-in-java/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Debugging: How the Signal0ne Docker Extension Uses AI to Simplify Container Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started with Signal0ne, a Docker Desktop extension that scans Docker containers&#39; state and logs in search of problems, analyzes the discovered issues, and outputs insights to help developers debug.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/debug-containers-ai-signal0ne-docker-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, Testing is an integral part of the software development process. Unit testing allows to test your functionality in isolation. This usually means that instead of performing real work (e.g. sending HTTP request to LLM), it needs to be replaced with something that only simulates the work and return some predefined result,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/unit-testing-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using a change counter with coalescing.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240424-00/?p=109700 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Split main.tf into seperate files</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When using HashiCorp Terraform as the Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool of choice, it becomes critical to organize the Terraform code as the Terraform project becomes more complex. One of the most common practices is to split the Terraform project from a single file (typically named main.tf) into multiple smaller files. This helps increase maintainability […] The article Terraform: Split main.tf into seperate files appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seamless Production Deployment with Elastic Beanstalk</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Production deployments can be complicated. You want to avoid disruption to your users and minimize downtime, but you also need to consider cost, time, risk, and how to recover from a failed deployment. You can balance the trade-offs between these considerations by choosing a deployment strategy. AWS Elastic Beanstalk is a managed AWS compute […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/seamless-production-deployment-with-elastic-beanstalk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MudBlazor with Blazor SSR – What You Need To Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post MudBlazor with Blazor SSR – What You Need To Know appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how to use MudBlazor with Blazor SSR! Blazor&#39;s Server Side Rendering can be used alongside this awesome control library for building your next Blazor app! The post MudBlazor with Blazor SSR – What You Need To Know appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/24/mudblazor-with-blazor-ssr-what-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers save up to 8 hours per week with JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI seems to be popping up everywhere, so it’s no surprise that it has made its way into software development. Fortunately, it’s not here to take over, but to make our lives a whole lot easier and a bit more fun. JetBrains joined the AI race on December 6 after the official launch of AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2024/04/developers-save-up-to-8-hours-per-week-with-jetbrains-ai-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing identity: Exploring application types and authentication flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building on the foundations laid out in an earlier blog post on IAM basics, this blog post dives into the world of application types and authentication flows.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/app-types-and-auth-flows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance: Choosing Between GetValueOrDefault() and Coalesce Operator for Nullable Integers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In dealing with nullable integers and the need for default values, two common approaches are the coalesce operator (??) and GetValueOrDefault(). Alternatively, utilizing HasValue with the conditional operator is demonstrated.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/24/general-performance-choosing-between-getvalueordefault-and-coalesce-operator-for-nullable-integers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HSTS Header Implementation in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 04:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to learn how to implement the HSTS header in ASP.NET Core applications. So let’s get going. What Is HSTS HTTP Strict Transport Security (HSTS) is a web security mechanism that forces browsers to access a website using only secure HTTPS connections. When enabled, the browser automatically upgrades any HTTP […] The post HSTS Header Implementation in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to upload a file with Blazor SSR in .NET 8?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Blazor has built-in support for handling file uploads. If you’re using one of the interactive render modes (or .NET 7 or earlier) you can use the dedicated InputFile component and use that to get hold of a file from the user. You can then save that file somewhere (to disk, or the cloud). Here’s a basic example using Blazor Server. @page &amp;quot;/FileUpload/InteractiveServer&amp;quot; @rendermode InteractiveServer
@code { private async Task UploadFile(InputFileChangeEventArgs e) { var saveFolder = Path.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Optimal Parameter Passing – Array vs. Params Keyword</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores the performance differences between passing parameters as arrays or using the params keyword in C#. Despite similarities in speed, the author recommends using the params keyword for its ease of use during function calls.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/23/code-it-any-way-you-want-optimal-parameter-passing-array-vs-params-keyword/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate ML workflows with Amazon SageMaker Studio Local Mode and Docker support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 19:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce two new capabilities in Amazon SageMaker Studio that will accelerate iterative development for machine learning (ML) practitioners: Local Mode and Docker support. ML model development often involves slow iteration cycles as developers switch between coding, training, and deployment. Each step requires waiting for remote compute resources to start up, which […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-ml-workflows-with-amazon-sagemaker-studio-local-mode-and-docker-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Plans with Semantic Kernel: Implementing the Microsoft Graph Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, Today we’re featuring a guest author on our Semantic Kernel blog, José Luis Latorre Millás, an MVP for Microsoft focused on AI. We will turn it over to Jose to dive into Making Plans with Semantic Kernel – Implementing the Microsoft Graph Plugin.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/making-plans-with-semantic-kernel-implementing-the-microsoft-graph-plugin 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Federal Agencies in Their Implementation of the Executive Order on AI – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 17:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Office of Management and Budget’s (OMB) Memorandum on Artificial Intelligence (M-24-10) (the “Memo”), part of the President’s comprehensive strategy on AI, outlines a structured approach for federal agencies to leverage artificial intelligence responsibly. The Memo provides direction that establishes a governance framework,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/fed-agencies-exec-order-ai-part1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactor your C# code with primary constructors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore C# 12&#39;s primary constructors through incremental refactoring of a Worker service.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/csharp-primary-constructors-refactoring 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code update – April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 16:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about the latest updates including added improvements to build API Message extensions with an auth-protected API.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/teams-toolkit-for-visual-studio-code-update-april-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using a change counter.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240423-00/?p=109697 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform: Remove Resource from State File (.tfstate)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Terraform’s declarative approach allows for defining infrastructure as code (IaC), enabling teams to automate the deployment and management of resources across various cloud providers, including Microsoft Azure and Amazon AWS. As infrastructure evolves, there may arise a need to remove resources from the Terraform state that are no longer required. When you manually delete resources […] The article Terraform: Remove Resource from State File (.tfstate) appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try Catch in C#: The Basics You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Try Catch in C#: The Basics You Need to Know appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how exception handling works in C# with the basics of try catch. This article is perfect for junior software engineers aiming to understand dotnet and C#. The post Try Catch in C#: The Basics You Need to Know appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/04/23/try-catch-in-c-the-basics-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significant new capabilities make it easier to use Amazon Bedrock to build and scale generative AI applications – and achieve impressive results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 11:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We introduced Amazon Bedrock to the world a little over a year ago, delivering an entirely new way to build generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications. With the broadest selection of first- and third-party foundation models (FMs) as well as user-friendly capabilities, Amazon Bedrock is the fastest and easiest way to build and scale secure generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-capabilities-make-it-easier-to-use-amazon-bedrock-to-build-and-scale-generative-ai-applications-and-deliver-impact/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building scalable, secure, and reliable RAG applications using Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 11:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the new enterprise-grade features for Knowledge Bases on Amazon Bedrock and how they align with the AWS Well-Architected Framework. With Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, you can quickly build applications using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) for use cases like question answering, contextual chatbots, and personalized search.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-scalable-secure-and-reliable-rag-applications-using-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the AskVS command in GitHub Copilot for Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot is an AI-driven coding assistant designed to streamline your coding tasks and boost productivity in various development environments. In this ongoing series, we focus on its integration with Visual Studio, illustrating how it can significantly enhance your workflow and coding experience.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/exploring-the-askvs-command-in-github-copilot-for-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking together an AsciiMath parser for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe how I hacked together an AsciiMath parser for .NET. I also show the existing implementations available and how I chose between them
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/hacking-together-an-asciimath-parser-for-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code Update – April 2024 (Roadmap Update)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 08:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the April update for Visual Studio Code for Java! In this blog we are going to share our roadmap for the next few months, and also recent product updates such as JDK 22 support and redesigned Project Settings experience,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-visual-studio-code-update-april-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance your .NET Testing #8: Contract tests with Verify</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The most common way to test the values of an object is to use assertions for each property to check exactly what the object contains. This can be done for types, classes, enumerables. The more aspects of the object that are tested, the more certain you can be that everything
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/enhance-contract-tests-verify-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code的更新 – 2024年4月 (产品路线图更新)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 07:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎来到 Visual Studio Code 的 Java 四月更新！在本篇博客中，我们将分享未来几个月的路线图，以及最近的更新，例如 JDK 22 支持和重新设计过的项目设置体验，让我们开始吧！ 未来 6 个月的路线图 我们很高兴与大家分享未来几个月的产品路线图！这个产品路线图有很多部分基于用户得来的反馈，因此我们要感谢社区提供的所有意见。我们将继续与我们的合作伙伴红帽一起努力，为 Visual Studio Code 上的 Java 开发人员提供最佳体验。以下是我们路线图的主要方向。 基础体验 支持最新的 JDK 是我们的首要任务。除此之外我们还将增加一些高级的代码导航和调试功能，因为这次会影响到开发者的日常工作体验。最后，我们将集成 javac 编译器替代我们当前的 ECJ 编译器以带来更好的构建体验。 性能和可靠性 性能和可靠性是我们次要的优先级，因为我们在这个领域听到了很多反馈意见。我们将专注于减少不稳定会话的数量，并优化每个会话的内存/CPU 使用率。 兼容性 去年我们发布了 Gradle 构建服务器时，社区给予了很多积极的反馈。在接下来的几个月里，我们将把用于Gradle for Java 插件（该插件应用了Gradle构建服务器）集成到我们的 Java 插件包中，并同时专注于提高 Gradle 项目的项目导入成功率。 项目管理 许多 Java 开发者来自传统的 Java IDE 背景，并提到他们希望拥有更好的 JDK 配置体验，因此我们将改进这个领域。此外，我们还将改进项目创建/导入体验和Java包创建工作流程。 用户体验 对于用户体验，我们主要会为开发人员添加更多的代码重构和操作选项，并使其更易于发现。我们还将使我们的 Java 语言服务器设置更易于发现。 AI 在AI方面，我们的插件将与 GitHub Copilot Chat 集成（现在它已经了具有可扩展性），以便 Java 开发者可以利用这种集成来使他们编写代码更加高效与方便，敬请关注。 产品更新 Java 22 支持 您已经可以在 Visual Studio Code 中使用 JDK 22 了。所有语言特性现在都得到了支持，以下是一些要点特性： 字符串模板（第二预览版） 这个功能在 JDK 21 中进行了预览，现在是第二次预览。其主要目的是为我们的程序提供一个比现有字符串连接代码更好的替代选项。您可以在此链接上查看此功能的详细信息。以下是此功能的演示。 隐式声明的类和实例主方法（第二预览版） 这个预览功能（也在 JDK 21 中进行了预览）主要针对 Java 学生和学习者，现在他们不必显式声明类或输入 public static void main(String[] args)，类或main方法可以被隐式声明。请查看下面的演示。 这些只是 Java 22 的一部分特性。有关完整的特性列表，请查看参考文档。 请注意，如果您要使用 Java 22 的预览功能，请务必查看此文档，了解如何启用预览功能。 改进的项目设置体验 在过去的几个月里，我们收到了很多关于我们的 Java 运行时以及 Java 类路径配置体验的反馈意见。在我们的最新版本中，我们推出了一个重新设计的体验，具有简化的布局。要访问它，您可以打开命令面板，然后键入“&amp;gt;Java: Configure Classpath”。 新布局有三个标签，分别是 Sources、JDK Runtime 和 Libraries。 Sources –
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing more enterprise-grade features for API customers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Increasing enterprise support with more security features and controls, updates to our Assistants API, and tools to better manage costs.
Link to article: https://openai.com/blog/more-enterprise-grade-features-for-api-customers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s commitment to child safety: adopting safety by design principles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re joining Thorn, All Tech Is Human, and other leading companies in an effort to prevent the misuse of generative AI to perpetrate, proliferate, and further sexual harms against children.
Link to article: https://openai.com/blog/child-safety-adopting-sbd-principles 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit testing BlobServiceClient with Azure blobs and NSubstitute</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 08:01:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I have blogged a whole lot about unit testing lately. Today&#39;s post is no exception. I recently migrated some of the last code we had running on the Microsoft.Azure.Storage.Blob package to Azure.Storage.Blobs. During that task, I had to rewrite some unit tests using asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/unit-testing-methods-on-blobserviceclient-with-azure-blob-storage-and-nsubstitute/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a URL Shortener in .NET Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 05:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with URLs in our applications, there are times when they may become too long, clunky, unreadable, and difficult to use. In such situations, we can employ a URL shortener to make them shorter, more readable, and easier to share. Essentially, a URL shortener takes our long URLs and provides a shorter URL that, […] The post How to Build a URL Shortener in .NET Applications appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; Pre-Conference Videos – Linux Development, Modules, Containers and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 19:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Pure Virtual C++ is our free one-day virtual conference for the whole C++ community. This year it will run on April 30th 15:00 UTC. Sign-up for free to get access to our five sessions on the day. Half of the pre-conference content for the conference is now available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-cpp-pre-conference-videos 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2024 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 19:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pure Virtual C++ is our free one-day virtual conference for the whole C++ community. This year it will run on April 30th 15:00 UTC. Sign-up for free to get access to our five sessions on the day and a host of pre-conference content which will roll out in the two weeks leading up to the conference.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/pure-virtual-cpp-2024-sessions-announced 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we built “Ask Learn”, the RAG-based knowledge service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 18:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            My name is Bob Tabor and I’m a member of Microsoft’s Skilling organization. We create documentation and training content about Azure, developer tooling and languages, AI, Windows and much more hosted at Microsoft Learn. Our organization also develops and maintains the content publishing platform,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/how-we-built-ask-learn-the-rag-based-knowledge-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate HyperPod clusters with Active Directory for seamless multi-user login</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker HyperPod is purpose-built to accelerate foundation model (FM) training, removing the undifferentiated heavy lifting involved in managing and optimizing a large training compute cluster. With SageMaker HyperPod, you can train FMs for weeks and months without disruption. Typically, HyperPod clusters are used by multiple users: machine learning (ML) researchers, software engineers, data scientists, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-hyperpod-clusters-with-active-directory-for-seamless-multi-user-login/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The executive’s guide to generative AI for sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are facing ever-increasing requirements for sustainability goals alongside environmental, social, and governance (ESG) practices. A Gartner, Inc. survey revealed that 87 percent of business leaders expect to increase their organization’s investment in sustainability over the next years. This post serves as a starting point for any executive seeking to navigate the intersection of generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-executives-guide-to-generative-ai-for-sustainability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Build of OpenJDK – April 2024 Patch &amp; Security Update Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenJDK April 2024 Patch &amp;amp; Security Updates We are happy to announce the latest April 2024 patch &amp;amp; security update release for the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK. See the release notes for detailed changes present in the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK binaries.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/microsoft-build-of-openjdk-april-2024-patch-security-update-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure CDN POP Locations: Interactive Map of Azure CDN Points of Presence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 16:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Azure CDN (Content Delivery Network) provides secure, reliable content delivery with a broad global reach along with rich features. The Azure CDN POP (point of presence) locations are not the same as the Azure Region locations, and Microsoft has the list of cities for the CDN locations published in the Azure documentation. However, […] The article Azure CDN POP Locations: Interactive Map of Azure CDN Points of Presence appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Preview for External REST Endpoint Invocation with Azure SQL Managed Instance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 15:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have an exciting opportunity for customers and partners to use External REST Endpoint Invocation with Azure SQL Managed Instance in a private preview. What is Azure SQL Managed Instance? Azure SQL Managed Instance is a PaaS service that has near 100% compatibility with the latest Enterprise Edition SQL Server database engine,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/private-preview-for-external-rest-endpoint-invocation-with-azure-sql-managed-instance 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy authentication with Azure App Service and Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 14:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the public preview of an improved configuration experience when using Microsoft Entra External ID with Azure App Service, simplifying authentication and authorization for external-facing apps so you can focus on your application&#39;s core features.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/app-service-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding state to the update notification pattern, part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What if the UI thread isn&#39;t there to save you?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240422-00/?p=109693 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Custom Code Inspections in IntelliJ IDEA – and More – With Qodana 2024.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 13:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains Qodana has been the talk of the code quality town since its official commercial release in July 2023. Not only is it the official JetBrains static code analysis platform for teams and therefore highly compatible with JetBrains IDEs and team tools, but Qodana also comprises a range of unique inspections, accompanied by outstanding customer […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/04/qodana-2024-1-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using type aliases to make code clearer with generics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you use generic types in C#, it is sometimes hard to understand what the generic argument can represent. For example, what do the strings represent in Dictionary&amp;lt;string, string&amp;gt;? To make the code clearer, you can use type aliases. // ❌ What does the string means? _ = new Dictionary&amp;lt;string, string&amp;gt;(); // Create aliases using UserId = string; using ProjectId = string; // Use the type aliases // ✅ It&#39;s…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Creating a List&lt;&gt; Using The Task.Parallel Library</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post discusses alternative approaches to adding items to a collection using For() or ForEach() from the Task Parallel Library.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/04/22/collection-performance-creating-a-list-using-the-task-parallel-library/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-In Rate Limiting in ASP.NET Core Web API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 05:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’re going to discuss Rate Limiting in ASP.NET Core, specifically version 8, and explore some ways of implementing it. So, Let’s start. What is Rate Limiting? Rate limiting controls the rate at which requests or events are allowed within a given time frame. In today’s world, where information flows at unprecedented rates, […] The post Built-In Rate Limiting in ASP.NET Core Web API appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Convert a String to Byte Array in C#: Encoding and Decoding Simplified</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How to Convert a String to Byte Array in C#: Encoding and Decoding Simplified appeared first on Dev Leader.Learn how to effectively convert a string to a byte array in C#! While it might seem straightforward on the surface, we have encodings to consider! The post How to Convert a String to Byte Array in C#: Encoding and Decoding Simplified appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Represent the Relationship of Properties Using Property Mappings From AutoMapper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 05:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll take a look at what property mappings are and how to retrieve them from AutoMapper. AutoMapper is a free .NET library that streamlines object mapping, reducing manual coding to boost development speed and minimize the risk of errors. Additionally, it offers versatile configuration options and supports complex needs like conditional mapping, […] The post Represent the Relationship of Properties Using Property Mappings From AutoMapper appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Convention over Configuration for IaC Deployment Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 02:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_04_2024/21_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Infrastructure as Code (IaC), every aspect of an organization’s infrastructure is defined and managed through code. This infrastructure deployment and configuration automation makes managing the organizations infrastructure much easier over time. Also, by committing the IaC code that configurations the infrastructure into source control, there are change tracking and other benefits for the organizations […] The article Benefits of Convention over Configuration for IaC Deployment Projects appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
