<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:16:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Totogi automated change request processing with Totogi BSS Magic and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post describes how Totogi automates change request processing by partnering with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center and using the rapid innovation capabilities of Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-totogi-automated-change-request-processing-with-totogi-bss-magic-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Sandboxes: Run Claude Code and Other Coding Agents Unsupervised (but Safely)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We introduced Docker Sandboxes in experimental preview a few months ago. Today, we’re launching the next evolution with microVM isolation, available now for macOS and Windows. We started Docker Sandboxes to answer the question: How do I run Claude Code or Gemini CLI safely? Sandboxes provide disposable, isolated environments purpose-built for coding agents. Each agent...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-sandboxes-run-claude-code-and-other-coding-agents-unsupervised-but-safely/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Claude Code Locally with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently showed how to pair OpenCode with Docker Model Runner for a privacy-first, cost-effective AI coding setup. Today, we&#39;re bringing the same approach to Claude Code, Anthropic&#39;s agentic coding tool. This post walks through how to configure Claude Code to use Docker Model Runner, giving you full control over your data, infrastructure, and spend....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-claude-code-locally-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Made Variable Inspections 87 Times Faster for Unreal Engine in Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever expanded a complex Unreal Engine variable in Rider’s debugger and had time to contemplate your life choices, this post is for you. We’ve rewritten our expression evaluator, and the results are dramatic: Variable inspection is up to 87 times faster on warm runs and 16 times faster on cold ones. The debugger […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/26/how-we-made-variable-inspections-87-times-faster-for-unreal-engine-in-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the First Speakers Heading to KotlinConf 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With each KotlinConf, developers from around the world come together to learn from leading experts, explore the latest industry insights, and engage with the Kotlin community. KotlinConf’25 alone welcomed attendees from over 50 countries. KotlinConf’26 is just a few months away, and we’re excited to introduce the first round of speakers who will be joining […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/meet-the-first-speakers-heading-to-kotlinconf-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream – From Detection to Remediation: Wiz in Your JetBrains IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join our upcoming IntelliJ IDEA livestream with Daniel Velikanski from Wiz to see how cloud security insights can be brought directly into your JetBrains IDE, helping you detect and address real risks as you code. Date: February 5, 2026 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Developers move fast in the cloud, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/new-livestream-engineers-talk-about-spring-boot-4-life-and-other-stuff/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force step up authentication in web applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 07:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post shows how to implement a step up authorization using the OAuth 2.0 Step Up Authentication Challenge Protocol RFC 9470. The application uses ASP.NET Core to implement the API, the web application and the identity provider. Duende IdentityServer is used to implement the OpenID Connect server standard and also OAuth DPoP token binding as […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2026/01/26/force-step-up-authentication-in-web-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Enterprise Trial – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customizing Docker Hardened Images In Part 1 and Part 2, we established the baseline. You migrated a service to a Docker Hardened Image (DHI), witnessed the vulnerability count drop to zero, and verified the cryptographic signatures and SLSA provenance that make DHI a compliant foundation. But no matter how secure a base image is, it...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-enterprise-trial-part-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Software Engineers Create Content as a Side Hustle?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Should software engineers create content as a side hustle? After 13 years and a 10-year break, here&#39;s the honest truth about what it actually takes.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/01/25/should-software-engineers-create-content-as-a-side-hustle 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String Performance: The Fastest Way to Get a String’s Length</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Retrieving the character count of a string in .NET has various methods: using Span with Length, Length, or Enumerable.Count(). This article will prove which is the fastest method.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/01/25/string-performance-the-fastest-way-to-get-a-strings-length/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Enterprise Trial – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Verifying Security and Compliance of Docker Hardened Images In Part 1 of this series, we migrated a Node.js service to Docker Hardened Images (DHI) and measured impressive results: 100% vulnerability elimination, 90% package reduction, and 41.5% size decrease. We extracted the SBOM and saw compliance labels for FIPS, STIG, and CIS. The numbers look compelling....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-enterprise-trial-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Check Out Copilot CLI - Dev Leader Weekly 124</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the Github Copilot CLI tool and how you can get started with it!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/01/24/lets-check-out-copilot-cli-dev-leader-weekly-124 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2026-01-24</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/01/24/weekly-recap-20260124 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Demo of Zero-Downtime Migrations Using Password Hashing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A practical demo of the zero-downtime migration pattern: run old + new password hash formats side-by-side, migrate users on login, and remove legacy safely.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/a-practical-demo-of-zero-downtime-migrations-using-password-hashing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI agents with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore using AWS CloudFormation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock AgentCore services are now being supported by various IaC frameworks such as AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), Terraform and AWS CloudFormation Templates. This integration brings the power of IaC directly to AgentCore so developers can provision, configure, and manage their AI agent infrastructure. In this post, we use CloudFormation templates to build an end-to-end application for a weather activity planner.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-ai-agents-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-using-aws-cloudformation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Amazon.com Catalog Team built self-learning generative AI at scale with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how the Amazon Catalog Team built a self-learning system that continuously improves accuracy while reducing costs at scale using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-the-amazon-com-catalog-team-built-self-learning-generative-ai-at-scale-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB TV Recap: Supercharging AI Agents with the Azure Cosmos DB MCP Toolkit (Ep. 110)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Episode 110 of Azure Cosmos DB TV, host Mark Brown is joined by Sajeetharan Sinnathurai to explore how the Azure Cosmos DB MCP Toolkit is changing the way developers build, deploy, and scale AI age
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-tv-ep-110-mcp-toolkit-ai-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot Debugging – Now Remote</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We released Spring Debugger in May 2025 to bring more clarity to the “magic” behind Spring Boot – helping you see what’s really happening inside your running application. By the end of 2025, the plugin had reached more than 300,000 unique downloads and became a trusted tool within the developer community. We’ve received a lot […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/spring-boot-debugging-now-remote/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing work context to your code in GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This week we shipped the GitHub Copilot SDK which takes the agent loop from the Copilot CLI and makes it easy to embed in other applications. We’ve been using, improving, and extending Copilot CLI for the last few months and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/bringing-work-context-to-your-code-in-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; has &lt;code&gt;scope_exit&lt;/code&gt; for running code at scope exit. C# says &#34;We have &lt;code&gt;scope_exit&lt;/code&gt; at home.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Windows Implementation Library (commonly known as wil) provides a helper called scope_exit which creates and returns an RAII object whose destructor runs the lambda you specify. This helper
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260123-00/?p=112008 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 3.4.0 Is Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ktor 3.4.0 improves stability and addresses outstanding issues. Highlights include OpenAPI generation, Ztsd support for the compression plugin, duplex streaming for OkHttp, Structured concurrency integrations for the HTTP request lifecycle, and much more. For a detailed list of all the changes, check out the What’s new page. Stability and performance With its focus on stability […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/ktor-3-4-0-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Automate Arm Migration with Docker MCP Toolkit, VS Code, and GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a collaboration between Docker and Arm, demonstrating how Docker MCP Toolkit and the Arm MCP Server work together to simplify architecture migrations. Moving workloads from x86 to Arm64 architecture has become increasingly important. Organizations seek to reduce cloud costs and improve performance. AWS Graviton, Azure Cobalt, and Google Cloud Axion have made...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/automate-arm-migration-docker-mcp-copilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposed 1.0 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the first major release of Exposed – a huge milestone for both the project and the Exposed team! This release brings many new exciting features, the most requested being R2DBC support, as well as performance enhancements and bug fixes. Exposed 1.0 also introduces a stable API that guarantees no breaking changes until the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/exposed-1-0-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unrolling the Codex agent loop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A technical deep dive into the Codex agent loop, explaining how Codex CLI orchestrates models, tools, prompts, and performance using the Responses API.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/unrolling-the-codex-agent-loop 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Local Development and Cloud Evaluation: Using Microsoft Devtunnels with Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Picture this scenario: you&#39;ve implemented a critical fix in your AI service and want to validate it against your comprehensive evaluation dataset. However, the prospect of deploying to Azure for a quick test creates an unwelcome delay in your development cycle. This challenge is common among AI developers. When develo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/bridging-local-development-cloud-evaluation-devtunnels-azure-ml 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using MCP Servers: From Quick Tools to Multi-Agent Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers are a spec for exposing tools, models, or services to language models through a common interface. Think of them as smart adapters: they sit between a tool and the LLM, speaking a predictable protocol that lets the model interact with things like APIs, databases, and agents without needing to know...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-servers-docker-toolkit-cagent-gateway/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize Xamarin.Forms to .NET MAUI with AWS Transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Transform is an agentic service that accelerates modernization, including .NET applications. With it, you can transform legacy .NET applications to modern cross-platform .NET. AWS Transform can port your Xamarin.Forms mobile applications to .NET Multi-platform App UI (MAUI). In this post, I’ll show you how to transform your Xamarin.Forms projects to modern .NET MAUI. Why […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-xamarin-forms-to-net-maui-with-aws-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codex Is Now Integrated Into JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI Codex is now natively integrated into the JetBrains AI chat, giving you another powerful option for tackling real development tasks right inside your IDE. You can use Codex with a JetBrains AI subscription, your ChatGPT account, or an OpenAI API key – all within the same AI сhat interface.See Codex in action in a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/01/codex-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Azure Cosmos DB Agent Kit: Your AI Pair Programmer Just Got Smarter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure Cosmos DB Agent Kit is an open-source collection of skills that teaches your AI coding assistant (GitHub Copilot, Claude Code, Gemini CLI) expert-level Azure Cosmos DB best practices. Install with one command, get production-ready g
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-agent-kit-ai-coding-assistants 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PDI built an enterprise-grade RAG system for AI applications with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PDI Technologies is a global leader in the convenience retail and petroleum wholesale industries. In this post, we walk through the PDI Intelligence Query (PDIQ) process flow and architecture, focusing on the implementation details and the business outcomes it has helped PDI achieve.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-pdi-built-an-enterprise-grade-rag-system-for-ai-applications-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How CLICKFORCE accelerates data-driven advertising with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how CLICKFORCE used AWS services to build Lumos and transform advertising industry analysis from weeks-long manual work into an automated, one-hour process.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-clickforce-accelerates-data-driven-advertising-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple helper function for attaching a progress handler to a Windows Runtime IAsync­Action­With­Progress or IAsync­Operation­With­Progress</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Windows Runtime has interfaces IAsync­Action and IAsync­Operation which represent asynchronous activity: The function starts the work and returns immediately, and then it calls you back when the work completes. Most language projections allow you to treat these as coroutines, so you can await
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260122-00/?p=112005 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3.2 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released another update for v2025.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This version brings the following valuable refinements: To see the full list of issues addressed in this version, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/intellij-idea-2025-3-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Dependencies Don’t Care About Your FIPS Configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            FIPS compliance is a great idea that makes the entire software supply chain safer. But teams adopting FIPS-enabled container images are running into strange errors that can be challenging to debug. What they are learning is that correctness at the base image layer does not guarantee compatibility across the ecosystem. Change is complicated, and changing...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/fips-dependencies-and-prebuilt-binaries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 2026.1 Early Access Program Has Begun</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ReSharper 2026.1 Early Access Program is now open, and the first EAP build brings a mix of C# productivity improvements, new inspections, performance work, and expanded C++ language support. As always, EAP builds are an opportunity to try upcoming features early and help us refine them before the final release. Here’s what’s new in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/22/resharper-2026-1-early-access-program/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2026.1 Early Access Program Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for Rider 2026.1 has just begun, and the first preview build for the upcoming major release is already out. There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: A reminder of what the EAP is all about The Early Access Program is a long-standing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/22/rider-2026-1-early-access-program-start/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ROI of Developer Experience: How a Better CI/CD Tool Pays for Itself</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Cameron Pavey, draft.dev. Developer experience (DevEx) directly correlates with engineering performance, which in turn drives competitive advantage. And yet many software engineering teams continue to operate on legacy CI/CD platforms that create unnecessary friction, burn developer hours, and ultimately limit business growth. While some teams remain trapped by […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/the-roi-of-dev-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling PostgreSQL to power 800 million ChatGPT users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An inside look at how OpenAI scaled PostgreSQL to millions of queries per second using replicas, caching, rate limiting, and workload isolation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/scaling-postgresql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marten’s Aggregation Projection Subsystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Marten has very rich support for projecting events into read, write, or query models. While there are other capabilities as well, the most common usage is probably to aggregate related events into a singular view. Marten projections can be executed Live, meaning that Marten does the creation of the view by loading the target events … Continue reading Marten’s Aggregation Projection Subsystem →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2026/01/22/martens-aggregation-projection-subsystem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside Praktika&#39;s conversational approach to language learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How Praktika uses GPT-4.1 and GPT-5.2 to build adaptive AI tutors that personalize lessons, track progress, and help learners achieve real-world language fluency
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/praktika 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Thomson Reuters built an Agentic Platform Engineering Hub with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post explains how TR&#39;s Platform Engineering team, a geographically distributed unit overseeing TR&#39;s service availability, boosted its operational productivity by transitioning from manual to an automated agentic system using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-thomson-reuters-built-an-agentic-platform-engineering-hub-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build agents to learn from experiences using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore episodic memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through the complete architecture to structure and store episodes, discuss the reflection module, and share compelling benchmarks that demonstrate significant improvements in agent task success rates.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-agents-to-learn-from-experiences-using-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-episodic-memory/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now in Public Preview: GitHub Copilot build performance for Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last year, we launched our new GitHub Copilot build performance capabilities in Private Preview. With help from our fantastic C++ community, we gathered insights and addressed key feedback. We’re happy to share that GitHub Copilot build performance for Windows is now in Public Preview. Today, all C++ developers can try out the new capabiliti
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/now-in-public-preview-github-copilot-build-performance-for-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How bunq handles 97% of support with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how bunq upgraded Finn, its in-house generative AI assistant, using Amazon Bedrock to transform user support and banking operations to be seamless, in multiple languages and time zones.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-bunq-handles-97-of-support-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Strands Agents to create a multi-agent solution with Meta’s Llama 4 and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a multi-agent video processing workflow using Strands Agents, Meta&#39;s Llama 4 models, and Amazon Bedrock to automatically analyze and understand video content through specialized AI agents working in coordination. To showcase the solution, we will use Amazon SageMaker AI to walk you through the code.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-strands-agents-to-create-a-multi-agent-solution-with-metas-llama-4-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA Conf 2026: Learn From the People Building the JVM Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’re invited to IntelliJ IDEA Conf 2026 – a free online conference for developers working across the JVM ecosystem. Join us for two days of in-depth technical talks, practical insights, and conversations with experts who build and shape modern Java and Kotlin development. The conference will take place online on March 26–27, 2026, with sessions […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/intellij-idea-conf-2026-learn-from-the-people-building-the-jvm-ecosystem/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the proper usage of a custom Win32 dialog class</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I discussed custom dialog classes. You can specify that a dialog template use your custom dialog class by putting the custom class&#39;s name in the CLASS statement of the dialog template. A c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260121-00/?p=112002 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Up with Recent Wolverine Releases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine has had a very frequent release cadence the past couple months as community contributions, requests from JasperFx Software clients, and yes, sigh, bug reports have flowed in. Right now I think I can justifiably claim that Wolverine is innovating much faster than any of the other comparable tools in the .NET ecosystem. Some folks … Continue reading Catching Up with Recent Wolverine Releases →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2026/01/21/catching-up-with-recent-wolverine-releases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context-Driven Development: Agent Skills for Microsoft Foundry and Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code will be generated, not written. Working with 100+ companies, I have seen this firsthand: most enterprise workloads taking dependencies on AI SDKs are usually net-new microservices. Hardly anyone has Windows-scale codebases for their new AI features. This is modular, greenfield work. Perfect for coding agents. The catch? Out-of-the-box
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/context-driven-development-agent-skills-for-microsoft-foundry-and-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Higgsfield turns simple ideas into cinematic social videos</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Higgsfield gives creators cinematic, social-first video output from simple inputs using OpenAI GPT-4.1, GPT-5, and Sora 2.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/higgsfield 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How countries can end the capability overhang</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our latest report reveals stark differences in advanced AI adoption across countries and outlines new initiatives to help nations capture productivity gains from AI.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/how-countries-can-end-the-capability-overhang 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Edu for Countries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Edu for Countries is a new OpenAI initiative helping governments use AI to modernize education systems and build future-ready workforces.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/edu-for-countries 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure Performance Diagnostics Tool for Java: Automated Java Performance Analysis in Kubernetes via Azure SRE Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce that the Azure Performance Diagnostics Tool for Java is now available for preview as part of the Azure SRE Agent platform, bringing intelligent, automated Java performance diagnoses. Currently supporting Java workloads deployed to Azure Kubernetes S
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/introducing-azure-performance-diagnostics-tool-for-java-automated-java-performance-analysis-in-kubernetes-via-azure-sre-agent 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing multimodal retrieval for Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll guide you through building multimodal RAG applications. You&#39;ll learn how multimodal knowledge bases work, how to choose the right processing strategy based on your content type, and how to configure and implement multimodal retrieval using both the console and code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-multimodal-retrieval-for-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid Common Pitfalls With JPA and Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was written together with Thorben Janssen, who has more than 20 years of experience with JPA and Hibernate and is the author of “Hibernate Tips: More than 70 Solutions to Common Hibernate Problems” and the JPA newsletter. Kotlin and Jakarta Persistence (also known as JPA) are a popular combination for server-side development. Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/how-to-avoid-common-pitfalls-with-jpa-and-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2601.15 - new Intel plugin, many buffer viewer improvements, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2601.15, which can be downloaded here. This release includes everything in the previous 2509.25 release, plus: A new Intel plugin with many new featu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2601-15 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.6-1 and 1.24.12-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-6-1-and-1-24-12-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easier Query Models with Marten</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Marten community made our first big release of the new year with 8.18 this morning. I’m particularly happy with a couple significant things in this release: The one consistent theme in those points is that Marten just got a lot better for our users for creating “query models” in systems. Let’s Build a TeleHealth … Continue reading Easier Query Models with Marten →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2026/01/20/easier-query-models-with-marten/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: On fire, putting out fires</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Remember, Microspeak is not necessarily jargon exclusive to Microsoft, but it&#39;s jargon that you need to know if you work at Microsoft. When something has gone horribly wrong and requires immediate attention, one way to describe it is to say that it is on fire. The obvious metaphor here is that the situation is so severe that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260120-00/?p=111998 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerToys 0.97 is here: a big Command Palette update and a new mouse utility</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/powertoys-0-97-is-here-a-big-command-palette-update-and-a-new-mouse-utility 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco and OpenAI redefine enterprise engineering with AI agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco and OpenAI redefine enterprise engineering with Codex, an AI software agent embedded in workflows to speed builds, automate defect fixes, and enable AI-native development.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/cisco 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making foreach on an IEnumerable allocation-free using reflection and dynamic methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe why foreach sometimes allocates, and show how you can use DynamicMethod and Reflection.Emit to go allocation-free
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/making-foreach-on-an-ienumerable-allocation-free-using-reflection-and-dynamic-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in .NET 10 and C# 14: Fast Model Validation for APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 06:59:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 is officially out, along with C# 14. Microsoft has released .NET 10 as Long-Term Support (LTS) as a successor to .NET 8. Like every version, it is not just an update but brings something new to the table. In this series, we will explore which aspects of software
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/new-in-net-10-and-c-14-fast-model-validation-for-apis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow powers actionable enterprise AI with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ServiceNow expands access to OpenAI frontier models to power AI-driven enterprise workflows, summarization, search, and voice across the ServiceNow Platform.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/servicenow-powers-actionable-enterprise-ai-with-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code opinion: why I prefer avoiding the Async suffix in C# asynchronous methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Should every asynchronous method name end with Async? Does it bring more benefits or more downsides? Let’s reason about this habit, which is common among C# developers.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/code-opinion-async-suffix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our approach to age prediction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT is rolling out age prediction to estimate if accounts are under or over 18, applying safeguards for teens and refining accuracy over time.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/our-approach-to-age-prediction 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards additional field filters (private preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a limited private preview that introduces the ability to add additional fields as filters on both the backlog and Kanban boards. This feature has been a long-standing request from the developer com
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-boards-additional-field-filters-private-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.11.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The second bug-fix update for TeamCity On-Premises 2025.11 is ready to be installed! In this update, we have addressed a number of issues, such as: All TeamCity bug-fix updates include performance and security improvements, so we recommend that you never skip these minor updates. See TeamCity 2025.11.2 Release Notes for the complete list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/teamcity-2025-11-2-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What was the secret sauce that allows for a faster restart of Windows 95 if you hold the shift key?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Commenter Otul Osan wondered what was happening when the user held the Shift key when restarting Windows. Windows displays the message &amp;quot;Windows is restarting&amp;quot; rather than doing a full cold restart of the system.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260119-06/?p=111995 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieve method source file location at runtime using Portable PDBs in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When debugging or logging, you often need to know where a method is defined in your source code. While .NET provides caller information attributes like [CallerMemberName], [CallerFilePath], and [CallerLineNumber], these only work at compile-time and require you to add parameters to your methods. What if you want to retrieve source file information for any method at runtime? One use-case is…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/retrieve-method-source-file-location-at-runtime-using-portable-pdbs-in-dotnet.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platform Debugger Architecture Redesign for Remote Development in 2026.1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ Platform provides a powerful debugger framework that plugins can extend to support various programming languages and runtime environments. To enable remote development scenarios – where the IDE interface runs on your local machine while code executes on a remote server – we’ve redesigned the debugger architecture. This guide walks you through the changes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/01/platform-debugger-architecture-redesign-for-remote-development-in-2026-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🚀React Native Windows v0.81 is here!!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            App developers require performance, stability, and cross-platform consistency such as fast startups, smooth UI, and seamless code sharing across Windows, Android, and iOS as these factors directly impact user experience, development efficiency, and business outcomes. High performance and stability ensure apps run reliably and respond quickly,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/react-native/%f0%9f%9a%80react-native-windows-v0-81-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
