<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Data Ingestion Building Blocks (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building AI applications, context is key. AI models have a knowledge cutoff and do not have access to your personal or company data by default. To generate high-quality answers, AI apps need two things: Access to high-quality data The ability to surface the right information at the right time
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-data-ingestion-building-blocks-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio November Update – Visual Studio 2026, Cloud Agent Preview, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-november-update-visual-studio-2026-cloud-agent-preview-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why changing keyboard shortcuts in Visual Studio isn’t as simple as it seems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A straight look at what’s behind the keys We’ve all tried unlearning a keyboard shortcut - it feels like forgetting how to breathe. Muscle memory doesn’t mess around. We wrestle with this every time someone suggest a “quick” shortcut change. It’s not just editing a keybinding but navigating a history that makes Visual Stu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/why-changing-keyboard-shortcuts-in-visual-studio-isnt-as-simple-as-it-seems 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipe dreams to pipeline realities: an Aspire Pipelines story</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Liked this blog post? It was originally posted on Safia Abdalla&#39;s blog, https://blog.safia.rocks/, check out more content there! OK, sit down folks, because this one is gonna be a long one. This is the all-encompassing blog post about the thing I&#39;v
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspire-pipelines 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing the Docker MCP Catalog: Commit Pinning, Agentic Auditing, and Publisher Trust Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trust is the most important consideration when you connect AI assistants to real tools. While MCP containerization provides strong isolation and limits the blast radius of malfunctioning or compromised servers, we’re continuously strengthening trust and security across the Docker MCP solutions to further reduce exposure to malicious code. As the MCP ecosystem scales from hundreds...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/enhancing-mcp-trust-with-the-docker-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Us Anything During JetBrains AMA Week</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains will be hosting a series of open Ask Me Anything (AMA) sessions on Reddit December 9–12. On scheduled days, our product teams will join r/jetbrains to talk directly with developers who use our tools every day. We’ll be there for honest conversations about what’s working, what’s not, and where your priorities lie. Your feedback […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/03/ask-us-anything-during-jetbrains-ama-week/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How confessions can keep language models honest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI researchers are testing “confessions,” a method that trains models to admit when they make mistakes or act undesirably, helping improve AI honesty, transparency, and trust in model outputs.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/how-confessions-can-keep-language-models-honest 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Stories Of Developers Using JetBrains Rider to Create, Collaborate, and Have Fun</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago, we introduced a free non-commercial use license option for JetBrains Rider, hoping to remove barriers for developers who code with no financial objective in mind for their projects. Recently, we put out a call for your stories – curious to learn how you’ve been using Rider throughout this year. What came back […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/03/5-stories-of-developers-using-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the initial People-First AI Fund grantees</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The OpenAI Foundation announces the initial recipients of the People-First AI Fund, awarding $40.5M in unrestricted grants to 208 nonprofits supporting community innovation and opportunity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/people-first-ai-fund-grantees 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.5-1 and 1.24.11-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-5-1-and-1-24-11-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>⭐Upcoming Virtual Event⭐ AI Dev Days, Level-Up Your AI Skills with Microsoft Reactor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 03:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/ai-dev-days-december-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Interaction Changes Everything: Treating AI Agents as Collaborators, Not Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft Ignite 2025, I joined Amanda Silver (CVP, Apps &amp;amp; Agents + 1ES GM) and Karl Piteira (1ES PM lead) on stage to talk about Microsoft&#39;s transformation into an AI-driven engineering organization. The big narrative was about agents as partners in the development lifecycle, moving from tools that assist, to intell
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/the-interaction-changes-everything-treating-ai-agents-as-collaborators-not-automation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single File Test Suites in Dotnet Csharp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:16:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction One of my favorite new features in .NET 10 is C# file-based apps (or file-based C# programs if you prefer). With this feature, we can create individual .cs files and then run them using dotnet run &amp;lt;file.cs&amp;gt;. On Unix OSes you can go even further and mark the files as executable and include a shebang (#!) directive as the first line to tell the OS what to run it with and then you can run the files directly without even calling dotnet run.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DirectX Graphics Samples Updated to Agility SDK &#43; Enhanced Barriers examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share all DirectX Graphics Samples have been updated to use the latest DirectX 12 Agility SDK. What’s New: Agility SDK Integration: All samples now leverage the latest Agility SDK for improved compatibility and faster adoption of new DirectX capabilities. Enhanced Barrie
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directx-graphics-samples-updated-to-agility-sdk-enhanced-barriers-examples 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Sensitive Mobile Operations with Device-Bound Request Signing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mobile security goes beyond verifying user identity. If an attacker steals a valid token, how will your backend distinguish a legitimate request from one reproduced in an emulator or cloned environment? This is a gap in traditional authentication flows when applied to the mobile environment. By linking each request to hardware-backed keys g
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/securing-sensitive-mobile-operations-with-device-bound-request-signing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress on TypeScript 7 - December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this year, the TypeScript team announced that we&#39;ve been porting the compiler and language service to native code to take advantage of better raw performance, memory usage, and parallelism. This effort (codenamed &amp;quot;Project Corsa&amp;quot;, and soon &amp;quot;TypeScript 7.0&amp;quot;)
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/progress-on-typescript-7-december-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use cd - in Powershell 7 to Return to Previous Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:16:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction A command that many shells have had forever and that PowerShell has had for a long time as well is ‘cd -’ which means “change directory to previous folder”. This means you could do something like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6
cd c:\dev c:\dev cd c:\temp c:\temp cd - c:\dev
This is quite handy in many situations. In particular, since I’ve modified my PowerShell Profile to NOT start in my users folder but instead to start in my c:\dev folder (from which I can easily get to any repo I may be working from), I very often find myself using cd - whenever I create a new terminal in the folder I want to be in such as when using VS Code.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grok Models Come to the AI Chat in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re expanding our AI offering with xAI’s Grok family of LLMs: Grok 4, Grok 4.1 Fast, Grok 4.1 Fast (Non-Reasoning), and Grok Code Fast 1. With the addition of these models in the AI chat across all JetBrains IDEs, you now have even more flexibility to choose the model that best fits your workflow. How […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/grok-models-come-to-the-ai-chat-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tata Neu delivers personalized shopping experiences for millions of users with Azure DocumentDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Azure DocumentDB, Tata Neu delivers seamless authentication for millions of users, accelerates credit card onboarding across partners, unifies loyalty programs for hundreds of millions of members, and powers AI-driven support experiences across more than 60 brands.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/tata-neu-delivers-personalized-shopping-experiences-for-millions-of-users-with-azure-documentdb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiler Agent - Delegate the analysis, not the performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Visual Studio 2026 we introduced Copilot Profiler Agent, a new AI-powered assistant that helps
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/delegate-the-analysis-not-the-performance 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI agents shouldn’t be hard. According to theCUBE Research, Docker makes it easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For most developers, getting started with AI is still too complicated. Different models, tools, and platforms don’t always play nicely together. But with Docker, that’s changing fast. Docker is emerging as essential infrastructure for standardized, portable, and scalable AI environments. By bringing composability, simplicity, and GPU accessibility to the agentic era, Docker is helping developers...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-ai-agents-shouldnt-be-hard-according-to-thecube-research-docker-makes-it-easy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: Big rocks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recall that Microspeak is not merely for jargon exclusive to Microsoft, but it&#39;s jargon that you need to know to survive at Microsoft. The term big rocks was introduced by Stephen Covey in the book The Seven Habits of Highly Effective People, which I suspect is very popular among senior executives, because senior execu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251202-00/?p=111830 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip 2025.3: Migration From Consoles to Query Files, Connection to Cloud Providers, Introspection Levels for Amazon Redshift, and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2025.3, the final major update of the year, is here! Let’s take a look at what it has to offer. Download DataGrip 2025.3 Migration from query consoles to query files Previously, when referring to the SQL files that are attached to a data source by default, we used the term query console, and their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/02/datagrip-2025-3-migration-from-consoles-to-query-files-connection-to-cloud-providers-introspection-levels-for-amazon-redshift-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | December 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? Calling GC.Collect() explicitly forces the garbage collector to run and reclaim memory from unreachable objects. However, it’s generally discouraged to use this method in most applications because the garbage collector is highly optimized to run automatically. Forcing it can lead to performance issues by interrupting the normal optimization process. Welcome to dotInsights […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/02/dotinsights-december-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a custom MSBuild SDK to reduce boilerplate in .NET projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is part of The C# Advent Calendar 2025, a series of 50 posts about C#. Be sure to check out the rest of the blog posts in the calendar! Over the years, I&#39;ve relied on Meziantou.DotNet.CodingStandard, a NuGet package, to establish a consistent baseline across all my .NET projects. This approach includes style enforcement, essential analyzers, sensible build defaults, and additional tooling.…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/creating-a-custom-msbuild-sdk-to-reduce-boilerplate-in-dotnet-projects.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Achieve Significant Build Performance Gains With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is brought to you by Mdu Sibisi, draft.dev. Long build times interfere with developer momentum, disrupt flow states, and negatively impact productivity. While seemingly minor gaps in work rate may appear negligible in the moment, they quickly accumulate into significant increases in release cycle times and infrastructure costs. (There’s a reason high-performance development […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/build-performance-gains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent updates to NetEscapades.EnumGenerators: [EnumMember] support, analyzers, and bug fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe some recent changes to the NetEscapades.EnumGenerators source generator, including support for [EnumMember] and new analyzers
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/recent-updates-to-netescapaades-enumgenerators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering owned entities in EF Core: Cleaner complex types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:12:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not all data in your application should live as a standalone table with its own ID and lifecycle. Sometimes you need a tightly coupled dependent object that exists alongside its parent, like a movie&#39;s budget, a survey&#39;s questions, or a customer&#39;s address. If you
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/mastering-owned-entities-in-ef-core-cleaner-complex-types/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AppendSelected parameter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Background The Property parameter introd
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/entrapowershell/appendselected-parameter 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claude Code &#43; Microsoft Foundry: Enterprise AI Coding Agent Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 01:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide covers setting up Claude Code CLI and VS Code extension with Microsoft Foundry, configuring CLAUDE.md for project context, integrating Spec Kit for structured development, and running Claude Code in GitHub Actions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/claude-code-microsoft-foundry-enterprise-ai-coding-agent-setup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain-Driven Design Misconceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Domain-Driven Design misconceptions often come from treating DDD like a checklist of patterns. Have you ever looked into Domain-Driven Design and thought, “Wow, this is totally overkill”? Well, you’re not alone. And I kind of agree, but not for the reasons you might think. I say you’re not alone because of this meme I did… Read More »Domain-Driven Design Misconceptions The post Domain-Driven Design Misconceptions appeared first on CodeOpinion.
Link to article: https://codeopinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data API builder’s &#34;request-body-strict&#34; Simplifies Client Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data API builder (DAB) provides REST and GraphQL endpoints over SQL Server, Azure Cosmos DB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and SQL Data Warehouse.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/data-api-builder-request-body-strict 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Platform Age Verification in .NET MAUI Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you&#39;re building apps that need to comply with upcoming age verification requirements in Texas (January 1, 2026), Utah (May 7, 2026), or Louisiana (July 1, 2026), you might be wondering how to handle age verification across Android, iOS, and Windows. The good news? Each platform provides its own age verification APIs, and we&#39;ve put togeth
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/cross-platform-age-verification-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the OSS AI Summit: Building with LangChain Event</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            December 10, 2025 8 am - 10 am Pacific Registration: https://aka.ms/OSSAISummitRegistration
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/join-the-oss-ai-summit-building-with-langchain-event 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#34;Golden Triangle&#34; of Agentic Development with Microsoft Agent Framework: AG-UI, DevUI &amp; OpenTelemetry Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the explosive era of Agentic AI, we&#39;re not just seeking more powerful models—we&#39;re searching for a development experience that lets developers actually get some sleep. When building Agents locally, we&#39;ve traditionally faced three major challenges:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/the-golden-triangle-of-agentic-development-with-microsoft-agent-framework-ag-ui-devui-opentelemetry-deep-dive 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade MSVC, improve C&#43;&#43; build performance, and refactor C&#43;&#43; code with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2026 introduces new GitHub Copilot capabilities to support C++ developers in three development tasks:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/upgrade-msvc-improve-c-build-performance-and-refactor-c-code-with-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I get my edit control text to be autoselected when I choose it to be the default focus in my dialog?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer had a Win32 dialog with a bunch of edit controls inside. In their WM_INIT­DIALOG message handler, they filled those edit controls with information and then decided which one should get initial focus when the dialog is shown to the user. To set the focus, they did SetFocus(GetDlgItem(hDlg, initialCon
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251201-00/?p=111825 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcoming Babu Annamalai to JasperFx Software</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting today, Babu Annamalai is taking a larger role at JasperFx Software (LLC) to help expand our support coverage to just about every time zone on the planet. Babu is a long time member of the Marten and now Critter Stack core team. In addition to some large contributions like the Partial API in Marten … Continue reading Welcoming Babu Annamalai to JasperFx Software →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/12/01/welcoming-babu-annamalai-to-jasperfx-software/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Engineers Talk About Spring Boot 4, Life, and Other Stuff</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us as we welcome the Spring team and Evgeny Borisov for a new IntelliJ IDEA livestream, where we’ll discuss what’s new in Spring Boot 4 and how all the new updates work in IntelliJ IDEA. Date: December 11, 2025 Time: 4:00–5:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this livestream, we’ll explore […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/new-livestream-engineers-talk-about-spring-boot-4-life-and-other-stuff/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Through the Noise: Smarter Context Management for LLM-Powered Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you’re working on a project and jotting down every single idea, experiment, and failure. After a while, your notes pile up so high that finding what’s useful takes more time and energy than the work itself. A similar problem faces users of software engineering (SE) agents: the agents “take notes” on every generated output, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/12/efficient-context-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Embedding Models and Unlock Semantic Search with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Embeddings have become the backbone of many modern AI applications. From semantic search to retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) and intelligent recommendation systems, embedding models enable systems to understand the meaning behind text, code, or documents, not just the literal words. But generating embeddings comes with trade-offs. Using a hosted API for embedding generation often results in...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-embedding-models-for-semantic-search/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating AI Development with GitHub Copilot: Real-World Use-Cases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Written by Destiny Hillis (Software Engineer II), Rachel Johnson (Software Engineer II), Tempest van Schaik (Principal Data Scientist), and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/accelerating-ai-development-with-github-copilot-real-world-use-cases 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and NORAD team up to bring new magic to “NORAD Tracks Santa”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and NORAD are bringing new magic to “NORAD Tracks Santa” with three ChatGPT holiday tools that let families create festive elves, toy coloring pages, and custom Christmas stories.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/norad-holiday-collaboration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accenture and OpenAI accelerate enterprise AI success</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Accenture and OpenAI are collaborating to help enterprises bring agentic AI capabilities into the core of their business and unlock new levels of growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/accenture-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI takes an ownership stake in Thrive Holdings to accelerate enterprise AI adoption</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI takes an ownership stake in Thrive Holdings to accelerate enterprise AI adoption, embedding frontier research and engineering directly into accounting and IT services to boost speed, accuracy, and efficiency while creating a scalable model for industry-wide transformation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/thrive-holdings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Programming Rule #6: Verify Resource Availability (Before You Access It)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_11_2025/30_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_11_2025/30_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article emphasizes the importance of defensive programming in .NET applications by validating resource availability before access. It outlines guidelines for checking connectivity, setting timeouts, and managing user experiences when resources are unavailable. The author shares personal insights and promotes Spargine, an open-source project designed to enhance defensive programming practices.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/11/30/defensive-programming-rule-6-verify-resource-availability-before-you-access-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping AI From Going Off The Rails - Dev Leader Weekly 117</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2025/29_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 19:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2025/29_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss different approaches for keeping AI on track when writing code.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/29/keeping-ai-from-going-off-the-rails-dev-leader-weekly-117 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-11-29</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2025/29_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 09:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2025/29_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/29/weekly-recap-20251129 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Slice Architecture: Where Does the Shared Logic Live?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2025/29_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_11_2025/29_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deciding where shared logic lives is the most critical moment in Vertical Slice Architecture adoption, as choosing incorrectly reintroduces the coupling the architecture aims to eliminate. This article proposes a three-tier approach to sharing code that balances technical infrastructure, domain concepts, and local feature logic.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/vertical-slice-architecture-where-does-the-shared-logic-live 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2025: A Kotlin Playground</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us live for five days of Advent of Code puzzles and five Kotlin livestreams on December 1–5. Solve the puzzles in Kotlin with help from Kotlin team experts and fun community guests, climb the leaderboard, learn new tricks, and have a chance to win some prizes along the way! Here’s what we have planned […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/advent-of-code-in-kotlin-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I have a Win32 drop-down combo box with a read-only edit control?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was writing a Win32 program and was looking for something like a combo box, in that it gave the user a choice among various fixed options, but sometimes the program would come up with a new option that wasn&#39;t on the list, and it would want to show that as the selection. On the other hand, the customer didn&#39;t want to give the user
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251128-00/?p=111820 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Advent of Code in Rust, With Just Enough AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A year ago, I wrote a blog post about solving Advent of Code puzzles using Rust as the implementation language. I believe it’s still relevant if you plan to use Rust this year. In one section, I advised limiting the use of AI and demonstrated how to disable the relevant functionality in RustRover, either partially […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/11/28/solving-advent-of-code-in-rust-with-just-enough-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Release Candidate Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Release Candidate for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 is now available, and we’re closing the Early Access Program for this development cycle. Thank you to everyone who evaluated the EAP builds, shared feedback, and reported issues. Your input has been invaluable in shaping the upcoming release. When we opened the IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 EAP, we outlined […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-2025-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Want Microservices, But Do You Really Need Them?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you know who managed to cut costs by a staggering 90% by abandoning microservices for a monolith in May 2023? Not a cash-strapped startup or an indie project—Amazon itself, for its Prime Video service. The same AWS that earns billions every year by selling microservices infrastructure admitted that, sometimes, a good old monolith wins. ...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/do-you-really-need-microservices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing ASP.NET Core OData 10.0.0 Preview 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to announce the release of ASP.NET Core OData 10.0.0 Preview 1, a major modernization update that embraces .NET&#39;s native System.DateOnly and System.TimeOnly types! This release upgrades to .NET 10.0 and replaces OData&#39;s proprietary Edm.Date and Edm.TimeOfDay CL
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-asp-net-core-odata-10-0-0-preview-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message-only windows are for messaging, not as a convenient victim for hosting UI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to show a dialog box, but they didn&#39;t want it to be attached to any of their existing windows because it was a general dialog that applied to all of their windows. So they had a great idea: Their program already had a message-only window, so they figured, &amp;quot;Hey, I already have this garbage window I can use as the owner of s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251127-00/?p=111817 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Went to BazelCon 2025 – Here’s Everything You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, BazelCon was held at the Omni Atlanta Hotel at Centennial Park for a very special occasion: the tenth anniversary of Bazel 🎉 For me, visiting from Europe, Atlanta made quite the first impression. The city felt bigger than anything I’ve seen back home, and with KubeCon happening right next door, the streets were […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/11/bazelcon-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in TeamCity 2025.11: AI Assistant, New Pipeline Features, Enhanced Server Encryption Settings, and More.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity 2025.11 introduces new build steps for pipelines, enhanced encryption settings, and a refreshed experience that makes powerful CI/CD workflows easier to create and manage. Here’s what’s new in this release. Introducing AI Assistant (Early Access) TeamCity is a true powerhouse, but mastering every one of its features can be challenging. To help you get […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/11/teamcity-202511/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.3.0.3: A Fresh Set of Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another set of updates for the 2025.3 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.3.0.3 The most notable fix of this build is that extension methods from source-only NuGet packages are now recognized correctly in the editor and by InspectCode. [RSRP-502165]. You can find the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/27/resharper-and-rider-2025-3-0-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Could Simply Add Nullability Check Support… Without Even Noticing It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            (The Growing Pains of a Good Idea: What Happens After JSpecify Adoption Begins) The good news: JSpecify is finally here JSpecify adoption is accelerating. You don’t even need to “install” it – nullability support now arrives automatically with your dependencies. If you somehow missed the long history behind the JSpecify effort and want a quick […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/one-could-simply-add-nullability-check-support-without-even-noticing-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing GitHub Audit Log in Microsoft Defender</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 07:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;tip&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Tips&amp;quot;]In today’s rapidly evolving DevSecOps landscape, the need for real-time v
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/visualizing-github-audit-log-in-microsoft-defender 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform &#43; Azure Multi-Region Naming Convention across Azure Regions, Resources, and Terraform Modules</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine this: your application goes down in a major Azure region outage. DNS traffic shifts to the secondary region as designed. Terraform kicks off to scale the backup environment. Everything should just seamlessly work… but it doesn’t. Why? Because names don’t match. Storage accounts are globally unique. Key Vault names are different across regions. Resource […] The article Terraform + Azure Multi-Region Naming Convention across Azure Regions, Resources, and Terraform Modules was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Myriad Genetics achieved fast, accurate, and cost-efficient document processing using the AWS open-source Generative AI Intelligent Document Processing Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Myriad Genetics partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to transform their healthcare document processing pipeline using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Nova foundation models, achieving 98% classification accuracy while reducing costs by 77% and processing time by 80%. We detail the technical implementation using AWS&#39;s open-source GenAI Intelligent Document Processing Accelerator, the optimization strategies for document classification and key information extraction, and the measurable business impact on Myriad&#39;s prior authorization workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How CBRE powers unified property management search and digital assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, CBRE and AWS demonstrate how they transformed property management by building a unified search and digital assistant using Amazon Bedrock, enabling professionals to access millions of documents and multiple databases through natural language queries. The solution combines Amazon Nova Pro for SQL generation and Claude Haiku for document interactions, achieving a 67% reduction in processing time while maintaining enterprise-grade security across more than eight million documents.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managed Tiered KV Cache and Intelligent Routing for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce Managed Tiered KV Cache and Intelligent Routing for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod, new capabilities that can reduce time to first token by up to 40% and lower compute costs by up to 25% for long context prompts and multi-turn conversations. These features automatically manage distributed KV caching infrastructure and intelligent request routing, making it easier to deploy production-scale LLM inference workloads with enterprise-grade performance while significantly reducing operational overhead.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply fine-grained access control with Bedrock AgentCore Gateway interceptors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 22:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are launching a new feature: gateway interceptors for Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway. This powerful new capability provides fine-grained security, dynamic access control, and flexible schema management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/apply-fine-grained-access-control-with-bedrock-agentcore-gateway-interceptors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Condé Nast accelerated contract processing and rights analysis with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Condé Nast used Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude to accelerate their contract processing and rights analysis workstreams. The company’s extensive portfolio, spanning multiple brands and geographies, required managing an increasingly complex web of contracts, rights, and licensing agreements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-conde-nast-accelerated-contract-processing-and-rights-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI-Powered Voice Applications: Amazon Nova Sonic Telephony Integration Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Available through the Amazon Bedrock bidirectional streaming API, Amazon Nova Sonic can connect to your business data and external tools and can be integrated directly with telephony systems. This post will introduce sample implementations for the most common telephony scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-ai-powered-voice-applications-amazon-nova-sonic-telephony-integration-guide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of California Los Angeles delivers an immersive theater experience with AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will walk through the performance constraints and design choices by OARC and REMAP teams at UCLA, including how AWS serverless infrastructure, AWS Managed Services, and generative AI services supported the rapid design and deployment of our solution. We will also describe our use of Amazon SageMaker AI and how it can be used reliably in immersive live experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/university-of-california-los-angeles-delivers-an-immersive-theater-experience-with-aws-generative-ai-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Day on Agentic Modernization Coming Soon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on December 9, 2025 between 9AM-1PM Pacific for .NET Day of Agentic Modernization! This is a free, one-day virtual event focused on the latest tooling, techniques, and guidance for modernizing your .NET applications. Whether you&#39;re upgrading legacy code, preparing for cloud workloads,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-day-on-agentic-modernization-coming-soon 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Mobileye’s REM™ with AWS Graviton: A focus on ML inference and Triton integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus on one portion of the REM™ system: the automatic identification of changes to the road structure which we will refer to as Change Detection. We will share our journey of architecting and deploying a solution for Change Detection, the core of which is a deep learning model called CDNet. We will share real-life decisions and tradeoffs when building and deploying a high-scale, highly parallelized algorithmic pipeline based on a Deep Learning (DL) model, with an emphasis on efficiency and throughput.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate models with the Amazon Nova evaluation container using Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post introduces the new Amazon Nova model evaluation features in Amazon SageMaker AI. This release adds custom metrics support, LLM-based preference testing, log probability capture, metadata analysis, and multi-node scaling for large evaluations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-models-with-the-amazon-nova-evaluation-container-using-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the technology: Workforce changes for AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore three essential strategies for successfully integrating AI into your organization: addressing organizational debt before it compounds, embracing distributed decision-making through the &amp;quot;octopus organization&amp;quot; model, and redefining management roles to align with AI-powered workflows. Organizations must invest in both technology and workforce preparation, focusing on streamlining processes, empowering teams with autonomous decision-making within defined parameters, and evolving each management layer from traditional oversight to mentorship, quality assurance, and strategic vision-setting.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Scalable DynamoDB Counter Operations in .NET Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Web applications use counter operations to deliver interactive user experiences. Whether tracking social media engagement metrics or managing e-commerce inventory levels, these operations must be both reliable and scalable. This post walks you through two architectural patterns that deliver predictable performance. To illustrate these patterns, let us consider a social media application post-liking feature. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/implementing-scalable-dynamodb-counter-operations-in-net-application/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security that strengthens the ecosystem: Docker’s upstream approach to CVE-2025-12735</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 24, 2025, Docker Hardened Images resolved CVE-2025-12735 in the Kibana project, which is the visualization and user interface layer for Elasticsearch. This CVE is a critical remote code execution vulnerability that scored 9.8 on the CVSS scale. While images from other hardened image vendors were still carrying the vulnerability, Docker’s security team and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/security-that-strengthens-the-ecosystem-dockers-upstream-approach-to-cve-2025-12735/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced performance for Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now achieve significant performance improvements when using Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import, with reduced end-to-end latency, faster time-to-first-token, and improved throughput through advanced PyTorch compilation and CUDA graph optimizations. With Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import you can to bring your own foundation models to Amazon Bedrock for deployment and inference at scale. In this post, we introduce how to use the improvements in Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At what point in the Windows development cycle is it too late to change the text of a translatable string?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in 2009, I noted that the &amp;quot;Prevent windows from being automatically arranged when moved to the edge of the screen&amp;quot; check box is a dreaded
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251126-00/?p=111815 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Spring Data AOT in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring’s AOT engine has been around since the Spring Native days, but Spring Data never really benefited from it – until now. Repository infrastructure is one of the most dynamic parts of the framework, and for years it relied heavily on proxies, reflection, and queries generated at runtime. That flexibility has a price: it slows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/spring-data-aot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Too Much News to Keep Quiet About</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve gathered the latest Kotlin highlights for you – from the Kotlin Reddit AMA and documentation updates to learning programs and Google Summer of Code 2025 projects. Whether you’re here to stay up to date or just looking for something interesting to explore, there’s plenty to dive into. Where You Can Learn More YouTube Highlights
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/kodees-kotlin-roundup-november-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 2: A Deeper Dive Into Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous article, we saw how to build a basic coding agent with list, read, write, and edit capabilities. Today, we’ll dive into how to extend the agents’ capabilities by creating additional tools within the Koog framework. As an example, we’ll be building an ExecuteShellCommandTool, teaching our agent to run code and close the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-2-a-deeper-dive-into-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OData Model Builder 3.0.0 Preview 1 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce that OData Model Builder 3.0.0 Preview 1 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.OData.ModelBuilder 3.0.0 Preview 1 This is a major release that brings the libr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-odata-model-builder-3-0-0-preview-1-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker AI introduces EAGLE based adaptive speculative decoding to accelerate generative AI inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker AI now supports EAGLE-based adaptive speculative decoding, a technique that accelerates large language model inference by up to 2.5x while maintaining output quality. In this post, we explain how to use EAGLE 2 and EAGLE 3 speculative decoding in Amazon SageMaker AI, covering the solution architecture, optimization workflows using your own datasets or SageMaker&#39;s built-in data, and benchmark results demonstrating significant improvements in throughput and latency.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
