<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:12:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Local Models to Agent Workflows: Building a Deep Research Solution with Microsoft Agent Framework on Microsoft Foundry Local</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction: A New Paradigm for AI Application Development In enterprise AI application development, we often face this dilemma: while cloud-based large language models are powerful
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/from-local-models-to-agent-workflows-building-a-deep-research-solution-with-microsoft-agent-framework-on-microsoft-foundry-local 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Scholarships from the JetBrains Foundation – Applications Are Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The JetBrains Foundation is offering up to 40 full scholarships for the Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence BSc program at Neapolis University Pafos starting this year. Find the complete program details here. What’s New for 2026 These scholarships are comprehensive, covering tuition, accommodation, medical insurance, visa fees, and a monthly stipend (€300). Graduates of programs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2026/02/10/full-scholarships-from-the-jetbrains-foundation-applications-are-now-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing strongly-typed IDs in .NET for safer domain models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:44:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we know that user requests can be unpredictable. When they request data, it is either successfully returned or not found. However, a &amp;quot;not found&amp;quot; result usually happens in two ways. First, the user might request a record, such as a basketball player, by passing an ID
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/pimplementing-strongly-typed-ids-in-net-for-safer-domain-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: .NET Projects and the Tools Behind Them</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 07:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference – the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the people […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2026/02/10/open-source-in-focus-dotnet-projects-and-the-tools-behind-them/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot reference implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post dives deeper into the implementation architecture for the Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automated-reasoning-checks-rewriting-chatbot-reference-implementation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Travel in Azure SQL with Temporal Tables</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications often need to know what data looked like before. Who changed it, when it changed, and what the previous values were. Rebuilding that history in application code is tedious and error prone. This is especially valuable when exposing a database to an AI agent through MCP servers like SQL MCP Server, where information discovery mat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/time-travel-in-azure-sql-with-temporal-tables 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale LLM fine-tuning with Hugging Face and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how this integrated approach transforms enterprise LLM fine-tuning from a complex, resource-intensive challenge into a streamlined, scalable solution for achieving better model performance in domain-specific applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-llm-fine-tuning-with-hugging-face-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Relic transforms productivity with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Working with the Generative AI Innovation Center, New Relic NOVA (New Relic Omnipresence Virtual Assistant) evolved from a knowledge assistant into a comprehensive productivity engine. We explore the technical architecture, development journey, and key lessons learned in building an enterprise-grade AI solution that delivers measurable productivity gains at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-relic-transforms-productivity-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate agentic application development with a full-stack starter template for Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to deploy Fullstack AgentCore Solution Template (FAST) to your Amazon Web Services (AWS) account, understand its architecture, and see how to extend it for your requirements. You will learn how to build your own agent while FAST handles authentication, infrastructure as code (IaC), deployment pipelines, and service integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-agentic-application-development-with-a-full-stack-starter-template-for-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent-to-agent collaboration: Using Amazon Nova 2 Lite and Amazon Nova Act for multi-agent systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how agent-to-agent collaboration on Amazon Bedrock works in practice, using Amazon Nova 2 Lite for planning and Amazon Nova Act for browser interaction, to turn a fragile single-agent setup into a predictable multi-agent system.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/agent-to-agent-collaboration-using-amazon-nova-2-lite-and-amazon-nova-act-for-multi-agent-systems/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should I do if a wait call reports &lt;CODE&gt;WAIT_&lt;WBR&gt;ABANDONED&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you call a wait function like Wait­For­Single­Object and receive the code WAIT_ABANDONED, what does it mean and what should you do? The documentation says that WAIT_ABANDONED means that you successfully claimed a mutex, but the thread that previously owned the mutex failed t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260209-00/?p=112049 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:34:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Better late than never, as I’m writing this in early February 2026… First, here are a few links to past years in review:
My 2017 Year in Review My 2018 Year in Review My 2019 Year in Review My 2020 Year in Review My 2021 Year in Review My 2022 Year in Review My 2023 Year in Review My 2024 Year in Review My Year in Review Post Checklist
Now on to the various categories…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Service Discovery in C# with Needlr: How It Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Needlr&#39;s automatic service discovery works in C# with convention-based registration, type scanning, and the DoNotAutoRegister attribute for .NET applications.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/09/automatic-service-discovery-in-c-with-needlr-how-it-works 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting more information in MSBuild binlogs with property tracking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSBuild binary logs (binlogs) are a powerful tool for diagnosing build issues. If you&#39;re not familiar with binlogs, check out my post Exploring a MSBuild binary log using the binary log viewer to get started, or Stop using diagnostic verbosity in MSBuild to understand why binlogs are better than diagnostic verbosity. By default, binlogs capture a lot of information, but you can get even more details about…
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing ChatGPT to GenAI.mil</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI for Government announces the deployment of a custom ChatGPT on GenAI.mil, bringing secure, safety-forward AI to U.S. defense teams.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bringing-chatgpt-to-genaimil 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing ads in ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI begins testing ads in ChatGPT to support free access, with clear labeling, answer independence, strong privacy protections, and user control.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/testing-ads-in-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolate the swiyu Public Beta management APIs using YARP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at hardening the security for the swiyu public beta infrastructure. The generic containers provide both management APIs and wallet APIs which support the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations 1.0 specification. The management APIs require both network protection and application security. This post looks at implementing the network isolation. Code: https://github.com/swiss-ssi-group/swiyu-passkeys-idp-loi-loa Blogs in this […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2026/02/09/isolate-the-swiyu-public-beta-management-apis-using-yarp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over Optimism of Rewrites in Software Engineering - Dev Leader Weekly 126</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 17:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss rewrites, refactors, and the constant inaccurate optimism as developers.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/08/over-optimism-of-rewrites-in-software-engineering-dev-leader-weekly-126 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2026-02-08</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 17:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/08/weekly-recap-20260208 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Factory vs Factory Method Pattern in C#: Key Differences Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understand the differences between Abstract Factory and Factory Method patterns in C# with code examples, use cases, and guidance on when to use each pattern.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/08/abstract-factory-vs-factory-method-pattern-in-c-key-differences-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects with Spargine: Global Phone Number and Postal Code Validation Made Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_02_2026/08_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CountryPhonePostalInfoRepository provides an efficient solution for validating phone numbers and postal codes globally, addressing the complexities of varying formats and rules. It offers a centralized API for reliable country-specific validation, enhancing data integrity in applications while simplifying maintenance and development. This tool ensures accurate, consistent validation logic.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/02/08/boost-your-net-projects-with-spargine-global-phone-number-and-postal-code-validation-made-easy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source Generation vs Reflection in Needlr: Choosing the Right Approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2026/07_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2026/07_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compare Needlr&#39;s source generation and reflection strategies for dependency injection in C# to choose the right approach for AOT, performance, and flexibility.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/07/source-generation-vs-reflection-in-needlr-choosing-the-right-approach 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering User Settings in SharePoint Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2026/07_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 01:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_02_2026/07_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            User preferences and settings are fundamental components of modern web applications. When developing SharePoint Framework (SPFx) solutions, the ability to store and manage user-specific configurations across devices and sessions becomes crucial for delivering personalized experiences. This article explores a robust, enterprise-ready pattern fo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/mastering-user-settings-in-sharepoint-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (Nov 2025 - Jan 2026)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 21:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.12.12 and 2026.01.16 registry releases and the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-nov-2025-jan-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured outputs on Amazon Bedrock: Schema-compliant AI responses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re announcing structured outputs on Amazon Bedrock—a capability that fundamentally transforms how you can obtain validated JSON responses from foundation models through constrained decoding for schema compliance. In this post, we explore the challenges of traditional JSON generation and how structured outputs solves them. We cover the two core mechanisms—JSON Schema output format and strict tool use—along with implementation details, best practices, and practical code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Amazon SageMaker HyperPod clusters using the HyperPod CLI and SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use the CLI and the SDK to create and manage SageMaker HyperPod clusters in your AWS account. We walk through a practical example and dive deeper into the user workflow and parameter choices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-clusters-using-the-hyperpod-cli-and-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI Skills Executor in .NET: Bringing Anthropic&#39;s Agent Pattern to the Microsoft Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When Anthropic released their Agent Skills framework, they published a blueprint for how enterprise organizations should structure AI agent capabilities. The pattern is straightforward: package procedural knowledge into composable skills that AI agents can discover and apply contextually. Microsoft, OpenAI, Cursor, and others have already adop
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/dotnet-ai-skills-executor-azure-openai-mcp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate generative AI models with an Amazon Nova rubric-based LLM judge on Amazon SageMaker AI (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the Amazon Nova rubric-based judge feature: what a rubric-based judge is, how the judge is trained, what metrics to consider, and how to calibrate the judge. We chare notebook code of the Amazon Nova rubric-based LLM-as-a-judge methodology to evaluate and compare the outputs of two different LLMs using SageMaker training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-generative-ai-models-with-an-amazon-nova-rubric-based-llm-judge-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masking Sensitive Data in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applications often need access to data without needing access to everything. Social Security numbers, email addresses, and phone numbers are common examples. Storing them is required. Exposing them broadly is not. This is especially valuable when exposing a database to an AI agent through MCP servers like SQL MCP Server, where safety and re
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/mask-data-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I prevent the user from changing the widths of ListView columns in version 5 of the common controls?, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we had figured out how to prevent the version 5 ListView Win32 common control from resizing columns, but we noticed that the cursor st
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260206-00/?p=112045 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Factory Design Pattern in C#: Complete Guide with Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Master the Abstract Factory design pattern in C# with complete code examples, real-world scenarios, and practical implementation guidance for creating families of related objects.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/06/abstract-factory-design-pattern-in-c-complete-guide-with-examples 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Korea privacy policy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Korea privacy policy
Link to article: https://openai.com/policies/kr-privacy-policy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making AI work for everyone, everywhere: our approach to localization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI shares its approach to AI localization, showing how globally shared frontier models can be adapted to local languages, laws, and cultures without compromising safety.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/our-approach-to-localization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Soft Delete in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sometimes applications need to remove data without actually losing it. Soft delete keeps rows in the database while making them invisible to normal application access. This is especially valuable when exposing a database to an AI agent through MCP servers like SQL MCP Server, where safety and reversibility matter. Lea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/soft-delete-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Keycloak with ASP.NET Core Using OAuth 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to integrate Keycloak with your .NET 10 API using Docker, Swagger UI with OAuth 2.0 Authorization Code flow, and JWT validation.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/integrate-keycloak-with-aspnetcore-using-oauth-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Associa transforms document classification with the GenAI IDP Accelerator and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Associa collaborated with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to build a generative AI-powered document classification system aligning with Associa’s long-term vision of using generative AI to achieve operational efficiencies in document management. The solution automatically categorizes incoming documents with high accuracy, processes documents efficiently, and provides substantial cost savings while maintaining operational excellence. The document classification system, developed using the Generative AI Intelligent Document Processing (GenAI IDP) Accelerator, is designed to integrate seamlessly into existing workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practical guide to Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to configure and use Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings for media asset search systems, product discovery experiences, and document retrieval applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-practical-guide-to-amazon-nova-multimodal-embeddings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Aspire Apps with Microsoft Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;About the Author&amp;quot;]This is a guest post from Jean-Marc Prieur from Microsoft&#39;s 1ES (One Engineering System) team. We help reduce developer toil across Microsoft by making it easy to build services that are secure and compliant from the start, for instance with Aspire and Entra ID.[/alert] TL;D
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/securing-dotnet-aspire-apps-with-microsoft-entra-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Framework 3.5 Moves to Standalone Deployment in new versions of Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The deployment model of .NET Framework 3.5 for future versions of Windows is changing. Starting with Windows 11 Insider Preview Build 27965, .NET Framework 3.5 must be obtained as a standalone installer and is no longer included as an optional Windows component. .NET Framework 3.5 is now available as a standalone installer for legacy
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-framework-3-5-moves-to-standalone-deployment-in-new-versions-of-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.7-1 and 1.24.13-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-7-1-and-1-24-13-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Enable Microsoft Entra ID for Azure Cosmos DB (NoSQL)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Strengthen Identity Security and Eliminate Account Keys Identity is becoming the new security perimeter. As organizations modernize their cloud applications, long‑lived secrets and shared keys introduce unnecessary risk. Azure Cosmos DB now fully supports Microsoft Entra ID for both control plane and data plane access, giving custo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/how-to-enable-microsoft-entra-id-for-azure-cosmos-db-nosql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I prevent the user from changing the widths of ListView columns in version 5 of the common controls?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we saw how to prevent the user from changing the widths of ListView columns, but the technique required version 6 of the common controls. What if you&#39;re stuck in the dark
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260205-00/?p=112042 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a .NET Log Analysis System using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Log analysis helps you maintain reliable applications by identifying issues, troubleshooting problems, and gaining operational insights. Traditional log analysis struggles with unstructured data and requires hours of manual work to extract meaningful patterns. Generative AI transforms this process by automatically identifying anomalies, understanding context, and surfacing specific recommendations without complex configuration. In this post, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/building-a-net-log-analysis-system-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending Qodana: Adding Custom Code Inspections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Qodana is a static code analysis tool that brings code inspections and quick-fixes from JetBrains IDEs to the realm of continuous integration. It can be run in the cloud, executed from a Docker container, integrated into CI/CD pipelines, or invoked through a JetBrains IDE. Qodana already offers an impressive suite of inspections, but it is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/02/extending-qodana-adding-custom-code-inspections/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Needlr: Fluent DI for .NET Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to install and configure Needlr for dependency injection in .NET with step-by-step setup, NuGet packages, and your first fluent DI application.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/05/getting-started-with-needlr-fluent-di-for-net-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 lowers the cost of cell-free protein synthesis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            An autonomous lab combining OpenAI’s GPT-5 with Ginkgo Bioworks’ cloud automation cut cell-free protein synthesis costs by 40% through closed-loop experimentation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-lowers-protein-synthesis-cost 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Trusted Access for Cyber</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces Trusted Access for Cyber, a trust-based framework that expands access to frontier cyber capabilities while strengthening safeguards against misuse.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/trusted-access-for-cyber 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – February 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            February is a strange little month. Short, quiet, and typically uneventful. There are fewer distractions and fewer launches, which makes it the ideal time to slow down and take a look at what is actually driving the tech world at the moment. This issue leans into that calm, with Trisha Gee joining us as our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/02/java-annotated-monthly-february-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal GitOps for Edge Applications with Azure IoT Operations and Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Building and operating edge applications is a team sport, especially when you&#39;re working with Azure IoT Operations (AIO), custom Rust services, and a mix of cloud and on-prem environments. Over the past year, our team set out to create a minimal GitOps workflow that&#39;s simple enough for small pilots, but
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/minimal-gitops-for-edge-applications-with-azdo 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing OpenAI Frontier</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI Frontier is an enterprise platform for building, deploying, and managing AI agents with shared context, onboarding, permissions, and governance.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-openai-frontier 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5.3-Codex System Card</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT‑5.3-Codex is the most capable agentic coding model to date, combining the frontier coding performance of GPT‑5.2-Codex with the reasoning and professional knowledge capabilities of GPT‑5.2.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-3-codex-system-card 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5.3-Codex</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.3-Codex is a Codex-native agent that pairs frontier coding performance with general reasoning to support long-horizon, real-world technical work.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-3-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating health questions with ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A family shares how ChatGPT helped them prepare for critical cancer treatment decisions for their son alongside expert guidance from his doctors.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/navigating-health-questions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Home for Multi-Agent Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VS Code has become the unified interface for all your coding agents. Manage local, background, and cloud agents in one place, use Claude and Codex agents alongside Copilot, and benefit from open standards like MCP and Agent Skills. Read the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/your-home-for-multi-agent-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows MIDI Services rollout - known issues and workarounds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 21:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There&#39;s a larger blog post with the features and benefits of Windows MIDI Services coming later this month (February 2026). This is just a quick post here to assist users with known issues or workarounds, in the interest of remaining transparent on this project. We performed a ton of testing with customers, partners, and our own equ
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/windows-midi-services-rollout-known-issues-and-workarounds 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for AI in Visual Studio (February)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After a busy January (catch up here), we&#39;re shifting focus to reliability and refinement. This month is about
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/roadmap-for-ai-in-visual-studio-february 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-install `azd` extensions in dev containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Auto-install azd extensions in dev containers Welcome to the first azd mini blog! Things move fast - new features ship, and it&#39;s easy to miss something useful. These short posts (1-minute reads, we promise) highlight features the team ships that you want to know about. No fluff, just what it is, why it m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azd-devcontainer-extensions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSVC Build Tools Versions 14.30 – 14.43 Now Available in Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When Visual Studio 2026 reached General Availability in November, it included several versions of the Microsoft C++ (MSVC) Build Tools: 14.50 (initially shipped with Visual Studio 2026) 14.44 (initially
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/msvc-build-tools-versions-14-30-14-43-now-available-in-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards integration with GitHub Copilot includes custom agent support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released the GitHub Copilot Coding Agent for Azure Boards to all customers. If you’re not already familiar with it, we recommend taking a few minutes to read this blog post for an overview and details. One of the top requests from cust
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-boards-integration-with-github-copilot-includes-custom-agent-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WinGet Configuration: Set up your dev machine in one command</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve set up a lot of dev machines in my life. Traditionally, this takes a lot of time to get everything just right, but now there&#39;s a faster way with WinGet Configuration files. Let me show you how to go from a fresh Windows install to a fully configured
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/winget-configuration-set-up-your-dev-machine-in-one-command 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2026 (version 1.109)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code January 2026 Release (1.109). Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/january-2026-(version-1.109) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2026 Insiders (version 1.109)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code January 2026 Release (1.109). Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/external-blogs/january-2026-insiders-version-1-109 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating your marketing ideation with generative AI – Part 2: Generate custom marketing images from historical references</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building upon our earlier work of marketing campaign image generation using Amazon Nova foundation models, in this post, we demonstrate how to enhance image generation by learning from previous marketing campaigns. We explore how to integrate Amazon Bedrock, AWS Lambda, and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless to create an advanced image generation system that uses reference campaigns to maintain brand guidelines, deliver consistent content, and enhance the effectiveness and efficiency of new campaign creation.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OS for Intelligence: How GitHub Bridges the Fragmented AI Landscape</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are currently living through the &amp;quot;fragmentation phase&amp;quot; of the AI revolution. If you’re a developer, you know the drill: You have
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/the-os-for-intelligence-how-github-bridges-the-fragmented-ai-landscape 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Bowl LX creates an opportunity for symphonic friendly wagering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This upcoming Sunday is Super Bowl LX, the championship game of the top professional American football league. The Super Bowl thinks that it is so important that it uses Roman numerals.) The Super Bowl is the single largest sporting event in the United States.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260204-01/?p=112039 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Idempotent Code Is Lying To You</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You have some code that handles placing an order. This could be an HTTP API or a message handler. You made it idempotent. You added a unique constraint on some kind of message ID. And somehow… you still end up double charging the customer’s credit card. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds… Read More »Your Idempotent Code Is Lying To You The post Your Idempotent Code Is Lying To You appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started with the Atlassian Rovo MCP Server Using Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that the remote Atlassian Rovo MCP server is now available in Docker’s MCP Catalog and Toolkit, making it easier than ever to connect AI assistants to Jira and Confluence. With just a few clicks, technical teams can use their favorite AI agents to create and update Jira issues, epics, and Confluence...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/atlassian-remote-mcp-server-getting-started-with-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These Junior Developers SUCK! They Just Don&#39;t Understand My Code!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When junior developers struggle with code reviews, the solution isn&#39;t to avoid them—it&#39;s to invest in their growth. Learn how to slow down to speed up by building your team&#39;s skills.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/04/these-junior-developers-suck-they-just-dont-understand-my-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Codex harness: how we built the App Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to embed the Codex agent using the Codex App Server, a bidirectional JSON-RPC API powering streaming progress, tool use, approvals, and diffs.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/unlocking-the-codex-harness 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced AI Management and Analytics for Organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re introducing the JetBrains Console, which provides enhanced AI management and analytics for organizations, including new capabilities to manage, observe, and control AI usage and costs across teams. AI is no longer an experiment for most development teams. It’s becoming part of the core toolchain. As usage increases, so does the need for clarity. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/02/enhanced-ai-management-and-analytics-for-organizations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wayland By Default in 2026.1 EAP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting from version 2026.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will run natively on Wayland in supported desktop configurations. This follows Wayland’s ascendance to the position of primary display server across contemporary Linux distributions. By making this change in our EAP releases first, we hope to be able to give more Linux users the opportunity to try the native […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/02/wayland-by-default-in-2026-1-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3Cs: A Framework for AI Agent Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every time execution models change, security frameworks need to change with them. Agents force the next shift. The Unattended Laptop Problem No developer would leave their laptop unattended and unlocked. The risk is obvious. A developer laptop has root-level access to production systems, repositories, databases, credentials, and APIs. If someone sat down and started using...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/the-3cs-a-framework-for-ai-agent-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VfL Wolfsburg turns ChatGPT into a club-wide capability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By focusing on people, not pilots, the Bundesliga club is scaling efficiency, creativity, and knowledge—without losing its football identity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/vfl-wolfsburg 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratizing business intelligence: BGL’s journey with Claude Agent SDK and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BGL is a leading provider of self-managed superannuation fund (SMSF) administration solutions that help individuals manage the complex compliance and reporting of their own or a client’s retirement savings, serving over 12,700 businesses across 15 countries. In this blog post, we explore how BGL built its production-ready AI agent using Claude Agent SDK and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/democratizing-business-intelligence-bgls-journey-with-claude-agent-sdk-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Quick Suite custom action connectors to upload text files to Google Drive using OpenAPI specification</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a secure file upload solution by integrating Google Drive with Amazon Quick Suite custom connectors using Amazon API Gateway and AWS Lambda.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-quick-suite-custom-action-connectors-to-upload-text-files-to-google-drive-using-openapi-specification/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI agents in enterprises: Best practices with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores nine essential best practices for building enterprise AI agents using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore. Amazon Bedrock AgentCore is an agentic platform that provides the services you need to create, deploy, and manage AI agents at scale. In this post, we cover everything from initial scoping to organizational scaling, with practical guidance that you can apply immediately.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-agents-in-enterprises-best-practices-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation notice: Teams Live Events meeting creation via Microsoft Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re announcing an important change for developers using Microsoft Graph APIs to create Teams Live Events. Starting March 31, 2026, the beta endpoint will no longer support the isBroadcast property of the on
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-notice-teams-live-events-meeting-creation-via-microsoft-graph 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI for healthcare data analysis with Amazon SageMaker Data Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 21, 2025, Amazon SageMaker introduced a built-in data agent within Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio that transforms large-scale data analysis. In this post, we demonstrate, through a detailed case study of an epidemiologist conducting clinical cohort analysis, how SageMaker Data Agent can help reduce weeks of data preparation into days, and days of analysis development into hours—ultimately accelerating the path from clinical questions to research conclusions.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Building a Python CRUD API with Azure Functions and Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Series: Building Serverless Applications with Azure Functions and Azure Cosmos DB In the first post of this series, we focused on establishing the fundamentals of serverless architectur
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/part-2-building-a-python-crud-api-with-azure-functions-and-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance improvements to MEF-based editor productivity extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you use editor productivity extensions for Visual Studio 2026, there&#39;s good news—they can now load faster! Extension developers with existing MEF-based editor productivity extensions should read this blog to learn about recent changes and how they might be affected.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/performance-improvements-to-mef-based-editor-productivity-extensions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some small stories about the giant satellite dish antenna that was behind Microsoft Building 11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in the day, if you wandered into the parking area behind Building 11 on the original Redmond Microsoft campus, you would find a very large satellite dish antenna. This antenna was used for receiving video signals, such as cable television feeds for distribution to the Redmond campus. One purpose was to provide cable TV service for inte
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260203-00/?p=112035 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Dependency Injection in C#: The Complete Guide to Needlr</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Needlr simplifies dependency injection in C# with automatic service discovery, source generation, and a fluent API for .NET applications.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/03/automatic-dependency-injection-in-c-the-complete-guide-to-needlr 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the (underwhelming) System.Diagnostics.Metrics source generators: System.Diagnostics.Metrics APIs - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I explore the source generators shipped in Microsoft.Extensions.Telemetry.Abstractions, explore the code, and discuss whether I would use them
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-strongly-typed-metics-with-a-source-generator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pick Your KotlinConf Workshop by What You Want to Learn</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi! Already coming to KotlinConf in Munich? Kick off the conference with a full day of hands-on workshops on May 20. Not going yet? Then this is a good moment to get your KotlinConf ticket and start with a workshop that matches what you want to learn. Asynchronous programming with Kotlin coroutines Learn how to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/02/pick-your-kotlinconf-workshop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sora feed philosophy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the Sora feed philosophy—built to spark creativity, foster connections, and keep experiences safe with personalized recommendations, parental controls, and strong guardrails.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/sora-feed-philosophy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
