<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:32:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Terraform &#43; Azure Multi-Region Naming Convention across Azure Regions, Resources, and Terraform Modules</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine this: your application goes down in a major Azure region outage. DNS traffic shifts to the secondary region as designed. Terraform kicks off to scale the backup environment. Everything should just seamlessly work… but it doesn’t. Why? Because names don’t match. Storage accounts are globally unique. Key Vault names are different across regions. Resource […] The article Terraform + Azure Multi-Region Naming Convention across Azure Regions, Resources, and Terraform Modules was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Myriad Genetics achieved fast, accurate, and cost-efficient document processing using the AWS open-source Generative AI Intelligent Document Processing Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Myriad Genetics partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to transform their healthcare document processing pipeline using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Nova foundation models, achieving 98% classification accuracy while reducing costs by 77% and processing time by 80%. We detail the technical implementation using AWS&#39;s open-source GenAI Intelligent Document Processing Accelerator, the optimization strategies for document classification and key information extraction, and the measurable business impact on Myriad&#39;s prior authorization workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How CBRE powers unified property management search and digital assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, CBRE and AWS demonstrate how they transformed property management by building a unified search and digital assistant using Amazon Bedrock, enabling professionals to access millions of documents and multiple databases through natural language queries. The solution combines Amazon Nova Pro for SQL generation and Claude Haiku for document interactions, achieving a 67% reduction in processing time while maintaining enterprise-grade security across more than eight million documents.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managed Tiered KV Cache and Intelligent Routing for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_11_2025/27_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce Managed Tiered KV Cache and Intelligent Routing for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod, new capabilities that can reduce time to first token by up to 40% and lower compute costs by up to 25% for long context prompts and multi-turn conversations. These features automatically manage distributed KV caching infrastructure and intelligent request routing, making it easier to deploy production-scale LLM inference workloads with enterprise-grade performance while significantly reducing operational overhead.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply fine-grained access control with Bedrock AgentCore Gateway interceptors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 22:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are launching a new feature: gateway interceptors for Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway. This powerful new capability provides fine-grained security, dynamic access control, and flexible schema management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/apply-fine-grained-access-control-with-bedrock-agentcore-gateway-interceptors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Condé Nast accelerated contract processing and rights analysis with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Condé Nast used Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude to accelerate their contract processing and rights analysis workstreams. The company’s extensive portfolio, spanning multiple brands and geographies, required managing an increasingly complex web of contracts, rights, and licensing agreements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-conde-nast-accelerated-contract-processing-and-rights-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI-Powered Voice Applications: Amazon Nova Sonic Telephony Integration Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Available through the Amazon Bedrock bidirectional streaming API, Amazon Nova Sonic can connect to your business data and external tools and can be integrated directly with telephony systems. This post will introduce sample implementations for the most common telephony scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-ai-powered-voice-applications-amazon-nova-sonic-telephony-integration-guide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of California Los Angeles delivers an immersive theater experience with AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will walk through the performance constraints and design choices by OARC and REMAP teams at UCLA, including how AWS serverless infrastructure, AWS Managed Services, and generative AI services supported the rapid design and deployment of our solution. We will also describe our use of Amazon SageMaker AI and how it can be used reliably in immersive live experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/university-of-california-los-angeles-delivers-an-immersive-theater-experience-with-aws-generative-ai-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Day on Agentic Modernization Coming Soon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on December 9, 2025 between 9AM-1PM Pacific for .NET Day of Agentic Modernization! This is a free, one-day virtual event focused on the latest tooling, techniques, and guidance for modernizing your .NET applications. Whether you&#39;re upgrading legacy code, preparing for cloud workloads,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-day-on-agentic-modernization-coming-soon 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Mobileye’s REM™ with AWS Graviton: A focus on ML inference and Triton integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus on one portion of the REM™ system: the automatic identification of changes to the road structure which we will refer to as Change Detection. We will share our journey of architecting and deploying a solution for Change Detection, the core of which is a deep learning model called CDNet. We will share real-life decisions and tradeoffs when building and deploying a high-scale, highly parallelized algorithmic pipeline based on a Deep Learning (DL) model, with an emphasis on efficiency and throughput.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate models with the Amazon Nova evaluation container using Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post introduces the new Amazon Nova model evaluation features in Amazon SageMaker AI. This release adds custom metrics support, LLM-based preference testing, log probability capture, metadata analysis, and multi-node scaling for large evaluations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-models-with-the-amazon-nova-evaluation-container-using-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the technology: Workforce changes for AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore three essential strategies for successfully integrating AI into your organization: addressing organizational debt before it compounds, embracing distributed decision-making through the &amp;quot;octopus organization&amp;quot; model, and redefining management roles to align with AI-powered workflows. Organizations must invest in both technology and workforce preparation, focusing on streamlining processes, empowering teams with autonomous decision-making within defined parameters, and evolving each management layer from traditional oversight to mentorship, quality assurance, and strategic vision-setting.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Scalable DynamoDB Counter Operations in .NET Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Web applications use counter operations to deliver interactive user experiences. Whether tracking social media engagement metrics or managing e-commerce inventory levels, these operations must be both reliable and scalable. This post walks you through two architectural patterns that deliver predictable performance. To illustrate these patterns, let us consider a social media application post-liking feature. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/implementing-scalable-dynamodb-counter-operations-in-net-application/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security that strengthens the ecosystem: Docker’s upstream approach to CVE-2025-12735</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 24, 2025, Docker Hardened Images resolved CVE-2025-12735 in the Kibana project, which is the visualization and user interface layer for Elasticsearch. This CVE is a critical remote code execution vulnerability that scored 9.8 on the CVSS scale. While images from other hardened image vendors were still carrying the vulnerability, Docker’s security team and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/security-that-strengthens-the-ecosystem-dockers-upstream-approach-to-cve-2025-12735/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced performance for Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now achieve significant performance improvements when using Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import, with reduced end-to-end latency, faster time-to-first-token, and improved throughput through advanced PyTorch compilation and CUDA graph optimizations. With Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import you can to bring your own foundation models to Amazon Bedrock for deployment and inference at scale. In this post, we introduce how to use the improvements in Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At what point in the Windows development cycle is it too late to change the text of a translatable string?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in 2009, I noted that the &amp;quot;Prevent windows from being automatically arranged when moved to the edge of the screen&amp;quot; check box is a dreaded
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251126-00/?p=111815 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Spring Data AOT in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring’s AOT engine has been around since the Spring Native days, but Spring Data never really benefited from it – until now. Repository infrastructure is one of the most dynamic parts of the framework, and for years it relied heavily on proxies, reflection, and queries generated at runtime. That flexibility has a price: it slows […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/spring-data-aot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: Too Much News to Keep Quiet About</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve gathered the latest Kotlin highlights for you – from the Kotlin Reddit AMA and documentation updates to learning programs and Google Summer of Code 2025 projects. Whether you’re here to stay up to date or just looking for something interesting to explore, there’s plenty to dive into. Where You Can Learn More YouTube Highlights
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/kodees-kotlin-roundup-november-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 2: A Deeper Dive Into Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous article, we saw how to build a basic coding agent with list, read, write, and edit capabilities. Today, we’ll dive into how to extend the agents’ capabilities by creating additional tools within the Koog framework. As an example, we’ll be building an ExecuteShellCommandTool, teaching our agent to run code and close the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-2-a-deeper-dive-into-tools/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OData Model Builder 3.0.0 Preview 1 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce that OData Model Builder 3.0.0 Preview 1 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.OData.ModelBuilder 3.0.0 Preview 1 This is a major release that brings the libr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-odata-model-builder-3-0-0-preview-1-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker AI introduces EAGLE based adaptive speculative decoding to accelerate generative AI inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker AI now supports EAGLE-based adaptive speculative decoding, a technique that accelerates large language model inference by up to 2.5x while maintaining output quality. In this post, we explain how to use EAGLE 2 and EAGLE 3 speculative decoding in Amazon SageMaker AI, covering the solution architecture, optimization workflows using your own datasets or SageMaker&#39;s built-in data, and benchmark results demonstrating significant improvements in throughput and latency.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (November 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-november-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Containers the Easy Way: Copilot &#43; VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing containers can be one of the most repetitive parts of modern development. Between remembering CLI commands, switching contexts, and digging through logs, it’s easy to lose focus on the actual code you’re building. The latest release of the VS Code Container Tools extension changes that by putting Copilot directly
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/manage-containers-the-easy-way-copilot-vs-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train custom computer vision defect detection model using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to migrate computer vision workloads from Amazon Lookout for Vision to Amazon SageMaker AI by training custom defect detection models using pre-trained models available on AWS Marketplace. We provide step-by-step guidance on labeling datasets with SageMaker Ground Truth, training models with flexible hyperparameter configurations, and deploying them for real-time or batch inference—giving you greater control and flexibility for automated quality inspection use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding data residency access to business customers worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI expands data residency for ChatGPT Enterprise, ChatGPT Edu, and the API Platform, enabling eligible customers to store data at rest in-region.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/expanding-data-residency-access-to-business-customers-worldwide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Community Contributions in Aspire 13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 20:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aspire 13.0 marks a major milestone, not just for the product, but for the vibrant community that helped shape it. This release includes meaningful contributions from community members across features, integrations, tooling, and documentation. We wanted to highlight some standout PRs from this release as a way to say thanks, and hopefully i
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/thanksgiving-contributions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical implementation considerations to close the AI value gap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 20:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS Customer Success Center of Excellence (CS COE) helps customers get tangible value from their AWS investments. We&#39;ve seen a pattern: customers who build AI strategies that address people, process, and technology together succeed more often. In this post, we share practical considerations that can help close the AI value gap.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/practical-implementation-considerations-to-close-the-ai-value-gap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing bidirectional streaming for real-time inference on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re introducing bidirectional streaming for Amazon SageMaker AI Inference, which transforms inference from a transactional exchange into a continuous conversation. This post shows you how to build and deploy a container with bidirectional streaming capability to a SageMaker AI endpoint. We also demonstrate how you can bring your own container or use our partner Deepgram&#39;s pre-built models and containers on SageMaker AI to enable bi-directional streaming feature for real-time inference.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warner Bros. Discovery achieves 60% cost savings and faster ML inference with AWS Graviton</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Warner Bros. Discovery (WBD) is a leading global media and entertainment company that creates and distributes the world’s most differentiated and complete portfolio of content and brands across television, film and streaming. In this post, we describe the scale of our offerings, artificial intelligence (AI)/machine learning (ML) inference infrastructure requirements for our real time recommender systems, and how we used AWS Graviton-based Amazon SageMaker AI instances for our ML inference workloads and achieved 60% cost savings and 7% to 60% latency improvements across different models.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical AI in practice: Technical foundations that fuel human-machine interactions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the complete development lifecycle of physical AI—from data collection and model training to edge deployment—and examine how these intelligent systems learn to understand, reason, and interact with the physical world through continuous feedback loops. We illustrate this workflow through Diligent Robotics&#39; Moxi, a mobile manipulation robot that has completed over 1.2 million deliveries in hospitals, saving nearly 600,000 hours for clinical staff while transforming healthcare logistics and returning valuable time to patient care.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperPod now supports Multi-Instance GPU to maximize GPU utilization for generative AI tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon SageMaker HyperPod now supports NVIDIA Multi-Instance GPU (MIG) technology, enabling you to partition powerful GPUs into multiple isolated instances for running concurrent workloads like inference, research, and interactive development. By maximizing GPU utilization and reducing wasted resources, MIG helps organizations optimize costs while maintaining performance isolation and predictable quality of service across diverse machine learning tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/hyperpod-now-supports-multi-instance-gpu-to-maximize-gpu-utilization-for-generative-ai-tasks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Memory in Foundry Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Give your agents the power to remember Imagine your agent never asks the same question twice. Until now, most agents hav
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/introducing-memory-in-foundry-agent-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Multi-Agent Workflows in Foundry Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Across industries, organizations are moving from experimenting with single agents to running AI at the center of their business operations. While single agents excel at focused tasks, customers quickly discover that real enterprise work stretches across multiple steps, involves different roles, and requires strong governance. To operationalize
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/introducing-multi-agent-workflows-in-foundry-agent-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation Customization, A Developer&#39;s Guide to Adaptive Custom Translation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Translation isn’t just converting words—it’s enabling global communication. Yet for businesses operating worldwide, achieving accuracy, speed, and domain-specific termino
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/translation-customization-a-developers-guide-to-adaptive-custom-translation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Content Understanding is now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft Ignite this year, we’re excited to announce that Azure Content Understanding in Foundry Tools is now generally available (GA). Over the past months, we’ve seen preview usage across industries, from large consultancies to healthcare leaders, with invaluable customer feedback shaping this release. With this GA release, we’r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/azure-content-understanding-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assess Agentic Risks with the AI Red Teaming Agent in Microsoft Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce major enhancements to the AI Red Teaming Agent in Microsoft Foundry for models and AI agentic pipelines, available now in public preview. These new capabilities enable organizations to proactively identify safety and security risks in both models and a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/assess-agentic-risks-with-the-ai-red-teaming-agent-in-microsoft-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing TypeSpec for Microsoft 365 Copilot – Build declarative agents faster with more confidence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that TypeSpec for Microsoft 365 Copilot is now generally available! This milestone marks the first stable release of the domain-specific language (DSL) designed to streamline how developers build and extend Micro
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-typespec-for-microsoft-365-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VTEX accelerates application scale-up by 88% with Amazon EKS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction VTEX, a global e-commerce company serving over 3,400 customers across 38 countries, has undergone a transformative journey since its inception in 2000. Evolving from a B2B textile software to a cloud-native, microservices-based e-commerce platform, VTEX has prioritized efficiency, resilience, and innovation. As part of the journey to a modernized SaaS application, VTEX realized it’s […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/how-vtex-reduced-legacy-net-framework-application-scale-up-time-by-88-with-amazon-eks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Approach for Coding Agent Safety</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Coding agents like Claude Code, Gemini CLI, Codex, Kiro, and OpenCode are changing how developers work. But as these agents become more autonomous with capabilities like deleting repos, modifying files, and accessing secrets, developers face a real problem: how do you give agents enough access to be useful without adding unnecessary risk to your local...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-sandboxes-a-new-approach-for-coding-agent-safety/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing the software supply chain shouldn’t be hard. According to theCUBE Research, Docker makes it simple</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s software-driven economy, securing software supply chains is no longer optional, it’s mission-critical. Yet enterprises often struggle to balance developer speed and security. According to theCUBE Research, 95% of organizations say Docker improved their ability to identify and remediate vulnerabilities, while 79% rate it highly effective at maintaining compliance with security standards. Docker embeds...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/securing-the-software-supply-chain-shouldnt-be-hard-according-to-thecube-research-docker-makes-it-simple/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open-source IntelliJ IDEA: A Simpler Way to Build and Contribute to the Community</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA’s source code has been publicly available for more than 15 years, helping millions of developers learn, experiment, and contribute to their IDE and build their own tools. Now, we’re taking our commitment to open-source to the next level by making it even easier for the community to explore, build, and contribute! What’s New? […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-open-source/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our approach to mental health-related litigation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re sharing our approach to mental health-related litigation. O handle sensitive cases with care, transparency, and respect while continuing to strengthen safety and support in ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/mental-health-litigation-approach 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the .NET boot process via host tracing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we enable host tracing and use that to understand how a .NET app boots up via the dotnet muxer, hostfxr, and hostpolicy.dll
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-the-dotnet-boot-process-via-host-tracing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fetching GitHub content from C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:32:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the many advantages of storing project assets on GitHub is that you can access them both manually and programmatically from anywhere. At elmah.io, we are using this for documentation, code snippets, and more. Instead of placing documents across multiple systems, we version them right alongside the code
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/fetching-github-content-from-c/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside JetBrains—the company reshaping how the world writes code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is integrating GPT-5 across its coding tools, helping millions of developers design, reason, and build software faster.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/jetbrains-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal APIs, CQRS, DDD… Or Just Use Controllers?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 22:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve probably seen this meme floating around, and it’s funny. Why? Because there’s some truth to it. At one end, we just have MVC controllers. At the very opposite end, simply MVC controllers again. But there in the middle lies all the abstraction, libraries, tools, etc. The list goes on. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where… Read More »Minimal APIs, CQRS, DDD… Or Just Use Controllers? The post Minimal APIs, CQRS, DDD… Or Just Use Controllers?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power up your ML workflows with interactive IDEs on SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker HyperPod clusters with Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) orchestration now support creating and managing interactive development environments such as JupyterLab and open source Visual Studio Code, streamlining the ML development lifecycle by providing managed environments for familiar tools to data scientists. This post shows how HyperPod administrators can configure Spaces for their clusters, and how data scientists can create and connect to these Spaces.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/power-up-your-ml-workflows-with-interactive-ides-on-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security that moves fast: Docker’s response to Shai Hulud 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 21, 2025, security researchers detected the beginning of what would become one of the most aggressive npm supply chain attacks to date. The Shai Hulud 2.0 campaign compromised over 25,000 GitHub repositories within 72 hours, targeting packages from major organizations including Zapier, ENS Domains, PostHog, and Postman. The malware&#39;s self-propagating design created a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/security-that-moves-fast-dockers-response-to-shai-hulud-2-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claude Opus 4.5 now in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 19:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anthropic&#39;s newest foundation model, Claude Opus 4.5, is now available in Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models from leading AI companies. In this post, I&#39;ll show you what makes this model different, walk through key business applications, and demonstrate how to use Opus 4.5&#39;s new tool use capabilities on Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/claude-opus-4-5-now-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy GPT-OSS models with Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to deploy the GPT-OSS-20B model on Amazon Bedrock using Custom Model Import while maintaining complete API compatibility with your current applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-gpt-oss-models-with-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: Introducing Edit Data (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview Working with table data is an essential part of database development — whether you’re validating behavior, debugging issues, or quickly seeding data. But switching between tools or writing repetitive T-SQL statements can slow down your workflow.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-edit-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate KMP Watchlist: Level Up Your Skills in 10 Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The best way to skip the “beginner mistakes” phase is to learn from the teams who have already solved them at scale. For Week 3 of KMP Level Up, we’ve curated the Top 10 KotlinConf talks that cover the full spectrum of adoption, from massive production case studies to deep dives into the compiler. Whether […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/the-ultimate-kmp-watchlist/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New release cadence and support lifecycle for Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Build Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with Visual Studio 2026, we are introducing a new support lifecycle for the Microsoft C++ (MSVC) Build Tools. We are also updating the MSVC release cadence. As Visual Studio moves to a Modern
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/new-release-cadence-and-support-lifecycle-for-msvc-build-tools 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio – Built for the Speed of Modern Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The release of Visual Studio 2026 two weeks ago marks the next evolution in Microsoft’s 50-year commitment to deliver the tools that developers love and enterprises trust, built to move at the pace of modern development. Software development is moving faster than ever, and Visual Studio is evolving right along with you. Today, we’re ann
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-built-for-the-speed-of-modern-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does XAML break down when I have an element that is half a billion pixels tall?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer reported that their program encountered rendering problems when they created elements that were a half billion pixels tall, and they wondered why this was happening. A half billion pixels is an awful lot of pixels. At 96 pixels per inch, that gives you an element whose height is over 82 miles (132 km). There is no monitor
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251124-00/?p=111811 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update, November 2025 – Extensibility Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.9.0 is out, and it brings the first version of our extensibility prototype! Read on for all of the details, and see the release notes for the full list of changes and bug fixes. To get support for Amper’s latest features, use IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Beta (or newer). New Amper website We revamped our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/11/amper-update-november-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Site Creation in Microsoft Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The SharePoint team is excited to (finally) bring Site Collection creation to Graph! Starting in Microsoft Graph beta you can now create new site collections! But that’s not all! Creating site collections through older APIs required that your application have Si
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/sharepoint-site-creation-in-microsoft-graph 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Kotlin Adoption Across Your Organization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the fifth post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/scaling-kotlin-adoption-across-your-organization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing shopping research in ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Shopping research in ChatGPT helps you explore, compare, and discover products with personalized buyer’s guides that simplify decision-making
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/chatgpt-shopping-research 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Programming Rule #5: Let the Compiler Work for You — Harness the Power of Type Checking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2025/23_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2025/23_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The excerpt discusses coding standards highlighted in &amp;quot;Rock Your Code: Coding Standards for Microsoft .NET,&amp;quot; emphasizing the pitfalls of using numerous public fields in a class. It advocates for strong typing, proper encapsulation, and input validation to enhance object integrity. The author underscores the importance of self-documenting code for maintainability.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/11/23/defensive-programming-rule-5-let-the-compiler-work-for-you-harness-the-power-of-type-checking/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Automate Azure Naming Conventions with the Build5Nines/naming/azure Terraform Module</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2025/23_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2025/23_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Naming resources in Azure shouldn’t feel like deciphering ancient hieroglyphics. Yet, without a solid standard, names can quickly become inconsistent, confusing, and downright chaotic. The result? A messy Azure environment that’s hard to search, manage, and govern. This guide will show you exactly how to establish and enforce Azure naming conventions using the open source Build5Nines/naming/azure Terraform module — […] The article How To Automate Azure Naming Conventions with the Build5Nines/naming/azure Terraform Module was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The False Comfort of the &#34;Happy Path&#34;: Decoupling Your Services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2025/22_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2025/22_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Coupling isn&#39;t just about code structure; it&#39;s about failure boundaries. Discover how to ensure your critical business logic survives when external dependencies like email or analytics go down.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-false-comfort-of-the-happy-path-decoupling-your-services 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rising Importance of Governance at SwampUP Berlin 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 12-14, the Docker team was out in numbers at JFrog SwampUP Berlin 2025. We joined technical sessions, put on a fireside chat, and had conversations with attendees there. We’d like to thank the folks at JFrog for having us there and putting on such a great show! Here&#39;s our takeaways from the event about software...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/the-rising-importance-of-governance-at-swampup-berlin-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline AI operations with the Multi-Provider Generative AI Gateway reference architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the Multi-Provider Generative AI Gateway reference architecture, which provides guidance for deploying LiteLLM into an AWS environment to streamline the management and governance of production generative AI workloads across multiple model providers. This centralized gateway solution addresses common enterprise challenges including provider fragmentation, decentralized governance, operational complexity, and cost management by offering a unified interface that supports Amazon Bedrock, Amazon SageMaker AI, and external providers while maintaining comprehensive security, monitoring, and control capabilities.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview 3 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview 3 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.OData.Core 9.0.0 Preview 3
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-odata-net-odl-9-preview-3-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignite 2025: A Developer’s Guide to Building Agents for Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ignite 2025 brought many innovations for developers building agents for Microsoft 365. From new capabilities in Declarative Agents and Custom Engine Agents to the introduction of Microsoft Agent 365, the platform now enables organizations to arch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/ignite-2025-a-developers-guide-to-building-agents-for-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Docker Hardened Images Patches Vulnerabilities in 24 hours</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 19, 2025, the Golang project published two Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVEs) affecting the widely-used golang.org/x/crypto/ssh package. While neither vulnerability received a critical CVSS score, both presented real risks to applications using SSH functionality in Go-based containers. CVE-2025-58181 affects SSH servers parsing GSSAPI authentication requests. The vulnerability allows attackers to trigger unbounded memory...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-docker-hardened-images-patch-cves-in-24-hours/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy geospatial agents with Foursquare Spatial H3 Hub and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you&#39;ll learn how to deploy geospatial AI agents that can answer complex spatial questions in minutes instead of months. By combining Foursquare Spatial H3 Hub&#39;s analysis-ready geospatial data with reasoning models deployed on Amazon SageMaker AI, you can build agents that enable nontechnical domain experts to perform sophisticated spatial analysis through natural language queries—without requiring geographic information system (GIS) expertise or custom data engineering pipelines.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Wipro PARI accelerates PLC code generation using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Wipro implemented advanced prompt engineering techniques, custom validation logic, and automated code rectification to streamline the development of industrial automation code at scale using Amazon Bedrock. We walk through the architecture along with the key use cases, explain core components and workflows, and share real-world results that show the transformative impact on manufacturing operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-wipro-pari-accelerates-plc-code-generation-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maybe somebody can explain to me how weak references solve the ODR problem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I proposed Using type aliasing to avoid the ODR problem with conditional compilation. A Reddit thread claimed that &amp;quot;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251121-00/?p=111807 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Hype: How to Use AI to Actually Increase Your Productivity as a Dev</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I started incorporating AI tools into my workflow, I was first frustrated. I didn&#39;t get the 5x or 10x gains others raved about on social. In fact, it slowed me down. But I persisted. Partly because I see it as my professional duty as a software engineer to be as productive as possible, partly...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-developer-productivity-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot 4: Leaner, Safer Apps and a New Kotlin Baseline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Boot 4.0 has officially landed. At JetBrains, we’ve been tracking the updates since the first milestones to ensure that IntelliJ IDEA delivers a smooth and reliable development experience. While many of the core capabilities come directly from Spring Framework 7, Spring Boot remains the adoption enabler that brings everything together: sensible defaults, consistent configuration, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/spring-boot-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more details about the issues resolved, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-2025-2-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSD explores applying generative Al to improve the deviation management process using AWS services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post has explores how MSD is harnessing the power of generative AI and databases to optimize and transform its manufacturing deviation management process. By creating an accurate and multifaceted knowledge base of past events, deviations, and findings, the company aims to significantly reduce the time and effort required for each new case while maintaining the highest standards of quality and compliance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/msd-explores-applying-generative-al-to-improve-the-deviation-management-process-using-aws-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating genomics variant interpretation with AWS HealthOmics and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we show you how agentic workflows can accelerate the processing and interpretation of genomics pipelines at scale with a natural language interface. We demonstrate a comprehensive genomic variant interpreter agent that combines automated data processing with intelligent analysis to address the entire workflow from raw VCF file ingestion to conversational query interfaces.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-genomics-variant-interpretation-with-aws-healthomics-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rufus scales conversational shopping experiences to millions of Amazon customers with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our team at Amazon builds Rufus, an AI-powered shopping assistant which delivers intelligent, conversational experiences to delight our customers. More than 250 million customers have used Rufus this year. Monthly users are up 140% YoY and interactions are up 210% YoY. Additionally, customers that use Rufus during a shopping journey are 60% more likely to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-rufus-scales-conversational-shopping-experiences-to-millions-of-amazon-customers-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinventing how .NET Builds and Ships (Again)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After I wrote my last post on how .NET builds and ships, I was cautiously optimistic that I wouldn&#39;t be writing another one. Or at least not another one about how we build and ship. That problem was done and dusted. .NET had done it! We&#39;d struck a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/reinventing-how-dotnet-builds-and-ships-again 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs: What’s New and What’s Next</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Build 2025, we introduced the Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs to help developers bring grounded AI into their solutions without rebuilding indexes or compromising security. The response has been encouraging, and your fee
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-copilot-apis-whats-new-and-whats-next 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop Faster with VS Code for the Web – Azure: Your Browser-Based Dev Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers can now move from idea to Azure-ready code in minutes with VS Code for the Web – Azure. This browser-based environment removes setup time, reduces friction, and gives you immediate access to pre-configured run
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/get-started-with-vs-code-for-the-web 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Complexity to Simplicity: Intelligent JVM Optimizations on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As cloud-native architectures scale across thousands of containers and virtual machines, Java performance tuning has become more distributed, complex, and error-prone than ever. As highlighted in our public preview announcement, traditional JVM optimization relied on ex
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/from-complexity-to-simplicity-intelligent-jvm-optimizations-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Public Preview of Azure Command Launcher for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the Public Preview of the Azure Command Launcher for Java, a new tool that helps developers, SREs, and infrastructure teams standardize and automate JVM configuration on Azure. The goal is to simplify tuning practices and reduce resource waste across Java workloads.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/announcing-the-public-preview-of-azure-command-launcher-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundry Local comes to Android—plus on-device speech, on-prem support, and a simpler SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re introducing a powerful new way to bring AI directly to your mobile apps: Foundry Local on Android. Starting now, you can build Android applications that run AI on-device—no cloud round trips required. Sign up for the gated preview here: https://aka.m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/foundry-local-comes-to-android 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Care Access achieved 86% data processing cost reductions and 66% faster data processing with Amazon Bedrock prompt caching</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how healthcare organizations can securely implement prompt caching technology to streamline medical record processing while maintaining compliance requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-care-access-achieved-86-data-processing-cost-reductions-and-66-faster-data-processing-with-amazon-bedrock-prompt-caching/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Updates and Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of updates and bug fixes for the 2025.3 release of ReSharper and Rider has just been made public. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.3.0.2 For the full list of issues resolved in this build, please refer to our issue tracker. Rider 2025.3.0.2 For the full list of issues we’ve resolved in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/20/resharper-rider-2025-3-0-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: Dynamic Data Masking for Azure Cosmos DB (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today marks a big step forward with the public preview of Dynamic Data Masking (DDM) for Azure Cosmos DB. This feature helps organizations protect sensitive data without requiring changes to application logic or database interactions. What is Dynamic Data Masking? Dynamic Data Masking (DDM) is a server-side, policy-driven
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-dynamic-data-masking-for-azure-cosmos-db-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Azure SRE Agent with Azure Cosmos DB: Smarter Diagnostics for Your Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/use-azure-sre-agent-with-azure-cosmos-db-smarter-diagnostics-for-your-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Private Preview: Safe Account Key rotation using Account Key Usage Metadata</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Account Key Usage Metadata is a new security and observability feature that helps Azure Cosmos DB customers avoid service disruptions during key rotations. It provides visibility when each account key was last used
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-private-preview-safe-account-key-rotation-using-account-key-usage-metadata 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and Foxconn collaborate to strengthen U.S. manufacturing across the AI supply chain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Foxconn are collaborating to design and manufacture next-generation AI infrastructure hardware in the U.S. The partnership will develop multiple generations of data-center systems, strengthen U.S. supply chains, and build key components domestically to accelerate advanced AI infrastructure.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-and-foxconn-collaborate 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner Integrates vLLM for High-Throughput Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Expanding Docker Model Runner’s Capabilities Today, we’re excited to announce that Docker Model Runner now integrates the vLLM inference engine and safetensors models, unlocking high-throughput AI inference with the same Docker tooling you already use. When we first introduced Docker Model Runner, our goal was to make it simple for developers to run and experiment...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-integrates-vllm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn AI-Assisted Programming With Junie: Free Courses From JetBrains Academy and Nebius</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For over 25 years, JetBrains has been driven by a desire to make developers more productive and enhance the developer experience by providing smarter, more efficient tools. JetBrains Academy advances this mission by empowering learners to study computer science and gain hands-on experience with the professional tools they’ll use in their future careers. AI is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/11/20/learn-ai-assisted-programming-with-junie-free-courses-from-jetbrains-academy-and-nebius/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps to GitHub migration Playbook: Unlocking Agentic DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure DevOps or GitHub Enterprise ? Today, in the Microsoft ecosystem, two Software Development Lifecycle management platforms coexist: - Azure DevOps is designed from the ground up for enterprise with advanced planning features through Azure Boards, build and release automation with Azure Pipelines, and a unique
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/azure-devops-to-github-migration-playbook-unlocking-agentic-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping 1,000 small businesses build with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is partnering with DoorDash, SCORE, and local organizations to help 1,000 small businesses build with AI. The Small Business AI Jam gives Main Street business owners hands-on tools and training to compete and grow.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/small-business-ai-jam 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early experiments in accelerating science with GPT-5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces the first research cases showing how GPT-5 accelerates scientific progress across math, physics, biology, and computer science. Explore how AI and researchers collaborate to generate proofs, uncover new insights, and reshape the pace of discovery.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/accelerating-science-gpt-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
