<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:12:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dev Blogs home page layout simplified</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Dev Blogs community! What we heard – part 2 In my previous post about the grid and list layout choices I shared the feedback we received after launching a Dev Blogs refresh. I also shared how we improved and provided options for the layout of posts. Today, I will address the other major feedback […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devblogs-news/dev-blogs-home-page-layout-simplified 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of a program that crashed on its first instruction</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Didn&#39;t even make it out of the gate.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241108-00/?p=110490 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Default Bundled Plugins in Fleet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recently, we announced the public rollout of the Fleet Plugins SDK – a step that finally allows plugins to be created and shared among the Fleet community at large. Believe it or not, this did not mark the very beginning of extensibility in Fleet. Fleet has always featured a variety of bundled plugins (currently upwards […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/11/default-bundled-plugins-in-fleet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Ways to Simplify CI/CD Pipelines on GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post focuses on three ways to simplify CI/CD pipelines deploying to Azure with GitHub Actions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/three-ways-to-simplify-cicd-pipelines-on-github-actions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI: The New Frontier for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 07:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AJ Enns reflects on his journey as a new developer and the impact of AI as an integrated, coding assistant for improving developer velocity. The year is 2024, and AI has been around for a while. ChatGPT broke onto the scene and changed the world forever. As soon as I heard about it, the first […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/ai-the-new-frontier-for-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2024/08_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Release Candidate is here! You can download the latest build from our website, from the free Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. To use this build, you need to have an active IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate subscription. With the big release day approaching fast, our team is putting the finishing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/intellij-idea-2024-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Prompt Management is now available in GA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 22:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Prompt Management, with new features that provide enhanced options for configuring your prompts and enabling seamless integration for invoking them in your generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-prompt-management-is-now-available-in-ga/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready for .NET Conf 2024!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The biggest .NET event of the year is almost here, its all free, all online, and you&#39;re invited!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/get-ready-for-dotnet-conf-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Zalando optimized large-scale inference and streamlined ML operations on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is cowritten with Mones Raslan, Ravi Sharma and Adele Gouttes from Zalando. Zalando SE is one of Europe’s largest ecommerce fashion retailers with around 50 million active customers. Zalando faces the challenge of regular (weekly or daily) discount steering for more than 1 million products, also referred to as markdown pricing. Markdown pricing is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-zalando-optimized-large-scale-inference-and-streamlined-ml-operations-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing Stability AI’s most advanced text-to-image models for media, marketing and advertising: Revolutionizing creative workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To stay competitive, media, advertising, and entertainment enterprises need to stay abreast of recent dramatic technological developments. Generative AI has emerged as a game-changer, offering unprecedented opportunities for creative professionals to push boundaries and unlock new realms of possibility. At the forefront of this revolution is Stability AI’s family of cutting-edge text-to-image AI models. These […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleashing-stability-ais-most-advanced-text-to-image-models-for-media-marketing-and-advertising-revolutionizing-creative-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a multi-tenant generative AI environment for your enterprise on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While organizations continue to discover the powerful applications of generative AI, adoption is often slowed down by team silos and bespoke workflows. To move faster, enterprises need robust operating models and a holistic approach that simplifies the generative AI lifecycle. In the first part of the series, we showed how AI administrators can build a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-multi-tenant-generative-ai-environment-for-your-enterprise-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance customer support with Amazon Bedrock Agents by integrating enterprise data APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has transformed customer support, offering businesses the ability to respond faster, more accurately, and with greater personalization. AI agents, powered by large language models (LLMs), can analyze complex customer inquiries, access multiple data sources, and deliver relevant, detailed responses. In this post, we guide you through integrating Amazon Bedrock Agents with enterprise data […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-customer-support-with-amazon-bedrock-agents-by-integrating-enterprise-data-apis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next big release for Rider is just around the corner! If you’re eager to get a sneak peek, you can download the Release Candidate version of Rider 2024.3 from our website right now. Here are the feature highlights of the Rider 2024.3 RC build: If you encounter any issues when using the Rider 2024.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/07/the-rider-2024-3-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2024.3 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get a preview of all the latest features and improvements set to be shipped with the next major ReSharper and .NET tools releases by downloading the Release Candidate builds that have just landed. Here are the lists of major improvements in each of the new builds: The ReSharper 2024.3 Release Candidate The ReSharper C++ 2024.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/07/rsrp-net-tools-2024-3-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I observe reads from a memory-mapped file when writing large blocks?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The CPU doesn&#39;t see the entire write at once.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241107-00/?p=110486 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave’s Faster or Not!: Exploring Early Return in .NET Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post introduces a series called &amp;quot;dotNetDave&#39;s Faster or Not!&amp;quot; which aims to explore performance claims in .NET. It discusses method return patterns, comparing early returns and single-exit methods. Despite minor performance differences favoring early returns, the author advocates for their use due to improved readability and reduced complexity in coding.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/07/dotnetdaves-faster-or-not-exploring-early-return-in-net-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging a managed identity connection to Azure SQL in Azure App Service using containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 07:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dominique St-Amand explores how to debug a managed identity connection from a container-based App Service to Azure SQL. So you’ve been eager to deploy your containerized web application that you’ve been working on for a while, to Azure App Service. You follow the best security practices which means you’ve setup your connection to your Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/debugging-a-managed-identity-connection-to-azure-sql-in-azure-app-service-using-containers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (October 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 06:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.10.21 registry release, 2024-10-18 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout October. This release adds support for Azure universal packages as a binary caching provider and other minor improvements. CppCon Talk on Managing C++ Dependencies I also gave […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-october-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAG with SQL Vector Store: A Low-Code/No-Code Approach using Azure Logic Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 05:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data is at the heart of every AI application, and efficient data ingestion is critical for success. With over 1,400 enterprise connectors, Logic Apps offers unmatched access to a diverse range of systems, applications, and databases, whether hosted in the cloud or on-premises. These connectors give businesses the flexibility to keep their data where it […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/sql-vector-store-data-ingestion-and-retrieval-using-azure-logic-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Customers Don’t Care About JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 22:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your customers do not care about the technology behind your app. What programming language, frameworks, libraries, or whatever tooling you’re using, they don’t care. They care about it providing them value and that it has certain characteristics. They want it to work. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my… Read More »Your Customers Don’t Care About JavaScript The post Your Customers Don’t Care About JavaScript appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleash the power of generative AI with Amazon Q Business: How CCoEs can scale cloud governance best practices and drive innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 21:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Hearst, one of the nation’s largest global, diversified information, services, and media companies, overcame these challenges by creating a self-service generative AI conversational assistant for business units seeking guidance from their CCoE.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleash-the-power-of-generative-ai-with-amazon-q-business-how-ccoes-can-scale-cloud-governance-best-practices-and-drive-innovation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 Goes Beta With Enhanced CLion Nova, Debug Servers, and OpenCV Image Viewer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of CLion 2024.3 is now available with key improvements and changes announced for the upcoming release. You can download build 243.21565.87 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 BETA Read the full release notes on YouTrack. Below is a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/11/clion-2024-3-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate foundation models into your code with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 17:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The rise of large language models (LLMs) and foundation models (FMs) has revolutionized the field of natural language processing (NLP) and artificial intelligence (AI). These powerful models, trained on vast amounts of data, can generate human-like text, answer questions, and even engage in creative writing tasks. However, training and deploying such models from scratch is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-foundation-models-into-your-code-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciting Announcement: Public Preview of Native Vector Support in Azure SQL Database!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Public Preview of Native Vector Support in Azure SQL Database We are excited to share that the dedicated vector data type in Azure SQL Database, which was previously available through the Early Adopter Preview, is now transitioning to Public Preview! As of today, the Vector data type and its associated functions are accessible to everyone, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/exciting-announcement-public-preview-of-native-vector-support-in-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a new, more conversational way to chat with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the fast-evolving world of software development, intuitive AI-driven interactions are becoming essential to unlocking new levels of productivity. Today, we’re excited to share our latest innovation – a guided chat experience within GitHub Copilot that reshapes how developers interact with AI. This guided chat experience is available in Visual Studio 2022 17.12 Preview 3 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/conversational-way-to-chat-with-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and deploy a UI for your generative AI applications with AWS and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS provides a powerful set of tools and services that simplify the process of building and deploying generative AI applications, even for those with limited experience in frontend and backend development. In this post, we explore a practical solution that uses Streamlit, a Python library for building interactive data applications, and AWS services like Amazon Elastic Container Service (Amazon ECS), Amazon Cognito, and the AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK) to create a user-friendly generative AI application with authentication and deployment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unearth insights from audio transcripts generated by Amazon Transcribe using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we examine how to create business value through speech analytics with some examples focused on the following: 1) automatically summarizing, categorizing, and analyzing marketing content such as podcasts, recorded interviews, or videos, and creating new marketing materials based on those assets, 2) automatically extracting key points, summaries, and sentiment from a recorded meeting (such as an earnings call), and 3) transcribing and analyzing contact center calls to improve customer experience.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to subscribe for GitHub copilot business without GitHub Enterprise: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know that now you can subscribe to GitHub Copilot Business without GitHub Enterprise (GHE), which means you can get GitHub Copilot Business as a standalone capability, while having the normal GitHub Enterprise features (repositories, actions, etc.) disabled. This post is a screenshot-based step-by-step guide on how to configure a new GitHub Copilot Business […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-subscribe-for-github-copilot-business-without-github-enterprise 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I declare an operator overload for my Windows Runtime class?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That&#39;s not something expressible in the Windows Runtime.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241106-00/?p=110478 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on Unreal Engine Support in TeamCity: UGS Integration and Open-Sourcing the Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve got a few exciting updates about the Unreal Engine plugin announced in the previous blog post. TL;DR – we’re adding Unreal Game Sync (UGS) integration and open-sourcing the plugin. These updates are all about making the CI/CD experience smoother for Unreal Engine devs and getting the community more involved. UGS Before diving in, let’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/11/unreal-engine-plugin-ugs-integration-and-open-sourcing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Your Setup with the Microsoft Dev Box Pre-Requisites Page</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Dev Box team has been working hard to streamline the onboarding process for Dev Box administrators when first trying out the service, especially for situations when you’re unsure of all the necessary steps. In this blog, we are introducing a solution to make this process smoother and more efficient. Introducing the Microsoft Dev Box […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/streamline-setup-with-microsoft-dev-box-pre-requisites 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New DevBlogs Layout: Choose your view – Grid or List</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 19:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Dev Blogs community! We are committed to continuously enhancing your experience on Microsoft Dev Blogs, guided by your invaluable feedback. Since the recent update on our site, we heard a lot of feedback about the masonry layout. We are excited to share how we’ve adapted to make to improve your experience. What We Heard […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devblogs-news/new-devblogs-layout-choose-your-view-grid-or-list 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: New in November</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 18:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This month, we’ve introduced new projects and topics to help you reach your coding goals in Kotlin, backend development, Git, or AI. Kotlin 🆕 Project: My first project with Kotlin. Easy Imagine that you’re the owner of a new small corner shop. You are doing well and want to determine how much you earned in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/11/05/jetbrains-academy-new-in-november/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Semantic Kernel for Java 1.4.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 18:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello Java AI developers! We are announcing the 1.4.0 release of the Semantic Kernel for Java. Please see the full changelog here. You can find our updates on our GitHub repository and the artifacts on Maven Central. What’s New in Semantic Kernel for Java 1.4.0? Vector Store Functionality Goes GA The central focus of this release is for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-semantic-kernel-for-java-1-4-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn how to create a Client-Server Application in under 45 Minutes in the new Season of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 17:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What if you could create a robust, versatile client-server application in under 45 minutes? With Visual Studio and GitHub Copilot, this is not only possible but also efficient and enjoyable. This Season of AI, we show you how to use developer tools like GitHub Copilot to create apps from scratch. This season of AI occurs […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/learn-how-to-create-a-client-server-application-in-under-45-minutes-in-the-new-season-of-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dockerize WordPress: Simplify Your Site’s Setup and Deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 15:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to Dockerize WordPress by following steps to create Dockerfiles, containerize existing WordPress instances, and set up Traefik for automatic TLS certificates.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-dockerize-wordpress/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the difference between Display size and Screen size in the Windows 95 display control panel?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            No meaningful difference, though others have created a difference.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241105-00/?p=110472 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messaging with Wolverine using Apache Pulsar</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of the Wolverine 3.0 release a couple weeks back, Wolverine gained a lightweight messaging transport option with Apache Pulsar. “Lightweight” just meaning “it doesn’t have a lot of features yet” To get started, first add this Nuget to your system: And just like that, you’re ready to start adding publishing rules and subscriptions … Continue reading Messaging with Wolverine using Apache Pulsar →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/11/05/messaging-with-wolverine-using-apache-pulsar/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update November 2024 – Project File Tooling, Compose Resources, KSP2, and Android Release Builds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 13:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.5.0 is now available! With this release, we’ve improved the IDE experience when working with multiple modules and project.yaml files, made nested completion in Amper configuration files more powerful, introduced support for Compose Resources and KSP2, improved Android release builds, and more! For the full list of changes and bug fixes in Amper 0.5.0, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2024/11/amper-update-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 11:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Java Annotated Monthly is here! Check out the latest news across Java, Spring, AI, and emerging technologies. We offer practical tutorials to enhance your skills, a curated list of November’s top tech events, both online and offline, and an exclusive feature by industry expert Mala Gupta. Stay informed, and stay ahead! Featured Content In this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/java-annotated-monthly-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Caching with Aspect-Oriented Programming and Metalama in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Introduction: Simplifying Caching with Aspect-Oriented Programming in .NET Aspect-Oriented Programming (AOP) offers elegant solutions for handling cross-cutting concerns in our .NET applications, such as method caching. In a previous article on GoatReview 🐐, we explored using Fody to implement a caching aspect. Although powerful, this tool presents significant challenges. Link to article: https://goatreview.com/simplifying-caching-with-aop-metalama/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s UlidGenerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of .NET 8 assemblies and NuGet packages created for efficient ULID generation, combining randomness with alphabetical sorting. ULIDs are compact, sortable identifiers offering uniqueness for distributed systems. The UlidGenerator class provides methods for generating ULIDs.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/05/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-ulidgenerator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent updates for NetEscapades.EnumGenerators: interceptors!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe the experimental interceptor support in NetEscapades.EnumGenerators that replaces ToString() calls with ToStringFast() automatically
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/recent-updates-for-netescapades-enumgenerators-interceptors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#x27;s new in .NET 9: System.Text.Json improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 08:38:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 9 is releasing in mid-November 2024. Like every .NET version, this introduces several important features and enhancements aligning developers with an ever-changing development ecosystem. In this blog series, I will explore critical updates in different areas of .NET. For this post, I will look through advancements in System.Text.
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/whats-new-in-net-9-system-text-json-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davide&#39;s Code and Architecture Notes - the Error Management Trio, and how it affects your software architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2024/05_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When designing a software system, we naturally focus more on the happy flow. But we should carefully plan to handle errors that fall into three categories: Validation, Transient, and Fatal.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/error-management-trio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GitHub Copilot in Data Wrangler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI did not write this blog post, but it will make your exploratory data analysis with Data Wrangler better! Today, we’re excited to introduce our first step of integrating the power of Copilot into Data Wrangler. With this first integration of Copilot with Data Wrangler, you’ll be able to: Use natural language to clean and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/announcing-github-copilot-in-data-wrangler 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSF Scorecard for .NET and the NuGet ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 17:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenSSF Scorecard is a tool developed by the Open Source Security Foundation (OpenSSF) that provides automated security assessments for open-source projects. The primary goal of the Scorecard project is to help developers and users determine the security posture of open-source software by generating a score based on a series of security-related checks. Using Scorecard, developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/nuget/openssf-scorecard-for-net-nuget 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.35: Organization Access Tokens, Docker Home, Volumes Export, and Terminal in Docker Desktop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.35 includes organization access tokens, a new Docker product home page, terminal enhancements, Docker Desktop for Red Hat Enterprise Linux, and improved performance on macOS.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-35/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wow! It’s easy to take the rapid pace of technological advancement for granted, especially given how many of us have been tech-natives for most of our lives. For Mac lovers, Infinite Mac takes a trip across the decades of the 1980s to 2000s through the lens of releases. Experience history all in your browser. Draw […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/11/04/dotinsights-november-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Chat History for Large Language Models (LLMs)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large Language Models (LLMs) operate with a defined limit on the number of tokens they can process at once, referred to as the context window. Exceeding this limit can have significant cost and performance implications. Therefore, it is essential to manage the size of the input sent to the LLM, particularly when using chat completion models. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/managing-chat-history-for-large-language-models-llms 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The making of Bring Back Plus/Minus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 15:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A lesson about the software forensics process involved in developing the Bring Back Plus/Minus extension, which brings back the plus/minus symbols to the editor outlining feature in Visual Studio 2022. While I did have the advantage of being able to look at the Visual Studio source code, I could have figured this out just as well without […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/the-making-of-bring-back-plus-minus 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the limits of time travel in the face of undefined behavior in C</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C imposes some constraints, but the principle is mostly still there.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241104-00/?p=110466 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Docker Desktop: How Signing In Unlocks Advanced Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Signing into Docker Desktop unlocks advanced features and integrations, enabling developers and admins to fully leverage Docker’s cloud-native tools for enhanced productivity, security, and scalability.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/maximizing-docker-desktop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AI Tools to Convert a PDF into Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to turn a PDF into a bunch of images with the help of Docker and AI tools.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/using-ai-tools-to-convert-a-pdf-into-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dobar Dan! Algorithm and Code Training School Heads to Serbia This Winter!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the beginning of 2025, the Algorithm and Code Training School (ACTS) camp is moving to an exciting new location – Serbia! While our summer camp in Romania was a great success, we’re taking things to the next level with an even more intensive competition format. This camp is perfect for young coders aiming to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/11/04/dobar-dan-algorithm-and-code-training-school-heads-to-serbia-this-winter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Full-Stack App With Go and React</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a language that emerged over 14 years ago, Go has many use cases. From web development, APIs, and CLIs to Wasm, cloud technologies, and even AI-powered tools, its applications are broad. The same goes for demo projects, which have countless variations and purposes! Now, wouldn’t it be great if there was a full-stack, API-oriented, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/11/04/create-a-full-stack-app-with-go-and-react/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Build GraphQL Services With Spring Boot Like Netflix</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with Netflix Staff Engineer, Paul Bakker, to discover how Netflix implements GraphQL services with Spring Boot and the DGS framework. Date: November 14, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Netflix uses GraphQL and the DGS framework (recently fully integrated with Spring […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.22 with improved checking minimal API permissions and logging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 07:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share with you a new version of Dev Proxy that helps you build robust apps connected to APIs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-22-with-improved-checking-minimal-api-permissions-and-logging 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core and Angular BFF using a YARP downstream API protected using certificate authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article demonstrates how to implement a downstream API protected by certificate authentication using Microsoft YARP reverse proxy in an ASP.NET Core web application. The application uses Angular for its UI and secures both the UI and the ASP.NET Core backend through a backend-for-frontend security architecture. The downstream API is secured with certificate authentication and […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/11/04/asp-net-core-and-angular-bff-using-a-yarp-downstream-api-protected-using-certificate-authentication/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Negotiation in an ASP.NET Core Minimal API Using Carter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll examine how to implement content negotiation in an ASP.NET Core Minimal API. Since there are several ways to implement content negotiation in .NET APIs, we’ll briefly discuss the different approaches and tradeoffs for each. Let’s focus on the ASP.NET Core Minimal API and then use the Carter library to make our […] The post Content Negotiation in an ASP.NET Core Minimal API Using Carter appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 中System.Text.Json 的新增功能</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 01:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2024/04_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Eirik Tsarpalis的 What’s new in System.Text.Json in .NET 9 – .NET Blog System.Text.Json的9.0 版本包含许多功能，主要侧重于 JSON 架构和智能应用程序支持。它还包括一些备受期待的增强功能，例如可空引用类型支持、自定义枚举成员名称、无序元数据反序列化和自定义序列化缩进。 获取最新信息 您可以通过引用 System.Text.Json NuGet 包的最新版本或 .NET 9 的最新 SDK 来尝试新功能。 JSON 架构导出器 新的 JsonSchemaExporter 类可以使用 JsonSerializerOptions 或 JsonTypeInfo 实例从 .NET 类型中提取 JSON 架构文档： using System.Text.Json.Schema; JsonSerializerOptions options = JsonSerializerOptions.Default; JsonNode schema = options.GetJsonSchemaAsNode(typeof(Person)); Console.WriteLine(schema.ToString()); //{ // &amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;object&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;null&amp;quot;], // […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/net-9-%e4%b8%adsystem-text-json-%e7%9a%84%e6%96%b0%e5%a2%9e%e5%8a%9f%e8%83%bd 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Round Trips are Evil, So Batch Your Queries When You Can</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 18:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software frequently helps our customers wring better performance or scalability out of our customer’s systems. A somewhat frequent opportunity for improving the responsiveness and throughput of systems is merely identifying ways to batch up requests from middle tier, server side code to the backing database or databases. There’s a certain amount of overhead in … Continue reading Network Round Trips are Evil, So Batch Your Queries When You Can →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Enum Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2024/03_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source collection of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, created and managed by the author since .NET 2 release. It includes the EnumExtensions class with utility methods for Enum types, such as GetDescription(), GetItems(), and Parse().
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/03/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-enum-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Memory of Stiver</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 13:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On October 20, the original author of the Fernflower Java decompiler, Stiver, passed away after a long fight against glioblastoma. Stiver was a German programmer of Russian origin, primarily developing software for medical equipment. Twenty years ago, he developed a deep professional interest in Java virtual machine internals. You may remember his research blog posts, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/in-memory-of-stiver/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Timezones WRECKED Me! – Dev Leader Weekly 68</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How Timezones WRECKED Me! – Dev Leader Weekly 68 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss fixing an issue in production is WAY harder than just following a tutorial on a happy path. The post How Timezones WRECKED Me! – Dev Leader Weekly 68 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/11/02/how-timezones-wrecked-me-dev-leader-weekly-68/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Architecture: The Missing Chapter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2024/02_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Clean Architecture&#39;s famous diagram is often misinterpreted as a project structure, leading developers to create artificial technical layers that scatter business logic across their codebase. Learn what the diagram really means and how to properly organize your code around business capabilities using components and clear boundaries.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/clean-architecture-the-missing-chapter 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and lessons for fine-tuning Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 21:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the best practices and lessons learned for fine-tuning Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku on Amazon Bedrock. We discuss the important components of fine-tuning, including use case definition, data preparation, model customization, and performance evaluation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-and-lessons-for-fine-tuning-anthropics-claude-3-haiku-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track, allocate, and manage your generative AI cost and usage with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 19:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock has launched a capability that organizations can use to tag on-demand models and monitor associated costs. Organizations can now label all Amazon Bedrock models with AWS cost allocation tags, aligning usage to specific organizational taxonomies such as cost centers, business units, and applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/track-allocate-and-manage-your-generative-ai-cost-and-usage-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance environmental sustainability in clinical trials using AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to use AWS to support a decentralized clinical trial across the four main pillars of a decentralized clinical trial (virtual trials, personalized patient engagement, patient-centric trial design, and centralized data management). By exploring these AWS powered alternatives, we aim to demonstrate how organizations can drive progress towards more environmentally friendly clinical research practices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advance-environmental-sustainability-in-clinical-trials-using-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Team at CppCon 2024: Trip Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft C++ team attended CppCon, the largest C++ conference in the world. This year, the conference was held in Aurora, Colorado from September 16-20. Microsoft Booth Our team managed a booth from Monday to Thursday of the week. This gave us an amazing opportunity to interact with the C++ community and discuss many topics […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/microsoft-c-team-at-cppcon-2024-trip-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – November 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The November 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include docstring template generation with Pylance, Fold/Unfold All Docstrings commands, a variable view with the Native REPL and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-november-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Performance of the “Proxy” Library</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article analyzes the performance of the &amp;quot;Proxy&amp;quot; library in various scenarios, demonstrating its significant advantages in indirect invocations and lifetime management across different platforms.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/analyzing-the-performance-of-the-proxy-library 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Q to find answers on Google Drive in an enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post covers the steps to configure the Amazon Q Business Google Drive connector, including authentication setup and verifying the secure indexing of your Google Drive content.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-q-to-find-answers-on-google-drive-in-an-enterprise/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Druva used Amazon Bedrock to address foundation model complexity when building Dru, Druva’s backup AI copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Druva enables cyber, data, and operational resilience for thousands of enterprises, and is trusted by 60 of the Fortune 500. In this post, we show how Druva approached natural language querying (NLQ)—asking questions in English and getting tabular data as answers—using Amazon Bedrock, the challenges they faced, sample prompts, and key learnings.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-druva-used-amazon-bedrock-to-address-foundation-model-complexity-when-building-dru-druvas-backup-ai-copilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AWS Bedrock with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the principal features of Semantic Kernel is its ability to integrate various AI services seamlessly. We are pleased to announce that this capability now extends to AWS Bedrock. With AWS Bedrock, you can access foundational models such as the Amazon Titan models. The new connector supports Chat Completion, Text Generation, and Text Embeddings, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/introducing-aws-bedrock-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Blogs for Experienced Programmers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following up on our previous article in which we shared some great multi-author blogs to follow, today we have a curated selection of personal blogs from top Java experts. These experts aren’t just the best at what they do – they’re also great at sharing their knowledge in ways that are easy to understand and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/top-java-blogs-for-experienced-programmers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft JDConf 2025: Building the future with Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Technology is advancing faster than ever, and developers are leading the charge, driving digital transformation and reshaping businesses everywhere. With the rise of AI and cloud-native architectures, Java developers are uniquely positioned to shape the future of enterprise applications. Java remains one of the most widely used programming languages globally, with 45% of developers actively […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/microsoft-jdconf-2025-building-the-future-with-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive AI at Microsoft Ignite 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Ignite 2024 is almost here! This year the in-person conference will be held in Chicago Illinois USA November 19th – 22nd and the Semantic Kernel team will be on site answering questions and sharing best practices and if you can’t attend in-person you can also sign up for free and watch it online or […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/productive-ai-at-microsoft-ignite-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Faster with dotNetTips.com Spargine 8: November 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine 8 was released on November 1st, 2024, featuring significant updates including NuGet packages for .NET 8. The update enhances performance with new utilities like TempFileManager, UlidGenerator, and improved JSON deserialization. Users are encouraged to explore these features and contribute feedback or suggestions to further enhance the project.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/01/coding-faster-with-dotnettips-com-spargine-8-november-2024-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On locale-aware substring matching, either case-sensitive or case-insensitive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s surprisingly complicated, but fortunately, somebody has done it for you.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241101-00/?p=110447 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allow your customers to access your copilots by integrating Copilot Studio with Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to securely integrate Microsoft Entra External ID with Copilot-powered applications in this step-by-step tutorial. Using the Generic OAuth 2.0 service provider in Copilot Studio, this guide shows you how to grant customers seamless access to your AI copilots.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/integrate-copilot-studio-with-external-id 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
