<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 22:26:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>No new Azure DevOps OAuth apps beginning February 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 22:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting February 3, 2025, we will no longer accept new registrations of Azure DevOps OAuth apps. This is the first step we’ll be taking towards our longer-term vision of sunsetting the Azure DevOps OAuth platform. Moving forward, we’ll be publicly advocating all developers that are building applications on top of Azure DevOps REST APIs to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/no-new-azure-devops-oauth-apps-beginning-february-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Power Platform Environment Creation &amp; Solution Imports with GitHub Actions (Federated Auth Setup)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 21:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Automate Power Platform Environment Creation &amp;amp; Solution Imports with GitHub Actions (Federated Auth Setup) Automating your CI/CD pipeline for Power Platform solutions streamlines development and reduces manual tasks. Integrating GitHub Actions with federated authentication provides secure and scalable access for creating environments, importing solutions, and even cleaning up temporary environments. This post guides you through […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/automate-power-platform-environment-creation-solution-imports-with-github-actions-federated-auth-setup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Multiplatform Development Roadmap for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 18:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Kotlin Multiplatform is now firmly established, development teams across the globe – including major companies like Shopify, Forbes, Haier, and Zürcher Kantonalbank – can harness its power in production environments. During Google I/O 2024 in May, Google announced their official support for Kotlin Multiplatform for sharing business logic across Android and iOS. This and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/10/kotlin-multiplatform-development-roadmap-for-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import data from Google Cloud Platform BigQuery for no-code machine learning with Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 18:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents an architectural approach to extract data from different cloud environments, such as Google Cloud Platform (GCP) BigQuery, without the need for data movement. This minimizes the complexity and overhead associated with moving data between cloud environments, enabling organizations to access and utilize their disparate data assets for ML projects. We highlight the process of using Amazon Athena Federated Query to extract data from GCP BigQuery, using Amazon SageMaker Data Wrangler to perform data preparation, and then using the prepared data to build ML models within Amazon SageMaker Canvas, a no-code ML interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized model monitoring for near real-time batch inference with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 17:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a framework to customize the use of Amazon SageMaker Model Monitor for handling multi-payload inference requests for near real-time inference scenarios. SageMaker Model Monitor monitors the quality of SageMaker ML models in production. Early and proactive detection of deviations in model quality enables you to take corrective actions, such as retraining models, auditing upstream systems, or fixing quality issues without having to monitor models manually or build additional tooling.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving into Function Calling and its JSON Schema in Semantic Kernel .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Diving into Function Calling and its JSON Schema in Semantic Kernel .NET Function-calling is one of the most exciting features of certain Large Language Models (LLMs), enabling developers to execute code directly in response to user queries. In Semantic Kernel, we streamline the process by allowing you to use built-in plugins or integrate your own code […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/diving-into-function-calling-and-its-json-schema-in-semantic-kernel-net 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily add Unreal Engine classes to your C&#43;&#43; project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 15:43:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 v17.11 introduces a new Add Unreal Engine Class dialog that lets you easily add common Unreal Engine classes to your project. You can also choose to which module to add your class, so you can keep your code organized and modular. To use this feature, you need to have an Unreal Engine […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/easily-add-unreal-engine-classes-to-your-c-project 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How useful is the hint passed to the std::unordered_… collections?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Only a little, or sometimes not at all.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241028-00/?p=110428 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2024.3 EAP Digest: Improved Navigation and Rename Refactoring for Framework Components, AI-Based Code Completion Updates, and Tailwind Color Preview for CSS Classes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 13:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s time for the WebStorm 2024.3 EAP digest, which will walk you through the new features and improvements in the upcoming release! The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the EAP builds and keep both your stable and EAP versions up to date. You can also manually download the EAP builds from our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/10/webstorm-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Best Practices 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 12:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JavaScript is undoubtedly the most used programming language in the world and is hugely influential on one of the largest technologies we have all come to rely on – the internet. With this power comes great responsibility, and the JavaScript ecosystem has been rapidly evolving, making it incredibly hard to keep up with the latest […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/10/javascript-best-practices-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get an Instance of IServiceProvider in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In modern .NET applications, dependency injection is a fundamental design pattern that promotes loose coupling and enhances maintainability. At the center of .NET’s dependency injection system lies the IServiceProvider interface, which acts as a service locator for retrieving service instances. Understanding how to obtain and work with an IServiceProvider instance is vital for developers who […] The post How to Get an Instance of IServiceProvider in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Identifiable Information Masking in Marten</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2024/27_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2024/27_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software helps our customers be more successful with their usage of the “Critter Stack” tools (or any other server side .NET tooling you might be using). The work in this post was delivered for a JasperFx customer to help protect their customer’s private information. If you need or want any help with event sourcing, … Continue reading Personal Identifiable Information Masking in Marten →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/10/27/personal-identifiable-information-masking-in-marten/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s IEnumerable Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2024/27_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2024/27_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source library of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, enhancing IEnumerable collections with various utility methods. It includes functionalities like adding distinct items, counting elements, and verifying uniqueness. Community involvement is encouraged for project improvement.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/27/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-ienumerable-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Codebases Become Spaghetti – Dev Leader Weekly 67</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_10_2024/26_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_10_2024/26_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How Codebases Become Spaghetti – Dev Leader Weekly 67 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how codebases grow in complexity with an example -- AND what to do! The post How Codebases Become Spaghetti – Dev Leader Weekly 67 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/10/26/how-codebases-become-spaghetti-dev-leader-weekly-67/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Idempotent REST APIs in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_10_2024/26_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_10_2024/26_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement idempotency in ASP.NET Core Web APIs to improve reliability and prevent duplicate operations in distributed systems.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/implementing-idempotent-rest-apis-in-aspnetcore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process Framework gets Python support and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 21:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we continue to empower developers in embedding AI into their workflows, we are thrilled to announce significant updates to the Microsoft Semantic Kernel’s Process Framework. Building on our introductory blog, we’ve made enhancements that further streamline business process automation and AI integration and help you to be successful with the Semantic Kernel Process Framework […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/process-framework-gets-python-support-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Digital Transformation Discovering Rome’s hidden treasures with an AI virtual assistant and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 18:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we want to highlight a customer story featuring Semantic Kernel here: Discovering Rome’s hidden treasures with an AI virtual assistant – Source EMEA On a sunny Monday morning in late September, a river of travelers flowed slowly through the Piazza della Rotonda. The focal point of the piazza is the Pantheon, the nearly 2,000- […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/ai-digital-transformation-discovering-romes-hidden-treasures-with-an-ai-virtual-assistant-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Planview built a scalable AI Assistant for portfolio and project management using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 16:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Planview was able to develop a generative AI assistant to address complex work management process by adopting Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-planview-built-a-scalable-ai-assistant-for-portfolio-and-project-management-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I explicitly specialize a templated C&#43;&#43; constructor, follow-up notes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can use a maker function, but that doesn&#39;t let you escape the problem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241025-00/?p=110420 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDE Services Cloud Release and Floating License Server End-of-Life Announcements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 10:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains IDE Services, the enterprise suite of products dedicated to improving developer productivity across an entire organization, is now available in the cloud! By offering a JetBrains-managed service, IDE Services Cloud simplifies license management, enhances security, and provides seamless scalability, ensuring that organizations can focus more on development and less on administration. As part of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/25/ide-services-cloud-release-and-floating-license-server-end-of-life-announcements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (October 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 20:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure SDKs release every month. This post includes the month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-october-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Entra profile information in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 20:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the ability to use Entra profile information in Azure DevOps. This has been a long-standing feature request from the community (ex. profile, picture, email, and name). Beyond the convenience of configuring profile information in one place and ensuring the accuracy of personal information, using Entra profile information in Azure DevOps provides […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/using-entra-profile-information-in-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eShop infused with AI – a comprehensive intelligent app sample with Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 19:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re featuring a sample application, called eShop. You can read the entire blog post and steps for running the application here: eShop infused with AI – a comprehensive intelligent app sample – .NET Blog Below, we have a brief summary of eShop and the integration with Semantic Kernel. Introducing eShop “support with AI” edition […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/eshop-infused-with-ai-a-comprehensive-intelligent-app-sample-with-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super charge your LLMs with RAG at scale using AWS Glue for Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 18:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will explore building a reusable RAG data pipeline on LangChain—an open source framework for building applications based on LLMs—and integrating it with AWS Glue and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless. The end solution is a reference architecture for scalable RAG indexing and deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/super-charge-your-llms-with-rag-at-scale-using-aws-glue-for-apache-spark/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From RAG to fabric: Lessons learned from building real-world RAGs at GenAIIC – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 18:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we cover the core concepts behind RAG architectures and discuss strategies for evaluating RAG performance, both quantitatively through metrics and qualitatively by analyzing individual outputs. We outline several practical tips for improving text retrieval, including using hybrid search techniques, enhancing context through data preprocessing, and rewriting queries for better relevance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/from-rag-to-fabric-lessons-learned-from-building-real-world-rags-at-genaiic-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance your Amazon Redshift cloud data warehouse with easier, simpler, and faster machine learning using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 17:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into a business use case for a banking institution. We will show you how a financial or business analyst at a bank can easily predict if a customer’s loan will be fully paid, charged off, or current using a machine learning model that is best for the business problem at hand.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-your-amazon-redshift-cloud-data-warehouse-with-easier-simpler-and-faster-machine-learning-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a generative AI-based application builder assistant using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 17:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agentic workflows are a fresh new perspective in building dynamic and complex business use- case based workflows with the help of large language models (LLM) as their reasoning engine or brain. In this post, we set up an agent using Amazon Bedrock Agents to act as a software application builder assistant.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-generative-ai-based-application-builder-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Upgrade Assistant Now Supports Upgrading to Centralized Package Mangement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use the .NET Upgrade Assistant tool to upgrade your projects to use NuGet Central Package Management (CPM).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-upgrade-assistant-cpm-upgrade 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 7: Enhanced AI Assistant for VCS, Debugger Updates, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 16:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re back with another set of features and improvements in the latest IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 Early Access Program build! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. As we start winding down the Early Access Program […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Your Company Adopt Remote Development?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 16:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adopting remote development is a significant decision for any company. At JetBrains, we talk to many customers about this shift. While we see growing demand, we also encounter many misconceptions about what remote development with cloud development environments (CDEs) can and cannot do. 1. What problems can you solve with remote development Before diving into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2024/10/should-your-company-adopt-remote-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from Amazon Rekognition people pathing: Exploring other alternatives</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 16:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After careful consideration, we made the decision to discontinue Rekognition people pathing on October 31, 2025. New customers will not be able to access the capability effective October 24, 2024, but existing customers will be able to use the capability as normal until October 31, 2025. This post discusses an alternative solution to Rekognition people pathing and how you can implement this solution in your applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transitioning-from-amazon-rekognition-people-pathing-exploring-other-alternatives/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to correctly use access tokens and ID tokens in your client application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 15:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the differences between access tokens and ID tokens and how to use them securely in your applications. This blog post explains why access tokens should be treated as opaque by client apps, and offers best practices for secure token handling.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/access-tokens-and-id-tokens 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Security incident response</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 15:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Microsoft 365 Certification verifies security incident response best practices.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-security-incident-response 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It rather involved being on the other side of the airtight hatchway: Defeating ASLR after you’ve gained RCE via ROP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you defeat ASLR, then you can defeat ASLR.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241024-00/?p=110417 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm and Rider Are Now Free for Non-Commercial Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 12:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a change in our licensing model that we believe will benefit the developer community – WebStorm and Rider are now free for non-commercial use! Read on to learn more about the change and why we’re making it, and be sure to check out the FAQ section below for additional details. What’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/24/webstorm-and-rider-are-now-free-for-non-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Microsoft 365 Copilot: Developer Camp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 12:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            📅 Date: November 07, 2024 | 🕘 Time: 9:00 AM – 10:30 AM (PT) |📍 Virtual Live Event: https://aka.ms/copilotdevcamp/live We’re thrilled to announce Microsoft 365 Copilot: Developer Camp 2024 – an exciting live event designed to inspire and empower developers to build next-generation Microsoft 365 Copilot Agents. We are inviting you in this adventure to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/join-the-microsoft-365-copilot-developer-camp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade Your Windows Forms .NET Projects to the Latest .NET Version for Enhanced Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Each release of .NET introduces a host of new features and bug fixes that enhance both performance and security. To leverage these benefits both service and desktop application developers must upgrade their applications to the latest .NET versions. Just like other developers wanting to take advantage of the latest .NET enhancements, we are actively upgrading […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/upgrade-your-windows-forms-net-projects-to-the-latest-net-version-for-enhanced-security 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Us Anything! Q&amp;A Session on Reddit With the CLion Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 08:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a while since the last Ask Me Anything session on Reddit with the CLion team. Today, we would like to get back to our roots and spend some time together to give you the opportunity to ask any questions you would like in r/cpp. Our team will be there, ready to provide you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/10/ama-reddit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2.4 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 07:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor version for IntelliJ IDEA – 2024.2.4. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, please […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-2-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specify runtime requirements in app manifest: Your key to success across Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Specify Runtime Requirements in App Manifest: Your Key to Success across Microsoft 365 Hosts Through extensive user research, we’ve identified what M365 users value most for boosting productivity. They want uninterrupted workflows, an all-in-one workspace, and minimal context switching. With this insight, we evolved Microsoft 365 into a unified platform across Teams, Outlook, M365 app […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/specify-runtime-requirements-in-app-manifest-your-key-to-success-across-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking generative AI for enterprises: How SnapLogic powers their low-code Agent Creator using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we learn how SnapLogic&#39;s Agent Creator leverages Amazon Bedrock to provide a low-code platform that enables enterprises to quickly develop and deploy powerful generative AI applications without deep technical expertise.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-generative-ai-for-enterprises-how-snaplogic-powers-their-low-code-agent-creator-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-generation learning experience using Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude: Innovation from Classworks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 19:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how Classworks uses Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet to deliver next-generation differentiated learning with Wittly.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/next-generation-learning-experience-using-amazon-bedrock-and-anthropics-claude-innovation-from-classworks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune a BGE embedding model using synthetic data from Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 19:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock to create synthetic data, fine-tune a BAAI General Embeddings (BGE) model, and deploy it using Amazon SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-a-bge-embedding-model-using-synthetic-data-from-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost post-call analytics with Amazon Q in QuickSight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 18:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to unlock powerful post-call analytics and visualizations, empowering your organization to make data-driven decisions and drive continuous improvement.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-post-call-analytics-with-amazon-q-in-quicksight/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a next generation chat assistant with Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Connect, Amazon Lex, LangChain, and WhatsApp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 18:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy a contextual AI assistant. We build a solution which provides users with a familiar and convenient interface using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Lex, and Amazon Connect, with WhatsApp as the channel.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-next-generation-chat-assistant-with-amazon-bedrock-amazon-connect-amazon-lex-langchain-and-whatsapp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eShop infused with AI – a comprehensive intelligent app sample</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Go beyond a simple demo app that demonstrates a chat bot and explore a real-world scale application that is infused with AI and illustrates the value of intelligent apps with features like semantic search, summarization, classification, sentiment scoring, chatbot, test data generation, evaluation tool, and E2E testing.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/e-shop-infused-with-ai-comprehensive-intelligent-dotnet-app-sample 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DirectSR Preview: Now Supporting AMD FidelityFX™ Super Resolution (FSR) 3.1 Upscaler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 17:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following our initial announcement of the DirectSR preview, we are pleased to share an update. DirectSR, our standardized super resolution (SR) API for D3D12 titles, now supports FSR 3.1 (upscaler-only), bringing enhanced upscaling capabilities to further improve your gaming experience. Learn more about FSR 3.1 here. What’s New with FSR 3.1? With this update, developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directsr-preview-fsr-3-1-upscaler 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I create a Windows Runtime IRandom­Access­Stream around a bunch of bytes or a classic COM IStream?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another wrapper function.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241023-00/?p=110411 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model-Based Testing with Testcontainers and Jqwik</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 13:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We demonstrate how to use model-based testing with jqwik and Testcontainers to automate regression testing on a REST API across different application environments.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/model-based-testing-testcontainers-jqwik/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Hands-On with Visual Studio, .NET, AI, and More at Live! 360 next month.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio LIVE! Orlando 2024 November 17-22 | Loews Royal Pacific Resort, Orlando, FL We’re only four weeks away from the final Visual Studio Live! event of the year, and we’re close to capacity! Live! 360 Orlando offers something for everyone—whether you’re a developer, IT professional, data specialist, or cybersecurity expert. You’ll have the opportunity […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/live-360-orlando-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending Messages to the Original Sender with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday I blogged about a small, convenience feature we snuck into he release of Wolverine 3.0 last week for a JasperFx Software customer I wrote about in Combo HTTP Endpoint and Message Handler with Wolverine 3.0. Today I’d like to show some additions to Wolverine 3.0 just to improve its ability to send responses back to the original sending application or … Continue reading Sending Messages to the Original Sender with Wolverine →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI foundation model training on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how organizations can cost-effectively customize and adapt FMs using AWS managed services such as Amazon SageMaker training jobs and Amazon SageMaker HyperPod. We discuss how these powerful tools enable organizations to optimize compute resources and reduce the complexity of model training and fine-tuning. We explore how you can make an informed decision about which Amazon SageMaker service is most applicable to your business needs and requirements.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate fine-tuning of Llama 3.x models with the new visual designer for Amazon SageMaker Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will show you how to set up an automated LLM customization (fine-tuning) workflow so that the Llama 3.x models from Meta can provide a high-quality summary of SEC filings for financial applications. Fine-tuning allows you to configure LLMs to achieve improved performance on your domain-specific tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-fine-tuning-of-llama-3-x-models-with-the-new-visual-designer-for-amazon-sagemaker-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement Amazon SageMaker domain cross-Region disaster recovery using custom Amazon EFS instances</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we guide you through a step-by-step process to seamlessly migrate and safeguard your SageMaker domain from one active Region to another passive or active Region, including all associated user profiles and files.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-amazon-sagemaker-domain-cross-region-disaster-recovery-using-custom-amazon-efs-instances/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soccer Analytics Copilot with Azure SQL and OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Football (aka Soccer in US 😀) Analisys Copilot provides an intuitive interface for users to interact with complex football data without needing advanced technical skills. By utilizing natural language processing, users can ask questions and retrieve detailed insights from vast datasets, including competitions, matches, teams, players, and events. This makes data exploration accessible to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/soccer-analytics-copilot-with-azure-sql-and-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Interview: Nana Janashia on Her Journey to DevOps and First Impressions of TeamCity Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 16:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to bring you an exclusive interview with Nana Janashia, the mastermind behind the largest DevOps YouTube channel – TechWorld with Nana. Nana has built an incredible career, sharing valuable insights about automation, cloud-native technologies, and everything DevOps with her global audience. But did you know that her journey started in marketing? In this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/exclusive-interview-nana-janashia-teamcity-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker at Cloud Expo Asia: GenAI, Security, and New Innovations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 15:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Cloud Expo Asia 2024, Docker showcased its latest innovations in AI integration, security best practices, and product updates, highlighting how containers empower GenAI workflows and enable efficient, secure software development.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-at-cloud-expo-asia-genai-security-and-new-innovations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET MAUI Welcomes Syncfusion Open-source Contributions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the release of the Syncfusion Toolkit for .NET MAUI, a set of free, open-source controls for .NET MAUI! Syncfusion has made 14 impressive UI controls freely available for .NET MAUI developers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-maui-welcomes-syncfusion-open-source-contributions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did Windows 95 shrink the default font size of windowed MS-DOS apps?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The effect was that it shrunk, but only sometimes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241022-00/?p=110401 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth Challenge Returns in November!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Prepare yourselves for the second season of the JetBrains Academy Youth Challenge, the competition for young coders and mathematicians. If you missed out last time or are ready to prove yourself again, this is your chance to win special prizes and compete with students worldwide. Choose your track The challenge continues with two tracks: math […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/10/22/youth-challenge-returns-in-november/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Mellum: JetBrains’ New LLM Built for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has taken a major step forward in advancing AI-driven development tools with the launch of Mellum, a proprietary large language model (LLM) specifically designed to assist software developers. Currently available only with JetBrains AI Assistant, Mellum provides faster, smarter, and more contextually aware code completion. There are hundreds of LLMs. Why Mellum? Unlike typical […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/10/22/introducing-mellum-jetbrains-new-llm-built-for-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug CMake Scripts on Linux with Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you are working on a CMake project that targets Linux, you may have encountered some challenges when trying to debug your CMake scripts and CMakeLists.txt files. You may have wondered why your variables are not set correctly, or why your custom commands are not executed as expected. Or you may have simply wanted to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/debug-cmake-scripts-on-linux-with-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip User Experience Survey Results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Recently, we conducted our first DataGrip UX Survey to better understand and prioritize the pain points that have the greatest impact on your experience. The data and feedback we gathered have helped us refine our plans to focus on what matters most to you. In this post, we’ll highlight the key findings from the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/10/22/datagrip-user-experience-survey-results/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding more extensions to Result&lt;T&gt;: Working with the result pattern - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to extend your LINQ-based result pattern code to handle more scenarios, such as Task&amp;gt; and collections of Result
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/working-with-the-result-pattern-part-3-adding-more-extensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Godot Game Builds With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Godot, an open-source game engine known for its versatility and simplicity, is gaining popularity among both indie developers and the broader game development community. While Godot comes with its own scripting language, GDScript, it also supports the widely-used C# language, familiar to Unity and Unreal Engine developers. In this tutorial, we will use “Dodge the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/10/automating-godot-game-builds-with-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop exposing your MediatR command/query in minimal API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MediatR has become a popular tool for implementing the mediator pattern in .NET applications, allowing developers to decouple request handlers from their senders. While MediatR offers numerous benefits, exposing its commands directly in APIs can lead to unexpected complications. In this article, we&#39;ll explore the potential issues that
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/stop-exposing-mediatr-command-minimal-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Maximizing Efficiency in .NET with Spargine’s JsonSerialization Class</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine, an open-source .NET 8 project, includes essential assemblies and NuGet packages developed since .NET 2. The JsonSerialization class facilitates efficient JSON operations with methods for serialization, deserialization, and validation.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/10/22/boost-your-net-projects-maximizing-efficiency-in-net-with-spargines-jsonserialization-class/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring C# 11 Features: What&amp;#x27;s New and How to Use It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# has been a popular programming language for many years now. It continuously evolves to include new features and adopt recent trends. Its flexibility makes it a language ideal for many different domains and platforms like desktop applications, enterprise systems, web development, games, cross-platform, and native mobile applications. Back when asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/exploring-c-11-features-whats-new-and-how-to-use-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java OpenJDK October 2024 Patch &amp; Security Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello Java customers! We are happy to announce the latest October 2024 patch &amp;amp; security update release for the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK. Download and install the binaries today. OpenJDK 21.0.5 OpenJDK 17.0.13 OpenJDK 11.0.25 Check our release notes page for details on fixes and enhancements. The source code of our builds is available now […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-openjdk-oct-2024-patch-security-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: How Microsoft streamlined regulatory compliance with GenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 23:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customer Case Study: How Microsoft streamlined regulatory compliance with GenAI Today we’re featuring an external blog from EY featuring Microsoft’s Semantic Kernel. This case study reveals how Microsoft legal teams are using GenAI to confidently manage regulatory change. Learn more here: How Microsoft uses GenAI for compliance | EY – Global How can you generate […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-how-microsoft-streamlined-regulatory-compliance-with-genai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 19:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re pleased to announce the general availability (GA) of Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import. This feature empowers customers to import and use their customized models alongside existing foundation models (FMs) through a single, unified API.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import-now-generally-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows MIDI Services October 2024 Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 18:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a little while since I last posted an update about Windows MIDI Services outside of our Discord Server, but we’ve been busy! With all the announcements today at Qualcomm’s Snapdragon Summit, I thought I’d dive in a bit on where we are with our new MIDI 1.0 and MIDI 2.0 stack on Windows. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/windows-midi-services-oct-2024-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Great Music with Windows on Arm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 18:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This week has been amazing, with our musician work really coming together at Qualcomm Snapdragon Summit 2024! There’s only so much time available in a keynote, so I thought I’d expand a bit more on the music-related announcements, especially for the new in-box features. Music is all around us. We purposefully listen to music in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/making-music-on-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a serverless web application to edit images using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a sample solution that you can use to deploy an image editing application by using AWS serverless services and generative AI services. We use Amazon Bedrock and an Amazon Titan FM that allow you to edit images by using prompts.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-a-serverless-web-application-to-edit-images-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brilliant words, brilliant writing: Using AWS AI chips to quickly deploy Meta LLama 3-powered applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will introduce how to use an Amazon EC2 Inf2 instance to cost-effectively deploy multiple industry-leading LLMs on AWS Inferentia2, a purpose-built AWS AI chip, helping customers to quickly test and open up an API interface to facilitate performance benchmarking and downstream application calls at the same time.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/brilliant-words-brilliant-writing-using-aws-ai-chips-to-quickly-deploy-meta-llama-3-powered-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for building robust generative AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Agents – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into the architectural considerations and development lifecycle practices that can help you build robust, scalable, and secure intelligent agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-for-building-robust-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-agents-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB EF Core Provider: What’s New?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest updates to the MongoDB EF Core Provider brings updates to change tracking, index creation, complex queries, and transactions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mongodb-ef-core-provider-whats-new 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.3 EAP 5: Support for the Call Hierarchy in CLion Nova and the New Project Status Widget</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new CLion 2024.3 EAP build, 243.20847.43, is out. You can download it for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 EAP This build introduces two major features: support for function call hierarchy in CLion Nova and a new project status […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/10/clion-2024-3-eap-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Gap Between the Classic and New UIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 15:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Any significant update to the UI and UX of a professional tool is likely to pose challenges for its users. We recognize that the new UI of JetBrains IDEs represents a major change and understand how unsettling it can be when the software you rely on for productivity is significantly reworked. However, in order for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/bridging-the-gap-between-the-classic-and-new-uis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to Azure Cosmos DB’s Portal Networking Settings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 14:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to share with you an update to the Azure Cosmos DB networking configuration options within the Azure Portal. This update introduces a split in the IP address list, now presented as two distinct categories: user IP addresses and Portal Middleware IPs. Managing IP access control policies is essential for maintaining a secure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/updates-to-azure-cosmos-dbs-portal-networking-settings 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does adding WS_MINIMIZE­BOX change how my window behaves when the user presses Win&#43;D?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It minimizes your window if it can.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241021-00/?p=110393 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Docker AI Tools for Devs to Provide Context for Better Code Fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to map your codebase in order to provide context for creating better AI-generated code fixes.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/using-docker-ai-tools-for-devs-to-provide-context-for-better-code-fixes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 6: Updated Structure Tool Window, Streamlined GraalVM Native Image Debugging, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP build is here, bringing new features and improvements for you to explore! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP 6 In this update, we’ve […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/10/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement security headers for an ASP.NET Core API supporting OpenAPI Swagger UI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 07:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article shows how to implement security headers for an application supporting an API and a swagger UI created from a open API in .NET 9. The security headers are implemented using the NetEscapades.AspNetCore.SecurityHeaders Nuget packages from Andrew Lock. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/WebApiOpenApi Deploying a web application which supports both an API and a UI have different […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/10/21/implement-security-headers-for-an-api-supporting-openapi-swagger-ui/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entity Framework Core Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 04:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Entity Framework Core (EF Core) is an object-relational mapper (ORM), enabling us to work with a database using .NET objects, eliminating much of the data-access code we usually need to write. EF Core supports many databases, including SQL Server, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and more, making it highly versatile. While EF Core provides many conveniences, following […] The post Entity Framework Core Best Practices appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing IBM Granite AI Models Now Available on Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IBM&#39;s Granite AI models, optimized for business applications, are now available on Docker Hub, making it easier for developers to deploy, scale, and customize AI-powered apps.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-ibm-granite-ai-models-now-available-on-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combo HTTP Endpoint and Message Handler with Wolverine 3.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 01:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2024/21_10_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Wolverine 3.0 last week, we snuck in a small feature at the last minute that was a request from a JasperFx Software customer. Specifically, they had a couple instances of a logical message type that needed to be handled both from Wolverine’s Rabbit MQ message transport, and also from the request … Continue reading Combo HTTP Endpoint and Message Handler with Wolverine 3.0 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
