<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Copilot Chat Prompts .NET Devs Should Steal Today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial intelligence is quickly becoming a key part of the modern .NET developer’s toolkit. With GitHub Copilot Chat, you can save countless hours, eliminate friction, and unlock new levels of creativity by simply asking the right questions. But what exactly should you ask? Here are five GitHub Copilot Chat prompts every .NET dev shoul
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/5-copilot-chat-prompts-dotnet-devs-should-steal-today 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Browser Automation Tool (Preview) in Azure AI Foundry Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 15:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview T
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/announcing-the-browser-automation-tool-preview-in-azure-ai-foundry-agent-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating FedRAMP Compliance with Docker Hardened Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) compliance costs typically range from $450,000 to over $2 million and take 12 to 18 months to achieve, time your competitors are using to capture government contracts. While you’re spending months configuring FIPS cryptography, hardening security baselines, and navigating 400+ security controls, your competitors are already shipping to...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/fedramp-compliance-with-hardened-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I disable pieces of the property sheet for a service in the Services MMC snap-in?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was developing a service, and they didn&#39;t want users to be able to change the service&#39;s startup type (e.g. change it from auto-start to disabled). They saw that other services had the &amp;quot;Startup type&amp;quot; field disabled. How can they get in on that action? They found that that they could get close to the desired behavior by restricting
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250806-00/?p=111440 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next Evolution of Docker Hardened Images: Customizable, FedRAMP Ready, AI Migration Agent, and Deeper Integrations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We launched Docker Hardened Images (DHI) in May, and in just two and a half months, adoption has accelerated rapidly across industries. From nimble startups to global enterprises, organizations are turning to DHI to achieve near-zero CVEs, shrink their attack surface, and harden their software supply chain, all without slowing down developers. In a short...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/the-next-evolution-of-docker-hardened-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Drift: The Pitfall of Local Machines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve seen it before. Someone says, “It works on my machine,” and suddenly you’re deep in a rabbit hole trying to understand why a project that works perfectly on one machine fails to build or test on another. That’s configuration drift – when a developer’s actual environment starts to deviate from the project’s intended configuration. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/08/configuration-drift-the-pitfall-of-local-machines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 11:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to this month’s Java Annotated Monthly – your pit stop for all things related to Java, Kotlin, frameworks, and the ever-shifting tech scene. From helpful reads to red-hot takes, we’ve lined up a range of articles for curious devs and ambitious teams. But wait, there’s more! As always, our AI corner is here, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/java-annotated-monthly-august-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a RAG application with LangChain and Local LLMs powered by Ollama</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Local large language models (LLMs) provide significant advantages for developers and organizations. Key benefits include enhanced data privacy, as sensitive information remains entirely within your own infrastructure, and offline functionality, enabling uninterrupted work even without internet access. While cloud-based LLM services are conveni
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/build-a-rag-application-with-langchain-and-local-llms-powered-by-ollama 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Fixed in IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the first-ever standalone What’s Fixed overview of an IntelliJ IDEA release! We are always working hard to make the IDE even more stable, reliable, and enjoyable to use. In previous releases, information about this work was blended into the What’s New content, making it very long and sometimes hard to grasp. To address […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/whats-fixed-intellij-idea-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Notebook Meets IntelliJ Platform: Advancing IDE Plugin Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The value of extensibility The ability to extend and customize software, from game mods to browser extensions, gives users a sense of freedom and the chance to bring their ideas to life. JetBrains IDEs already provide this sense of freedom through their support for plugins. For some time now, creating plugins for JetBrains IDEs has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/08/kotlin-notebook-meets-intellij-platform-advancing-ide-plugin-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use EdDSA signatures to validate tokens in ASP.NET Core using OpenID Connect</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 09:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some identity providers use the EdDSA / ED25519 algorithm to sign and issue tokens. This post shows how to validate the tokens using the Nuget package from ScottBrady and ASP.NET Core. Using the default OpenID Connect setup, the keys are not read and the tokens cannot be validated. The error message could return something like […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/08/06/use-eddsa-signatures-to-validate-tokens-in-asp-net-core-using-openid-connect/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI for Beginners - Java Edition launched</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 08:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IN ONE hour, all ONLINE, complete our ne
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/generative-ai-for-beginners-java-edition-launched 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI assistant using Amazon Q Business with Amazon S3 clickable URLs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 01:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build an AI assistant using Amazon Q Business that responds to user requests based on your enterprise documents stored in an S3 bucket, and how the users can use the reference URLs in the AI assistant responses to view or download the referred documents, and verify the AI responses to practice responsible AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ai-assistant-using-amazon-q-business-with-amazon-s3-clickable-urls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Providing ChatGPT to the Entire U.S. Federal Workforce</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, OpenAI for Government is announcing a new partnership with the U.S. General Services Administration (GSA) to launch a transformative initiative. For the next year, ChatGPT Enterprise will be available to the entire federal executive branch workforce at essentially no cost.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/providing-chatgpt-to-the-entire-us-federal-workforce 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework August 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 22:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for August 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of August 05, 2025. This update contains non-secu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-august-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (July 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 20:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.07.25 registry release, 2025-06-20,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone’s a Snowflake: Designing Hardened Image Processes for the Real World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 18:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hardened container images and distroless software are the new hotness as startups and incumbents alike pile into the fast-growing market. In theory, hardened images provide not only a smaller attack surface but operational simplicity. In practice, there remains a fundamental – and often painful – tension between the promised security perfection of hardened images and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hardened-image-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing MCP Support in AI Shell Preview 6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 18:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI Shell Preview 6 is here! We are super excited to announce the latest preview release of AI Shell. This release focuses on enhancing the user experience with new features, improved error handling, and better integration with Model Context Protocol (MCP) tools. What&#39;s new at a glance
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/preview-6-ai-shell 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring new Agent Quality and NLP evaluators for .NET AI applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building AI applications, comprehensive evaluation is crucial to ensure your systems deliver accurate, reliable, and contextually appropriate responses. We&#39;re excited to announce key enhancements to the Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Evaluation libraries with new
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/exploring-agent-quality-and-nlp-evaluators 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights from Microsoft Exchange with the Microsoft Exchange connector for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a fully managed, generative AI-powered assistant that helps enterprises unlock the value of their data and knowledge. With Amazon Q Business, you can quickly find answers to questions, generate summaries and content, and complete tasks by using the information and expertise stored across your company’s various data sources and enterprise systems. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-from-microsoft-exchange-with-the-microsoft-exchange-connector-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2015 Retirement: Support reminder for older versions of Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 16:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Support for Visual Studio 2015 will end on October 14, 2025. If you’re using an older version of Visual Studio, we want to keep you productive and secure when using Visual Studio, and strongly recommend you upgrade to Visual Studio 2022, which brings the power of Copilot to your development workflow. It also contains key productivity improve
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2015-retirement-support-reminder-for-older-versions-of-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Conf 2025 - Announcing the Call for Content</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey .NET developers! 🎉 The moment we&#39;ve all been waiting for is here - the Call for Content for .NET Conf 2025 is officially open! We want YOU to be part of this amazing celebration of everyt
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-conf-2025-announcing-the-call-for-content 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RustRover 2025.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 15:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This version introduces major debugger enhancements, including remote and on-chip support, a new color scheme, improved borrow checker assistance, additional Rust learning resources, and more. RustRover goes AI Junie, the in-IDE coding agent, is now 30% faster, connects to external sources via MCP, and supports remote development. AI Assistant adds even smarter code completion for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/08/05/rustrover-2025-2-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable AI with Azure Cosmos DB - Video Series</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scalable AI in Action with Azure Cosmos DB – A Monthly Partner Showcase As AI continues to reshape industries, customers are seeking scalable, real-time solutions that integrate seamlessly with their existing data platforms. Azure Cosmos DB, with its global distribution, low latency, and multi-model support, is uniquely p
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/scalable-ai-with-azure-cosmos-db-video-series 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are Windows semiannual updates named H1 and H2?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows issues monthly updates, but the bigger updates happen twice a year. The one that happens in the first half of the year is called the H1 release, and the one in the second half is the H2 release. The letter H refers to &amp;quot;half&amp;quot;, which is the same pattern used by finance people to refer to the first and second halves of fiscal years. (Q
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250805-00/?p=111435 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin DSL: What’s New?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 13:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the last few TeamCity releases, we made some improvements to the Kotlin DSL. This is a summary of these enhancements. Custom path for Kotlin DSL files TeamCity has always had strict requirements regarding the directory location for Kotlin DSL files. It insisted on saving the files under the .teamcity directory, which had some drawbacks. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/08/kotlin-dsl-what-s-new/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 13:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Along with making Laravel Idea free for PhpStorm users, this release brings improvements to the remote development experience, JetBrains AI tools, and more. Download PhpStorm 2025.2 Junie coding agent MCP support Support for the Model Context Protocol (MCP) allows you to connect Junie to external sources like databases, file systems, and APIs. You can now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/08/phpstorm-2025-2-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2025.2 Is Now Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 12:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2025.2 introduces updates for working with HTTP servers, smarter inspections powered by data flow analysis (DFA), and a new non-blocking Welcome screen. This release also brings significant quality improvements to golangci-lint support, including version 2, making the integration more robust for real-time code analysis. Let’s take a closer look at all the new additions […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/08/05/goland-2025-2-is-now-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Your Ideas Clickable With Kineto by JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 12:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While developing a website or an app, you’ll encounter loads of technical challenges that need to be solved – from how to code the functionality to how to host it. Delivering even a simple to-do app requires a hefty technology stack, a team of professionals, and hours of testing and maintenance. This is the reason […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kineto/2025/08/make-your-ideas-clickable-with-kineto-by-jetbrains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.2 Is Here: Better CLion Nova, Smarter Embedded Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion 2025.2 is now available. This latest version of the JetBrains IDE for C and C++ includes the following key updates: You can download CLion 2025.2 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu, or via a patch update from version 2025.1. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.2 CLion Nova […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/clion-2025-2-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2025.2: AI Toolkit for AI Engineers and More!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2025.2 introduces the AI Toolkit: everything AI engineers need – now natively supported in your IDE. This release’s other highlights include the last supported version of PyCharm Community, improvements to AI Assistant, Junie, and notebooks, as well as a persistent UI for updating .lock files and other enhancements. Download the latest version from our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/08/pycharm-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains is a Platinum Sponsor of the Godot Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 10:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we believe deeply in the value of diverse developer tools and open-source ecosystems, and so we’re thrilled to announce that we’ve just become a Platinum Sponsor of the Godot Foundation! Godot is a fantastic game engine, with a very different approach to other game engines. It’s open source, not for profit and driven […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/05/jetbrains-is-a-platinum-sponsor-of-the-godot-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passkey support for ASP.NET Core identity: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at the passkey support added to ASP.NET Core Identity and the Blazor Web App template, explore how it works, and look at the implementation
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-6-passkey-support-for-aspnetcore-identity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Outside-In Approach to Discover Unknown Codebases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 08:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Jumping into a new codebase is never easy. It takes time, patience, and often a fair bit of frustration. And when the codebase is legacy — undocumented, inconsistent, and complex — the challenge grows infinitely...In this article, based on the work we&#39;ve done with my colleague Alexandre
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/outside-approach-discover-unknown-codebases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to integration test exception handlers in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 07:34:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Global exception handling in ASP.NET Core is one of those features you often just set and forget. Unless you realize that your error log is awfully quiet, applications with failing or misconfigured exception handling can cause severe problems for your end users. In this post, I&#39;ll show
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/how-to-integration-test-exception-handlers-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost tracking multi-tenant model inference on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 01:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to track and analyze multi-tenant model inference costs on Amazon Bedrock using the Converse API&#39;s requestMetadata parameter. The solution includes an ETL pipeline using AWS Glue and Amazon QuickSight dashboards to visualize usage patterns, token consumption, and cost allocation across different tenants and departments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cost-tracking-multi-tenant-model-inference-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating worst case frontier risks of open weight LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_25/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this paper, we study the worst-case frontier risks of releasing gpt-oss. We introduce malicious fine-tuning (MFT), where we attempt to elicit maximum capabilities by fine-tuning gpt-oss to be as capable as possible in two domains: biology and cybersecurity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/estimating-worst-case-frontier-risks-of-open-weight-llms 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gpt-oss-120b &amp; gpt-oss-20b Model Card</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_24/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We introduce gpt-oss-120b and gpt-oss-20b, two open-weight reasoning models available under the Apache 2.0 license and our gpt-oss usage policy.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-oss-model-card 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing gpt-oss</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re releasing gpt-oss-120b and gpt-oss-20b—two state-of-the-art open-weight language models that deliver strong real-world performance at low cost. Available under the flexible Apache 2.0 license, these models outperform similarly sized open models on reasoning tasks, demonstrate strong tool use capabilities, and are optimized for efficient deployment on consumer hardware.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-oss 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Weights and AI for All</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI’s next frontier isn’t just about capability—it’s about who gets to use it. Our mission to put AI in the hands of as many people as possible is what drives us. Today’s release of our most capable open-weights models is a major step forward that makes advanced AI more open, flexible, and accessible worldwide.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/open-weights-and-ai-for-all 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Docker MCP Toolkit Works with VS Code Copilot Agent Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 20:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the rapidly evolving landscape of software development, integrating modern AI tools is essential to boosting productivity and enhancing the developer experience. One such advancement is the integration of Docker&#39;s Model Context Protocol (MCP) Toolkit with Visual Studio Code’s GitHub Copilot Agent Mode. This powerful combination transforms how developers interact with containerized applications, enabling autonomous...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-toolkit-and-vs-code-copilot-agent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Questions: What You Should Really Be Asking Your Hardened Image Provider Before You Press the Buy Button</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 19:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When evaluating hardened image providers, don&#39;t just look for buzzwords like &amp;quot;zero-CVE&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;minimal.&amp;quot; True security in a dynamic environment demands a nuanced understanding of their process, their commitment, and their flexibility. For platform, DevOps, and SecOps teams, these are the critical questions that reveal whether a provider offers genuine security that enhances your workflow,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/container-security-hardened-images-questions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI judging AI: Scaling unstructured text analysis with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we highlight how you can deploy multiple generative AI models in Amazon Bedrock to instruct an LLM model to create thematic summaries of text responses. We then show how to use multiple LLM models as a jury to review these LLM-generated summaries and assign a rating to judge the content alignment between the summary title and summary description.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-judging-ai-scaling-unstructured-text-analysis-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI-driven course content generation system using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore each component in detail, along with the technical implementation of the two core modules: course outline generation and course content generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-an-ai-driven-course-content-generation-system-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Handmade.com modernizes product image and description handling with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon OpenSearch Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Handmade.com, a leading hand-crafts marketplace, modernized their product description handling by implementing an AI-driven pipeline using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon OpenSearch Service. The solution combines Anthropic&#39;s Claude 3.7 Sonnet LLM for generating descriptions, Amazon Titan Text Embeddings V2 for vector embedding, and semantic search capabilities to automate and enhance product descriptions across their catalog of over 60,000 items.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-handmade-com-modernizes-product-image-and-description-handling-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-opensearch-service/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate your open-source dependency scanning with Advanced Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Any experiences that require additional setup is cumbersome, especially when there are multiple people needed. In GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps, we&#39;re working to make it easier to enable features and scale out enablement across your enterprise. You can now automatically inject the dependency scanning task into a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/automate-your-open-source-dependency-scanning-with-advanced-security 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 brings powerful updates to help you stay productive, write better code, and confidently adopt the latest technologies. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu. This blog post gives you a quick overview […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Update C&#43;&#43; syntax using Next Edit Suggestions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 16:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working in a C++ repo, you often are maintaining and updating existing code just as often as you are writing new code. However, updating code in C++ can often require navigating to several different locations in a file to ensure consistency, which can disrupt your logical workflow. For example, changing a data member’s access level typi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/dynamically-update-c-syntax-using-next-edit-suggestions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant Update: Better Context, Greater Offline Flexibility, Deeper IDE Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 15:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains AI Assistant just got a major upgrade, giving you smarter completions, better project understanding, and more control over how AI works in your IDE. Smarter code completion: more languages, model flexibility, and better context-awareness With ongoing improvements to our Mellum model and smarter context collection via RAG, AI completion now provides more relevant results […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/08/jetbrains-ai-assistant-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in Azure AI Foundry | July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 15:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Deep Research Agent (Public Preview): Automate complex, multi-step web research with OpenAI’s o3-deep-research model, now available in Azure AI Foundry Agent Service. GPT-image-1 model: Adds input fidelity controls and partial image streaming for advanced image editing and generation.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/whats-new-in-azure-ai-foundry-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new Dependabot NuGet updater: 65% faster with native .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you&#39;ve ever waited impatiently for Dependabot to update your .NET dependencies, or worse, watched it fail with cryptic errors, we have some great news. Over the past year, the Dependabot team has worked on a refactor of the NuGet updater, and the results are impressive. From hybrid to native The previous NuGet updater use
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/the-new-dependabot-nuget-updater 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip and Database tools UX Survey #2 Results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 14:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Hello, DataGrip community! We’re back with the results of our second UX Survey. It’s been nearly a year since the first one, and thanks to your feedback, we’ve made some significant improvements to enhance your experience with DataGrip and Database tools. What was done based on the previous survey: And much more! Check out […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/08/04/datagrip-and-database-tools-ux-survey-2-results/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I read more than 4GB of data from a file in a single call to &lt;code&gt;Read­File&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The nNumber­Of­Bytes­To­Read parameter to Read­File is a 32-bit unsigned integer, which limits the number of bytes that could be read at once to 4GB. What if you need to read more than 4GB? The Read­File function cannot read more than 4GB of data at a time. At the time the function was or
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250804-00/?p=111432 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2025.2: Junie and AI Assistant Upgrades, Faster Rails Project Startup, Enhanced Bundler Management, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2025.2 is out! In this blog post, we briefly go over the highlights of this release. For a detailed description, check out our What’s New page. You can get the new build from our website or via the free Toolbox App. AI Assistant JetBrains AI Assistant has received a major upgrade, offering smarter code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/08/rubymine-2025-2-junie-and-ai-assistant-upgrades-faster-rails-project-startup-enhanced-bundler-management-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2025.2: TypeScript-Go Language Server Support, Baseline Support, Bun Improvements, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 12:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our second major release of 2025 is here! This release introduces various new features and addresses several challenges. Key improvements include experimental TypeScript-Go language server support, Baseline support, Bun improvements, and a range of essential updates. Starting with this release, we’ll be including noteworthy features from minor updates in our main release blog posts. Since […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/08/webstorm-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2025.2 Release Candidate Is Ready!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’ve made the Release Candidate for MPS 2025.2 available for you to download. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.2 RC Feel free to check out the earlier updates that the EAP 1 and EAP 2 builds introduced recently. The full list of fixed issues can be found here. Your JetBrains MPS team
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/08/the-mps-2025-2-rc-ready/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue and verify credentials using the Swiss Digital identity public beta, ASP.NET Core and .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 05:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to issue and verify identities (verifiable credentials) using the Swiss Digital identity and trust infrastructure, (swiyu), ASP.NET Core and .NET Aspire. The swiyu infrastructure is implemented using the provided generic containers which implement the OpenID for Verifiable Credential Issuance and the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations standards as well as many other […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/08/04/issuer-and-verify-credentials-using-the-swiss-digital-identity-public-beta-asp-net-core-and-net-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we’re optimizing ChatGPT for</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We build ChatGPT to help you thrive in all the ways you want. Learn how we&#39;re improving support for tough moments, have rolled out reminders to take breaks, and are working on better life advice, all guided by expert input.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/how-we&#39;re-optimizing-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Untapped Power of Veteran Engineers: Why Companies Are Overlooking Their Most Valuable Assets – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_08_2025/03_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_08_2025/03_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The content emphasizes the critical value of veteran software engineers, highlighting how their experience can enhance team outcomes beyond coding roles. It critiques the trend of assigning key positions to less experienced individuals, leading to poor project execution. The article proposes leveraging veteran engineers in management, mentorship, and technical consultancy to improve software development practices.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/08/03/the-untapped-power-of-veteran-engineers-why-companies-are-overlooking-their-most-valuable-assets-part-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Survive The Sprint - Dev Leader Weekly 104</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2025/02_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2025/02_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to survive your software development sprint or... consider moving on!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/02/how-to-survive-the-sprint-dev-leader-weekly-104 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-08-01</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2025/02_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 06:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2025/02_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/02/weekly-recap-20250801 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Keep Your Data Boundaries Intact in a Modular Monolith</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2025/02_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_08_2025/02_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want real boundaries in your modular monolith? This article shows how to enforce them at the database level using Postgres schemas, roles, and EF Core — so your modules can&#39;t step on each other&#39;s data, even by accident.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/how-to-keep-your-data-boundaries-intact-in-a-modular-monolith 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 19:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the newly announced Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser Tool. We explore why organizations need cloud-based browser automation and the limitations it addresses for FMs that require real-time data access. We talk about key use cases and the core capabilities of the AgentCore Browser Tool. We walk through how to get started with the tool.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-browser-tool/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Code Interpreter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 19:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Code Interpreter, a fully managed service that enables AI agents to securely execute code in isolated sandbox environments. We discuss how the AgentCore Code Interpreter helps solve challenges around security, scalability, and infrastructure management when deploying AI agents that need computational capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-the-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-code-interpreter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 16:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the release of TypeScript 5.9! If you&#39;re not familiar with TypeScript, it&#39;s a language that builds on JavaScript by adding syntax for types. With types, TypeScript makes it possible to check your code to avoid bugs ahead of time. The TypeScript type-checker does all this, and is also the foundation of grea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observing and evaluating AI agentic workflows with Strands Agents SDK and Arize AX</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 16:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present how the Arize AX service can trace and evaluate AI agent tasks initiated through Strands Agents, helping validate the correctness and trustworthiness of agentic workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/observing-and-evaluating-ai-agentic-workflows-with-strands-agents-sdk-and-arize-ax/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AIOps with Amazon Q Developer CLI and MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 15:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to implement a low-code no-code AIOps solution that helps organizations monitor, identify, and troubleshoot operational events while maintaining their security posture. We show how these technologies work together to automate repetitive tasks, streamline incident response, and enhance operational efficiency across your organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-aiops-with-amazon-q-developer-cli-and-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containerize legacy Spring Boot application using Amazon Q Developer CLI and MCP server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 15:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you’ll learn how you can use Amazon Q Developer command line interface (CLI) with Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers integration to modernize a legacy Java Spring Boot application running on premises and then migrate it to Amazon Web Services (AWS) by deploying it on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/containerize-legacy-spring-boot-application-using-amazon-q-developer-cli-and-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two related questions about keeping track of PIDs of IPC clients</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was writing a program that was intended to run in the background and was looking for recommendations on how to store its PID so that other programs can find it and start communicating with the background process. Another customer was writing a provider program that will have multiple clients connect to it. They want the p
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250801-00/?p=111427 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs. Java: Choosing the right tool for your next project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 13:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rust and Java couldn’t be any more different. One is a battle-tested giant with enterprise-scale use cases. The other is a relative newbie with a rapidly growing community and real-world applications. While Rust is praised for its focus on safety and performance, its complexity presents a challenge to adopters (arguably, the steep learning curve is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/08/01/rust-vs-java/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figma uses AI to transform digital design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Figma is transforming digital design with AI. David Kossnick shares how tools like Figma Make empower teams to prototype, collaborate, and build with AI—reshaping workflows for designers, developers, and non-technical creators alike.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/figma-david-kossnick 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Declarative Persistence in Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 19:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To continue a consistent theme about how Wolverine is becoming the antidote to high ceremony Clean/Onion Architecture approaches, Wolverine 4.8 added some significant improvements to its declarative persistence support (partially after seeing how a recent JasperFx Software client was encountering a little bit of repetitive code). A pattern I try to encourage — and many … Continue reading Improved Declarative Persistence in Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/07/31/improved-declarative-persistence-in-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenAI vs. Agentic AI: What Developers Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 19:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI (GenAI) and the models behind it have already reshaped how developers write code and build applications. But a new class of artificial intelligence is emerging: agentic AI. Unlike GenAI, which focuses on content generation, agentic systems can plan, reason, and take actions across multiple steps, enabling a new approach to building intelligent, goal-driven...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/genai-vs-agentic-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us at Azure Dev Summit 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 18:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The success of AI-powered apps and agents hinges not only on cutting edge models and AI platforms, but on the developers who are chartered with designing innovative services that are secure, scalable, and grounded in the right knowledge. The inaugural Azure Dev Summit on October 13-16, 2025
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//join-us-at-azure-dev-summit-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AWS Batch Support for Amazon SageMaker Training jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 17:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Batch now seamlessly integrates with Amazon SageMaker Training jobs. In this post, we discuss the benefits of managing and prioritizing ML training jobs to use hardware efficiently for your business. We also walk you through how to get started using this new capability and share suggested best practices, including the use of SageMaker training plans.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-aws-batch-support-for-amazon-sagemaker-training-jobs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured outputs with Amazon Nova: A guide for builders</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We launched constrained decoding to provide reliability when using tools for structured outputs. Now, tools can be used with Amazon Nova foundation models (FMs) to extract data based on complex schemas, reducing tool use errors by over 95%. In this post, we explore how you can use Amazon Nova FMs for structured output use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/structured-outputs-with-amazon-nova-a-guide-for-builders/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI agents unifying structured and unstructured data: Transforming support analytics and beyond with Amazon Q Plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to enhance Amazon Q with custom plugins to combine semantic search capabilities with precise analytics for AWS Support data. This solution enables more accurate answers to analytical questions by integrating structured data querying with RAG architecture, allowing teams to transform raw support cases and health events into actionable insights. Discover how this enhanced architecture delivers exact numerical analysis while maintaining natural language interactions for improved operational decision-making.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Strands Agents SDK: A technical deep dive into agent architectures and observability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we first introduce the Strands Agents SDK and its core features. Then we explore how it integrates with AWS environments for secure, scalable deployments, and how it provides rich observability for production use. Finally, we discuss practical use cases, and present a step-by-step example to illustrate Strands in action.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-strands-agents-sdk-a-technical-deep-dive-into-agent-architectures-and-observability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated .NET and JDBC Drivers with Native Vector Data Support for High-Performance AI Workload</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released major updates to our data access libraries, bringing native support for vector data to both the .NET and JDBC ecosystems, unlocking significant performance gains for AI and machine learning workloads. Microsoft.Data.SqlClient 6.1.0 With the new SqlVector class, you can now handle vector data in bin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/updated-net-and-jdbc-drivers-with-native-vector-data-support-for-high-performance-ai-workload 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The Security Issues Threatening AI Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is issue 1 of a new series - MCP Horror Stories - where we will examine critical security issues and vulnerabilities in the Model Context Protocol (MCP) ecosystem and how Docker MCP Toolkit provides enterprise-grade protection against these threats. What is MCP? The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is a standardized interface that enables AI...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-security-issues-threatening-ai-infrastructure/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build dynamic web research agents with the Strands Agents SDK and Tavily</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 14:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce how to combine Strands Agents with Tavily’s purpose-built web intelligence API, to create powerful research agents that excel at complex information gathering tasks while maintaining the security and compliance standards required for enterprise deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-dynamic-web-research-agents-with-the-strands-agents-sdk-and-tavily/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Use AI to Learn to Code?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 14:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ll start by acknowledging that you probably already do. And honestly? We get it. Programming is hard! Learning materials can be poorly structured and lack good visualizations. Sometimes your teacher is a math genius who is bad at talking. And hey, AI is pretty capable for beginner-level problems. It can make the implementation much faster […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/07/31/should-you-use-ai-to-learn/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A consequence of the weird &lt;code&gt;wReserved&lt;/code&gt; value at the start of the &lt;code&gt;DECIMAL&lt;/code&gt; structure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not too long ago, I explained why why there is a weird wReserved value at the start of the DECIMAL structure. Markus Grohs pointed out
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250731-00/?p=111423 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New with Mellum: Expanded Language Support and New Ways to Use it Locally</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 13:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This summer, we’re making Mellum, our code completion model, easier for developers to use locally, and we’re introducing support for more languages than ever. Here’s what’s new: Mellum-all – now on Hugging Face We’ve just released Mellum-all, the next open-source installation of Mellum, which has been trained to support all major programming languages. Earlier Mellum […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/07/whats-new-with-mellum-expanded-language-support-and-new-ways-to-use-it-locally/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why AI Agents as Your Team Should Be Your Next Learning Move</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 12:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s be honest: if you’re in software today, AI is already on your team—whether you’ve invited it or not. But here’s the critical truth every developer and team lead should understand: using AI tools is not the same as understanding AI agents. That’s why we created the course AI Agents as Your Team. It’s a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/07/31/ai-agents-free-course/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing TeamCity Recipes: Reusable CI/CD Building Blocks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 12:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Build steps are often repeated over and over – within a single project or team, or even across a whole organization. These patterns tend to get copy-pasted, manually adapted, and maintained in parallel. This can lead to inconsistencies and extra maintenance work. With the latest TeamCity release, we’re addressing that problem head-on. Say hello to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/07/introducing-teamcity-recipes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Quick-Fix Options: Smarter Automation and Cleaner Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 12:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern development is fast-paced – bugs, style violations, and code smells need to be caught early and fixed quickly. It’s also time-consuming and tedious to manually make fixes. That’s why Qodana’s Quick-Fix feature is designed to go beyond static analysis – it automatically improves your codebase using predefined strategies that fit your team’s needs. Quick-Fix […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/07/quick-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarter AI Edits in Visual Studio Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we first set out to get smarter AI edits in Visual Studio Copilot, we knew we were tackling a deeply complex problem. It wasn’t just about generating great suggestions—it was about figuring out how to seamlessly apply those suggestions to your code. While the idea seemed simple at first glance, the reality w
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/smarter-ai-edits-in-visual-studio-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CodeCanvas 2025.2: Now With Cursor and Jupyter Notebook Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 10:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CodeCanvas 2025.2 is here, and this release is packed with updates we think you’ll like. The main highlight is the support for Cursor and Jupyter notebooks. But there’s plenty more under the hood, including network policy controls, usage limits, and a bunch of smaller but useful improvements. Cursor support Cursor is one of the fastest-growing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/07/codecanvas-2025-2-now-with-cursor-and-jupyter-notebook-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Steps Up: Enhancing Bazel Support in CLion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 10:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains has officially taken over development and maintenance of the Bazel for CLion and Bazel for IntelliJ plugins. This shift allows us to tackle long-standing issues and improve the overall experience of working with Bazel projects in JetBrains IDEs. As of July 2025, these plugins are no longer offered by, nor affiliated with, Google. What’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/07/bazel-for-clion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazel Plugin Release: General Availability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 10:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Bazel Plugin for IntelliJ IDEA Is Now Generally Available! After much anticipation, we are finally ready to announce the general availability (GA) of the new Bazel plugin for IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, and GoLand – now developed by JetBrains! After months of focused development and valuable feedback from our EAP users, we’re officially launching our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/bazel-ga-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents with the A2A .NET SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 10:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI Agents with the A2A .NET SDK The AI development landscape is rapidly evolving. Autonomous agents are becoming increasingly sophisticated, specialized, and capable of handling complex tasks across diverse domains. From customer service bots to data analysis agents, from content creation assistants to workflow orchestrators
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/building-ai-agents-a2a-dotnet-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increased Subscription Pricing for IDEs, .NET Tools, dotUltimate, and the All Products Pack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 09:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For the past three years, we’ve worked hard to maintain our subscription prices while improving our products, building new tools, and adding features across our entire toolset. Like many businesses, we’re facing rising costs due to inflation. This means we can no longer keep our subscription prices at the current levels. The new prices will […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/07/31/increased-subscription-pricing-for-ides-net-tools-dotultimate-and-the-all-products-pack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Analytical Queries with Semantic Kernel and In-Memory SQL Processing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Semantic Kernel in-memory SQL processing for analytical queries In today&#39;s world, large language models (LLMs) like Azure OpenAI&#39;s GPT models have significantly changed how users interact with data-driven applications. While these models are excellent at understanding language, they can fall short on precise, structured computations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/semantic-kernel-sql-processing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot for Xcode: Introducing Copilot Vision, Custom Instructions, Locale-Aware Responses, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 03:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce updates to GitHub Copilot for Xcode, bringing new ways to interact with AI and streamline your development workflow. With Copilot Vision, you can upload and chat with images—like screenshots and UI designs—directly in Xcode. We’ve also introduced global
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/github-copilot-for-xcode-introducing-copilot-vision-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Stargate Norway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_24/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re launching Stargate Norway—OpenAI’s first AI data center initiative in Europe under our OpenAI for Countries program. Stargate is OpenAI’s overarching infrastructure platform and is a critical part of our long-term vision to deliver the benefits of AI to everyone.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-stargate-norway 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (July 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 22:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Full-Stack App with React and Aspire: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we will build we will build a TODO app from start to finish using Aspire and React. We will do this using the CLI and C# Dev Kit. The todo items will be stored in a SQLite database. The React front-end will use a Web API to handle all the interactions with the data. I&#39;m going to be showing this with the dotnet CLI, Aspire CLI a
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Laravel Idea Plugin is Now Free for PhpStorm Users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 16:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting July 30, 2025, we’re making Laravel Idea free for PhpStorm users. If you already have the Laravel Idea plugin installed, you get full access to all plugin features at no extra cost. Laravel Idea is the smartest Laravel development environment based on PhpStorm. Developed by Adel Faizrakhmanov, the plugin has 1.5M+ downloads from JetBrains […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/07/laravel-idea-is-now-free/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate the creation of handout notes using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 16:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can build an automated, serverless solution to transform webinar recordings into comprehensive handouts using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation for video analysis. We walk you through the implementation of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation to transcribe and detect slide changes, as well as the use of Amazon Bedrock foundation models (FMs) for transcription refinement, combined with custom AWS Lambda functions orchestrated by AWS Step Functions.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline GitHub workflows with generative AI using Amazon Bedrock and MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 16:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post explores how to create powerful agentic applications using the Amazon Bedrock FMs, LangGraph, and the Model Context Protocol (MCP), with a practical scenario of handling a GitHub workflow of issue analysis, code fixes, and pull request generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-github-workflows-with-generative-ai-using-amazon-bedrock-and-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing General Availability of UNISTR function and ANSI SQL || Operator in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 15:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the General Availability (GA) of two long-standing capabilities that address critical needs for SQL developers and enterprise customers in Azure SQL Database and Azure SQL Managed Instance, configured with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/announcing-general-availability-of-unistr-function-and-ansi-sql-operator-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, how can I await multiple coroutines and capture the results?, part 0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A while ago, I investigated ways of awaiting multiple C++/WinRT corotuines and capturing the results. I started with winrt::when_all(), but really I co
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250730-00/?p=111421 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Plan Validation in Copilot Studio Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 10:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever wonder why your agent&#39;s answers can be right but for the wrong reasons? Let&#39;s dive into why that matters, with a brief foray into epistemology (bear with me!) Knowledge: More Than Just Right Answers Imagine asking someone the time, and they confidently reply, “2:30 PM.” They&#39;re correct—but what if their watch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/plan-validation-cat-kit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping Students Get Unstuck: AI-Based Hints for Online Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 10:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In online learning environments, tasks can often stump students, which can be challenging to navigate since teachers can’t always be there to help. Our Education Research team develops innovative features for education tools and recently built a smart AI-based hints tool that provides personalized feedback for students who might need help solving tasks. This tool […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/07/ai-hints-for-online-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three lessons for creating a sustainable AI advantage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Intercom built a scalable AI platform with 3 key lessons—from evaluations to architecture—to lead the future of customer support.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/intercom 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
