<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 18:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring azd extensions: Enhance your Azure developer experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Exploring azd extensions: Enhance your Azure developer experience The Azure Developer CLI (azd) has a new feature called extensions that empowers developers to customize their workflow with azd. If you&#39;re a developer building on Azure, maybe you already have a &amp;quot;wish list&amp;quot; of CLI capabilities. If so, you might be able to create an ext
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azd-extension-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents at Work: Putting MSSQL MCP Server into Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How often have you wished you could just talk to your data? Imagine extracting crucial insights, updating records, or building complex reports without wrestling with intricate query languages or relying on a dedicated developer. For many professionals, the true power of their enterprise data remains locked behind technical barriers, h
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/mssql-mcp-server-in-action-susans-journey 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Leadership Series</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Progress Or Perfection? Staying Quality-Focused as a Team Under Pressure Everyone from growth-mindset gurus to Agile die-hards talk about ways in which we can iterate as developers. Release an MVP, build as you go, “minimize waste, maximize value” to stay lean, and do it all while prioritizing user feedback. But as much merit as these […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/06/qodana-leadership-series-minaev/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New YouTrack Prices Starting from October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re introducing a few changes to YouTrack prices, which will take effect on October 1, 2025. What’s not changing What will be changing Read on to learn about the reasons for this change, how to prepare, and what it means for YouTrack Cloud and Server customers. Why are we making this change? Our current pricing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2025/06/new-youtrack-prices-starting-from-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in Azure AI Foundry | June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Key dev updates: Agent Service hits GA with Model Context Protocol (MCP) support—integrate any backend with standardized JSON-RPC calls, no more custom OpenAPI specs. New models include o3-pro for enterprise reasoning, Sora for video generation, and DeepSeek-R1 for open-source reasoning. Platform chan
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/whats-new-in-azure-ai-foundry-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest NoSQL Java Ecosystem Updates: June 2024 - June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the latest roundup of key updates across the Azure Cosmos DB Java ecosystem! The largest external customers of Azure Cosmos DB API for NoSQL, running some of th
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/latest-nosql-java-ecosystem-updates-june-2024-june-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context extraction from image files in Amazon Q Business using LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we look at a step-by-step implementation for using the custom document enrichment (CDE) feature within an Amazon Q Business application to process standalone image files. We walk you through an AWS Lambda function configured within CDE to process various image file types, and showcase an example scenario of how this integration enhances Amazon Q Business&#39;s ability to provide comprehensive insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/context-extraction-from-image-files-in-amazon-q-business-using-llms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 mid-year link clearance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visualizing all the books of the world in ISBN space. What it says on the tin. Back in 2013, there was a series of promotional videos for the golf European Tour titled &amp;quot;Every Shot Imaginable&amp;quot;, in which golfers attempted silly tasks. P
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250630-01/?p=111323 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing the power of the empty set in API design: Requesting zero items</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A team was proposing a method that was at its essence a Read(n) that takes the maximum number of items to read. The reality was more complicated than that: The parameter n was really a configuration property on an operation, but it had the same meaning: It set the maximum number of items to return. The team s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250630-00/?p=111320 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AWS architecture diagrams using Amazon Q CLI and MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q Developer CLI with the AWS Diagram MCP and the AWS Documentation MCP servers to create sophisticated architecture diagrams that follow AWS best practices. We discuss techniques for basic diagrams and real-world diagrams, with detailed examples and step-by-step instructions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-aws-architecture-diagrams-using-amazon-q-cli-and-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool Calling with Local LLMs: A Practical Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Which local model should I use for tool calling? When building GenAI and agentic applications, one of the most pressing and persistent questions is: “Which local model should I use for tool calling?” We kept hearing again and again, from colleagues within Docker and the developer community, ever since we started working on Docker Model...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/local-llm-tool-calling-a-practical-evaluation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find Public Symbols That Can Be Internal Using Roslyn</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I got a question about how to find all public symbols in a solution that can be internal. This is a common scenario when you want to reduce the visibility of your code to improve encapsulation. You can use Roslyn as a library to analyze the code in a solution and find such symbols. I&#39;ve already written about how to use Roslyn as a library to analyze and rewrite code in a solution: .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.1.4: Another Set of Bug-fixes Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 08:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A fourth set of updates for the 2025.1 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.1.4 comes with the following fixes For the full list of resolved issues, please refer to our issue tracker. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/30/resharper-and-rider-2025-1-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI in Australia—OpenAI’s Economic Blueprint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, OpenAI, in partnership with Mandala Partners, is sharing the OpenAI AI Economic Blueprint for Australia. At a time when boosting productivity has emerged as a national priority for Australia, the Blueprint provides a clear, actionable plan for how Australia can unlock the full economic and social potential of artificial intelligence.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/openais-australia-economic-blueprint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source AI Editor: First Milestone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are open sourcing the GitHub Copilot Chat extension. It’s the first milestone in making VS Code an open source AI editor. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/open-source-ai-editor:-first-milestone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Mastering Method Returns with Spargine’s SimpleResult Type</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2025/29_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_06_2025/29_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET development community is increasingly favoring result types like SimpleResult over exceptions for routine error handling, enhancing reliability and performance. SimpleResult allows returning values alongside exceptions, supports multiple errors, and improves clarity in code. This utility promotes efficient error handling in various application contexts.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/29/boost-your-net-projects-mastering-method-returns-with-spargines-simpleresult-type/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back on 20&#43; Years of Programming - Dev Leader Weekly 100</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss my reflections looking back on 20 years of programming and building software.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/28/looking-back-on-20-years-of-programming-dev-leader-weekly-100 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-06-27</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 06:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/06/28/weekly-recap-20250627 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testcontainers Best Practices for .NET Integration Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_06_2025/28_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Integration tests shouldn&#39;t rely on external infrastructure—but they also shouldn&#39;t mock everything away. In this post, we look at how to use Testcontainers in .NET to spin up real Postgres and Redis instances in your tests, how to manage container lifecycle using IAsyncLifetime, and how to structure your xUnit fixtures for speed and reliability
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/testcontainers-best-practices-dotnet-integration-testing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Model Context Protocol Support (preview) in Azure AI Foundry Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 22:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative-AI agents only become useful when they can do things—query systems of record, trigger workflows, or look up specialized knowledge. Until now that meant hand-rolling Azure Functions, managing OpenAPI specs, or writing custom pl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/announcing-model-context-protocol-support-preview-in-azure-ai-foundry-agent-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating C# Model Context Protocol servers with Amazon Q Developer CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 21:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to create your own Model Context Protocol (MCP) server with C# and .NET. You will use Amazon Q Developer Command-Line Interface (Amazon Q CLI) as an MCP client. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open standard that lets Artificial Intelligence (AI) models safely interact with external tools and resources. MCP enhances […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/integrating-c-model-context-protocol-servers-with-amazon-q-developer-cli/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs: Unlocking enterprise knowledge for AI with the Retrieval API — Now in Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 17:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Build 2025, we introduced the Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs. Developers now have an extensibility layer that empowers them to create intelligent, AI-driven experiences deeply integrated with the Microsoft 365 ecosystem. These API
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-copilot-apis-unlocking-enterprise-knowledge-for-ai-with-the-retrieval-api 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS costs estimation using Amazon Q CLI and AWS Cost Analysis MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q CLI with the AWS Cost Analysis MCP server to perform sophisticated cost analysis that follows AWS best practices. We discuss basic setup and advanced techniques, with detailed examples and step-by-step instructions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-costs-estimation-using-amazon-q-cli-and-aws-cost-analysis-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Easy Private AI Assistant with Goose and Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Goose is an innovative CLI assistant designed to automate development tasks using AI models. Docker Model Runner simplifies deploying AI models locally with Docker. Combining these technologies creates a powerful local environment with advanced AI assistance, ideal for coding and automation. Looking for a seamless way to run AI-powered development tasks locally without compromising on...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-an-ai-assistant-with-goose-and-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I get errors or warnings about some weird symbol called ?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform..., part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have been investigating why a project is getting an error about a weird C++/CX symbol, and we tracked it down to three things:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250627-00/?p=111316 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Extension Methods to Extension Members: Unlocking New Possibilities in .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article examines the significance of extension methods in .NET, emphasizing their role in enhancing existing types without altering source code. It also introduces Extension Members in .NET 10 (C# 14), allowing the addition of both methods and properties, thus expanding developers&#39; capabilities. While there are limitations, they improve code maintainability and flexibility.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/27/from-extension-methods-to-extension-members-unlocking-new-possibilities-in-net-10/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic Claude Sonnet 4 and Opus 4 Now Available in GitHub Copilot for JetBrains and Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 05:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anthropic Claude Sonnet 4 and Claude Opus 4 are now available in GitHub Copilot Chat for JetBrains IDEs and Eclipse. Model Availability✨
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/anthropic-claude-sonnet-4-and-opus-4-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot for Xcode Adds Support for Anthropic Claude Sonnet 4 and Opus 4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 02:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot for Xcode now supports Anthropic Claude Sonnet 4 and Claude Opus 4, bringing more powerful AI assistance to your Swift, Objective-C, and Apple platform development.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/copilot-for-xcode-adds-support-for-claude-sonnet-4-and-opus-4 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailor responsible AI with new safeguard tiers in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 22:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the new safeguard tiers available in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails, explain their benefits and use cases, and provide guidance on how to implement and evaluate them in your AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/tailor-responsible-ai-with-new-safeguard-tiers-in-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Channels as a In-Memory Message Bus – Beware!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 21:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re looking at using .NET Channels as a replacement for a MediatR, or if you’re not in .NET but searching for an in-memory producer-consumer API, hang on a second—because you might be in for a pile of pain. That’s not actually what you want. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of… Read More ».NET Channels as a In-Memory Message Bus – Beware! The post .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s Still About the Data: Practical Approach to Building with Agentic AI, LLMs and Generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s no denying the massive wave of excitement around Agentic AI, Multi-Agent Systems, Generative AI, and Large Language Models (LLMs). Whether it’s people experimenting with Copilots, implementing RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation) patterns, spinning up AI agents, or integrating LLMs into enterprise apps, there’s a real energy behind this shift. But as exciting (and disruptive) as this […] The article It’s Still About the Data: Practical Approach to Building with Agentic AI, LLMs and Generative AI was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing MSSQL MCP Server (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 20:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next leap in data interaction isn&#39;t just about efficient processing; it&#39;s about intuitive and meaningful conversation with your own data. For years, the true power of SQL Server databases has been locked behind complex query languages and specialized tools, accessible primarily to developers and database adm
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/introducing-mssql-mcp-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simpler XAML in .NET MAUI 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building UI in .NET MAUI with XAML continues to be the most popular approach. It&#39;s easy to see the nesting structure of your UI, works for most use cases with hot reload, and it supports powerful state flow with data binding. One of the downsides is how verbose it can become. Every page requires you to declare the namespaces for any types used
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/simpler-xaml-in-dotnet-maui-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured data response with Amazon Bedrock: Prompt Engineering and Tool Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We demonstrate two methods for generating structured responses with Amazon Bedrock: Prompt Engineering and Tool Use with the Converse API. Prompt Engineering is flexible, works with Bedrock models (including those without Tool Use support), and handles various schema types (e.g., Open API schemas), making it a great starting point. Tool Use offers greater reliability, consistent results, seamless API integration, and runtime validation of JSON schema for enhanced control.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon SageMaker AI Random Cut Forest for NASA’s Blue Origin spacecraft sensor data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use SageMaker AI to apply the Random Cut Forest (RCF) algorithm to detect anomalies in spacecraft position, velocity, and quaternion orientation data from NASA and Blue Origin’s demonstration of lunar Deorbit, Descent, and Landing Sensors (BODDL-TP).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-amazon-sagemaker-ai-random-cut-forest-for-nasas-blue-origin-spacecraft-sensor-data/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Azure Storage Connector for PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to introduce the Azure Storage Connector for PyTorch (azstoragetorch), a new library that brings seamless, performance-optimized integration between Azure Storage and PyTorch. The library makes it easy to access and store data in Azure Blob Storage directly within your training workflows. What is PyTorch?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/introducing-the-azure-storage-connector-for-pytorch 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I get errors about some weird symbol called ?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform..., part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are investigating why a project is getting an error about a weird C++/CX symbol, and we thought we had figured it out, but our a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250626-00/?p=111314 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Electronic Arts standardized C&#43;&#43; builds across Windows and Linux with Visual Studio Build Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Electronic Arts (EA), the Frostbite Enginering Workflows team has thousands of developers who work on powerful game engines behind popular games. EA has relied on Visual Studio for years due to several features such as IntelliSense, Build Insights, and the overall debugging experience and eagerly use newer integrations such as GitHub Copi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/how-electronic-arts-standardized-c-builds-across-windows-and-linux-with-visual-studio-build-tools 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizable, no-code voice agent automation with GPT-4o</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Retell AI is transforming the call center with AI voice automation powered by GPT-4o and GPT-4.1. Its no-code platform enables businesses to launch natural, real-time voice agents that cut call costs, boost CSAT, and automate customer conversations—without scripts or hold times.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/retell-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 EAP 7: Low-Level Exception Suppression and Other Updates for Debugging Games</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 09:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2025.2 is shaping up to be an exciting release for game developers, no matter which engine you work with. Over the last few EAP builds, we’ve been rolling out targeted improvements to make debugging smoother, faster, and more reliable, whether you’re building with Unreal Engine, Unity, Godot, or custom C++ frameworks. In the latest […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/06/26/rider-2025-2-eap-7-low-level-exception-suppression/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.29 with refactored architecture, MCP server, and exposed LM prompts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 07:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce Dev Proxy v0.29, with a major architectural overhaul, control over language model prompts, and improved diagnostics. Whether you&#39;re building, debugging, or customizing your API simulations, this version gives you more power and clarity than ever before. In this version: Architectural refactoring to
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-29-with-refactored-architecture-mcp-server-and-exposed-lm-prompts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet Configuration Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Recently, the Microsoft ISE team completed a customer engagement that involved managing edge deployments to factory floors across geographical locations. This system needed to support existing workloads migrated from Azure IoT Hub, new workloads for processing IoT data feeds, and machine learning workloads for performing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/fleet-configuration-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Terraform State in Azure Blob Storage using Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When your team loses control of its Terraform state file, it loses control of everything in the subscription. An unencrypted or publicly exposed .tfstate isn’t just embarrassing—it’s a roadmap to your entire cloud estate. A breach of the state file is a major security breach that puts the future of your organization at risk. Improperly […] The article Securing Terraform State in Azure Blob Storage using Best Practices was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Live</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 19:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the MPS 2025.2 Early Access Program (EAP). You can download the first 2025.2 EAP build and try it out now! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.2 EAP The release brings numerous bug fixes and improvements, such as: Resolve info is now correctly updated when copying references into the clipboard. The Show Node Info dialog has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/06/the-mps-2025-2-eap-has-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Azure Resource Manager reliance on Azure DevOps sign-ins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure DevOps will no longer depend on the Azure Resource Manager (ARM) resource (https://management.azure.com) when you sign in or refresh Microsoft Entra access tokens. Previously, Azure DevOps required the ARM audience during sign-in and token refresh flows. This requirement meant administrators had to allow all Azure DevOps users to bypa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/removing-azure-resource-manager-reliance-on-azure-devops-sign-ins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent multi-agent business expert using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 16:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a multi-agent system using multi-agent collaboration in Amazon Bedrock Agents to solve complex business questions in the biopharmaceutical industry. We show how specialized agents in research and development (R&amp;amp;D), legal, and finance domains can work together to provide comprehensive business insights by analyzing data from multiple sources.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-multi-agent-business-expert-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving cost-efficiency and speed in claims data processing with Amazon Nova Micro and Amazon Nova Lite</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we shared how an internal technology team at Amazon evaluated Amazon Nova models, resulting in notable improvements in inference speed and cost-efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/driving-cost-efficiency-and-speed-in-claims-data-processing-with-amazon-nova-micro-and-amazon-nova-lite/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker State of App Dev: AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is changing software development — but not how you think The hype is real, but so are the challenges. Here&#39;s what developers, teams, and tech leaders need to know about AI’s uneven, evolving role in software. Rumors of AI’s pervasiveness in software development have been greatly exaggerated. A look under the hood shows adoption...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-state-of-app-dev-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your information has been permanently deleted, for small values of permanently</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of a periodic purge of unused online accounts, I deleted my account from a company ten months ago. Let&#39;s call that company Contoso. I received a confirmation that said, &amp;quot;Your personal information and items associated with your account have now been deleted. This action is permanent and cannot be reversed.&amp;quot; Yesterday, I got a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250625-01/?p=111308 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I get errors about some weird symbol called ?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform..., part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A colleague was writing a fuzz test and ran into a build error. vccorlib.lib(climain.obj) : error LNK2019: unresolved external symbol &amp;quot;?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform@@$00@Platform@@@Z&amp;quot; (?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform@@$00@P
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250625-00/?p=111306 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Spring Boot With Spring Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 07:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Boot is a marvel of developer productivity. It hides the plumbing and gets you up and running fast. Components are “miraculously” autowired, properties are “magically” resolved, and database connections materialize seemingly without explicit configuration. But when something goes wrong, the magic becomes a mystery, and debugging becomes a deep dive into the framework’s internal […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/demystifying-spring-boot-with-spring-debugger/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Chronicles: Why Developers Should Care About User Experience (Yes, You!)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            User Experience (UX) focuses on the emotional and practical interactions users have with software. It emphasizes designing with the user in mind, which is often overlooked by engineers and managers. Effective UX involves usability, accessibility, performance, and more. Improving UX enhances user satisfaction, loyalty, and overall product success in software development.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/25/ux-chronicles-why-developers-should-care-about-user-experience-yes-you/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel Python Gets a Major Vector Store Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce a significant update to Semantic Kernel Python&#39;s vector store implementation. Version 1.34 brings a complete overhaul that makes working with vector data simpler, more intuitive, and more powerful. This update consolidates the API, improves developer experience, and adds new capabilities that streamline AI development
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-python-gets-a-major-vector-store-upgrade 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Agents observability using Arize AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce a new integration between Arize AI and Amazon Bedrock Agents that addresses one of the most significant challenges in AI development: observability. In this post, we demonstrate the Arize Phoenix system for tracing and evaluation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-agents-observability-using-arize-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How SkillShow automates youth sports video processing using Amazon Transcribe</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 15:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SkillShow, a leader in youth sports video production, films over 300 events yearly in the youth sports industry, creating content for over 20,000 young athletes annually. This post describes how SkillShow used Amazon Transcribe and other Amazon Web Services (AWS) machine learning (ML) services to automate their video processing workflow, reducing editing time and costs while scaling their operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-skillshow-automates-youth-sports-video-processing-using-amazon-transcribe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NewDay builds A Generative AI based Customer service Agent Assist with over 90% accuracy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 15:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Sergio Zavota and Amy Perring from NewDay. NewDay has a clear and defining purpose: to help people move forward with credit. NewDay provides around 4 million customers access to credit responsibly and delivers exceptional customer experiences, powered by their in-house technology system. NewDay’s contact center handles 2.5 million calls annually, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/newday-builds-a-generative-ai-based-customer-service-agent-assist-with-over-90-accuracy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abusing copyright strings to trick software into thinking it&#39;s running on your competitor&#39;s PC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One very complicated part of bringing up Plug and Play was bootstrapping the entire process. After all, the number of computers that supported the Plug and Play specification started at zero, because the specification was still being written. A lot of clever tricks were used to retrofit Plug and Play onto legacy hardware.¹ The Wind
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250624-00/?p=111299 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern CI/CD for a Post-VMware World: Embrace KubeVirt With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 11:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In November 2023, Broadcom acquired VMware for a whopping USD 69 billion. The strategic goal behind the acquisition was to enable customers to create and modernize their cloud environments, both private and hybrid. Following the acquisition, VMware perpetual license holders started receiving cease-and-desist letters from Broadcom. Users can continue using the software, but can no […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/06/kubevirt-with-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Your Code in Check With Qodana On-Prem Lite, Our Newest, Easy-to-Deploy Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 11:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve probably heard of Qodana Self-Hosted, but now we’re bringing you a different kind of Self-Hosted Qodana that’s on-premises, Qodana On-Prem Lite, making powerful code quality analysis more accessible than ever. Designed for teams seeking a streamlined, resource-efficient solution, this new offering brings the benefits of Qodana to a more on-premises environment with a focus […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/06/qodana-on-prem-lite/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with stacked branches in git (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post looking at stacked branches I describe how to handle scenarios such as merging one of your stacked branches and handling changes to main
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/working-with-stacked-branches-in-git-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving scalable growth with OpenAI o3, GPT-4.1, and CUA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unify, an AI-powered GTM platform, uses OpenAI’s o3, GPT-4.1, and CUA to automate prospecting, research, and outreach. With hyper-personalized messaging and an always-on workflow, Unify helps teams generate pipeline at scale while focusing on high-impact customer interactions.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/unify 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Now in Public Preview: Create Dev Boxes on Behalf of Your Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that one of our most-requested features is officially in Public Preview: You can now create Dev Boxes on behalf of your developers
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/public-preview-create-dev-boxes-on-behalf-of-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.3 is out with a number of useful fixes. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. The latest update brings the following improvements: For a comprehensive overview of the fixes, see […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/06/intellij-idea-2025-1-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No-code data preparation for time series forecasting using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Canvas offers no-code solutions that simplify data wrangling, making time series forecasting accessible to all users regardless of their technical background. In this post, we explore how SageMaker Canvas and SageMaker Data Wrangler provide no-code data preparation techniques that empower users of all backgrounds to prepare data and build time series forecasting models in a single interface with confidence.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/no-code-data-preparation-for-time-series-forecasting-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an agentic multimodal AI assistant with Amazon Nova and Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how agentic workflow patterns such as Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), multi-tool orchestration, and conditional routing with LangGraph enable end-to-end solutions that artificial intelligence and machine learning (AI/ML) developers and enterprise architects can adopt and extend. We walk through an example of a financial management AI assistant that can provide quantitative research and grounded financial advice by analyzing both the earnings call (audio) and the presentation slides (images), along with relevant financial data feeds.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation of MS-APP-ACTS-AS header in Shifts Management Microsoft Graph APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In app-only access scenarios, Shifts Management Graph APIs previously required the MS-APP-ACTS-AS: userId header to indicate the user on whose behalf the application was acting. However, this conflicted with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-of-ms-app-acts-as-header-in-shifts-management-microsoft-graph-apis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.2.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.2.0 release is out! This version includes both new and stable language features, tooling updates, performance improvements for different platforms, and important fixes. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin 2.2.0 or the release notes on GitHub. Join the Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/06/kotlin-2-2-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside Access: Join Us at VS Live! Redmond for a Week of Deep Developer Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A long time ago, I stood in a packed room at VS Live! and watched developers erupt in applause after a debugging demo shaved hours off a real-world problem. That was the moment I realized this wasn’t just a conference—it was a place where developers and toolmakers come together to push the craft forward. I’m excited to announce that I
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/inside-access-join-us-at-vs-live-redmond-for-a-week-of-deep-developer-learning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MIDL compiler still has trouble with double greater-than signs, sadly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The parser for the Microsoft MIDL compiler has long suffered from the problem of the double greater-than sign. This problem plagued C++ until C++11 added a special rule:¹ [temp.names] (4): When parsing a template-argument-list, the first non-nested &amp;gt; is taken as the ending delimiter rath
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250623-00/?p=111295 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSS Project Lessons Learned with David Giard</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I got to talk to David Giard on his podcast last week about some of the lessons I’ve learned the hard way across several large OSS projects. For a little background, I got to follow through on a 15 to 20 year dream of mine to found a company called JasperFx Software LLC to build … Continue reading OSS Project Lessons Learned with David Giard →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/06/23/oss-project-lessons-learned-with-david-giard/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Exclude Your Windows App from Screen Capture and Recall</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some applications are displaying sensitive information. With Recall, Windows can take a screenshot of your screen regularly and store sensitive information. You can exclude your application from this feature, and screen capture more generally, by using SetWindowDisplayAffinity and the WDA_EXCLUDEFROMCAPTURE flag. This is a Windows API function that allows you to set the display affinity of a window, which…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/how-to-exclude-your-windows-app-from-screen-capture-and-recall.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover Junie for PhpStorm: A Game-Changing AI Coding Agent for PHP Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 09:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Junie, the AI coding agent by JetBrains, PhpStorm has entered the realm of agentic IDEs. Now, the PhpStorm IDE doesn’t just provide classical developer productivity tools and AI assistance features, but can also do massive amounts of work for PHP developers autonomously. Unlike other coding agent plugins, Junie is native to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/06/discover-junie-for-phpstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wire Up XUnit Logging for Crazy Integration Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I worked a little bit this weekend on a small new feature in Wolverine that we’ll need as part of our forthcoming “CritterWatch” tooling. What I was doing isn’t that interesting, but the killer problem was that it required me to write an integration test that would: Needless to say, it’s a long running test … Continue reading Wire Up XUnit Logging for Crazy Integration Testing →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
