<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wayland By Default in 2026.1 EAP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting from version 2026.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will run natively on Wayland in supported desktop configurations. This follows Wayland’s ascendance to the position of primary display server across contemporary Linux distributions. By making this change in our EAP releases first, we hope to be able to give more Linux users the opportunity to try the native […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/02/wayland-by-default-in-2026-1-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3Cs: A Framework for AI Agent Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every time execution models change, security frameworks need to change with them. Agents force the next shift. The Unattended Laptop Problem No developer would leave their laptop unattended and unlocked. The risk is obvious. A developer laptop has root-level access to production systems, repositories, databases, credentials, and APIs. If someone sat down and started using...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/the-3cs-a-framework-for-ai-agent-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VfL Wolfsburg turns ChatGPT into a club-wide capability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By focusing on people, not pilots, the Bundesliga club is scaling efficiency, creativity, and knowledge—without losing its football identity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/vfl-wolfsburg 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratizing business intelligence: BGL’s journey with Claude Agent SDK and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BGL is a leading provider of self-managed superannuation fund (SMSF) administration solutions that help individuals manage the complex compliance and reporting of their own or a client’s retirement savings, serving over 12,700 businesses across 15 countries. In this blog post, we explore how BGL built its production-ready AI agent using Claude Agent SDK and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/democratizing-business-intelligence-bgls-journey-with-claude-agent-sdk-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Quick Suite custom action connectors to upload text files to Google Drive using OpenAPI specification</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a secure file upload solution by integrating Google Drive with Amazon Quick Suite custom connectors using Amazon API Gateway and AWS Lambda.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-quick-suite-custom-action-connectors-to-upload-text-files-to-google-drive-using-openapi-specification/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI agents in enterprises: Best practices with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores nine essential best practices for building enterprise AI agents using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore. Amazon Bedrock AgentCore is an agentic platform that provides the services you need to create, deploy, and manage AI agents at scale. In this post, we cover everything from initial scoping to organizational scaling, with practical guidance that you can apply immediately.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-agents-in-enterprises-best-practices-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation notice: Teams Live Events meeting creation via Microsoft Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re announcing an important change for developers using Microsoft Graph APIs to create Teams Live Events. Starting March 31, 2026, the beta endpoint will no longer support the isBroadcast property of the on
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-notice-teams-live-events-meeting-creation-via-microsoft-graph 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI for healthcare data analysis with Amazon SageMaker Data Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 21, 2025, Amazon SageMaker introduced a built-in data agent within Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio that transforms large-scale data analysis. In this post, we demonstrate, through a detailed case study of an epidemiologist conducting clinical cohort analysis, how SageMaker Data Agent can help reduce weeks of data preparation into days, and days of analysis development into hours—ultimately accelerating the path from clinical questions to research conclusions.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Building a Python CRUD API with Azure Functions and Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Series: Building Serverless Applications with Azure Functions and Azure Cosmos DB In the first post of this series, we focused on establishing the fundamentals of serverless architectur
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/part-2-building-a-python-crud-api-with-azure-functions-and-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance improvements to MEF-based editor productivity extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you use editor productivity extensions for Visual Studio 2026, there&#39;s good news—they can now load faster! Extension developers with existing MEF-based editor productivity extensions should read this blog to learn about recent changes and how they might be affected.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/performance-improvements-to-mef-based-editor-productivity-extensions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some small stories about the giant satellite dish antenna that was behind Microsoft Building 11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in the day, if you wandered into the parking area behind Building 11 on the original Redmond Microsoft campus, you would find a very large satellite dish antenna. This antenna was used for receiving video signals, such as cable television feeds for distribution to the Redmond campus. One purpose was to provide cable TV service for inte
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260203-00/?p=112035 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Dependency Injection in C#: The Complete Guide to Needlr</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Needlr simplifies dependency injection in C# with automatic service discovery, source generation, and a fluent API for .NET applications.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/02/03/automatic-dependency-injection-in-c-the-complete-guide-to-needlr 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the (underwhelming) System.Diagnostics.Metrics source generators: System.Diagnostics.Metrics APIs - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I explore the source generators shipped in Microsoft.Extensions.Telemetry.Abstractions, explore the code, and discuss whether I would use them
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-strongly-typed-metics-with-a-source-generator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pick Your KotlinConf Workshop by What You Want to Learn</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi! Already coming to KotlinConf in Munich? Kick off the conference with a full day of hands-on workshops on May 20. Not going yet? Then this is a good moment to get your KotlinConf ticket and start with a workshop that matches what you want to learn. Asynchronous programming with Kotlin coroutines Learn how to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/02/pick-your-kotlinconf-workshop/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sora feed philosophy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the Sora feed philosophy—built to spark creativity, foster connections, and keep experiences safe with personalized recommendations, parental controls, and strong guardrails.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/sora-feed-philosophy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer now supports Dark Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 20:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you spend time in the Azure Portal’s using Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer, you know it’s a “lots of screens, lots of tabs, lots of work happening” kind of place. So I’m excited to share a small upgrade that makes a big difference: Dark Mode is now supported in Cosmos DB Data Explorer.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-data-explorer-now-supports-dark-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Clarus Care uses Amazon Bedrock to deliver conversational contact center interactions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate how Clarus Care, a healthcare contact center solutions provider, worked with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) team to develop a generative AI-powered contact center prototype. This solution enables conversational interaction and multi-intent resolution through an automated voicebot and chat interface. It also incorporates a scalable service model to support growth, human transfer capabilities--when requested or for urgent cases--and an analytics pipeline for performance insights.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Greenfield System with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JasperFx Software works hand in hand with our clients to improve our client’s outcomes on software projects using the “Critter Stack” (Marten and Wolverine). Based on our engagements with client projects as well as the greater Critter Stack user base, we’ve built up quite a few optional usages and settings in the two frameworks to … Continue reading Building a Greenfield System with the Critter Stack →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying compiler error messages closely: Input file paths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A colleague was working in a project that used a number of data files to configure how the program worked. They wanted one portion of the configuration file to be included only if a particular build flag was set. Let&#39;s say that the configuration file is C:\repos\contoso\config\Contoso.config. &amp;amp;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260202-00/?p=112027 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Kotlin Ecosystem Mentorship Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: The Kotlin Foundation is launching a mentorship program that pairs experienced open-source maintainers with new Kotlin contributors to help them make their first meaningful contributions, with branded swag and a chance to win a trip to KotlinConf. I still remember my first contribution to an open-source library. It was Typhoon, a widely popular dependency […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/02/kotlin-ecosystem-mentorship/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog x ACP: Connect an Agent to Your IDE and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We hope you’re staying up to date with our latest posts and have checked out our tutorials on how to create coding agents in Koog and connect ACP-compliant agents to your JetBrains IDE. As useful as these guides are, one important piece was hitherto missing from the puzzle: How do you make your Koog agent […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/02/koog-x-acp-connect-an-agent-to-your-ide-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use client assertions in ASP.NET Core using OpenID Connect, OAuth DPoP and OAuth PAR</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at implement client assertions in an ASP.NET Core application OpenID Connect client using OAuth Demonstrating Proof of Possession (DPoP) and OAuth Pushed Authorization Requests (PAR). Code: https://github.com/swiss-ssi-group/swiyu-passkeys-idp-loi-loa Blogs in this series: Setup An ASP.NET code application is setup to authentication using OpenID Connect and OAuth PAR. The web application is an OIDC […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2026/02/02/use-client-assertions-in-asp-net-core-using-openid-connect-oauth-dpop-and-oauth-par/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowflake and OpenAI partner to bring frontier intelligence to enterprise data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Snowflake partner in a $200M agreement to bring frontier intelligence into enterprise data, enabling AI agents and insights directly in Snowflake.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/snowflake-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Codex app</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the Codex app for macOS—a command center for AI coding and software development with multiple agents, parallel workflows, and long-running tasks.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-the-codex-app 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects with Spargine: High-Performance ULIDs with the Ulid Struct</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2026/01_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_02_2026/01_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Spargine 8, I introduced the UlidGenerator type to make working with ULIDs easier in .NET applications. For the .NET 10 release, I took this idea further — converting ULIDs into a first-class value type (struct) in the DotNetTips.Spargine.Core assembly, similar in spirit to the built-in Guid type. Why? Because modern distributed applications increasingly need … Continue reading Boost Your .NET Projects with Spargine: High-Performance ULIDs with the Ulid Struct →
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Side Projects and Soft Skills in Interviews - Dev Leader Weekly 125</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 21:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss interviews with a focus on side projects and soft skills.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/01/31/side-projects-and-soft-skills-in-interviews-dev-leader-weekly-125 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2026-01-31</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 20:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/01/31/weekly-recap-20260131 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana for Android: Increasing Code Quality for Kotlin-First Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When people think about tooling for Android development, the conversation often gravitates towards platform-specific concerns: UI performance, layout validation, device compatibility, or resource management. Yet for many Android teams, the most persistent challenges don’t sit at the platform level – they’re in the team’s Kotlin codebase itself. As Android projects scale, Kotlin brings strong language […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2026/01/qodana-for-android-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containerize Your .NET Applications Without a Dockerfile</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2026/31_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to containerize .NET applications without writing a single line of Dockerfile. The .NET SDK has built-in support for publishing directly to container images.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/containerize-your-dotnet-applications-without-a-dockerfile 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating generative AI models with Amazon Nova LLM-as-a-Judge on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Evaluating the performance of large language models (LLMs) goes beyond statistical metrics like perplexity or bilingual evaluation understudy (BLEU) scores. For most real-world generative AI scenarios, it’s crucial to understand whether a model is producing better outputs than a baseline or an earlier iteration. This is especially important for applications such as summarization, content generation, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluating-generative-ai-models-with-amazon-nova-llm-as-a-judge-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI Agents with Claude Agent SDK and Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Agent Framework now integrates with the Claude Agent SDK, enabling you to build AI agents powered by Claude&#39;s full agentic capabilities. This integration brings together the Agent Framework&#39;s consistent agent abstraction with Claude&#39;s powerful features, including fil
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/build-ai-agents-with-claude-agent-sdk-and-microsoft-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify ModelOps with Amazon SageMaker AI Projects using Amazon S3-based templates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how you can use Amazon S3-based templates to simplify ModelOps workflows, walk through the key benefits compared to using Service Catalog approaches, and demonstrates how to create a custom ModelOps solution that integrates with GitHub and GitHub Actions—giving your team one-click provisioning of a fully functional ML environment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simplify-modelops-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-projects-using-amazon-s3-based-templates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale AI in South Africa using Amazon Bedrock global cross-Region inference with Anthropic Claude 4.5 models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how global cross-Region inference routes requests and where your data resides, then show you how to configure the required AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) permissions and invoke Claude 4.5 models using the global inference profile Amazon Resource Name (ARN). We also cover how to request quota increases for your workload. By the end, you&#39;ll have a working implementation of global cross-Region inference in af-south-1.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q4 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your quarterly dose of plugin dev news, tools, and tips from JetBrains. 🧩 Marketplace Updates Integration Tests Now Part of Automated Moderation Integration test results are now displayed directly on the plugin page, alongside Plugin Verifier results on the Versions tab. These tests help ensure that a plugin version works smoothly in the IDE and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2026/01/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q4-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why not store the &lt;code&gt;SAFEARRAY&lt;/code&gt; reference count as a hidden allocation next to the &lt;code&gt;SAFEARRAY&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I described how Safe­Array­Add­Ref keeps its reference count in a side table, commenter Koro Unhallowed wondered
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260130-00/?p=112025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) - January 2026: Configuration &amp; Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the round up of the azd releases in January 2026! This blog post (covers release versions 1.23.0, 1.23.1,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-january-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (January 2026)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 22:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-january-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.3.2 Updates Out Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released another update for ReSharper, Rider and the .NET tools version 2025.3. You can update to this version from inside those tools, using the Toolbox app or our website. Let’s take a look at the latest updates. Rider 2025.3.2 Agent Client Protocol (ACP) agent registry support You can now browse and install ACP-compatible […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/29/resharper-and-rider-2025-3-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB TV Recap - From Burger to Bots – Agentic Apps with Cosmos DB and LangChain.js | Ep. 111</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Episode 111 of Azure Cosmos DB TV, host Mark Brown is joined by Yohan Lasorsa to explore how developers can build agent-powered applications using a fully serverless architecture. This episode focuses on a practical, end-to-end exa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-tv-recap-from-burger-to-bots-agentic-apps-with-cosmos-db-and-langchain-js-ep-111 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I retain access to the data in a &lt;code&gt;SAFEARRAY&lt;/code&gt; after my method returns?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The original problem our customer had was that the data in a SAFEARRAY disappeared even though they had called Safe­Array­Add­Ref. We learned why this is the case,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260129-00/?p=112023 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v2.1 with configuration hot reload and stdio proxying</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the release of Dev Proxy v2.1.0! This release brings two major productivity features that developers have been asking for: automatic configuration hot reload and stdio traffic proxying - perfect for testing MCP servers and other stdio-based tools. In this version:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v2-1-with-configuration-hot-reload-and-stdio-proxying 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Dev in 2025: Excerpts From the State of Game Development Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we approach the midpoint of the decade, game developers face an evolving landscape shaped by shifting job security, technology choices, platform strategies, and practical AI adoption. Our State of Game Development 2025 report reveals critical insights that provide a clearer picture of where the industry is heading. Layoffs and job security concerns The game […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2026/01/29/game-dev-in-2025-excerpts-from-the-state-of-game-development-report/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside OpenAI’s in-house data agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How OpenAI built an in-house AI data agent that uses GPT-5, Codex, and memory to reason over massive datasets and deliver reliable insights in minutes.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/inside-our-in-house-data-agent 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retiring GPT-4o, GPT-4.1, GPT-4.1 mini, and OpenAI o4-mini in ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On February 13, 2026, alongside the previously announced retirement⁠ of GPT‑5 (Instant, Thinking, and Pro), we will retire GPT‑4o, GPT‑4.1, GPT‑4.1 mini, and OpenAI o4-mini from ChatGPT. In the API, there are no changes at this time.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/retiring-gpt-4o-and-older-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Microsoft Graph User Configuration API (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the public preview of the User Configuration API in the Microsoft Graph beta endpoint. The User Configuration API is a new set of endpoints that you can use to create, read, update, and delete user configuration objects in Exchange Online mail folders. User configuration objects—also
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-the-microsoft-graph-user-configuration-api-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing instability in production-scale agent reinforcement learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On January 28, 2026, Hugging Face announced that they have upstreamed the Post-Training Toolkit into TRL as a first-party integration, making these diagnostics directly usable in production RL and agent post-training pipelines. This enables closed-loop monitoring and control patterns that are increasingly necessary for
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/diagnosing-instability-in-production-scale-agent-rl 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Cosmos DB Infrastructure with GitHub Copilot CLI and Azure Cosmos DB Agent Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern infrastructure work is increasingly agent driven, but only if your AI actually understands the platform you’re deploying. This guide shows how to turn GitHub Copilot CLI into an Azure Cosmos DB aware infrastructure expert by loading the Azure Cosmos DB Agent Kit. In under a minute, you’ll give Copil
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/accelerate-your-cosmos-db-infrastructure-with-github-copilot-cli-and-azure-cosmos-db-agent-kit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET AI Essentials - The Core Building Blocks Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is transforming how we build applications. The .NET team has prioritized keeping pace with the rapid changes in generative AI and continue to provide tools, libraries, and guidance for .NET developers building intelligent apps. With .NET, developers have a powerful ecosystem to integrate AI seamlessly into their ap
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-ai-essentials-the-core-building-blocks-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Framework (SPFx) roadmap update – January 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We enter 2026 with the SharePoint Framework stronger than ever. Adoption has expanded, feedback has sharpened our priorities, and the platform continues to power intelligent and scalable experiences across Microsoft 365. December marked an important milestone with the release of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/sharepoint-framework-spfx-roadmap-update-january-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I lose the data even though I called &lt;code&gt;Safe­Array­Add­Ref&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer had a method that received a SAFEARRAY, and they called Safe­Array­Add­Ref to add a reference to it so that they could continue using the array after the method returned, but they found that if they tried to use the array later, the safearray-&amp;gt;pData was NULL, and if they c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260128-00/?p=112021 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACP Agent Registry Is Live: Find and Connect AI Coding Agents in Your JetBrains IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI coding agents are multiplying fast. Some of the most common ones include Gemini CLI, Claude Code, Auggie, OpenCode, and Copilot, and more are being released every day. Each comes with its own unique strengths, specific setups, and varying levels of editor support. Keeping track of what’s out there, let alone getting it running in your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/01/acp-agent-registry/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendor Lock-In vs. Strategic Partnership for Your CI/CD</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Jakkie Koekemoer &amp;amp; Shweta, draft.dev. Traditional wisdom in the dev world is that once you opt for proprietary APIs or vendor-specific tooling, migrating to alternative platforms is costly or impractical to adopt in the future. That’s why engineering teams have considered vendor lock-in a trap. You end up […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/vendor-lock-in-vs-strategic-partnership/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Data JDBC Made Easy with IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA is well-known for its Spring Framework support. The IDE helps with bean navigation, on-the-go bean injection, Spring Data methods completion, and assistance with generating HTTP requests for controllers. One of the areas that IDEA is good at is dealing with JPA. You, as a developer, can: Before IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3, dealing with Spring […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2026/01/spring-data-jdbc-made-easy-with-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Colab Support Is Now Available in PyCharm 2025.3.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm is designed to support the full range of modern Python workflows, from web development to data and ML/AI work, in a single IDE. An essential part of these workflows is Jupyter notebooks, which are widely used for experimentation, data exploration, and prototyping across many roles. PyCharm provides first-class support for Jupyter notebooks, both locally […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2026/01/google-colab-support-is-now-available-in-pycharm-2025-3-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in .NET 10 and C# 14: Multi-Tenant Rate Limiting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:06:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 is officially out, along with C# 14. Microsoft has released .NET 10 as Long-Term Support (LTS) as a successor to .NET 8. Like every version, it is not just an update but brings something new to the table. In this series, we will explore which aspects of software
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/new-in-net-10-and-c-14-multi-tenant-rate-limiting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects with Spargine: Supercharge Your .NET Apps with NetworkHelper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NetworkHelper is a utility created to streamline network-related operations for .NET applications. It centralizes code for network diagnostics, logging, and performance tuning, offering a clean API for tasks like retrieving IP addresses and statistics. This reduces code duplication, enhances reliability, and simplifies maintenance for developers.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/01/28/boost-your-net-projects-with-spargine-supercharge-your-net-apps-with-networkhelper/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMEA Youth &amp; Wellbeing Grant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Apply for the EMEA Youth &amp;amp; Wellbeing Grant, a €500,000 program funding NGOs and researchers advancing youth safety and wellbeing in the age of AI.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/emea-youth-and-wellbeing-grant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The next chapter for AI in the EU</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI launches the EU Economic Blueprint 2.0 with new data, partnerships, and initiatives to accelerate AI adoption, skills, and growth across Europe.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/the-next-chapter-for-ai-in-the-eu 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping your data safe when an AI agent clicks a link</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI protects user data when AI agents open links, preventing URL-based data exfiltration and prompt injection with built-in safeguards.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/ai-agent-link-safety 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
