<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 15:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using SQL Server&#39;s new AI features and Python to create a T-SQL assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;Guest Post&amp;quot;]Rodrigo Ribeiro Gomes, Head of Innovation at Power Tuning, has been leveraging the new AI features in SQL Server engine to simplify the lives of DBAs and developers. He generously shared his experience with us: thank you, Rodrigo![/alert] I recently created a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/using-sql-servers-new-ai-features-and-python-to-create-a-t-sql-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 15: A custom shared pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we made our trackable object implementation&#39;s constructors and assignment operations non-throwing, although it came at a cost of making
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250829-00/?p=111526 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your Copilot with SonarQube via Docker MCP Toolkit and Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the era of AI copilots and code generation tools productivity is skyrocketing, but so is the risk of insecure, untested, or messy code slipping into production. How do you ensure it doesn’t introduce vulnerabilities, bugs, or bad practices? A widely adopted tool to help address these concerns is SonarQube. It provides a rich set...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/blog-sonarqube-copilot-docker-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.1 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 09:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the first minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 – v2025.2.1. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-2-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Boti: The AI assistant transforming how the citizens of Buenos Aires access government information with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes the agentic AI assistant built by the Government of the City of Buenos Aires and the GenAIIC to respond to citizens’ questions about government procedures. The solution consists of two primary components: an input guardrail system that helps prevent the system from responding to harmful user queries and a government procedures agent that retrieves relevant information and generates responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/meet-boti-the-ai-assistant-transforming-how-the-citizens-of-buenos-aires-access-government-information-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering air quality research with secure, ML-driven predictive analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a data imputation solution using Amazon SageMaker AI, AWS Lambda, and AWS Step Functions. This solution is designed for environmental analysts, public health officials, and business intelligence professionals who need reliable PM2.5 data for trend analysis, reporting, and decision-making. We sourced our sample training dataset from openAFRICA. Our solution predicts PM2.5 values using time-series forecasting.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/empowering-air-quality-research-with-secure-ml-driven-predictive-analytics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Finance built an AI assistant using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Kendra to support analysts for data discovery and business insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Amazon Finance technical team develops and manages comprehensive technology solutions that power financial decision-making and operational efficiency while standardizing across Amazon’s global operations. In this post, we explain how the team conceptualized and implemented a solution to these business challenges by harnessing the power of generative AI using Amazon Bedrock and intelligent search with Amazon Kendra.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-finance-built-an-ai-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-kendra-to-support-analysts-for-data-discovery-and-business-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with the Aspire CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Aspire CLI is a powerful, cross-platform tool designed to streamline the development, management, and deployment of application systems. Whether you’re building a simple website or an enterprise-scale distributed application with microservices and queues and databases, the Aspire CLI offers an interactive-first experience to help you cre
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/getting-started-with-the-aspire-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Awesome Copilot MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re excited to announce the Awesome Copilot MCP Server - a simple way to search those customizations and save them directly to your repository from the MCP server. In early July, we announced the community-driven Awesome GitHub Co
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/announcing-awesome-copilot-mcp-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 16:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve released another update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 – v2025.1.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following updates: To find out more about the resolved issues, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/intellij-idea-2025-1-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 14: Nonthrowing moves with the shared tracking pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So far, we&#39;ve been working on an alternate design for tracking pointers, but we found that it had the unfortunate property of having potentially-throwing constructors and m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250828-00/?p=111524 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bob’s Used Books: Build a .NET Serverless Application on AWS – Part 2: Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 13:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This post covers the architecture and components of a modern .NET serverless application, demonstrating implementation patterns for authentication, data storage, image processing, and API management that showcase the optimization benefits of this architecture. AWS serverless architecture provides improved scalability, cost-efficiency, and reduced operational overhead. Part 1 of this series focused on initial setup and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/bobs-used-books-build-a-net-serverless-application-on-aws-part-2-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure by Design: A Shift-Left Approach with Testcontainers, Docker Scout, and Hardened Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced world of software development, product teams are expected to move quickly: building features, shipping updates, and reacting to user needs in real-time. But moving fast should never mean compromising on quality or security. Thanks to modern tooling, developers can now maintain high standards while accelerating delivery. In a previous article, we explored...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/a-shift-left-approach-with-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing gpt-realtime and Realtime API updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re releasing a more advanced speech-to-speech model and new API capabilities including MCP server support, image input, and SIP phone calling support.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-realtime 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog 0.4.0 Is Out: Observable, Predictable, and Deployable Anywhere You Build</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 09:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Featuring Langfuse and W&amp;amp;B Weave Support, Ktor Integration, Native Structured Output, iOS Target, GPT-5, and More. Koog 0.3.0 was about making agents smarter and persistent. Koog 0.4.0 is about making them observable, seamlessly deployable in your stack, and more predictable in their outputs – all while introducing support for new models and platforms. Read on […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/08/koog-0-4-0-is-out-observable-predictable-and-deployable-anywhere-you-build/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper’s New Out-of-Process Engine Cuts UI Freezes in Visual Studio by 80%</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio power users love ReSharper’s deep analysis, but the cost has been the occasional UI hiccup that breaks the flow of work. In ReSharper 2025.2, analysis runs in a separate 64-bit worker out of Visual Studio’s UI process. Previously, ReSharper shared Visual Studio’s UI process, so long analyses could stall the UI thread. Now, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/28/resharper-s-new-out-of-process-engine-cuts-ui-freezes-in-visual-studio-by-80/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting nonprofit and community innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI launches a $50M People-First AI Fund to help U.S. nonprofits scale impact with AI. Applications open Sept 8–Oct 8, 2025 for grants in education, healthcare, research, and more.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/supporting-nonprofit-and-community-innovation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for AI in Visual Studio (September)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 18:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to share our public roadmap, which outlines the next steps in evolving Visual Studio with AI-powered agentic experiences. With every month, we aim to deliver smarter, faster, and more intuitive tools that enhance your coding experience. Disclaimer: The items outlined here represent ongoing work for the month. They
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/roadmap-for-ai-in-visual-studio-september 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EFCore.Visualizer - View Entity Framework Core query plan inside Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog from Giorgi Dalakishvili, the developer of EFCore.Visualizer. Entity Framework Core is a powerful, feature-rich ORM powering many of today&#39;s applications. W
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/ef-core-visualizer-view-entity-framework-core-query-plan-inside-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercury foundation models from Inception Labs are now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 15:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we announce that Mercury and Mercury Coder foundation models from Inception Labs are now available through Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. We demonstrate how to deploy these ultra-fast diffusion-based language models that can generate up to 1,100 tokens per second on NVIDIA H100 GPUs, and showcase their capabilities in code generation and tool use scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mercury-foundation-models-from-inception-labs-are-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2025.3 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.3, which we plan to introduce in November. After reviewing your feedback and our strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following: 🚀 Transitioning to the CLion Nova language engine as the default. 🏗️ Improvements to project formats and build tools. 🎛️ Improvements to features for embedded development. 🤖 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/2025-3-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 13: Restoring the strong exception guarantee</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we created a tracking pointer class based on std::shared_ptr. We found a problem with the move-assignment operator: It didn&#39;t satisfy the str
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250827-00/?p=111518 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop Accelerates Innovation with Faster Release Cadence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce a major evolution in how we deliver Docker Desktop updates to you. Starting with Docker Desktop release 4.45.0 on 28 August we&#39;re moving to releases every two weeks, with the goal of reaching weekly releases by the end of 2025. Why We&#39;re Making This Change You&#39;ve told us you want faster...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-updates-every-two-weeks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Science With Kotlin: A Powerlifting Case Study</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Adele Carpenter. Adele is a Software Engineer and Consultant at Trifork Amsterdam, where she works on educational systems in the Kotlin/Java/Spring ecosystem and advises customers on their projects. TL;DR This blog post uses a dataset from the sport of powerlifting to get you up and running with Kotlin Notebooks, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/exploring-data-science-with-kotlin-a-powerlifting-case-study/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Incremental Source Generators in C#: A Complete Guide with Example</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 12:08:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the Previous blog, I discussed source generators. .NET has introduced an improved version of a source generator, called Incremental Source Generator. The new type generates code faster and reduces the code, improving readability. In this post, I will introduce the new type of source generator and compare it to
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/mastering-incremental-source-generators-in-csharp-a-complete-guide-with-example/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and Anthropic share findings from a joint safety evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Anthropic share findings from a first-of-its-kind joint safety evaluation, testing each other’s models for misalignment, instruction following, hallucinations, jailbreaking, and more—highlighting progress, challenges, and the value of cross-lab collaboration.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-anthropic-safety-evaluation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Outside-In Discovery with Claude Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 08:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a previous article available below, I walked through a structured approach to exploring new codebases.An Outside-In Approach to Discover Unknown CodebasesJumping into a new codebase is never easy. It takes time, patience, and often a fair bit of frustration. And when the codebase is legacy — undocumented,
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/augmented-outside-discovery-claude-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for the Best School Year Ever? Join Our STEM Clubs, Camps, and Competitions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 07:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The start of a new school year brings new chances to learn, grow, and geek out on the stuff you love. If you’re into math, coding, or AI, we’ve got you covered with fun and challenging activities. Youth Clubs Join one (or more) of our free online clubs to sharpen your skills, prep for olympiads, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/08/27/new-school-year-2025-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encoding Changes for Template Arguments in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 05:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In previous versions of the Semantic Kernel, the encoding of template arguments was performed automatically if the argument type was a string. The encoding was not applied for custom types, anonymous types, or collections. With the latest changes, we&#39;ve introduced stricter rules: if automatic encoding is enabled (the default be
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/encoding-changes-for-template-arguments-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Authentication Changes in Semantic Kernel Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 05:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In previous versions of the Semantic Kernel Python, the default fallback authentication mechanism for Azure services like AzureChatCompletion was DefaultAzureCredential from the Azure Identity library. This provided a convenient way to authenticate without explicitly passing credentials, especially during development.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/azure-authentication-changes-in-semantic-kernel-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Transform for .NET now supports connection to Azure Repos and Azure Artifacts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 20:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In May 2025, we launched AWS Transform for .NET with the capability to connect and download .NET code bases from GitHub, GitLab, or Bitbucket for transformation (described in the AWS Transform User Guide). AWS Transform now also supports code bases in Azure Repos and Azure Artifacts. With this new capability, you can transform .NET applications […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/aws-transform-for-net-now-supports-connection-to-azure-repos-and-azure-artifacts/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Kotlin Notebook Helps You Teach Programming</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kotlin Notebook is a great tool for educators who want to teach programming in a more hands-on way. It lets you combine runnable code, Markdown textual explanations, and visualizations in one interactive environment. There’s no need to switch between multiple windows with slides, live demos, and IDEs during lectures. You can use a single notebook […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/how-kotlin-notebook-helps-teach-programming/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn how Amazon Health Services improved discovery in Amazon search using AWS ML and gen AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Amazon Health Services (AHS) solved discoverability challenges on Amazon.com search using AWS services such as Amazon SageMaker, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon EMR. By combining machine learning (ML), natural language processing, and vector search capabilities, we improved our ability to connect customers with relevant healthcare offerings.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/learn-how-amazon-health-services-improved-discovery-in-amazon-search-using-aws-ml-and-gen-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Visual Studio August Update is here - smarter AI, better debugging, and more control</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The August 2025 update for Visual Studio 2022 (v17.14) is now available, and it’s all about helping developers stay focused, productive, and in control. Whether you&#39;re building games, tuning performance, or exploring AI, this release brings meaningful improvements that make everyday development smoother and smarter.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/the-visual-studio-august-update-is-here-smarter-ai-better-debugging-and-more-control 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Terminal Preview 1.24 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 16:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re back with another Terminal release for you! This development cycle, we focused on overall quality of life improvements and bug fixes. We are also updating Windows Terminal stable to version 1.23, which will include all of the features from
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/windows-terminal-preview-1-24-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a CI/CD Pipeline for iOS Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 15:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Kumar Harsh, draft.dev. Developing and releasing iOS applications involves navigating a complex web of code signing, provisioning profiles, multiple iOS versions, and stringent App Store guidelines/requirements. Without an automated continuous integration, continuous delivery and/or deployment (CI/CD) pipeline, these challenges can lead to slower release cycles, increased errors, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/08/cicd-for-ios/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 12: A shared tracking pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The tracking pointer designs we&#39;ve been using so far have had O(n) complexity on move, where n is the number of outstanding tracking pointers. But we can reduce this to O(1) by the classic technique of introducing another level of indirection. What we can do is give every trackable object
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250826-00/?p=111506 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing an old .NET Core native library loading issue on Alpine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I walk through the process of solving a native library loading issue on alpine with an old .NET runtime, showing the steps we took and the solution
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/fixing-an-old-dotnet-core-native-library-loading-issue-on-alpine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Ruby Debuggers: byebug, debug gem, and the Power of RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 07:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, Ruby developers! Whether you are a seasoned Ruby developer or just getting started, mastering the debugger will save you time and frustration when tracking down bugs. At RubyMine, we’ve spent years building debugging tools for Ruby. In this blog series, we’re sharing some of the insights we’ve gained along the way. In this post, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/08/unveiling-ruby-debuggers-byebug-debug-gem-and-the-power-of-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping people when they need it most</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How we think about safety for users experiencing mental or emotional distress, the limits of today’s systems, and the work underway to refine them.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/helping-people-when-they-need-it-most 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Connections with Entra ID Support in the DocumentDB VS Code Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 22:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re thrilled to announce a major update to the DocumentDB for VS Code extension that will make life easier for enterprise developers. With
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/secure-your-connections-with-entra-id-support-in-the-documentdb-vs-code-extension 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for Kotlin Multiplatform and Compose Multiplatform – August 2025 Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 18:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post outlines our priorities and the general direction for our Kotlin Multiplatform and Compose Multiplatform projects over the next six to twelve months. Our goals for Kotlin Multiplatform are closely aligned with those detailed in the Kotlin roadmap. Be sure to check it out for more context around the direction we’re heading. Key priorities […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kmp-roadmap-aug-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot for Azure (Preview) Launches in Visual Studio 2022 with Azure MCP Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 18:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The GitHub Copilot for Azure extension is now in Public Preview for Visual Studio 2022 (17.14+). It brings a curated set of Azure developer tools—exposed through the Azure MCP server—directly into GitHub Copilot Agent Mode in Visual Studio. The extension automatically installs and manages the Azure MCP server, so you can query resources, d
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/github-copilot-for-azure-preview-launches-in-visual-studio-2022-with-azure-mcp-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MauiReactor: An MVU Approach for .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog from Adolfo Marinucci. I&#39;m a full-stack developer from Italy, primarily focused on Microsoft technologies ranging from cross-platform applications with .NET MAUI to ASP.NET Core backend services hosted on Azure. I&#39;m the creator of MauiReactor, a UI library for .N
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mauireactor-mvu-for-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 11: Repairing assignment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we made sure that tracking pointers to const objects couldn&#39;t be converted into tracking pointers to non-const objects, but I noted that fixing this introduced a new pro
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250825-00/?p=111497 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Worktree: Managing Multiple Working Directories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Git worktree is a powerful feature that allows you to have multiple working directories associated with a single repository. Instead of switching branches and potentially losing uncommitted work, you can check out different branches in separate directories simultaneously without recloning the repository. Git worktree creates additional working trees linked to the same repository. Each worktree can have a…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/git-worktree-managing-multiple-working-directories.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning and Deploying GPT Models Using Hugging Face Transformers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 11:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hugging Face is currently a household name for machine learning researchers and enthusiasts. One of their biggest successes is Transformers, a model-definition framework for machine learning models in text, computer vision, audio, and video. Because of the vast repository of state-of-the-art machine learning models available on the Hugging Face Hub and the compatibility of Transformers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/08/fine-tuning-and-deploying-gpt-models-using-hugging-face-transformers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the OpenAI Learning Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_08_2025/25_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI announces the launch of OpenAI Learning Accelerator, an initiative that aims to bring advanced AI to India’s educators and millions of learners nationwide through accelerated AI research, training, and deployment.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/learning-accelerator 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Harness the Power of Async Queues with Spargine’s ChannelQueue</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_08_2025/24_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_08_2025/24_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Spargine library introduces ChannelQueue, an efficient, thread-safe queue for .NET asynchronous programming, addressing the lack of a built-in async queue. It supports various features like async operations, bounded capacities, cancellation, and batch processing, making it ideal for managing async data flows and enhancing application responsiveness.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/08/24/boost-your-net-projects-harness-the-power-of-async-queues-with-spargines-channelqueue/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Mistakes of New Managers and Leads - Dev Leader Weekly 106</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss some of the biggest mistakes made by new managers and team leads.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/23/top-mistakes-of-new-managers-and-leads-dev-leader-weekly-106 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-08-22</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 06:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/08/23/weekly-recap-20250822 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Cost of Abstractions in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2025/23_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not all abstractions are created equal. Some isolate real volatility and protect your system from change. Others quietly pile up complexity and hide performance problems. Learn when to embrace abstractions versus when they become technical debt that slows down your team.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-real-cost-of-abstractions-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone is talkin’ bout vibes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 18:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Leading up to Microsoft Ignite, I wanted to pressure-test something the community keeps talking about: vibe coding. It’s a style of AI-assisted development where you describe outcomes in natural language and your assistant does most of the scaffolding, refacto
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/everyone-is-talkin-bout-vibes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Geospatial Analysis and GIS Workflows with Amazon Bedrock Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applying emerging technologies to the geospatial domain offers a unique opportunity to create transformative user experiences and intuitive workstreams for users and organizations to deliver on their missions and responsibilities. In this post, we explore how you can integrate existing systems with Amazon Bedrock to create new workflows to unlock efficiencies insights. This integration can benefit technical, nontechnical, and leadership roles alike.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-geospatial-analysis-and-gis-workflows-with-amazon-bedrock-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the basics: A comprehensive foundation model selection framework for generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the model landscape expands, organizations face complex scenarios when selecting the right foundation model for their applications. In this blog post we present a systematic evaluation methodology for Amazon Bedrock users, combining theoretical frameworks with practical implementation strategies that empower data scientists and machine learning (ML) engineers to make optimal model selections.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/beyond-the-basics-a-comprehensive-foundation-model-selection-framework-for-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking GPT-5’s Freeform Tool Calling: A New Era of Seamless Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5 models are now available in Azure AI Foundry via Azure OpenAI. Designed for advanced reasoning and generation. One of the core capabilities of the model is tool calling, which enables it to interact with external systems by generating an
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/unlocking-gpt-5s-freeform-tool-calling-a-new-era-of-seamless-integration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate intelligent document processing with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce our open source GenAI IDP Accelerator—a tested solution that we use to help customers across industries address their document processing challenges. Automated document processing workflows accurately extract structured information from documents, reducing manual effort. We will show you how this ready-to-deploy solution can help you build those workflows with generative AI on AWS in days instead of months.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-intelligent-document-processing-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker HyperPod enhances ML infrastructure with scalability and customizability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduced three features in SageMaker HyperPod that enhance scalability and customizability for ML infrastructure. Continuous provisioning offers flexible resource provisioning to help you start training and deploying your models faster and manage your cluster more efficiently. With custom AMIs, you can align your ML environments with organizational security standards and software requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-enhances-ml-infrastructure-with-scalability-and-customizability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin on the Backend – What’s New From KotlinConf 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 15:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            KotlinConf 2025 has firmly placed server-side Kotlin in the spotlight, and rightly so. Between Spring collaboration, an upgraded ecosystem, performance boosts, AI tooling, and the adoption of the language by big companies, this is Kotlin at its (backend) best. Here’s a breakdown of what was announced, what’s new, and what you absolutely must check out […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kotlin-on-the-backend-what-s-new-from-kotlinconf-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 10: Proper conversion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we added the ability to convert tracking pointers to non-const objects into tracking pointers to const objects, but we noted that there&#39;s a problem. The problem is that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250822-00/?p=111494 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Drive Integration, Python 3.11 in Conda Environments, and Security improvements in Datalore 2025.4</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 10:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.4 is now available, bringing support for Google Drive folders as data connections, Python 3.11 in conda environments, and a dozen of small behind-the-scenes enhancements and bug fixes. These updates are already available for Datalore Cloud users, and Datalore On-Premises users can get them by updating their Datalore instance. Google Drive integration At Datalore, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/08/22/google-drive-integration-python-3-11-in-conda-environments-and-security-improvements-in-datalore-2025-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 09:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview 2 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.OData.Core 9.0.0 Preview 2
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/odata-net-9-preview-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating life sciences research</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how a specialized AI model, GPT-4b micro, helped OpenAI and Retro Bio engineer more effective proteins for stem cell therapy and longevity research.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/accelerating-life-sciences-research-with-retro-biosciences 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create embeddings in SQL Server 2025 RC0 with a local ONNX model on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 01:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of SQL Server 2025 RC0, we have enabled the ability to use a local ONNX model on th
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/create-embeddings-in-sql-server-2025-rc0-with-a-local-onnx-model-on-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
