<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Working with Git Submodules: Managing Dependencies Across Repositories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In complex software projects, it’s common to split functionality across multiple repositories. One common scenario arises when your main project depends on outputs or components developed in another repository that&#39;s also evolving in parallel. Managing this dependency effectively—especially when only a specific part of the secondary reposi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/git-submodules-and-dependencies 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for the .NET 10 GC (DATAS)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is cross-posted from Maoni&#39;s blog post original Medium article Preparing for the .NET 10 GC by permission. Preparing for the .NET 10 GC In .NET 9 we enabled DATAS by default. But .NET 9 is not an LTS relea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/preparing-for-dotnet-10-gc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vxceed builds the perfect sales pitch for sales teams at scale using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Vxceed used Amazon Bedrock to develop this AI-powered multi-agent solution that generates personalized sales pitches for field sales teams at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/vxceed-builds-the-perfect-sales-pitch-for-sales-teams-at-scale-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting Your KotlinConf Proposal: Expert Tips to  Help You Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thinking about sharing your Kotlin expertise on the big stage? KotlinConf is the premier event for all things Kotlin, and getting a talk accepted for inclusion in the conference is a fantastic way to contribute to the community and elevate your profile. However, submitting a talk proposal, especially for the first time, can feel daunting. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/crafting-your-kotlinconf-proposal-expert-tips/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a secure MLOps platform based on Terraform and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Machine learning operations (MLOps) is the combination of people, processes, and technology to productionize ML use cases efficiently. To achieve this, enterprise customers must develop MLOps platforms to support reproducibility, robustness, and end-to-end observability of the ML use case’s lifecycle. Those platforms are based on a multi-account setup by adopting strict security constraints, development best […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-a-secure-mlops-platform-based-on-terraform-and-github/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Runtime API design principles around read-write properties: Idempotence and self-assignment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Objects in the Windows Runtime can have properties, and those properties could be read-only or read-write. For read-write properties, there are a few general principles. Today we&#39;re going to look at this one: Setting a property to its current value is legal and has no effect.¹ For example: // C# o
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251008-00/?p=111660 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Captain’s Chair: Pradumna Saraf</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Captains are leaders from the developer community that are both experts in their field and are passionate about sharing their Docker knowledge with others. “From the Captain’s Chair” is a blog series where we get a closer look at one Captain to learn more about them and their experiences. Today, we are interviewing Pradumna...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/from-the-captains-chair-pradumna-saraf/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling All Non-Commercial JetBrains Rider Users: Tell Us Your Stories!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, everyone! It’s been almost a year since we made Rider free for non-commercial use. To celebrate this milestone, we want to spotlight the amazing projects it helped create. We’re looking to interview a handful of users who’ve taken advantage of the free non-commercial use license, whether it was to build a side project, contribute […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/08/calling-all-non-commercial-rider-users/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Local AI on Any GPU: Docker Model Runner Now with Vulkan Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running large language models (LLMs) on your local machine is one of the most exciting frontiers in AI development. At Docker, our goal is to make this process as simple and accessible as possible. That’s why we built Docker Model Runner, a tool to help you download and run LLMs with a single command. Until...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-vulkan-gpu-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing impact and scale with ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how HiBob uses ChatGPT Enterprise and custom GPTs to scale AI adoption, boost revenue, streamline HR workflows, and deliver AI-powered features in the Bob platform.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/hibob 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel and Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week we announced Microsoft Agent Framework, you can find all the details: In the blog post here: Introduci
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-and-microsoft-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing a new OData.NET serializer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the major, recurring complaints of the OData.NET libraries is the performance overhead of the serialization stack. We have done a lot of work to improve the serialization performance, but the existing architecture limits how far we can go. For this reason, we have started work on a new serialization stack for OData.NET libraries that ad
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-a-new-odata-net-serializer 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Programming with Microsoft .NET: Anticipate Errors and Eliminate Bugs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This discusses the principles of defensive programming to enhance software development. It emphasizes error prevention strategies such as input validation, comprehensive error handling, and assumption checking. By adopting these practices, developers can create reliable, maintainable applications, reduce bugs and their associated costs, and improve overall code quality and user satisfaction.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/10/08/defensive-programming-with-microsoft-net-anticipate-errors-and-eliminate-bugs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in Azure AI Foundry | September 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Models (GA + Preview): GPT‑5‑Codex (GA) brings multimodal code reasoning &amp;amp; repo intelligence; Sora adds video‑to‑video (Preview); Grok 4 Fast (Preview) enables low‑latency reasoning / non‑reasoning routing; o4‑mini RFT graduates to GA for reward‑driven optimization.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/whats-new-in-azure-ai-foundry-september-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your API Errors Suck (Here’s How to Fix Them)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 21:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’ve been using an HTTP API as a consumer and how ti deals with it’s HTTP API Errors is terrible. Tt’s returning back a 200 OK. And in the body of the response, it has an error property that has a user facing message. You might be thinking, if you just return a 400 status… Read More »Your API Errors Suck (Here’s How to Fix Them) The post Your API Errors Suck (Here’s How to Fix Them) appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the new Azure DevOps Server RC Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release candidate (RC) of Azure DevOps Server, bringing new features previously available in our hosted version. You can download Azure DevOps Server RC tod
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/announcing-the-new-azure-devops-server-rc-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet JetBrains at Azure Dev Summit 2025 (Lisbon, Oct 13–16)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains will be at Azure Dev Summit 2025 in Lisbon, and we’d love to connect with attendees interested in learning more about our products and services. My name is Max Solovyev, and I’m the Head of Growth at .NET and GameDev Tools – I’ll be on site and available throughout the event for brief, no-pressure […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/07/meet-jetbrains-at-azure-dev-summit-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Amazon QuickSight data stories creation with agentic AI using Amazon Nova Act</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Nova Act automates QuickSight data story creation, saving time so you can focus on making critical, data-driven business decisions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-amazon-quicksight-data-stories-creation-with-agentic-ai-using-amazon-nova-act/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement automated monitoring for Amazon Bedrock batch inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrated how a financial services company can use an FM to process large volumes of customer records and get specific data-driven product recommendations. We also showed how to implement an automated monitoring solution for Amazon Bedrock batch inference jobs. By using EventBridge, Lambda, and DynamoDB, you can gain real-time visibility into batch processing operations, so you can efficiently generate personalized product recommendations based on customer credit data.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer and AI Code Reviewer: Reviewing AI-Generated Code in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enhancing the role of the developer with the responsibility of reviewing AI-generated code is a transformative step for developers. You become a critical gatekeeper for the quality, reliability, and maintainability of code produced by advanced AI tools like GitHub Copilot. While the volume of code reviews may increase, so does the opportuni
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/developer-and-ai-code-reviewer-reviewing-ai-generated-code-in-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the end of support for VRML in Internet Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was cleaning out some old documents and found an email from 1999 on some changes to Internet Explorer. Most of it is boring, but I found this part interesting: VRML is being removed from IE5.5 and will only be available on Windows Update. The company that supplied the component cancelled the project¹ (and at th
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251007-00/?p=111657 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Now Supports DAP Debuggers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest EAP build of CLion 2025.3, released yesterday, includes support for the Debug Adapter Protocol (DAP), which allows CLion to communicate with a variety of additional debuggers. Besides the bundled LLDB and GDB, you can now work with third-party implementations that support DAP. This feature brings CLion closer to becoming an IDE that is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/10/dap-debuggers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powered by Docker: How Open Source Genius Cut Entropy Debt with Docker MCP Toolkit and Claude Desktop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is part of the Powered by Docker series, where we feature use cases and success stories from Docker partners and practitioners. This story was contributed by Ryan Wanner. Ryan has more than fifteen years of experience as an entrepreneur and 3 years in AI space developing software and is the founder of Open Source...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/open-source-genius-cut-entropy-debt-docker-mcp-claude/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disrupting malicious uses of AI: October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how OpenAI is detecting and disrupting malicious uses of AI in our October 2025 report. Learn how we’re countering misuse, enforcing policies, and protecting users from real-world harms.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/disrupting-malicious-uses-of-ai-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes to inline image representation in Outlook on the web and new Outlook for Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’d like to inform you about an update to how inline images are represented in the HTML body of Outlook emails in Outlook on the web and the new Outlook for Windows. This change may impact how your add-in identifies and processes inline images when using the attachment ID. What’s changing? Previously, inl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/changes-to-inline-images-in-outlook 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Granite 4.0 Models Now Available on Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 21:29:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers can now discover and run IBM’s latest open-source Granite 4.0 language models from the Docker Hub model catalog, and start building in minutes with Docker Model Runner. Granite 4.0 pairs strong, enterprise-ready performance with a lightweight footprint, so you can prototype locally and scale confidently. The Granite 4.0 family is designed for speed, flexibility,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ibm-granite-4-0-models-now-available-on-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlimited access to Docker Hardened Images: Because security should be affordable, always</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 21:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every organization we speak with shares the same goal: to deliver software that is secure and free of CVEs. Near-zero CVEs is the ideal state. But achieving that ideal is harder than it sounds, because paradoxes exist at every step. Developers patch quickly, yet new CVEs appear faster than fixes can ship. Organizations standardize on...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/unlimited-access-to-docker-hardened-images-because-security-should-be-affordable-always/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI: How PowerSchool safeguards millions of students with AI-powered content filtering using Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how PowerSchool built and deployed a custom content filtering solution using Amazon SageMaker AI that achieved better accuracy while maintaining low false positive rates. We walk through our technical approach to fine tuning Llama 3.1 8B, our deployment architecture, and the performance results from internal validations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-how-powerschool-safeguards-millions-of-students-with-ai-powered-content-filtering-using-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Nova Will Become the Default Engine for All Users in v2025.3 – Here’s What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion Nova became the default language engine for new users starting with v2024.2. Since then, we’ve delivered the features users wanted most and addressed key bugs. We’ve also received very positive feedback from people and organizations who have tried the new engine and compared it with the legacy one, CLion Classic. All of this has […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/10/nova-default-for-all/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains × Zed: Open Interoperability for AI Coding Agents in Your IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, our mission is simple: help developers achieve engineering excellence without distractions or vendor lock-in. Today, we’re excited to share that we’re collaborating with Zed on the Agent Client Protocol (ACP) – an open protocol that lets AI coding agents work inside editors, including JetBrains IDEs, if both are ACP-compatible. Why this collaboration matters […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/10/jetbrains-zed-open-interoperability-for-ai-coding-agents-in-your-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Dev/Test Benefit Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Before joining Microsoft, I served as VP of Application Development at one of the largest temporary staffing companies in the United States. I’ll never forget the look on our CFO’s face when I told him we needed two to three additional cloud environments to support a large-scale modernization project. His
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-dev-test-benefit-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 ReSharper Features Every .NET Developer Should Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Around 15 years ago, I got my first assistant job at a university department. Frankly, I only used ReSharper for its solution-wide analysis, which would alert me whenever I broke the spaghetti code I got served. I did not know about all the refactorings yet. It was only at my second job that my awesome […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/06/9-resharper-features-every-dotnet-developer-should-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code comments should apply to the state of the system at the point the comment &#34;executes&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Comments inside the body of a function should apply to the state of the system at the point the comment &amp;quot;executes&amp;quot;. Here&#39;s an example of poor comment placement: // Widget is already vibrating, so we update the waveform in place. // Else the waveform parameters will be set when we start vibrating. if (waveformParameters !
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251006-00/?p=111655 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker at AI Engineer Paris: Build and Secure AI Agents with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week, Docker was thrilled to be part of the inaugural AI Engineer Paris, a spectacular European debut that brought together an extraordinary lineup of speakers and companies. The conference, organized by the Koyeb team, made one thing clear: the days of simply sprinkling &#39;AI dust&#39; on applications are over. Meaningful results demand rigorous engineering,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-engineer-paris-build-secure-ai-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of CI/CD in 2025: Key Insights from the Latest JetBrains Survey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The CI/CD tools market has become increasingly complex over the past few years. DevOps engineers now have to manage a wide range of tools, all with their own complex setups and features. JetBrains’ TeamCity and Research departments came together to produce a joint survey looking into the CI/CD tool market in 2025. To gain […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/10/the-state-of-cicd/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find an Available Network Port for a server in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with network programming in .NET, you might need to find an available port on your system. This is particularly useful when creating server applications, running tests, or developing tools that need to bind to a network port without conflicts. Here&#39;s a simple way to get an available port using the Socket class: Socket s = new Socket(AddressFamily.InterNetwork, SocketType.Stream,…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/how-to-find-an-available-network-port-in-dotnet.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Llama.cpp Gets an Upgrade: Resumable Model Downloads</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve all been there: you&#39;re 90% of the way through downloading a massive, multi-gigabyte GGUF model file for llama.cpp when your internet connection hiccups. The download fails, and the progress bar resets to zero. It&#39;s a frustrating experience that wastes time, bandwidth, and momentum. Well, the llama.cpp community has just shipped a fantastic quality-of-life improvement...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/llama-cpp-resumable-gguf-downloads/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codex is now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI Codex is now generally available with powerful new features for developers: a Slack integration, Codex SDK, and admin tools like usage dashboards and workspace management—making Codex easier to use and manage at scale.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/codex-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The yield return keyword allows you to pause and resume execution of a method, enabling lazy evaluation without generating intermediate collections. This makes writing custom iterators simple and efficient. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 📆 Just two more days […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/06/dotinsights-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing apps in ChatGPT and the new Apps SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re introducing a new generation of apps you can chat with, right inside ChatGPT. Developers can start building them today with the new Apps SDK, available in preview.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-apps-in-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Rider 2025.2.3: The Third Set of Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A third set of updates for the 2025.2 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper ReSharper 2025.2.3 comes with the following fixes: For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/06/resharper-and-rider-2025-2-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to Java Annotated Monthly! Wow, September really flew by! We’ve gathered all the top Java news and insights to help you catch up on anything you missed. First up, we’re diving headfirst into a big splash around Java 25 and all the updates it brings along. Then, as always, you’ll find plenty of tech […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/10/java-annotated-monthly-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMD and OpenAI announce strategic partnership to deploy 6 gigawatts of AMD GPUs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AMD and OpenAI have announced a multi-year partnership to deploy 6 gigawatts of AMD Instinct GPUs, beginning with 1 gigawatt in 2026, to power OpenAI’s next-generation AI infrastructure and accelerate global AI innovation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-amd-strategic-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating AI adoption in Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Allied for Startups release the Hacktivate AI report with 20 actionable policy ideas to accelerate AI adoption in Europe, boost competitiveness, and empower innovators.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/accelerating-ai-uptake-in-europe 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AgentKit, new Evals, and RFT for agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re releasing new tools to help developers go from prototype to production faster: AgentKit, expanded evals capabilities, and reinforcement fine-tuning for agents.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-agentkit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Secure Passwords with PBKDF2PasswordHasher in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_10_2025/05_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_10_2025/05_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The PBKDF2PasswordHasher in Spargine is essential for securely handling passwords in modern applications. It uses the PBKDF2 algorithm to hash passwords with a unique salt and multiple iterations, making it resistant to brute-force attacks. Upcoming updates will enhance its versatility by supporting additional algorithms, ensuring future readiness.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/10/05/boost-your-net-projects-secure-passwords-with-pbkdf2passwordhasher-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing With Underperforming Team Members - Dev Leader Weekly 111</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2025/04_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2025/04_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss navigating situations where team members are underperforming.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/10/04/dealing-with-underperforming-team-members-dev-leader-weekly-111 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-10-03</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2025/04_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 06:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2025/04_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/10/04/weekly-recap-20251003 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Stored Procedures and Functions With EF Core and PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2025/04_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2025/04_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use PostgreSQL stored procedures and functions with EF Core to handle complex queries, atomic operations with locking, and database-specific features while keeping the type safety and convenience of EF Core.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/using-stored-procedures-and-functions-with-ef-core-and-postgresql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock global AI inference scalability using new global cross-Region inference on Amazon Bedrock  with Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet 4.5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 21:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are increasingly integrating generative AI capabilities into their applications to enhance customer experiences, streamline operations, and drive innovation. As generative AI workloads continue to grow in scale and importance, organizations face new challenges in maintaining consistent performance, reliability, and availability of their AI-powered applications. Customers are looking to scale their AI inference workloads across […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-global-ai-inference-scalability-using-new-global-cross-region-inference-on-amazon-bedrock-with-anthropics-claude-sonnet-4-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure ingress connectivity to Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway using interface VPC endpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to access AgentCore Gateway through a VPC interface endpoint from an Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instance in a VPC. We also show how to configure your VPC endpoint policy to provide secure access to the AgentCore Gateway while maintaining the principle of least privilege access.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/secure-ingress-connectivity-to-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway-using-interface-vpc-endpoints/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for AI in Visual Studio (October)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 19:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to share our public roadmap, which outlines the next steps in evolving Visual Studio with AI-powered agentic experiences. With every month, we aim to deliver smarter, faster, and more intuitive tools that enhance your coding experience. Disclaimer: The items outlined here represent ongoing work for the month. They
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/roadmap-for-ai-in-visual-studio-october 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amper Update, October 2025 – Compose Hot Reload and UX Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amper 0.8.0 is out, with Compose Hot Reload, a customizable Kotlin compiler version, new JavaScript and Wasm platforms, and many other improvements to both the IDE and CLI experience. Read on for all of the details, and see the release notes for the full list of changes and bug fixes. To get support for Amper’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/amper/2025/10/amper-update-october-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we get weak functions for static linking? The Visual C&#43;&#43; compiler says &#34;We have weak functions at home&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ELF object file has this thing called &amp;quot;weak functions&amp;quot;. These are functions present in a library that are used by the linker to resolve a symbol only if the main program doesn&#39;t provide a resolution for them. The Visual C++ compiler doesn&#39;t have &amp;quot;weak functions&amp;quot; in this sense, but that doesn&#39;t mean that equivalent functionality
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251003-00/?p=111650 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Lab to Live: A Blueprint for a Voice-Powered AI Sales Coach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Until recently, building real-time voice AI for production was challenging. Developers faced hurdles such as managing audio streams and ensuring low-latency performance. That landscape is changing. The
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/from-lab-to-live-a-blueprint-for-a-voice-powered-ai-sales-coach 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance agentic workflows with enterprise search using Kore.ai and Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how organizations can enhance their employee productivity by integrating Kore.ai’s AI for Work platform with Amazon Q Business. We show how to configure AI for Work as a data accessor for Amazon Q index for independent software vendors (ISVs), so employees can search enterprise knowledge and execute end-to-end agentic workflows involving search, reasoning, actions, and content generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-agentic-workflows-with-enterprise-search-using-kore-ai-and-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate development with the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore MCP server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Model Context Protocol (MCP) Server. With built-in support for runtime, gateway integration, identity management, and agent memory, the AgentCore MCP Server is purpose-built to speed up creation of components compatible with Bedrock AgentCore. You can use the AgentCore MCP server for rapid prototyping, production AI solutions, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-development-with-the-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-mcpserver/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released the next minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 – v2025.2.3. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/10/intellij-idea-2025-2-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Live! Orlando – Your Ultimate Learning Adventure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine swapping stories with fellow developers over dinner as the Florida sun sets, then beginning the next morning with a stroll past the resort’s palm-lined walkways before catching your first session across
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-live-orlando-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (September 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-september-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog × A2A: Building Connected AI Agents in Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever tried building a system of multiple AI agents, you’ve probably run into the problem. It starts simple enough: You’ve got one agent writing blog posts, another proofreading them, and maybe a third suggesting or generating images. Individually, they’re effective. But getting them to work together? That’s where things might start falling apart. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/10/koog-a2a-building-connected-ai-agents-in-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AXA Belgium’s Journey to Running .NET Web APIs on AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Among others, the insurance industry is embracing the benefits of cloud-focused serverless computing services to run code without the overhead of provisioning or managing servers. Moving on-premises .NET Web APIs to such destinations come with a broad range of considerations. This blog post provides a return of experience from AXA Belgium’s engineering team and their […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/axa-belgiums-journey-to-running-net-web-apis-on-aws-lambda/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem with inferring from a function call operator is that there may be more than one</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I wrote briefly on writing a helper class for generating a particular category of C callback wrappers around C++ methods. This particular
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251002-00/?p=111647 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and Visual Studio 2026: Day-One Compatibility, Migration Steps, and Performance Gains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Visual Studio 2026 Insiders is here, and the next major VS update is on the horizon. As with any new Visual Studio version, one of the first questions developers ask is: “Will my extensions work after updating – especially ReSharper?”. The short answer is a resounding “yes”. But there’s more to the story, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/02/resharper-and-visual-studio-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Shell Scripts to Science Agents: How AI Agents Are Transforming Research Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s 2 AM in a lab somewhere. A researcher has three terminals open, a half-written Jupyter notebook on one screen, an Excel sheet filled with sample IDs on another, and a half-eaten snack next to shell commands. They’re juggling scripts to run a protein folding model, parsing CSVs from the last experiment, searching for literature,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-science-agents-research-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning Local Models with Docker Offload and Unsloth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve been experimenting with local models for a while now, and the progress in making them accessible has been exciting. Initial experiences are often fantastic, many models, like Gemma 3 270M, are lightweight enough to run on common hardware. This potential for broad deployment is a major draw. However, as I&#39;ve tried to build meaningful,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/fine-tuning-models-with-offload-and-unsloth/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With GPT-5, Wrtn builds lifestyle AI for millions in Korea</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wrtn scaled AI apps to 6.5M users in Korea with GPT-5, creating ‘Lifestyle AI’ that blends productivity, creativity, and learning—now expanding across East Asia.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/wrtn 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving PHP open source forward</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we want the PHP community to shine. First and foremost, we do this by building PhpStorm, the best IDE for PHP development; but we also support and help drive the PHP Foundation; have just organised PHPverse, accessible for everyone worldwide; and recently we made the Laravel Idea plugin free for all. On top […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/10/moving-php-open-source-forward/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Fabric Eventhouse to Store Great Expectations Validation Results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a previous post, we explored how to perform data validations with Great Expectations (GX) in Microsoft Fabric. We walked through how to set up the validation framework and ensure your data meets the quality standards expected. Now, in thi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/leveraging-fabric-eventhouse-to-store-great-expectations-validation-results 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (September 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 05:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.09.17 registry release, the 2025-08-29 and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-september-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI announces strategic collaboration with Japan’s Digital Agency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Japan’s Digital Agency partner to advance generative AI in public services, support international AI governance, and promote safe, trustworthy AI adoption worldwide.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/strategic-collaboration-with-japan-digital-agency 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
