<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why can’t I find the injected name of a templated class’s templated base class?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The compiler needs help finding it because it&#39;s not findable at the time the template is parsed.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240517-00/?p=109774 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding at the Speed of Innovation: AI and more with Azure SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 13:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Build 2024 approaches, the Azure SQL Database team is preparing a great line-up of product announcements. Innovation continues to be a big theme as we prepare to showcase exciting experiences powered by SQL data and generative AI. The ideal starting point for the new generation of AI-ready SQL apps is Azure SQL Database,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/ai-and-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hub-and-Spoke Network Topology in Microsoft Azure using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A hub-and-spoke network topology is a popular design pattern used to manage and control network traffic when deploying enterprise workloads to Microsoft Azure. This article will guide you through deploying a hub-and-spoke network in Microsoft Azure using HashiCorp Terraform. We will cover the basic concepts, provide sample Terraform code, discuss security best practices to ensure […] The article Deploying Hub-and-Spoke Network Topology in Microsoft Azure using Terraform appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Exercise Caution When Using Take() with a Basic Count</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article advises caution when using the LINQ method Take() with a basic count, suggesting that a range might be recommended by code analyzers. However, benchmark results indicate that using Take() with a simple count is 1.63 times faster than employing a range in such cases.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/17/collection-performance-exercise-caution-when-using-take-with-a-basic-count/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplified State Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post advocates for a simplifying a complex network of states into simple states that correlate with user expectations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/simplified-state-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Source Generators to Validate IOptions in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 02:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll look at how to use source generators to validate IOptions and ensure they meet the required configuration expectations. Let’s dive in! Why We Need to Validate IOptions In ASP.NET Core we have ample choice when it comes to configuration providers. This gives us freedom when choosing a way to set our […] The post Using Source Generators to Validate IOptions in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; at VS Code Day 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 21:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking to get caught up on new C++ features released in the last year? Check out the new YouTube video What’s New with C++ in VS Code posted for VS Code Day 2024. VS Code Day is an annual event hosted by the VS Code team which lets you elevate your development workflow with the latest and greatest features from Visual Studio Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/cpp-at-vs-code-day-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2405.15: Agility SDK 1.614 support and misc bug fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 21:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2405.15, which can be downloaded here. This release has a handful of bug fixes and also adds support for the Direct3D 12 Agility SDK version 1.614. Notably this SDK adds support for the 999e5 texture format.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2405-15 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLDR: Google I/O 2024 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 20:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Google I/O 2024 Keynote was a showcase of technological innovation, underscoring Google’s relentless pursuit of excellence in artificial intelligence (AI). With CEO Sundar Pichai, the event was a celebration of the significant strides made in the past year and a glimpse into the future of AI-driven advancements. Central to the keynote was the Gemini […] The article TLDR: Google I/O 2024 Keynote appeared first on Build5Nines.
Link to article: https://build5nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Permission Prompt API available for Office Add-ins on the web</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 19:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft now requires Office Add-in developers to prompt users for permission to access their device capabilities. To do this, you can now implement the Device Permission API.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/device-permission-prompt-api-available-for-office-add-ins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine’s Test Support Diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 18:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m working on fixing a reported bug with Wolverine today and its event forwarding from Marten feature. I can’t say that I yet know why this should-be-very-straightforward-and-looks-exactly-like-the-currently-passing-tests bug is happening, but it’s a good time to demonstrate Wolverine’s automated testing support and even how it can help you to understand test failures. First off, and … Continue reading Wolverine’s Test Support Diagnostics →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/16/wolverines-test-support-diagnostics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility SDK 1.614.0: R9B9G9E5 support for Render Targets and UAVs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today the DirectX team is excited to announce the release of the Agility SDK 1.614.0 which includes full support for R9G9B9E5_SHAREDEXP (999E5) texture format for render targets and UAV read/writes! This new Agility SDK is also fully supported by PIX. To get the latest release head on over to our Agility SDK downloads page.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agility-sdk-1-614-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How LotteON built a personalized recommendation system using Amazon SageMaker and MLOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with HyeKyung Yang, Jieun Lim, and SeungBum Shim from LotteON. LotteON aims to be a platform that not only sells products, but also provides a personalized recommendation experience tailored to your preferred lifestyle. LotteON operates various specialty stores, including fashion, beauty, luxury, and kids, and strives to provide a personalized shopping […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-lotteon-built-a-personalized-recommendation-system-using-amazon-sagemaker-and-mlops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – May 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 15:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the May release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd), which includes a new demo mode, various .NET Aspire enhancements, and bug fixes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-may-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 14:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new season of our Early Access Program has officially started! The first EAP build for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 is now available for download, offering a sneak peek at some of the exciting updates in the pipeline. You can download the new version from our website, update directly from inside the IDE or via the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/05/intellij-idea-2024-2-eap-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us at Build 2024: Get the latest on Azure Cosmos DB in Seattle or online!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 14:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you ready to dive into the future of AI and data innovation? Microsoft Build 2024 is just around the corner, taking place May 21–23 in Seattle and online. Azure Cosmos DB has lots in store at Build this year and you won’t want to miss it!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/join-us-at-build-2024-get-the-latest-on-azure-cosmos-db-in-seattle-or-online 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling a single item from a C&#43;&#43; parameter pack by its index</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Combining a few tools to make a new tool.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240516-00/?p=109771 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 13:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re glad to announce the opening of the RubyMine 2024.2 Early Access Program. In this blog post, we’ll share what you can expect in this release cycle. What’s coming in RubyMine 2024.2? In this update, our goal is to enhance your RubyMine experience by incorporating new AI features, improving remote work capabilities, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/05/rubymine-2024-2-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing with Accessibility in Mind at Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 13:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Celebrate the Global Accessibility Awareness Day GAAD by taking actionable and easy steps to build accessibility into your development life-cycle! Learn how tools like Accessibility Insights &amp;amp; Visual Studio can help find accessibility issues in development.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/developing-with-accessibility-in-mind-at-microsoft 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve your code quality with GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 12:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous post, we discussed GitHub Copilot’s Slash Commands, which allow you to trigger specific actions within Visual Studio with simple text-based inputs. Now, let’s explore the /optimize command and its potential to improve code quality in Visual Studio. Refactoring with /optimize In a recent exploration by Bruno Capuano,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/improve-your-code-quality-with-github-copilot-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload File from URL to Azure Blob Storage using Azure CLI with Bash and PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 11:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure CLI az storage blob upload command can be used to upload a local file into Azure Blob Storage. However, there are times when it would be easier to upload a file straight from the HTTP(S) URL into Azure Blob Storage. Unfortunately the Azure CLI does not have a command for this specific scenario, […] The article Upload File from URL to Azure Blob Storage using Azure CLI with Bash and PowerShell appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Performance Difference Between Static and Non-Static Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores the performance disparity between static and non-static methods, commonly recommended for efficiency by code analysis tools.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/16/code-it-any-way-you-want-performance-difference-between-static-and-non-static-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oren Eini – Building a Database Engine in C# and .NET – June 18th Livestream</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 05:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on June 18th, 2024, at 2:00 PM UTC on JetBrains TV for our latest livestream with our special guest, the prolific Oren Eini, when they give their presentation, “Building a Database Engine in C# and .NET”. Join Oren Eini, CEO of RavenDB, as he delves into the intricate process of constructing a database […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/16/oren-eini-building-a-database-engine-in-csharp-and-dotnet-june-18th-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Generate a Random Color Name in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 22:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to generate a random color name using the KnownColor enumeration. This enum is particularly useful in UI design and data visualization, as it provides a wide variety of preset colors. Let’s begin. Understanding the KnownColor Enumeration To understand why we would even need to generate a random color […] The post How to Generate a Random Color Name in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled Message Delivery with Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 22:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine has the ability to schedule the delivery of messages for a later time. While Wolverine certainly isn’t trying to be Hangfire or Quartz.Net, the message scheduling in Wolverine today is valuable for “timeout” messages in sagas, or “retry this evening” type scenarios, or reminders of all sorts. If using the Azure Service Bus transport, … Continue reading Scheduled Message Delivery with Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/15/scheduled-message-delivery-with-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Looping Over a Collection Using Span and ReadOnlySpan</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article explores the performance benefits of utilizing Span and ReadOnlySpan for collection processing, highlighting advantages such as improved performance, reduced memory pressure, enhanced safety, and compatibility with modern API design. Span allows read-write access and efficient iteration with lightweight storage, while ReadOnlySpan provides read-only access to prevent accidental modifications, offering similar benefits for collection processing.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/15/collection-performance-looping-over-a-collection-using-span-and-readonlyspan/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Developers at Microsoft Build: Docker Unveils Integrations and Sessions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 18:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker&#39;s presence at Microsoft Build is more than just a showcase — it’s a portal to the future of application development. Visit our booth to interact with Docker experts, experience live demos, and explore the powerful capabilities of Docker Desktop and other Docker products.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-microsoft-build-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework May 2024 Servicing Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recap of the latest servicing updates for .NET and .NET Framework for May 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-may-2024-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless exam generator application from your own lecture content using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Crafting new questions for exams and quizzes can be tedious and time-consuming for educators. The time required varies based on factors like subject matter, question types, experience level, and class level. Multiple-choice questions require substantial time to generate quality distractors and ensure a single unambiguous answer, and composing effective true-false questions demands careful effort to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-exam-generator-application-from-your-own-lecture-content-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate NLP inference with ONNX Runtime on AWS Graviton processors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ONNX is an open source machine learning (ML) framework that provides interoperability across a wide range of frameworks, operating systems, and hardware platforms. ONNX Runtime is the runtime engine used for model inference and training with ONNX. AWS Graviton3 processors are optimized for ML workloads, including support for bfloat16, Scalable Vector Extension (SVE), and Matrix […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-nlp-inference-with-onnx-runtime-on-aws-graviton-processors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn how Amazon Ads created a generative AI-powered image generation capability using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Ads helps advertisers and brands achieve their business goals by developing innovative solutions that reach millions of Amazon customers at every stage of their journey. At Amazon Ads, we believe that what makes advertising effective is delivering relevant ads in the right context and at the right moment within the consumer buying journey. With that […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/learn-how-amazon-ads-created-a-generative-ai-powered-image-generation-capability-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing backward compatibility with Microsoft Graph PowerShell v2.19</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release introduces backward compatibility support to address the issues some of our users encountered with versions 2.17 and 2.18.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-backward-compatibility-with-microsoft-graph-powershell-v2-19 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data API builder becomes Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing Data API builder General Availability On May 15th, Data API builder becomes Generally Available. Data API builder for Azure SQL Databases – Generally Available It’s been a long road, getting from there to here. Nearly three years ago, Data API builder began as just a dream.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/data-api-builder-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready for Visual Studio at Build 2024: Join Thousands Online!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MICROSOFT BUILD 2024 Watch it Live! or On-Demand – Starting Next Tuesday! Next week, from May 21st, I’ll be diving into Microsoft Build 2024, and I invite you to come along for the ride—virtually! We’ll explore cutting-edge developments in Visual Studio,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-at-build-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get ready for Microsoft Build 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us at the upcoming Microsoft Build conference from May 21-23, 2024, online (for free) or in person in Seattle. Sit in on identity-focused breakout sessions and demos, while also exploring a broad range of talks on Microsoft’s latest developer tools and technologies. Network with industry leaders and like-minded professionals and create valuable connections at this dynamic event.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/get-ready-for-build-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Data API builder General Availability for Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            About Data API builder for Azure Databases Exciting news! The Data API Builder for Azure Cosmos DB is now officially available! Say goodbye to developer headaches when accessing databases for client applications. Requiring no code, the Data API Builder provides secure,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-data-api-builder-general-availability-for-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the most efficient device selector query that selects no devices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking for the most efficient way of rejecting everything.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240515-00/?p=109764 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Guide to Containerizing Llamafile with Docker for AI Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Walk through how to use Docker to containerize llamafile, an executable that brings together all the components needed to run an LLM chatbot with a single file.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/a-quick-guide-to-containerizing-llamafile-with-docker-for-ai-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering DevOps Engineers with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of technology, the role of DevOps Engineers is becoming increasingly complex and critical. As organizations strive for higher reliability and performance, increased automation workflows, and smoother release processes, the integration of generative AI technologies, such as those offered by Azure OpenAI, is revolutionizing the realm of DevOps. DevOps Engineers can now […] The article Empowering DevOps Engineers with Generative AI through technologies like Azure OpenAI appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Default and per Request Timeout in HttpClient</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 03:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll demonstrate how to set a default request timeout for all requests and configure specific request timeout settings for individual requests using HttpClient. In modern software development, managing HTTP requests efficiently is vital for keeping our applications fast and reliable. The HttpClient enables us to effectively execute HTTP calls in .NET applications. […] The post Change Default and per Request Timeout in HttpClient appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy-on-Write performance and debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 20:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a follow-up to our previous coverage of Dev Drive and copy-on-write (CoW) linking. See our previous articles from May 24, 2023, October 13, 2023, and November 2, 2023. Dev Drive was released in Windows 11 in October, 2023, and will be part of Windows Server 2025 this fall,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/copy-on-write-performance-and-debugging 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAG architecture with Voyage AI embedding models on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart and Anthropic Claude 3 models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 19:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide an overview of the state-of-the-art embedding models by Voyage AI and show a RAG implementation with Voyage AI’s text embedding model on Amazon SageMaker Jumpstart, Anthropic’s Claude 3 model on Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon OpenSearch Service. Voyage AI’s embedding models are the preferred embedding models for Anthropic. In addition to general-purpose embedding models, Voyage AI offers domain-specific embedding models that are tuned to a particular domain.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing NuGet Commands in C# Dev Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 19:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the April release of C# Dev Kit, you can now manage your NuGet packages directly from Visual Studio Code using the new commands in the command palette. To add a NuGet package to your project, use the command “NuGet: Add NuGet Package”.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/nuget/announcing-nuget-commands-in-c-dev-kit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporate offline and online human – machine workflows into your generative AI applications on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 17:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recent advances in artificial intelligence have led to the emergence of generative AI that can produce human-like novel content such as images, text, and audio. These models are pre-trained on massive datasets and, to sometimes fine-tuned with smaller sets of more task specific data. An important aspect of developing effective generative AI application is Reinforcement […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/incorporate-offline-and-online-human-machine-workflows-into-your-generative-ai-applications-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications with Amazon Titan Text Premier, Amazon Bedrock, and AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 17:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Titan Text Premier, the latest addition to the Amazon Titan family of large language models (LLMs), is now generally available in Amazon Bedrock. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading artificial intelligence (AI) companies like AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Stability AI, and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-titan-text-premier-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curating a collection of free Microsoft Copilot prompts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 15:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing a new community-lead repository: a collection of prompts to help you use the power of Microsoft Copilot across Microsoft 365.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/curating-a-collection-of-free-microsoft-copilot-prompts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Docker Image Builds with Pulumi and Docker Build Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Pulumi&#39;s new Docker Build provider works with Docker Build Cloud to streamline building, deploying, and managing containerized applications.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/pulumi-and-docker-build-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The confidential coffee maker was not the only source of shenanigans at the IBM Boca office</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The culture (and weather) clash continues.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240514-00/?p=109759 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Semantic Kernel to create a Time Plugin with .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 13:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plugins are one of the most powerful features of Semantic Kernel and in this demo we show how you can easily use Plugins with the power of Auto Function Calling from AI Models. A Glimpse into the Demonstration Time Information Plugin In the demo we implement a simple class TimeInformantionPlugin with one function to retrieve the UTC time in string format.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/using-semantic-kernel-to-create-a-time-plugin-with-net 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Proxy Servers with Ease: New Advancements in Docker Desktop 4.30</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.30 offers new proxy authentication enhancements, especially on the Windows front, to ensure seamless integration and interaction.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/navigating-proxy-servers-docker-desktop-4-30/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.30: Proxy Support with SOCKS5, NTLM and Kerberos, ECI for Build Commands, Build View Features, and Docker Desktop on RHEL Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read about new features in Docker Desktop 4.30, such as improved SOCKS5 proxy support, advanced integration with NTLM and Kerberos, and extended Enhanced Container Isolation to secure build environments.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-30/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AzAPI Terraform Provider Dynamic Properties Feature instead of jsonencode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AzAPI Terraform provider for Microsoft Azure has introduced a feature known as dynamic properties. This feature simplifies resource definitions by enabling the use of HCL (HashiCorp Configuration Language) blocks instead of JSON blocks that would previously require the use of JSON encoding (via jsonencode) and decoding (via jsondecode). This is a great improvement to […] The article Using AzAPI Terraform Provider Dynamic Properties Feature instead of jsonencode appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Use IServiceCollection in Console Applications – What You Need To Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post How To Use IServiceCollection in Console Applications – What You Need To Know appeared first on Dev Leader.How can you use an IServiceCollection in console applications to get dependency injection? Is this a viable option if you don&#39;t want to use Autofac? The post How To Use IServiceCollection in Console Applications – What You Need To Know appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/05/14/how-to-use-iservicecollection-in-console-applications-what-you-need-to-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to primary constructors in C#12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I introduce C#12 primary constructors, describe the various ways to use them and how they work behind the scenes.
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/an-introduction-to-primary-constructors-in-csharp-12/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code It Any Way You Want: Performance Considerations for Sealed and Internal Classes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article explores the historical belief that sealed and internal classes in .NET might offer performance advantages, but suggests that in modern .NET runtimes, compiler optimizations, and hardware advancements, the difference in performance is likely negligible, emphasizing that design considerations should drive decisions regarding class sealing or internalization rather than performance concerns.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/14/code-it-any-way-you-want-performance-considerations-for-sealed-and-internal-classes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Slash Commands with GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 08:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot, the AI-powered coding assistant, offers a range of features designed to streamline your coding experience in Visual Studio. In this new series, we take a closer look at the power of Slash Commands and discuss how they can make your coding workflow smoother and more efficient.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/mastering-slash-commands-with-github-copilot-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Test your Architecture (and more) with ArchUnit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 08:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the power of ArchUnit and learn how to bolster your software architecture testing.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/unit-test-architecture-with-archunit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure CI/CD: Govern seamlessly from start to finish</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 07:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debjyoti Ganguly shares insights on a resilient end-to-end cloud governance framework for Azure CI/CD pipelines. Hey there, tech enthusiasts! This article serves as a technical guide to implementing a resilient end-to-end cloud governance framework for Azure CI/CD pipelines. It is designed to be vendor-agnostic and aligns seamlessly with enterprise security objectives,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/azure-ci-cd-govern-seamlessly-from-start-to-finish 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning Service for Kubernetes Architects: Deploy Your First Model on AKS with AZ CLI v2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 07:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Joseph Masengesho provides a step-by-step tutorial on how to deploy your first ML model on AKS. In a previous post, I provided a lengthy write-up about my understanding of using Kubernetes as a compute target in Azure ML from a Kubernetes architect’s perspective.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/azure-machine-learning-service-for-kubernetes-architects-deploy-your-first-model-on-aks-with-az-cli-v2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Result Pattern in .NET Web API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 04:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the expanding world of APIs, meaningful error responses can be just as crucial as well-structured success responses, and here, the Result Pattern can help us greatly. To introduce the Result Pattern, we will go through a series of iterations, presenting different ways of passing information about the success or failure of a given operation. […] The post Using the Result Pattern in .NET Web API appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Started using Semantic Kernel .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 01:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi all, With Microsoft Build approaching, we wanted to share some walk throughs of using Semantic Kernel to get started if you haven’t already. Today we’re going to dive into the Getting Started guide we have in the main Semantic Kernel GitHub repository for .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/how-to-get-started-using-semantic-kernel-net 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI GTP-4o Now Available in Azure OpenAI Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 21:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, OpenAI announced the the new GPT-4o multi-modal model that integrates text, video, and audio capabilities. This new GPT-4o version raises the standard for generative and conversational AI. This new version has some really amazing AI features, like real-time speech translation, and conversational interaction capabilities with vision and audio support. While OpenAI is releasing the […] The article OpenAI GTP-4o Now Available in Azure OpenAI Service appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine’s HTTP Model Does More For You</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 21:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the things I’m wrestling with right now is frankly how to sell Wolverine as a server side toolset. Yes, it’s technically a message library like MassTransit or NServiceBus. It can also be used as “just” a mediator tool like MediatR. With Wolverine.HTTP, it’s even an alternative HTTP endpoint framework that’s technically an alternative … Continue reading Wolverine’s HTTP Model Does More For You →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/05/13/wolverines-http-model-does-more-for-you/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of generative AI techniques for clinical report summarization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 19:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a comparison of results obtained by two such techniques: zero-shot and few-shot prompting. We also explore the utility of the RAG prompt engineering technique as it applies to the task of summarization. Evaluating LLMs is an undervalued part of the machine learning (ML) pipeline.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluation-of-generative-ai-techniques-for-clinical-report-summarization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Conf 2024: Accelerating Innovation in AI and Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 17:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The fourth annual Azure Cosmos DB Conf, held on April 16, 2024, was an exciting event for developers, product managers and C-Suite executives focused on the cutting-edge of cloud data management and AI-driven applications. Featuring a comprehensive lineup of talks and discussions,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-conf-2024-accelerating-innovation-in-ai-and-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in Orleans 8 for Scalable Distributed Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s take a look at what is new with Orleans for building robust, scalable distribute applications with Orleans 8 and integration with .NET Aspire.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/whats-new-in-orleans-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use AI-Powered Rename Suggestions to rename your C&#43;&#43; variables in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 16:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are very excited to announce C++ support for AI-Powered Rename Suggestions from GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio 2022. Seamlessly integrated into your familiar Rename workflow in the IDE, AI-powered rename suggestions dynamically generate name suggestions for any C++ identifier. It will generate proposed names based on its usage and your code’s style to help you strike a balance between describing the variable with appropriate descriptive qualities while remaining concise.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retiring SharePoint Framework domain isolated web parts for SharePoint Online</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 15:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the retirement of the domain isolated web parts feature in SharePoint Framework (SPFx).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/retiring-sharepoint-framework-domain-isolated-web-parts-for-sharepoint-online 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2024 Recordings Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            All recordings for our Pure Virtual C++ 2024 conference are now available. Thanks to everyone who came along and hope to see you again next year! You can find the full playlist on YouTube. Main Sessions Automated Test of Shader Code –
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/pure-virtual-cpp-2024-recordings-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before you try to change something, make sure you can change nothing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Nobody touch anything.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240513-00/?p=109750 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Scheduled Trigger in GitHub Actions using Cron expression</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are many times when scheduled triggers are very useful when configuring GitHub Actions workflows. Luckily, GitHub Actions supports the ability to configure scheduled triggers that includes support for using cron expressions to define the schedule timing. In this article, we’ll look at configuring scheduled triggers on GitHub Actions workflows and a few tips on […] The article Configure Scheduled Trigger in GitHub Actions using Cron expression appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to avoid conflicts when testing your dotnet templates locally</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you author a dotnet template, you can use the dotnet install and dotnet new commands to create a new project based on your local template. However, dotnet install may conflict with a previous installation of the template published as a NuGet package. In this post, I describe how to avoid this conflict and how to test your template locally. dotnet has a few hidden arguments that you can use to debug…
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Optimizing Sequence Comparison</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article discusses different methods for comparing two collections for identity in programming. It introduces the use of the SequenceEqual() method for comparing sequences in the LINQ extension methods, as well as the StructuralSequenceEqual() method, which is beneficial for comparing custom classes based on the values of their elements rather than object references.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/13/collection-performance-optimizing-sequence-comparison/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>无障碍应用程序之旅：键盘可访问性和 .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 07:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本篇翻译于Rachel Kang (SHE/HER) 的 The Journey to Accessible Apps: Keyboard Accessibility and .NET MAUI 首先让我们一起来看看您的应用程序是否支持键盘访问： 启动您的其中一个应用。 如果您的设备尚未连接物理键盘，请连接物理键盘。 像平常一样导航您的应用程序，并且仅使用键盘来执行此操作。 这次体验如何？是否轻松？是否与您通常使用应用程序的体验相匹配？ 确保您的应用程序体验在仅通过键盘导航时同样出色，这对于构建一个对所有人都包容且可访问的应用程序体验至关重要。 Web内容可访问性指南 (WCAG) 若要了解键盘可访问性的详细信息，可以从 Web 内容可访问性指南 (WCAG) 开始。 WCAG 是一组针对 Web 可访问性的技术标准，被广泛引用，并扩展到 Web 以外的各种应用程序和平台。 它已成为全球标准和法律基准，并随着技术的发展而不断发展。 在各种指南中，有一个经常被忽视的是指南第2.1条，该指南表明开发人员应“使所有功能可通过键盘访问”。 这包括四个成功标准： 成功标准 2.1.1 键盘 内容的所有功能都可以通过键盘界面操作，而无需对单个按键的时间进行特定的控制，除非底层功能需要依赖用户移动路径而不仅仅是端点的输入。 成功标准 2.1.2 无键盘陷阱 如果您可以使用键盘界面将键盘焦点移动到页面的某个组件，那么您只需使用键盘界面就可以将焦点从该组件移开，并且如果它需要的不仅仅是未修改的箭头或 Tab 键或其他标准退出方法，则用户会被告知移动焦点的方法。 成功标准 2.1.3 键盘（无例外） 内容的所有功能都可以通过键盘界面进行操作，无需为各个按键分配特定的时间。 成功标准 2.1.4 字符快捷键 如果您在仅使用字母(包括大写和小写字母)、标点符号、数字或符号字符的内容中实现键盘快捷键，则至少满足以下条件之一： 关闭 有一种机制可以关闭快捷方式； 重新映射 有一种机制可以重新映射快捷键，使其包含一个或多个不可打印的键盘键（例如 Ctrl、Alt）； 仅在焦点上活动 用户界面组件的键盘快捷键仅在该组件具有焦点时活动。 对这些标准的基本理解将有助于您开始开发键盘可访问的应用程序。 键盘可访问性和 .NET MAUI 除了各种其他考虑因素之外，.NET MAUI的设计目标之一是实现更轻松地开发键盘可访问的体验。 因此，熟悉Xamarin.Forms键盘行为的开发人员注意到了一些改进，以提高他们应用程序中的键盘可访问性。 对于可通过键盘界面操作的所有功能，所有交互式控件都必须是键盘可聚焦的（可以接收键盘焦点）和键盘可导航的（可以使用键盘进行导航）。 这也包括避免让不可见的内容键盘可访问。 正如我们应该期望可见控件可以通过键盘进行聚焦和导航一样，我们应该期望不可见/不存在的控件无法通过键盘访问或呈现。 为了避免键盘陷阱，我们确保可以通过键盘导航进入、内部和外部当前视图内的所有相关控件。 例如，如果您导航具有多个 CollectionView 的屏幕，.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Call an Action From Another Controller in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 06:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to call an action from another controller in .NET MVC. We sometimes need to call an action method from another action method within the same controller or a different controller class. So, let’s see how to do that. Why We Need to Call the Action From Another Controller? […] The post How to Call an Action From Another Controller in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SonarCloud with ASP.NET Core, Angular and github actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 05:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article demonstrates how to implement code analysis and Static Application Security Testing (SAST) using SonarCloud and GitHub Actions. The solution involves building a secure web application with ASP.NET Core for the backend and an Angular UI for the frontend, following a backend-for-frontend security architecture. Both the ASP.NET Core (C#) codebase and the Angular (TypeScript […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/05/13/using-sonarcloud-with-asp-net-core-angular-and-github-actions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2024/12_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2024/12_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore how to integrate the Azure Storage SDK into a .NET application. We’ll cover the steps to read and write blobs from Azure Storage, and we’ll also discuss how to obtain your Storage Account Key. By the end of this guide, you’ll have a simple command-line application that can interact with […] The article Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with C# appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with Javascript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll explore how to integrate the Azure Storage client library for Javascript into a Node.js application. We’ll cover the steps to read and write blobs from Azure Storage, and we’ll also discuss how to obtain your Storage Account Key. By the end of this guide, you’ll have javascript code that can interact […] The article Read and Write Azure Blob Storage with Javascript appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imposter Syndrome and YOU – Dev Leader Weekly 43</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Imposter Syndrome and YOU – Dev Leader Weekly 43 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss imposter syndrome and how it affects you as a software engineer. The post Imposter Syndrome and YOU – Dev Leader Weekly 43 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/05/11/imposter-syndrome-and-you-dev-leader-weekly-43/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find the Latitude and Longitude of a Location in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 05:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will learn how to find the latitude and longitude of a location in C# using the Google Maps Geocoding API. We’ll introduce two different methods for obtaining the coordinates: using the GoogleMaps.LocationServices NuGet package, which simplifies the process but can be less flexible, and using HttpClient directly, which provides us more […] The post How to Find the Latitude and Longitude of a Location in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Resilient Cloud Applications With .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_05_2024/11_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By designing your applications with resilience in mind, you can create robust and reliable systems, even when the going gets tough. In this newsletter, we&#39;ll explore the tools and techniques we have in .NET to build resilient systems.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/building-resilient-cloud-applications-with-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making AI powered .NET apps more consistent and intelligent with Redis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 20:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone! Today we’re featuring a guest author from another team in Microsoft on our Semantic Kernel blog. Today’s topic will cover how to use Azure Cache for Redis, which is an in-memory datastore that allows you to further expand the performance and scalability of your applications that are using AzureOpenAI.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/making-ai-powered-net-apps-more-consistent-and-intelligent-with-redis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS DeepRacer enables builders of all skill levels to upskill and get started with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 18:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s technological landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) are becoming increasingly accessible, enabling builders of all skill levels to harness their power. As more companies adopt AI solutions, there’s a growing need to upskill both technical and non-technical teams in responsibly expanding AI usage. Getting hands-on experience is crucial for understanding and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-deepracer-enables-builders-of-all-skill-levels-to-upskill-and-get-started-with-machine-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform customer engagement with no-code LLM fine-tuning using Amazon SageMaker Canvas and SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 16:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) creates tailored customer experiences that align with a brand’s unique voice. Amazon SageMaker Canvas and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart democratize this process, offering no-code solutions and pre-trained models that enable businesses to fine-tune LLMs without deep technical expertise, helping organizations move faster with fewer technical resources. SageMaker Canvas provides an intuitive […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transform-customer-engagement-with-no-code-llm-fine-tuning-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-and-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to (and how not to) design REST APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 14:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Everyone seems to love best practices or rules for designing REST APIs. But is all this guidance good advice? Let’s find out. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts, including this video showing everything in this post. “REST” API Rules I stumbled upon a post outlining rules around… Read More »How to (and how not to) design REST APIs The post How to (and how not to) design REST APIs appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct streaming of SharePoint Driveitem content in Microsoft Graph now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 14:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now directly download content of a file (of a Driveitem) in a SharePoint Online site through a single call.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/direct-streaming-of-sharepoint-driveitem-content-in-microsoft-graph-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An informal comparison of the three major implementations of std::string</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pros and cons.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240510-00/?p=109742 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform String ‘replace’ Function  for RegEx String Replacement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HashiCorp Terraform offers a lot of powerful functions that can be used for string manipulation within your Infrastructure as Code (IaC) projects. Among these functions is the versatile replace function, which enables users to perform both simple string replacements as well as regular expressions (RegEx) based string replacement. In this article, we’ll look deeper into […] The article Using Terraform String ‘replace’ Function for RegEx String Replacement appeared first on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream – Matt Ellis and Antonio Antunes – An Eye For Success With Odin Inspector and JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us Tuesday, June 4, 2024, at 2:00 pm UTC (check other timezones) for a free livestream, An Eye For Success With Odin Inspector and JetBrains Rider, with Antonio Antunes from Sirenix and Matt Ellis from JetBrains. Register now to get a reminder, or join us on YouTube JetBrains and Sirenix have joined forces to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/05/10/livestream-matt-ellis-and-antonio-antunes-an-eye-for-success-with-odin-inspector-and-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Performance Tip: Type Conversion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article explores type conversion in programming, comparing the traditional syntax with the newer &amp;quot;as&amp;quot; keyword in .NET. While the &amp;quot;as&amp;quot; keyword improves code readability, benchmark results suggest that the conventional method is slightly more performant, advising developers to stick with traditional type conversion unless significant performance improvements are observed with the &amp;quot;as&amp;quot; keyword.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/05/10/general-performance-tip-type-conversion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronizing multiple remote Git Repositories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            summary of the post
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/synchronizing-multiple-remote-git-repositories 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate QR Codes With QRCoder in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will discuss how to generate QR codes, specifically with the .NET library QRCoder. We will generate basic QR codes that contain simple strings, discuss reading from and writing QR codes to a database, and try out real-life use cases, such as phoning numbers and opening web pages. Let’s first align on […] The post Generate QR Codes With QRCoder in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
