<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:02:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Docker Hardened Images: Secure Helm Charts for Deployments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Development teams are under growing pressure to secure their software supply chains. Teams need trusted images, streamlined deployments, and compliance-ready tooling from partners they can rely on long term. Our customers have made it clear that they’re not just looking for one-off vendors. They’re looking for true security partners across development and deployment. That’s why...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hardened-images-helm-charts-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leader Election and Virtual Actors in Wolverine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A JasperFx Software client was asking recently about the features for software controlled load balancing and “sticky” agents I’m describing in this post. Since these features are both critical for Wolverine functionality and maybe not perfectly documented already, it’s a great topic for a new blog post! Both because it’s helpful to understand what’s going … Continue reading Leader Election and Virtual Actors in Wolverine →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/29/leader-election-and-virtual-actors-in-wolverine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data API builder 1.6: Advanced Behaviors with Special HTTP Headers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data API builder (DAB) provides REST and GraphQL endpoints over SQL Server, Azure Cosmos DB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and SQL Data Warehouse. REST endpoints support several HTTP headers that let you control how requests behave. These headers give you precision over updates, caching, and discovering new resources.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/data-api-builder-16-http-headers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Claude Agent in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: The new Claude Agent is now seamlessly integrated into JetBrains IDEs via the AI chat and included in the JetBrains AI subscription. No extra plugins, no extra subscriptions – just advanced AI coding assistance built on Anthropic’s Agent SDK, which powers Claude Code, right inside your IDE. The new agent leverages Anthropic models, including […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/09/introducing-claude-agent-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Overload Resolution For Parameter Arrays in C&#43;&#43;/CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In the below discussion, .NET Framework refers to the older version of the Microsoft Common Language Runtime, also known as &amp;quot;Desktop Framework&amp;quot; (versions 4.0 through 4.8.x) while .NET refers t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/fixing-overload-resolution-for-parameter-arrays-in-c-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I enumerate the overflow icons in the Notification Area without showing them?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I demonstrated enumerating notification icons via UI Automation. Part of the exercise was enumerating the icons in the overflow area. This was done by finding the button that expands the over
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250929-00/?p=111637 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building OpenAI with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At OpenAI, we rely on our own technology to help streamline work, scale expertise, and drive outcomes. In our new series, OpenAI on OpenAI, we share lessons to help other organizations do the same.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/building-openai-with-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting inbound leads into customers at OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI used AI to deliver personalized answers at scale, converting inbound leads into customers.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-inbound-sales-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving sales productivity and customer success at OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI boosts sales productivity by automating prep, centralizing knowledge, and scaling top-selling practices.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-gtm-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering teams to unlock insights faster at OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s research assistant helps teams analyze millions of support tickets, surface insights faster, and scale curiosity across the company.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-research-assistant 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving support with every interaction at OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI uses AI to enhance support, cutting response times, improving quality, and scaling to meet hypergrowth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-support-model 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker MCP Toolkit: MCP Servers That Just Work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we want to highlight Docker MCP Toolkit, a free feature in Docker Desktop that gives you access to more than 200 MCP servers. It’s the easiest and most secure way to run MCP servers locally for your AI agents and workflows. The MCP toolkit allows you to isolate MCP servers in containers, securely configure...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-toolkit-mcp-servers-that-just-work/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I tried out JetBrains’ code analysis tool Qodana”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the English version of the Japanese article first published by Jan Maki on Qiita. This post was not commissioned by Qodana and was written independently. For more information please reach out to them in the comments or via their link tree. Qodana is JetBrains’ code analysis platform for quality and aspects of code […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/09/i-tried-out-jetbrains-code-analysis-tool-qodana/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Git insteadOf to Automatically Replace HTTPS URLs with SSH</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with Git repositories, you often encounter URLs in HTTPS format, especially when cloning from GitHub, GitLab, or other hosting services. However, if you prefer using SSH for authentication (which is often more convenient with key-based auth), manually changing URLs can be tedious. Also, it can be even harder when dealing with submodules. Git&#39;s insteadOf configuration option provides an…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/using-git-insteadof-to-automatically-replace-https-urls-with-ssh.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combating online child sexual exploitation &amp; abuse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how OpenAI combats online child sexual exploitation and abuse with strict usage policies, advanced detection tools, and industry collaboration to block, report, and prevent AI misuse.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/combating-online-child-sexual-exploitation-abuse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing parental controls</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re rolling out parental controls and a new parent resource page to help families guide how ChatGPT works in their homes.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-parental-controls 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buy it in ChatGPT: Instant Checkout and the Agentic Commerce Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re taking first steps toward agentic commerce in ChatGPT with new ways for people, AI agents, and businesses to shop together.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/buy-it-in-chatgpt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Sprint to Wolverine 5.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Little update since the last check in on Wolverine 5.0. I think right now that Wolverine 5.0 hits by next Monday (October 6th). To be honest, besides documentation updates, the biggest work is just pushing more on the CritterWatch backend this week to see if that forces any breaking changes in the Wolverine internals. What’s … Continue reading Last Sprint to Wolverine 5.0 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/09/28/last-sprint-to-wolverine-5-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Simplify Unique Key Generation with KeyGenerator in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_09_2025/28_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The KeyGenerator in Spargine is an efficient tool for generating unique keys using GUIDs, ideal for object IDs and database records. It offers methods for creating keys with or without prefixes. This utility simplifies the process of generating unique keys, enhancing workflow in .NET projects, alongside the UlidGenerator for ULIDs.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/09/28/boost-your-net-projects-simplify-unique-key-generation-with-keygenerator-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ardalis Fall 2025 Speaking Tour</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2025/27_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2025/27_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I may have gone a bit overboard this year... I&#39;ve scheduled myself for 5 developer conferences in 4 weeks during October 2025! If you&#39;re…
Link to article: https://ardalis.com/ardalis-fall-2025-speaking-tour/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Secure APIs with Role-Based Access Control in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2025/27_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2025/27_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) in ASP.NET Core with custom authorization handlers, permission-based policies, and clean extension methods for both Minimal APIs and MVC controllers.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/building-secure-apis-with-role-based-access-control-in-aspnetcore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Hotkey Typer — type long prompts with a hotkey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 22:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I&#39;m recording demos or making videos I often need to reproduce long prompts or blocks of text on-screen. Manually retyping them every time is slow and error-prone, and pasting from the clipboard can feel jerky and reveal private content. I wanted a tiny, reliable app that would
Link to article: https://montemagno.com/announcing-hotkey-typer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing Your .NET MAUI Apps for Google Play&#39;s 16 KB Page Size Requirement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you&#39;re a .NET MAUI developer publishing apps to Google Play, there&#39;s an important requirement coming your way. Starting November 1st, 2025, Google Play will require all new apps and updates targeting Android 15+ to support 16 KB page sizes on 64-bit devices. What is the 16 KB Page Size Requirement? Androi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/maui-google-play-16-kb-page-size-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building health care agents using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this solution, we demonstrate how the user (a parent) can interact with a Strands or LangGraph agent in conversational style and get information about the immunization history and schedule of their child, inquire about the available slots, and book appointments. With some changes, AI agents can be made event-driven so that they can automatically send reminders, book appointments, and so on.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-health-care-agents-using-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build multi-agent site reliability engineering assistants with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a multi-agent SRE assistant using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, LangGraph, and the Model Context Protocol (MCP). This system deploys specialized AI agents that collaborate to provide the deep, contextual intelligence that modern SRE teams need for effective incident response and infrastructure management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-multi-agent-site-reliability-engineering-assistants-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why didn&#39;t Windows 95 setup install a miniature Windows 95 so that it could be written as a 32-bit program?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I noted some time ago that Windows 95 Setup was actually three programs running under three different operating systems. The first part was an MS-DOS program, which was used if you installed Windows 9
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250926-00/?p=111629 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trust Paradox: When Your AI Gets Catfished</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The fundamental challenge with MCP-enabled attacks isn&#39;t technical sophistication. It&#39;s that hackers have figured out how to catfish your AI. These attacks work because they exploit the same trust relationships that make your development team actually functional. When your designers expect Figma files from agencies they&#39;ve worked with for years, when your DevOps folks trust...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-prompt-injection-trust-paradox/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Resource Management in mssql-python through Context Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reviewed by: Sumit Sarabhai
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/simplifying-resource-management-in-mssql-python-through-context-manager 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking MCP in JetBrains: How Copilot Uses Sampling, Prompts, Resources, and Elicitation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 07:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the enhanced capability of the MCP on JetBrains, you can now bring prompts, resources, and even interac
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/unlocking-mcp-in-jetbrains-how-copilot-uses-sampling-prompts-resources-and-elicitation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Java Open-Source Projects Use IntelliJ IDEA: Real-World Examples – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 07:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of this series, we introduced some of the Java community’s most recognized open-source projects. Now, we’re back with more standouts: projects that speed up builds, strengthen testing, and simplify working with modern web stacks. And as always, IntelliJ IDEA helps maintainers move faster, confidently, and with a focus on quality. 🌿 jsoup […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/09/26/how-java-open-source-projects-use-intellij-idea-real-world-examples-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partnering with AARP to help keep older adults safe online</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and AARP are partnering to help older adults stay safe online with new AI training, scam-spotting tools, and nationwide programs through OpenAI Academy and OATS’s Senior Planet initiative.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/aarp-partnership-older-adults-online-safety 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2509.25 - support for new D3D features and devices, and misc bug fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 21:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2509.25, which can be downloaded here. This release includes everything in the previous 2507.11 release, plus: A compatibility fix to make PIX work on Windows 11 24H2 or 25H2 with K
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2509-25 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DoWhile loops now supported in Amazon Bedrock Flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 20:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce support for DoWhile loops in Amazon Bedrock Flows. With this powerful new capability, you can create iterative, condition-based workflows directly within your Amazon Bedrock flows, using Prompt nodes, AWS Lambda functions, Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Flows inline code, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3), […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dowhile-loops-now-supported-in-amazon-bedrock-flows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PropHero built an intelligent property investment advisor with continuous evaluation using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how we built a multi-agent conversational AI system using Amazon Bedrock that delivers knowledge-grounded property investment advice. We explore the agent architecture, model selection strategy, and comprehensive continuous evaluation system that facilitates quality conversations while facilitating rapid iteration and improvement.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-prophero-built-an-intelligent-property-investment-advisor-with-continuous-evaluation-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate benefits claims processing with Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the benefits administration industry, claims processing is a vital operational pillar that makes sure employees and beneficiaries receive timely benefits, such as health, dental, or disability payments, while controlling costs and adhering to regulations like HIPAA and ERISA. In this post, we examine the typical benefit claims processing workflow and identify where generative AI-powered automation can deliver the greatest impact.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-benefits-claims-processing-with-amazon-bedrock-data-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Aspire 9.5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aspire 9.5 is here with exciting new features and improvements that enhance the developer experience for building distributed applications. For the complete list of changes and technical details, visit the official Aspire 9.5 release notes. Let&#39;s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-aspire-95 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility SDK 1.618: Advanced Shader Delivery and 1.716 out of preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce the retail release of AgilitySDK 1.618, available on Agility SDK Downloads today! This release promotes our 1.716 features out of preview and also
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agility-sdk-1-618 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing WinUI Gallery 2.7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &amp;amp;nbs
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ifdef-windows/announcing-winui-gallery-2-7 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data API builder 1.6: Flexible Logging for Every Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously, developers were limited to the default log levels and filters hardcoded into DAB. With release 1.6, you can now configure filters and levels for logs emitted by the engine. This release also adds new sinks. In addition to Application Insights and OpenTelemetry publishing, Data API builder now suppo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/data-api-builder-16-logging 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuing Positive Impact: This Year’s AI4SE Interns in their New Roles at JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our last post, we introduced the talented intern cohort from our AI for Software Engineering (AI4SE) research partnership with Delft University of Technology (TU Delft). In this post, we’re excited to spotlight the next chapter in their journey: their evolution from interns to full-time members of our tech team. As interns, they didn’t just […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/ai4se-interns-employees-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing AWS Transform for .NET detailed transformation reports</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adi Parab, Charlize Yeh, Eunah Lee, Nits Jeganathan, Ramapulla Chennuru, Saksham Bhalla, and Samiullah Mohammed contributed to this blog post. AWS Transform for .NET is an agentic AI service for modernizing .NET applications at scale. Customers have asked us for more transparency into what happens during transformation, such as the reasons for file changes and actionable error […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/announcing-aws-transform-for-net-detailed-transformation-reports/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samples note: Use comments to describe what code does, not what you wish the code would do</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows API design is samples-driven. This means that when a team proposes an API, we want them to demonstrate how to use that API with a sample code fragment. We do this so that we can evaluate the ergonomics of the API and see
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250925-00/?p=111627 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider Roadmap: What to Expect From the Upcoming Updates and Releases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Rider 2025.2 already out in the wild and the 2025.3 release cycle underway, we want to take a step back and give you a broader picture of where Rider is headed. This roadmap covers our plans for Rider 2025.3 and what you can expect from the minor updates included in the 2025.2 release line. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/09/25/rider-rider-roadmap-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Docker Premium Support and TAM service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Docker Customer Success and Technical Account Management organizations are excited to introduce the Premium Support and TAM service — a new service designed to extend Docker’s support to always-on 24/7, priority SLAs, expert guidance, and TAM add-on services. We have carefully designed these new services to support our valued customers’ developers and global business...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-the-docker-premium-support-and-tam-service/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run, Test, and Evaluate Models and MCP Locally with Docker &#43; Promptfoo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Promptfoo is an open-source CLI and library for evaluating LLM apps. Docker Model Runner makes it easy to manage, run, and deploy AI models using Docker. The Docker MCP Toolkit is a local gateway that lets you set up, manage, and run containerized MCP servers and connect them to AI agents. Together, these tools let...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/evaluate-models-and-mcp-with-promptfoo-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Framework (SPFx) roadmap update – September 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are humbled to see the incredible momentum of SharePoint Framework (SPFx) and the growth it is driving with our customers and partners. There are tens of millions of users using custom SPFx solutions each day worldwide in Microsoft 365. Your innovation and feedback continue to shape its suc
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/sharepoint-framework-spfx-roadmap-update-september-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More ways to work with your team and tools in ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT business plans now support shared projects, smarter connectors, and enhanced compliance features to help teams work faster and more securely.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/more-ways-to-work-with-your-team 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the performance of our models on real-world tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces GDPval, a new evaluation that measures model performance on real-world economically valuable tasks across 44 occupations.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gdpval 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming Complexity: Intuitive Evaluation Framework for Agentic Chatbots in Business-Critical Environments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The landscape of conversational AI has undergone a seismic shift with the emergence of large language models (LLMs). These sophisticated systems have transformed chatbots from rigid, rule-based interactions to dynamic, seemingly intelligent conversations. But with this transformation comes a fundamental challenge: how do
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/intuitive-evaluation-framework-for-agentic-chatbots 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v1.2 with mock response mirroring and improved performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 06:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to announce the release of Dev Proxy v1.2! This update introduces mock response mirroring capabilities that make API simulation more realistic. Whether you&#39;re building complex applications that need dynamic responses or optimizing your development workflow, this release delivers the tools you need to create authentic API experie
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v1-2-with-mock-response-mirroring-and-improved-performance 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Silicon, Graphics, Media and AI (SiGMA) team is hiring!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 06:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you want to be a part of the Silicon, Graphics, Media and AI (SiGMA) platform team? We are hiring for multiple positions – if you’re interested in knowing more about opportunities in SiGMA, please see the below for more details! Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/sigma-engineering-hiring-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing ChatGPT Pulse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we&#39;re releasing a preview of ChatGPT Pulse to Pro users on mobile. Pulse is a new experience where ChatGPT proactively does research to deliver personalized updates based on your chats, feedback, and connected apps like your calendar.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-chatgpt-pulse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRUD-Sourcing is why Your Event Streams Are Bloated</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 21:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I see the same two issues come up over and over with event sourcing — they cause a lot of pain and they shouldn’t have to. Most of the pain stems from bad modeling, specifically because of CRUD-Sourcing. In this post I want to show why long event streams usually mean you’re modeling the wrong… Read More »CRUD-Sourcing is why Your Event Streams Are Bloated The post CRUD-Sourcing is why Your Event Streams Are Bloated appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2026 Insiders: Using Podman for Container Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Podman is an open-source container engine that has rapidly gained popularity for its daemonless architecture, rootless operation, and compatibility with Docker CLI commands. Unlike Docker, Podman does not require a central daemon, offering improved security and flexibili
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/visual-studio-2026-insiders-using-podman-for-container-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Windows still tinkering with critical sections?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adrian aka Silent aka CookiePLMonster did a deep investigation into how a 20 year old bug in GTA San Andreas surfaced in W
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250924-00/?p=111624 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Python So Popular in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 11:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While other programming languages come and go, Python has stood the test of time and firmly established itself as a top choice for developers of all levels, from beginners to seasoned professionals. Whether you’re working on intelligent systems or data-driven workflows, Python has a pivotal role to play in how your software is built, scaled, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/09/why-is-python-so-popular/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kotlin AI Stack: Build AI Agents With Koog, Code Smarter With Junie, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 08:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is changing how we build software, and Kotlin is ready to meet that change by empowering developers to build AI-powered apps and by enhancing the developer experience through AI-based tools. This post explores both angles: the tools for developing AI-powered apps, both from JetBrains and from the community, and the ways Kotlin is evolving […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/the-kotlin-ai-stack-build-ai-agents-with-koog-code-smarter-with-junie-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAP and OpenAI partner to launch sovereign ‘OpenAI for Germany’</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SAP and OpenAI launch OpenAI for Germany, a 2026 partnership to bring secure, sovereign AI to Germany’s public sector, enabling safe, efficient public services.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/openai-for-germany 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Diary of How JasperFx Helps Our Clients</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_09_2025/24_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For any shops using the “Critter Stack” (Marten and Wolverine), JasperFx Software offers support contracts and custom consulting engagements in support of these tools — or really anything you might be doing on the server side with .NET as well. Something we’ve had some success with, especially lately, is positioning these “support” contracts as essentially … Continue reading Little Diary of How JasperFx Helps Our Clients →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching the LLM Good Habits: How Azure MCP Uses Best-Practice Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 23:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/teaching-the-llm-good-habits-how-azure-mcp-uses-best-practice-tools 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running deep research AI agents on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 20:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI agents are evolving beyond basic single-task helpers into more powerful systems that can plan, critique, and collaborate with other agents to solve complex problems. Deep Agents—a recently introduced framework built on LangGraph—bring these capabilities to life, enabling multi-agent workflows that mirror real-world team dynamics. The challenge, however, is not just building such agents but […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/running-deep-research-ai-agents-on-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundry Local Meets More Silicon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 19:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Foundry Local is a high-performance local AI runtime stack that brings Azure AI Foundry’s power to client devices. Foundry Local lets you build and ship cross-platform AI apps that run models with acceleration on a wide range of hardware. The Evolution of AI Acceleration On-device AI has progressed
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/foundry-local-meets-more-silicon 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ktor roadmap and previews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 19:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As in previous years, we have been working on the Ktor roadmap, and we want to say thank everyone for their contributions and feedback to help us prioritize the roadmap! The OpenAPI and WebRTC support is already in preview since the Ktor 3.3.0 release. Check out the What’s New section for a full overview of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/ktor-roadmap-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate tokenization with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails for secure data handling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to integrate Amazon Bedrock Guardrails with third-party tokenization services to protect sensitive data while maintaining data reversibility. By combining these technologies, organizations can implement stronger privacy controls while preserving the functionality of their generative AI applications and related systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-tokenization-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails-for-secure-data-handling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From AI-Generated to Production-Ready Code: WebStorm Refactorings for the Modern Workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve all been there. You ask your AI tool to generate a React component, and the initial result works perfectly in the beginning. The AI gives you a functional 250-line component that gets the job done quickly and is exactly what you need for rapid prototyping. But even though AI does indeed excel at generating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2025/09/from-ai-generated-to-production-ready-code-webstorm-refactorings-for-the-modern-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another lesson learned from the Windows 98 on-stage USB blue screen</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Production Studios (commonly known inside Microsoft simply as Microsoft Studios) is a large broadcast studio nestled in the trees on Microsoft&#39;s main Redmond Campus.¹ Here&#39;s a video hosted by Luke Burbank, local
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250923-00/?p=111621 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI, Oracle, and SoftBank expand Stargate with five new AI datacenter sites</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI, Oracle, and SoftBank announce five new Stargate AI datacenter sites, accelerating a $500B, 10-gigawatt U.S. infrastructure buildout to power next-generation AI and create tens of thousands of jobs.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/five-new-stargate-sites 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The Drive-By Localhost Breach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 4 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that expose the devastating vulnerabilities in AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker MCP Gateway provides enterprise-grade protection against sophisticated attack vectors. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) has transformed how developers integrate AI agents with their development environments. Tools like...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mpc-horror-stories-cve-2025-49596-local-host-breach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging Unit Test Generation with in-IDE TestSpark</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Test generation is an essential yet time-consuming part of quality assurance. Automating test-generation techniques means accelerating the development process and improving the quality of the final software. However, traditional automated techniques, and their respective tools, are not usually user-friendly, having a command-line interface and not being integrated with the IDE. To boost acceleration and quality […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/09/testspark-unit-test-generation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sleep-pc: a .NET Native AOT tool to make Windows sleep after a timeout</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe a small native AOT .NET tool that I built to force a Windows PC to go to sleep after a timer expires
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/sleep-pc-a-dotnet-tool-to-make-windows-sleep-after-a-timeout/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression Trees in C#: Building Dynamic LINQ Queries at Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:05:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tired of endless if-else blocks just to build queries? What if your LINQ queries could write themselves at runtime? Today, we will unfold expression trees, which can be used to create dynamic queries at runtime. I will show how to use expression trees in your project and understand their advantages
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/expression-trees-in-c-building-dynamic-linq-queries-at-runtime/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a secure MCP server using OAuth and Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 05:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article shows how to implement a secure model context protocol (MCP) server using OAuth and Entra ID. The MCP server is implemented using ASP.NET Core and uses Microsoft Entra ID to secure the API. An ASP.NET Core application using Azure OpenAI and semantic kernel is used to implement the MCP client for the agent […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/09/23/implement-a-secure-mcp-server-using-oauth-and-entra-id/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancements to XAML Live Preview in Visual Studio for .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The XAML Live Preview feature in Visual Studio 2022 version 17.14 introduces a significant usability improvement for .NET MAUI projects: the XAML Live Preview window is now available during design time, eliminating the requirement to initiate a debug session. This change streamlines the UI dev
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/enhancements-to-xaml-live-preview-in-visual-studio-for-net-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the new SqlVector type with EF Core and Dapper</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure SQL vector support has been generally available for a few months now, and the ecosystem is quickly evolving to make working with vectors in your applications as seamless and efficient as possible. With the release of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/using-the-new-sqlvector-type-with-ef-core-and-dapper 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid ML experimentation for enterprises with Amazon SageMaker AI and Comet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showed how to use SageMaker and Comet together to spin up fully managed ML environments with reproducibility and experiment tracking capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/rapid-ml-experimentation-for-enterprises-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-comet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islands Theme: The New Look Coming to JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 16:24:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with version 2025.2.3, JetBrains IDEs will offer a new look: the Islands theme, available in both dark and light modes. This update is a visual refresh, which means that all functionality will remain the same. The new theme can be turned on or off in the Appearance settings. This step brings us closer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/09/islands-theme-the-new-look-coming-to-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Trusted Publishing enhances security on NuGet.org</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce Trusted Publishing on nuget.org — a simpler, safer way to publish NuGet packages from GitHub Actions. Rather than relying on long‑lived API keys, your workflow can use a short‑lived GitHub OIDC token to request a temporary, single‑use NuGet API key. These keys expire quickly (≈ 1 hour), eliminating long‑
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/enhanced-security-is-here-with-the-new-trust-publishing-on-nuget-org 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why was Windows 3.0&#39;s WinHelp called an online help system when it ran offline?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I described Windows 3.0&#39;s WinHelp as &amp;quot;a program for browsing online help files.&amp;quot; But Windows 3.0 predated the Internet, and these help files were available even if the computer was not
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250922-00/?p=111619 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch migrate .sln files to .slnx format across repositories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET has introduced a new solution file format called .slnx that offers significant improvements over the traditional .sln format: Better readability: XML-based structure that&#39;s human-readable Simplified merging: Reduces merge conflicts compared to the legacy format Easier parsing: Can be manipulated programmatically outside IDEs (for .NET devs, you can use microsoft/vs-solutionpersistence) To start using…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/batch-migrate-sln-files-to-slnx-format-across-repositories.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American-made innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            American-made innovation
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/american-made-innovation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.9.0 Released: Compose Multiplatform for Web Goes Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Multiplatform for web, powered by Wasm, is now in Beta! This major milestone shows that Compose Multiplatform for web is no longer just experimental, but ready for real-world use by early adopters. This is more than a technical step forward. It’s a community achievement, made possible by feedback from early adopters of the Alpha […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/09/compose-multiplatform-1-9-0-compose-for-web-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a safe, observable AI infrastructure for 1 million classrooms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how SchoolAI, built on OpenAI’s GPT-4.1, image generation, and TTS, powers safe, teacher-guided AI tools for 1 million classrooms worldwide—boosting engagement, oversight, and personalized learning.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/schoolai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and NVIDIA announce strategic partnership to deploy 10 gigawatts of NVIDIA systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and NVIDIA announce a strategic partnership to deploy 10 gigawatts of AI datacenters powered by NVIDIA systems, with the first phase launching in 2026.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-nvidia-systems-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
