<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:08:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bringing tic-tac-toe to life with AWS AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RoboTic-Tac-Toe is an interactive game where two physical robots move around a tic-tac-toe board, with both the gameplay and robots’ movements orchestrated by LLMs. Players can control the robots using natural language commands, directing them to place their markers on the game board. In this post, we explore the architecture and prompt engineering techniques used to reason about a tic-tac-toe game and decide the next best game strategy and movement plan for the current player.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New T-SQL AI Features are now in Public Preview for Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the start of this year, we released a new set of T-SQL AI features for embedding your relational data for AI applications. Today, we have brought those features to Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. This post will help you get started usi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/ai-functions-public-preview-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A step-by-step guide to modernizing .NET applications with GitHub Copilot agent mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Upgrading an old .NET app doesn’t have to mean chasing broken builds and cryptic errors. Yet for many developers, a simple version bump turns into hours of dependency conflicts and manual fixes. Modernization isn’t just about staying current. Older frameworks can introduce security risks, slow performance, and block cloud adoptio
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/modernizing-dotnet-with-github-copilot-agent-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker &#43; Unsloth: Build Custom Models, Faster</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building and Running Custom Models Is Still Hard Running AI models locally is still hard. Even as open-source LLMs grow more capable, actually getting them to run on your machine, with the right dependencies, remains slow, fragile, and inconsistent. There’s two sides to this challenge: Model creation and optimization: making fine-tuning and quantization efficient. Model...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-unsloth-build-custom-models-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperPod enhances ML infrastructure with security and storage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post introduces two major enhancements to Amazon SageMaker HyperPod that strengthen security and storage capabilities for large-scale machine learning infrastructure. The new features include customer managed key (CMK) support for encrypting EBS volumes with organization-controlled encryption keys, and Amazon EBS CSI driver integration that enables dynamic storage management for Kubernetes volumes in AI workloads.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/hyperpod-enhances-ml-infrastructure-with-security-and-storage/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps and GitHub Repositories — Next Steps in the Path to Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In May, we talked about the evolution of GitHub Copilot from a coding assistant into an AI powered peer programmer. Since then, GitHub has taken a major step forward - becoming an open platform for agentic devel
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-and-github-repositories-next-steps-in-the-path-to-agentic-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating generative AI applications with a platform engineering approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, I will illustrate how applying platform engineering principles to generative AI unlocks faster time-to-value, cost control, and scalable innovation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-generative-ai-applications-with-a-platform-engineering-approach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Microsoft Teams SDK (Formerly the Teams AI Library)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;UPDATE November 17: We&#39;re excited to announce that the Teams AI Library is now called the Microsoft Teams SDK.&amp;quot;]The Teams SDK, now generally available in C# and JavaScript and in public preview for Python, remains a developer’s one-stop-shop to build anything, including conversational agents, for Micros
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-the-updated-teams-ai-library-and-mcp-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spend Less Time Upgrading, More Time Coding in Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the past, moving to the next major version of Visual Studio could take hours, sometimes days, to recreate your dev environment the way you like it. Visual Studio 2026 makes it easier than ever to stay current with the latest productivity features, performance improvements, and security fixes all without disrupting your flow. With the new Vi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/spend-less-time-upgrading-more-time-coding-in-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Innovation to Enterprise Trust with Microsoft Agent 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The bridge between agent innovation and enterprise readiness While teams can build an agent in just a few days, deployin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/from-innovation-to-enterprise-trust-with-microsoft-agent-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: GitHub Copilot Chat GA and New Public Previews for Edit Data, Data-tier Application, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code continues to evolve, delivering features that make SQL development more integrated, more consistent, and more developer-friendly. In version v1.37.0, we’re announcing the Public Preview of Edit Data,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-copilot-ga-edit-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 3 Pro Is Now Available in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest AI model from Google, Gemini 3 Pro, is now live in JetBrains IDEs. From day one, it powers AI Chat and soon will be available in Junie, our coding agent, giving you smarter reasoning, stronger instruction following, and seamless integration into your workflow. What’s new Gemini 3 Pro shows clear improvements that matter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/gemini-3-pro-is-now-available-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Major New Agentic Capabilities for GitHub Copilot in JetBrains and Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot is taking a major step forward with expanded, deeply integrated support for JetBrains and Eclipse — bringing a new generation of agentic, intelligent capabilities directly into your favorite Java IDEs. This release strengthens Copilot’s cross-IDE experience, unifies agentic workflows, and unlocks m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/new-agentic-capabilities-for-github-copilot-in-jetbrains-and-eclipse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public preview of vector indexing in Azure SQL DB, Azure SQL MI, and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to share that DiskANN vector indexing is now in public preview across Azure SQL Database, Azure SQL Managed Instance, and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. DiskANN is a cutting-edge algorithm for efficient vector similarity search, making it ideal for powering recommendation systems
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/public-preview-of-vector-indexing-in-azure-sql-db-azure-sql-mi-and-sql-database-in-microsoft-fabric 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Generally Available: Azure Cosmos DB Fleet Pools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce two updates to Azure Cosmos DB fleets: Fleet pools – now generally available Fleet analytics – now in public preview Azure Cosmos DB fleets enables developers to build scalable, isolated, and cost-effective multi-tenant or Software as a Service (SaaS) applications. Today,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-generally-available-azure-cosmos-db-fleet-pool 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Release of MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting today, you can download the second EAP release for MPS 2025.3 and try all the latest updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 EAP 2 This release includes several noteworthy improvements: JavaDoc language overhaul The JavaDoc language has been completely migrated to use the jetbrains.mps.lang.text language for text representation and editing. This change should have minimal impact […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/11/the-mps-2025-3-eap2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch a Chat UI Agent with Docker and the Vercel AI SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running a Chat UI Agent doesn’t have to involve a complicated setup. By combining Docker with the Vercel AI SDK, it’s possible to build and launch a conversational interface in a clean, reproducible way. Docker ensures that the environment is consistent across machines, while the Vercel AI SDK provides the tools for handling streaming responses...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/launch-chat-ui-agent-docker-vercel-ai-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping Decision‑Makers Say Yes to Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the fourth post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/helping-decision-makers-say-yes-to-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: Projects We’re Proud to Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference — the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and to contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/11/18/open-source-in-focus-projects-we-re-proud-to-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Companies complaining .NET moves too fast should just pay for post-EOL support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe a solution to .NET &amp;quot;releasing too quickly&amp;quot;: just pay for support of older versions, such as HeroDevs&#39; Never Ending Support for .NET 6
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/companies-using-dotnet-need-to-suck-it-up-and-pay-for-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Read Models with EF Core Projections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 08:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can&#39;t really argue against the importance of performance in any application. Even if the system is not time-critical, efficient and time-saving operations are cornerstones of the system. Data fetching is the primary step for improving the performance of most applications. If you use Entity Framework Core (EF
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/building-read-models-with-ef-core-projections/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intuit and OpenAI join forces on new AI-powered experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Intuit have entered a $100M+ multi-year partnership to launch Intuit app experiences in ChatGPT and expand Intuit’s use of OpenAI’s frontier models to power personalized financial tools.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/intuit-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing MSVC AddressSanitizer for ARM64 targets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announceÂ AddressSanitizerÂ (ASan) support for the Microsoft C++ (MSVC) Build Tools forÂ ARM64 targets.Â ASan is a runtime memory error detector thatÂ
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/introducing-msvc-addresssanitizer-for-arm64-targets 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your complete guide to Amazon Quick Suite at AWS re:Invent 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, re:Invent will be held in Las Vegas, Nevada, from December 1 to December 5, 2025, and this guide will help you navigate our comprehensive session catalog and plan your week. The sessions cater to business and technology leaders, product and engineering teams, and data and analytics teams interested in incorporating agentic AI capabilities across their teams and organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/your-complete-guide-to-amazon-quick-suite-at-aws-reinvent-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate enterprise solutions with agentic AI-powered consulting: Introducing AWS Professional Service Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m excited to announce AWS Professional Services now offers specialized AI agents including the AWS Professional Services Delivery Agent. This represents a transformation to the consulting experience that embeds intelligent agents throughout the consulting life cycle to deliver better value for customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-enterprise-solutions-with-agentic-ai-powered-consulting-introducing-aws-professional-service-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Claude: Transforming business with agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Claude are enabling enterprises like Cox Automotive and Druva to deploy production-ready agentic AI systems that deliver measurable business value, with results including up to 63% autonomous issue resolution and 58% faster response times. We examine the technical foundation combining Claude&#39;s frontier AI capabilities with AgentCore&#39;s enterprise-grade infrastructure that allows organizations to focus on agent logic rather than building complex operational systems from scratch.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing C# 14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# 14 ships with .NET 10. The highlight is new extension members, but there&#39;s a lot more features that make your life as a developer more productive. And, we&#39;ve added new features that enable some of the performance improvements you can experience in .NET 10. Read on for a tour of all the new features, and find links to dive de
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-csharp-14 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing F# 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            F# 10 is now shipping with .NET 10 and Visual Studio 2026. This version is a refinement release focused on clarity, consistency, and performance, bringing small but meaningful improvements that make your everyday code more legible and robust. You can get F# 10 today in a few ways:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-fsharp-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect that Windows is running in S-Mode, redux</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Igor Levicki asked for a plain C version of the sample code to detect whether Windows is running in S-Mode. I didn&#39;t write one for two reasons. First, I didn&#39;t realize that so many people still tried to use COM from plain C. A
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251117-00/?p=111795 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Features in Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider provides robust support for working with databases directly within the IDE – powered by DataGrip! Rider and DataGrip smooth development workflows by allowing you to manage and interact with a variety of database systems. This integration enhances productivity for developers who frequently work with data. Database projects and connectivity There has long been support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/17/database-features-in-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize GUID creation performance in .NET applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many .NET projects use well-known GUIDs as identifiers for activities, interop scenarios, database keys, and other purposes. It&#39;s common to see code like new Guid(&amp;quot;01234567-8901-2345-6789-012345678901&amp;quot;) throughout applications. While this approach is readable and straightforward, it comes with a hidden performance cost that can impact application startup time. This is a micro-optimization that primarily…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/optimize-guid-creation-performance-in-dotnet-applications.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Prepare for the Future of Programming</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Start a start-up? Scratch that. Call your mom. Go back to school? Don’t go back to school. Learn to code? Don’t learn to code. Forget coding. Only prompt engineering matters now. Actually, I heard it’s overrated. You think we’re gonna be prompting in 5 years? 2 years? Nonsense. All this hype is being blown so […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/11/17/how-to-prepare-for-the-future-of-programming/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Your Calendars! Qodana Events in November</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As 2025 starts racing to a close, the JetBrains Qodana team is ending the year with a series of events dedicated to what matters most in modern software development: secure workflows, high-quality code, and practical tooling that empowers developers to ship with confidence. Whether you’re working in security engineering, backend development, DevOps, or AI-powered applications, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/11/mark-your-calendars-qodana-events-in-november/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI named Emerging Leader in Generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI has been named an Emerging Leader in Gartner’s 2025 Innovation Guide for Generative AI Model Providers. The recognition reflects our enterprise momentum, with over 1 million companies building with ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gartner-2025-emerging-leader 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement forgot your password using swiyu, ASP.NET Core Identity and Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post show to implement a “Forgot your password” flow using the Swiss Digital identity and trust infrastructure, (swiyu) in an ASP.NET Core web application using ASP.NET Core Identity and Duende IdentityServer. The generic containers from swiyu are used to integrate the Swiss E-ID and the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations standards. .NET Aspire is used […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/11/17/implement-forgot-your-password-using-swiyu-asp-net-core-identity-and-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Diffusion Models Could Change Developer Workflows in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers spend much of their time editing, refactoring, and debugging rather than producing entirely new code. Code creation tends to involve non-sequential back-and-forth refinement rather than typing out a complete function in one uninterrupted sequence. You might sketch a part, adjust parameters, skip ahead, then revisit earlier sections to refine them. Diffusion models, and in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/why-diffusion-models-could-change-developer-workflows-in-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Programming Rule #4: Safe and Efficient Type Casting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_11_2025/16_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_11_2025/16_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article emphasizes defensive programming by highlighting safe type compatibility checks in .NET. It advises using the &#39;is&#39; keyword to prevent InvalidCastException and warns against unnecessary type casts that clutter code and affect performance. The open-source project Spargine aids developers with tools for better validation and logging, promoting cleaner, more resilient applications.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/11/16/defensive-programming-rule-4-safe-and-efficient-type-casting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is My Developer Career JUST Maintenance?! - Dev Leader Weekly 116</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss just how much of our developer careers are maintaining software systems.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/15/is-my-developer-career-just-maintenance-dev-leader-weekly-116 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-11-14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/15/weekly-recap-20251114 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Is Heading to VSLive! Orlando</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Next week we’ll be in Orlando, Florida for Visual Studio Live!, and if you work with .NET, we’d like to meet you. You’ll find the JetBrains booth (#118) in the conference expo area throughout the week. Stop by to: We’ll also have special offers available for those who visit the booth.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/15/jetbrains-is-heading-to-vslive-orlando/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring C# File-based Apps in .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With .NET 10, Microsoft introduced file-based apps, which give you the ability to write C# code in a single .cs file and run it directly, without any project or solution files. This feature finally makes C# approachable for quick scripts and utilities
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/exploring-csharp-file-based-apps-in-dotnet-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a biomedical research agent with Biomni tools and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a production-ready biomedical research agent by integrating Biomni&#39;s specialized tools with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, enabling researchers to access over 30 biomedical databases through a secure, scalable infrastructure. The implementation showcases how to transform research prototypes into enterprise-grade systems with persistent memory, semantic tool discovery, and comprehensive observability for scientific reproducibility .
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-biomedical-research-agent-with-biomni-tools-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your web apps hands-free with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Graphical user interfaces have carried the torch for decades, but today’s users increasingly expect to talk to their applications. In this post we show how we added a true voice-first experience to a reference application—the Smart Todo App—turning routine task management into a fluid, hands-free conversation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/make-your-web-apps-hands-free-with-amazon-nova-sonic/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the power of generative AI: Druva’s multi-agent copilot for streamlined data protection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI is transforming the way businesses interact with their customers and revolutionizing conversational interfaces for complex IT operations. Druva, a leading provider of data security solutions, is at the forefront of this transformation. In collaboration with Amazon Web Services (AWS), Druva is developing a cutting-edge generative AI-powered multi-agent copilot that aims to redefine the customer experience in data security and cyber resilience.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/harnessing-the-power-of-generative-ai-druvas-multi-agent-copilot-for-streamlined-data-protection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Trial – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            First steps: Run your first secure, production-ready image Container base images form the foundation of your application security. When those foundations contain vulnerabilities, every service built on top inherits the same risk. Docker Hardened Images addresses this at the source. These are continuously-maintained, minimal base images designed for security: stripped of unnecessary packages, patched proactively,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-trial-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 💚 Spring 7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Major Spring Framework releases don’t come around often – and when they do, they tend to reshape how we build applications for years to come. Spring Framework 7 is one of those releases. It simplifies many aspects of development, cleans up some long-standing pain points, and introduces features that previously required custom annotations or boilerplate-heavy […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-2025-3-spring-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I can use &lt;CODE&gt;WM_&lt;WBR&gt;COPY&lt;WBR&gt;DATA&lt;/CODE&gt; to send a block of data to another window, but how does it send data back?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The WM_COPY­DATA message can be used to send a blob of data from one window to another. The window manager does the work of copying the data from the sending process to the receiving process, but how does the receiving process send data back? If the only information that needs to come back is a success/failure,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251114-00/?p=111792 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure MCP Server Now Built-In with Visual Studio 2026: A New Era for Agentic Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing cloud resources often means juggling multiple tools, writing custom scripts, and switching contexts between your IDE and cloud management portals. These extra steps slow development and make it harder to build intelligent, secure applications efficiently. We’re excited to announce that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/azure-mcp-server-now-built-in-with-visual-studio-2026-a-new-era-for-agentic-workflows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Great AI Productivity Divide: Why Are Some Developers 5x Faster?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered developer tools claim to boost your productivity, doing everything from intelligent auto-complete to (https://openai.com/index/introducing-codex/). But the productivity gains users report have been something of a mixed bag. Some groups claim to get 3-5x (or more), productivity boosts, while other devs claim to get no benefit at all—or even losses of up to 19%. I...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-productivity-divide-developers-5x-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial Videos: Setting up GitHub Copilot for your Company</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide shares a series of videos that walk you through setting up GitHub and GitHub Copilot end-to-end for your company. These are especially useful for organizations starting from scratch who want to leverage GitHub Copilot and are looking to get started. These videos were recorded as of October 2025.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/tutorial-videos-setting-up-github-copilot-for-your-company 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing OpenAI for Ireland</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI launches OpenAI for Ireland, partnering with the Irish Government, Dogpatch Labs and Patch to help SMEs, founders and young builders use AI to innovate, boost productivity and build the next generation of Irish tech startups.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-for-ireland 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAPI.NET: The Biggest Update Ever</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 20:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the Biggest Update Ever: OpenAPI.NET v2 &amp;amp; v3 We are excited to announce two major releases of the OpenAPI.NET library—the most significant update since its launch in 2018. These updates ensure developers can build and document modern, interoperable APIs with the latest OpenAPI specifications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/openapi/openapi-net-release-announcements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code - November 2025 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce that the November 2025 release of the Python extension for Visual Studio Code is now available! This release includes the following announcements: Add Copilot Hover Summaries as docstring Localized Copilot Ho
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-november-2025-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A first look at the all‑new UX in Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2026 introduces a refreshed user experience, thoughtfully crafted for clarity, accessibility, and a clean interface that feels right at home on Windows. This update is the result of extensive collaboration with developers and incorporates valuable feedback from the community. We’ve improved typography, iconography, and the over
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/a-first-look-at-the-all%e2%80%91new-ux-in-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cagent Comes to Docker Desktop with Built-In IDE Support through ACP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop now includes cagent bundled out of the box. This means developers can start building AI agents without a separate installation step. For those unfamiliar with cagent: it’s Docker’s open-source tool that lets you build AI agents using YAML configuration files instead of writing code. You define the agent’s behavior and tools, and cagent...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/cagent-comes-to-docker-desktop-with-built-in-ide-support-through-acp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could we use CTAD to simplify the use of WRL&#39;s Callback function?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Commenter Bwmat asked, &amp;quot;Can CTAD avoid the need for the lengthy type name in the last example?&amp;quot; This was in response to the rather lengthy type in the explicit specialization void MyClass::RegisterCompletion(ABI::IAsy
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251113-00/?p=111787 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The WhatsApp Data Exfiltration Attack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 5 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that highlight the critical vulnerabilities threatening AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker’s comprehensive AI security platform provides protection against these threats. Model Context Protocol (MCP) promises seamless integration between AI agents and communication platforms like WhatsApp, enabling automated message...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-whatsapp-data-exfiltration-issue/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding neural networks through sparse circuits</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is exploring mechanistic interpretability to understand how neural networks reason. Our new sparse model approach could make AI systems more transparent and support safer, more reliable behavior.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/understanding-neural-networks-through-sparse-circuits 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring Seamless User Experience in Modernization Projects with AI‑Generated Stagehand and Playwright UI Tests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When modernizing legacy systems, the user interface often becomes the make-or-break factor for project success. While backend improvements matter, users interact with the frontend and that&#39;s where trust is built or broken. Using AI‑generated tools like Stagehand with Microsoft&#39;s Playwright helps ensure a smooth user experience during moderni
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/app-modernization-llm-driven-ui-tests-hve 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Philips Is scaling AI literacy across 70,000 employees</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Philips is scaling AI literacy with ChatGPT Enterprise, training 70,000 employees to use AI responsibly and improve healthcare outcomes worldwide.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/philips 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5.1 for developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.1 is now available in the API, bringing faster adaptive reasoning, extended prompt caching, improved coding performance, and new apply_patch and shell tools.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-1-for-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code 2025: What Our Contributors Built</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Congrats to all GSoC 2025 contributors and mentors! This year’s projects have made a real impact on the Kotlin ecosystem and the contributions are already being integrated, used, and appreciated. Thank you all for your hard work! Let’s take a closer look at this year’s projects: IntelliJ Platform Gradle Plugin – Gradle Reporting and Parallel […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/google-summer-of-code-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session Guide to Azure AI Foundry @ Microsoft Ignite: Must-See Developer Sessions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Ignite 2025 is the ultimate opportunity for developers to dive deep into what’s new with Azure AI Foundry. We curated the top sessions designed for hands-on learning, practical demos, and expert insights. Whether you’re
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/ignitedevsessions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Copilot auto model selection (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Faster responses, a lower chance of rate limiting, and 10% off premium requests for paid users - auto picks the best available model for each request based on current capacity and performance. With auto, you don&#39;t need to choose a specific model. Copilot automatical
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-copilot-auto-model-selection-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perform wide-sweeping refactors using C&#43;&#43; code editing tools for GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [cta-button text=&amp;quot;Sign up for our Private Preview&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;https://aka.ms/code-editing-tools-private-preview&amp;quot; color=&amp;quot;btn-primary&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot;] Refactoring a C++ codebase can often require tracking updates across various sections of multiple files to ensure accuracy and relevancy. Historically, developers have relied on manual searches acr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/perform-wide-sweeping-refactors-using-c-code-editing-tools-for-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize Your C&#43;&#43; Build Times with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Long build times are one of the top pain points for C++ projects. If you’ve ever waited too long for a C++ build to finish, you know how much it can slow down your productivity. In past years, we introduced C++ Build Insights to help you analyze traces and find bottlenecks. However, we know that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/optimize-your-c-build-times-with-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix build issues using GitHub Copilot after upgrading MSVC Build Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [cta-button text=&amp;quot;Sign up for the Private Preview waitlist&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/C2S6NV3&amp;quot; color=&amp;quot;btn-primary&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot;] A few problems have reared their heads at every company where I’ve worked on C++ as a Software Engineer over the past 20 years. For the most part, those problems have nothing to do with the language
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/app-modernization-cpp-private-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2025 (version 1.106)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code October 2025 Release (1.106). Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/october-2025-(version-1.106) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Developers Really Mean by “Bad Code”</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The phrase “bad code” gets thrown around in reviews and online forums all the time. But what does it actually mean? It’s a good example of the vague terms that occasionally make the rounds in developer circles without much to qualify them. We’ve collected opinions on the subject, metrics, and code risks that you can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/11/what-is-bad-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Rotating the tree</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another algorithm for non-recursively deleting the nodes of a binary tree comes from boost. Reading library code is a bit cumbersome because library code tries to be generic, but if you unwind the traits classes, you ge
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251112-00/?p=111784 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.50: Indispensable for Daily Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.50 represents a major leap forward in how development teams build, secure, and ship software. Across the last several releases, we&#39;ve delivered meaningful improvements that directly address the challenges you face every day: faster debugging workflows, enterprise-grade security controls that don&#39;t get in your way, and seamless AI integration that makes modern development...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-50/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2025 Windows Musician Technology and Arm64 Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s no surprise that Arm64 PCs hit a sweet spot for music creation and live performance. They are thin and light, have excellent battery life (I used a Surface Laptop 7 at the entire NAMM show and never had to charge it despite giving presentations and demos), great screens, USB-4 ports that support Thunderbolt 3, and are super quiet. They
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/fall-2025-windows-musician-technology-and-arm64-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuro drives national retail wins with ChatGPT Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Neuro uses ChatGPT Business to scale nationwide with fewer than seventy employees. From drafting contracts to uncovering insights in customer data, the team saves time, cuts costs, and turns ideas into growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/neurogum 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fighting the New York Times’ invasion of user privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is fighting the New York Times’ demand for 20 million private ChatGPT conversations and accelerating new security and privacy protections to protect your data.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/fighting-nyt-user-privacy-invasion 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5.1 Instant and GPT-5.1 Thinking System Card Addendum</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This GPT-5 system card addendum provides updated safety metrics for GPT-5.1 Instant and Thinking, including new evaluations for mental health and emotional reliance.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-system-card-addendum-gpt-5-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5.1: A smarter, more conversational ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re upgrading the GPT-5 series with warmer, more capable models and new ways to customize ChatGPT’s tone and style. GPT-5.1 starts rolling out today to paid users.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
