<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:09:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Enterprise AI Complexity: Multi-Agent Orchestration with the Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Architectural Imperative: Why Multi-Agent Orchestration is Essential In modern enterprise AI systems, the scope and complexity of real-world business ch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/unlocking-enterprise-ai-complexity-multi-agent-orchestration-with-the-microsoft-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Testing with Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Ever had to write tests that need a real database, and found yourself juggling local setups or dummy data? Testcontainers might just be your new best friend. In this article, we&#39;ll explore how Testcontainers can simplify integration testing by spinning up real services in Docker containers on-demand. We&#39;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/testing-with-testcontainers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI in South Korea—OpenAI’s Economic Blueprint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI&#39;s Korea Economic Blueprint outlines how South Korea can scale trusted AI through sovereign capabilities and strategic partnerships to drive growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/south-korea-economic-blueprint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build scalable creative solutions for product teams with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how product teams can leverage Amazon Bedrock and AWS services to transform their creative workflows through generative AI, enabling rapid content iteration across multiple formats while maintaining brand consistency and compliance. The solution demonstrates how teams can deploy a scalable generative AI application that accelerates everything from product descriptions and marketing copy to visual concepts and video content, significantly reducing time to market while enhancing creative quality.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a proactive AI cost management system for Amazon Bedrock – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore advanced cost monitoring strategies for Amazon Bedrock deployments, introducing granular custom tagging approaches for precise cost allocation and comprehensive reporting mechanisms that build upon the proactive cost management foundation established in Part 1. The solution demonstrates how to implement invocation-level tagging, application inference profiles, and integration with AWS Cost Explorer to create a complete 360-degree view of generative AI usage and expenses.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a proactive AI cost management system for Amazon Bedrock – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce a comprehensive solution for proactively managing Amazon Bedrock inference costs through a cost sentry mechanism designed to establish and enforce token usage limits, providing organizations with a robust framework for controlling generative AI expenses. The solution uses serverless workflows and native Amazon Bedrock integration to deliver a predictable, cost-effective approach that aligns with organizational financial constraints while preventing runaway costs through leading indicators and real-time budget enforcement.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline code migration using Amazon Nova Premier with an agentic workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Nova Premier with Amazon Bedrock can systematically migrate legacy C code to modern Java/Spring applications using an intelligent agentic workflow that breaks down complex conversions into specialized agent roles. The solution reduces migration time and costs while improving code quality through automated validation, security assessment, and iterative refinement processes that handle even large codebases exceeding token limitations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-code-migration-using-amazon-nova-premier-with-an-agentic-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Context to Copilot: Azure Cosmos DB Best Practices, Right in Your VS Code Workspace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers love GitHub Copilot for its instant, intelligent code suggestions. But what if those suggestions could also reflect your specific database and workload patterns? That’s now possible with a new feature in Azure Cosmos DB for VS Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/bringing-context-to-copilot-azure-cosmos-db-best-practices-right-in-your-vs-code-workspace 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The next chapter for UK sovereign AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI expands its UK partnership with a new Ministry of Justice agreement, bringing ChatGPT to civil servants. It also introduces UK data residency for ChatGPT Enterprise, ChatGPT Edu, and the API Platform to support trusted and secure AI adoption.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/the-next-chapter-for-uk-sovereign-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Planning in Visual Studio (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Quick prompts are great for small fixes, but they fall short on big projects. You end up rewriting instructions, tweaking them constantly, and hoping the model stays on track. It gives Copilot a visible, structured path to follow, one that updates as it works and keeps you in control at every step. In Agent Mode, Copilot can now create plan
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-planning-in-visual-studio-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authorization: Domain or Application Layer?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m diving into a super common question that’s really important: where should your authorization live? Should it live within your domain or your application layer? I am going to show some real world code examples and some simple guidelines so you can keep your software architecture consistent and avoid authorization code scattered everywhere. YouTube Check… Read More »Authorization: Domain or Application Layer? The post Authorization: Domain or Application Layer? appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Matter: The AI Development Companion for Product Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’ve spent 25 years building tools for developers. Over the past two years, we’ve seen that AI isn’t just changing how developers write code – it’s beginning to reshape the entire process of product development. Not only is AI making developers more productive, helping with everything from code completion to testing and deployment, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/matter/2025/10/introducing-matter-the-ai-development-companion-for-product-teams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI Agentic RAG search application with React, SQL Azure and Azure Static Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Leveraging OpenAI for semantic searches on structured databases like Azure SQL enhances search accuracy and context-awareness, providing more relevant and insightful results. This example showcases the use of Azure SQL for storing and searching data with AI. By implementing the RAG pattern with Azure SQL, the sample e
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-an-ai-agentic-rag-search-application-with-react-sql-azure-and-azure-static-web-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes &lt;CODE&gt;cheap_&lt;WBR&gt;steady_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt; faster than &lt;CODE&gt;std::&lt;WBR&gt;chrono::&lt;WBR&gt;high_&lt;WBR&gt;resolution_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I noted that There is a std::chrono::high_resolution_clock, but no low_resolution_clock.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251022-00/?p=111714 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metagenomi generates millions of novel enzymes cost-effectively using AWS Inferentia</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we detail how Metagenomi partnered with AWS to implement the Progen2 protein language model on AWS Inferentia, achieving up to 56% cost reduction for high-throughput enzyme generation workflows. The implementation enabled cost-effective generation of millions of novel enzyme variants using EC2 Inf2 Spot Instances and AWS Batch, demonstrating how cloud-based generative AI can make large-scale protein design more accessible for biotechnology applications .
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/metagenomi-generates-millions-of-novel-enzymes-cost-effectively-using-aws-inferentia/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Offload: Automating Everyday Workflows with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every developer eventually hits a wall with their local machine. Maybe it’s training an AI model that drains your CPU, compiling a massive codebase that makes your fan sound like a jet engine, or simply trying to run GPU workloads on a laptop that doesn’t have one. The result is the same: slow builds, limited...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/getting-started-docker-offload/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Python to Kotlin: A Transition Worth Making</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was written by an external contributor. When it comes to writing short scripts or CRUDs, Python is a great choice. With its rich ecosystem and broad adoption, it can be easily used to scrape some data or to perform data analysis. However, maintaining a large codebase in Python can be very problematic. Python’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/10/from-python-to-kotlin-a-transition-worth-making/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding metadata to fallback endpoints in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss fallback endpoints and show how adding metadata to MVC or Razor Page fallback endpoints has some quirks to be aware of
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/adding-metadata-to-fallback-endpoints-in-aspnetcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI in Japan—OpenAI’s Japan Economic Blueprint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI’s Japan Economic Blueprint outlines how Japan can harness AI to boost innovation, strengthen competitiveness, and enable sustainable, inclusive growth.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/japan-economic-blueprint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Model Choice in VS Code with Bring Your Own Key</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how the new Language Model Chat Provider API in VS Code is enabling more model choice and extensibility for chat experiences via the Bring Your Own Key experience. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/expanding-model-choice-in-vs-code-with-bring-your-own-key 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless deployment for your Amazon SageMaker Canvas models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how to take an ML model built in SageMaker Canvas and deploy it using SageMaker Serverless Inference, helping you go from model creation to production-ready predictions quickly and efficiently without managing any infrastructure. This solution demonstrates a complete workflow from adding your trained model to the SageMaker Model Registry through creating serverless endpoint configurations and deploying endpoints that automatically scale based on demand .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a multi-agent voice assistant with Amazon Nova Sonic and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Nova Sonic&#39;s speech-to-speech capabilities can be combined with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to create sophisticated multi-agent voice assistants that break complex tasks into specialized, manageable components. The approach demonstrates how to build modular, scalable voice applications using a banking assistant example with dedicated sub-agents for authentication, banking inquiries, and mortgage services, offering a more maintainable alternative to monolithic voice assistant designs.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate large-scale AI training with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training operator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy and manage machine learning training workloads using the Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training operator, which enhances training resilience for Kubernetes workloads through pinpoint recovery and customizable monitoring capabilities. The Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training operator helps accelerate generative AI model development by efficiently managing distributed training across large GPU clusters, offering benefits like centralized training process monitoring, granular process recovery, and hanging job detection that can reduce recovery times from tens of minutes to seconds.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing Visual Studio Extension Compatibility: Effortless Migration for Extension Developers and Users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have great news for extension users and developers: Visual Studio 2026 is introducing an extension compatibility model designed specifically to make your life easier. Our top priority is to ensure that your extensions continue to work seamlessly across Visual Studio releases - with no extra effort required from you. For users: exten
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/modernizing-visual-studio-extension-compatibility-effortless-migration-for-extension-developers-and-users 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: The hockey stick on wheels</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The &amp;quot;hockey stick graph&amp;quot; is a graph which shows slow initial growth, followed by a rapid linear increase. The resulting shape resembles a hockey stick, with the blade of the stick represented by the nearly-flat initial section, and the handle of the stick represented by the rapi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251021-00/?p=111710 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a Richer ”docker model run” Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The command line is where developers live and breathe. A powerful and intuitive CLI can make the difference between a frustrating task and a joyful one. That’s why we’re excited to announce a major upgrade to the interactive chat experience in Docker Model Runner, our tool for running AI workloads locally. We&#39;ve rolled out a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-run-prompt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Cost Management” Is Now “Account Throughput” and It’s Moving</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve made a small but important change in the Azure portal for Azure Cosmos DB to make it easier to manage your account-level throughput. The “Cost Management” section has been renamed to “Account Throughput” and can now be found under the Settings section of your Azure Cosmos DB
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/cost-management-is-now-account-throughput 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing ChatGPT Atlas, the browser with ChatGPT built in</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT Atlas, the browser with ChatGPT built it. Get instant answers, summaries, and smart web help—right from any page. With privacy settings you can control. Available now for MacOS.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-chatgpt-atlas 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What about the icons in pifmgr.dll?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I discussed the intended uses of the icons in progman.exe and moricons.dll and we even looked at those icons (
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251020-00/?p=111706 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner Meets Open WebUI: A Simpler Way to Run Local AI Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, I’m Sergei Shitikov - a Docker Captain and Lead Software Engineer living in Berlin. I&#39;m focused on DevOps, developer experience, open source, and local AI tools. I created this extension to make it easier for anyone - even without a technical background - to get started with local LLMs using Docker Model Runner and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/open-webui-docker-desktop-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to Rider 2025.3: ASP.NET and Database Issue Detection In The Monitoring Tool Window</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Rider 2025.3, the Monitoring tool window has become even more powerful with the addition of database and ASP.NET issue detection. These new capabilities let you track slow queries, inefficient request handling, and other performance bottlenecks in real time – right alongside CPU, memory, and GC activity. You can explore these new additions in the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/20/rider-2025-3-asp-dotnet-and-database-issue-monitoring/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing latest Azure Cosmos DB Python SDK: Powering the Future of AI with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to announce the stable release of Azure Cosmos DB Python SDK version 4.14.0! This release brings together months of innovation and collaboration, featuring ground-breaking capabilities that have been battle-tested in production environments. Many of these features were developed in c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-latest-azure-cosmos-db-python-sdk-powering-the-future-of-ai-with-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Developer&#39;s Guide to Fine-Tuning GPT-4o for Image Classification on Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re a machine learning practitioner, app developer, or just curious about the latest in AI, this guide shows how you can quickly boost image classification accuracy using cutting-edge Vision-Language Models (VLM) on Azure—no deep learning expertise required. In this walkthrough, you’ll see how to fine-tune GPT-4o on
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/a-developers-guide-to-fine-tuning-gpt-4o-for-image-classification-on-azure-ai-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science Learning Curve: Insights from 18k Learners Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 06:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The world of computer science (CS) education is changing rapidly. From AI-powered tools to new modes of online and blended learning, it has never been more dynamic – or more critical. Education research has looked into some aspects of how students learn computer science, but when we ask the big questions about who is learning […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/10/computer-science-learning-curve/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering the Art of Public Speaking: Lessons from a Lifetime of Teaching and Sharing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_10_2025/19_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_10_2025/19_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For decades, the author has focused on improving code quality through teaching and speaking, emphasizing the joy of mentoring developers. Despite the shift to virtual formats, they believe in-person interactions are essential for effective learning. The author highlights the importance of preparation, resilience against criticism, and making a positive impact on individuals.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/10/19/mastering-the-art-of-public-speaking-lessons-from-a-lifetime-of-teaching-and-sharing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Steps for Setting Up a New .NET Project the Right Way</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_10_2025/18_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_10_2025/18_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to properly set up a new .NET project with EditorConfig for code consistency, Directory.Build.props for centralized configuration, central package management, static code analysis, Docker Compose or .NET Aspire for local orchestration, and GitHub Actions for CI/CD.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/6-steps-for-setting-up-a-new-dotnet-project-the-right-way 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your Azure Cosmos DB Efficiency with Azure Advisor Insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB is
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/boost-your-azure-cosmos-db-efficiency-with-azure-advisor-insights 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add MCP Servers to OpenAI’s Codex with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI assistants are changing how we write code, but their true power is unleashed when they can interact with specialized, high-precision tools. OpenAI&#39;s Codex is a formidable coding partner, but what happens when you connect it directly to your running infrastructure? Enter the Docker MCP Toolkit. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) Toolkit acts as a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/connect-codex-to-mcp-servers-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How TP ICAP transformed CRM data into real-time insights with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how TP ICAP used Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon Bedrock Evaluations to build ClientIQ, an enterprise-grade solution with enhanced security features for extracting CRM insights using AI, delivering immediate business value.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-tp-icap-transformed-crm-data-into-real-time-insights-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principal Financial Group accelerates build, test, and deployment of Amazon Lex V2 bots through automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the post Principal Financial Group increases Voice Virtual Assistant performance using Genesys, Amazon Lex, and Amazon QuickSight, we discussed the overall Principal Virtual Assistant solution using Genesys Cloud, Amazon Lex V2, multiple AWS services, and a custom reporting and analytics solution using Amazon QuickSight.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/principal-financial-group-accelerates-build-test-and-deployment-of-amazon-lex-v2-bots-through-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond vibes: How to properly select the right LLM for the right task</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss an approach that can guide you to build comprehensive and empirically driven evaluations that can help you make better decisions when selecting the right model for your task.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/beyond-vibes-how-to-properly-select-the-right-llm-for-the-right-task/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splash Music transforms music generation using AWS Trainium and Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Splash Music is setting a new standard for AI-powered music creation by using its advanced HummingLM model with AWS Trainium on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod. As a selected startup in the 2024 AWS Generative AI Accelerator, Splash Music collaborated closely with AWS Startups and the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to fast-track innovation and accelerate their music generation FM development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlined Setup, Stronger Guardrails for Microsoft Dev Box</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce a new capability that simplifies Dev Box setup—enabling platform engineers and project admins to specify images and SKUs directly when configuring Dev Box pools, without needing to create Dev Box definitions at the Dev Cent
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/streamlined-setup-stronger-guardrails-for-microsoft-dev-box 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using RAII to remedy a defect where not all code paths performed required exit actions, follow-up</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we looked at a way to use the RAII design pattern (Resource Acquisition Is Initialization) to ensure that a function eventually got called on all code paths
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251017-00/?p=111698 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Still Use jQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            jQuery is a household name among web developers who have been around the block. Initially released in 2006, it took the web development world by storm with its easy and intuitive syntax for navigating a document, selecting DOM elements, handling events, and making AJAX requests. At its peak in 2015, jQuery featured on 62.7 percent...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-i-still-use-jquery-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koog 0.5.0 Is Out: Smarter Tools, Persistent Agents, and Simplified Strategy Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 07:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently released Koog 0.5.0, introducing full Agent2Agent (A2A) protocol support, which makes it easier than ever to build systems of interconnected AI agents in Kotlin. But A2A is just the beginning. Koog 0.5.0 brings a host of improvements that make agents more persistent, tools smarter, and strategy design more intuitive. Let’s dive into the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/10/koog-0-5-0-is-out-smarter-tools-persistent-agents-and-simplified-strategy-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterative fine-tuning on Amazon Bedrock for strategic model improvement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 23:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations often face challenges when implementing single-shot fine-tuning approaches for their generative AI models. The single-shot fine-tuning method involves selecting training data, configuring hyperparameters, and hoping the results meet expectations without the ability to make incremental adjustments. Single-shot fine-tuning frequently leads to suboptimal results and requires starting the entire process from scratch when improvements are […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/iterative-fine-tuning-on-amazon-bedrock-for-strategic-model-improvement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2025 Is Coming Up Soon!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey everyone! We’re excited to announce that JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf returns this November. Join us on Wednesday, November 5 for a full day of inspiring talks, live Q&amp;amp;A sessions, and deep dives into the latest in plugin development. Whether you’re just getting started or already publishing on JetBrains Marketplace, you’ll find new ideas, practical techniques, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/10/jetbrains-plugin-developer-conf-2025-is-coming-up-soon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voice AI-powered drive-thru ordering with Amazon Nova Sonic and dynamic menu displays</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 18:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll demonstrate how to implement a Quick Service Restaurants (QSRs) drive-thru solution using Amazon Nova Sonic and AWS services. We&#39;ll walk through building an intelligent system that combines voice AI with interactive menu displays, providing technical insights and implementation guidance to help restaurants modernize their drive-thru operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/voice-ai-powered-drive-thru-ordering-with-amazon-nova-sonic-and-dynamic-menu-displays/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing document AI and structured outputs by fine-tuning Amazon Nova Models and on-demand inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 18:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides a comprehensive hands-on guide to fine-tune Amazon Nova Lite for document processing tasks, with a focus on tax form data extraction. Using our open-source GitHub repository code sample, we demonstrate the complete workflow from data preparation to model deployment. Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-document-ai-and-structured-outputs-by-fine-tuning-amazon-nova-models-and-on-demand-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciting new capabilities and enhancements for M365 Developer Program - October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 15:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft 365 Developer Program has long been a great resource for developers building solutions on the Microsoft 365 platform. Today, we’re thrilled to share some exciting updates that make onboarding easier, environments more ca
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/exciting-new-capabilities-and-enhancements-for-m365-developer-program-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA&#39;s Harmonized Landsat and Sentinel-2 (HLS) Data Now Available on Microsoft&#39;s Planetary Computer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NASA’s vast archive of Earth observation data has long been a cornerstone for scientific discovery, environmental monitoring, and global sustainability efforts. Now, Microsoft has made it even easier for researchers, developers, and decision-makers to access and utilize this critical resource. Through a collaboration with NASA, the H
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/nasa-hls-on-mpc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using RAII to remedy a defect where not all code paths performed required exit actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A team asked me to review their pull request that fixed a bug that was caused by failing to perform some required action along all code paths. Here&#39;s a simplified sketch: void MySpecialFeature::OnButtonClick() { try { auto file = PickFile(); if (!file) { DismissUI(); return;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251016-00/?p=111691 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Docker Builds with Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building Docker images is an important component of the software delivery pipeline for modern applications. It’s how we package our apps and services so that they can be distributed to others and deployed to production. While the Dockerfile has long been the standard for defining container images, it is known to be challenging to make...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/debug-docker-builds-with-visual-studio-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “10x” Commandments of Highly Effective Go</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from John Arundel of Bitfield Consulting, a Go trainer and writer who runs a free newsletter for Go learners. His most recent book is The Deeper Love of Go. Ever wondered if there’s a software engineer, somewhere, who actually knows what they’re doing? Well, I finally found the one serene, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/10/16/the-10x-commandments-of-highly-effective-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Is Sunsetting CodeCanvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We started the development of CodeCanvas back in 2022, with the strong belief that cloud development environments (CDEs) would make development faster, smoother, and more efficient. With this goal in mind, we launched CodeCanvas publicly in 2024 and started accumulating users. We dove into the issues they faced in their development workflows and how we […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/10/jetbrains-is-sunsetting-codecanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a secure MCP OAuth desktop client using OAuth and Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article demonstrates how to implement a secure MCP OAuth desktop client using Microsoft Entra ID. The MCP server is built with ASP.NET Core and secured using Microsoft Entra ID. The MCP client is a .NET console application that must acquire an OAuth access token to interact with the MCP server. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/McpSecurity Setup A […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/10/16/implement-a-secure-mcp-oauth-desktop-client-using-oauth-and-entra-id/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
