<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 22:13:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Agents in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 22:13:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview We are excited to announce support for agents as part of the Semantic Kernel ecosystem: Agent Framework (Semantic Kernel GitHub Repo) An agent may be thought of as an AI entity that is focused on a performing a particular role.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/introducing-agents-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (July 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 19:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.07.12 release, 2024-07-10 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout July. This month’s release includes some minor changes to output, bug fixes, and documentation improvements.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-july-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resource Estimation Challenge at QRISE 2024: Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 18:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This spring, we partnered with Quantum Coalition to offer a challenge at QRISE 2024 - a six-week-long event aiming to get students started doing research projects in areas of interest in quantum computing industry. Meet the challenge winners and learn about their projects!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/qsharp/resource-estimation-challenge-at-qrise-2024-recap 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline insurance underwriting with generative AI using Amazon Bedrock – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 16:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Underwriting is a fundamental function within the insurance industry, serving as the foundation for risk assessment and management. Underwriters are responsible for evaluating insurance applications, determining the level of risk associated with each applicant, and making decisions on whether to accept or reject the application based on the insurer’s guidelines and risk appetite. In this […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-insurance-underwriting-with-generative-ai-using-amazon-bedrock-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import a fine-tuned Meta Llama 3 model for SQL query generation on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 15:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the process of fine-tuning Meta Llama 3 8B on SageMaker to specialize it in the generation of SQL queries (text-to-SQL). Meta Llama 3 8B is a relatively small model that offers a balance between performance and resource efficiency. AWS customers have explored fine-tuning Meta Llama 3 8B for the generation of SQL queries—especially when using non-standard SQL dialects—and have requested methods to import their customized models into Amazon Bedrock to benefit from the managed infrastructure and security that Amazon Bedrock provides when serving those models.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarity Search with FAISS and Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-driven world, finding similar items within large datasets is a common challenge. Whether it’s recommending products, identifying similar documents, or clustering data points, efficient similarity search is crucial. This blog post will explore how to leverage FAISS (Facebook AI Similarity Search) and Azure SQL to perform similarity searches on Wikipedia movie plots data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/faiss-and-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the difference between Data­Package­View.Get­Uri­Async and Data­Package­View.Get­Web­Link­Async?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just improving on an ambiguous name.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240801-00/?p=110085 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | August 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? In 1936, Russian engineer Vladimir Lukyanov built a mechanical computer known as a Water Integrator that carefully manipulated water in a room full of interconnected pipes and pumps. The water level in various chambers represented stored numbers, and the computer could solve complex mathematical equations. I’m sure the last thing Vladimir wanted […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/08/01/dotinsights-august-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2024.2 Release Candidate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next major CLion release is around the corner, and the v2024.2 RC is already available! To install CLion 2024.2 RC (build 242.20224.214), download it from our website, update via the Toolbox App, or use this snap package (for Ubuntu). You need an active subscription or a trial license to use the CLion 2024.2 RC. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/08/2024-2-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code的更新 – 2024年7月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 09:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎来到 Visual Studio Code 7月份的 Java 更新！本博客将覆盖最新的 Gradle 功能增强、用户体验改进以及新的 Spring 功能，让我们开始吧！ Gradle 功能增强 支持 Gradle 的 HCR （热代码替换） HCR（热代码替换）是 VS Code Java 调试器支持的一项高级功能。它允许您启动调试会话并更改 Java 文件而无需重启，调试器将在运行中的 JVM 中替换代码。以前，这项功能不支持 Gradle 插件中使用的 Gradle 构建服务器。在我们最近的更新中，我们已经实现了这一支持，现在您可以在调试会话中利用 HCR。这里有一个此功能的演示。 要了解有关 HCR 的更多详情，请访问此链接。 委托测试到 Gradle 在我们的最新插件发布中，我们增加了“Delegate Test to Gradle”的支持，这允许您在 VS Code Java 中执行测试中委托Gradle进行测试，确保结果与命令行工具保持一致，并利用 Gradle 工具中的优势。要使用此功能，只需在运行测试之前选择“Delegate Test to Gradle”作为默认测试配置文件。这里有一个如何使用它的演示。 在这次发布中，我们只支持“运行测试”，但我们也计划很快支持“调试测试”，所以请继续关注。下面是这个功能的演示。 要使用上述 Gradle 功能，请安装 Extension Pack for Java 和 Gradle for Java插件。 用户体验改进 在文件管理器中创建 Java 包 创建 Java 包是 Java 开发人员经常执行的任务，根据用户反馈，我们已将此操作添加到文件管理器的右键菜单中。要访问它，用户只需在文件管理器中右键单击一个文件夹，并在那里找到“Create Java Package”以及其他常见的 Java 任务。以下是参考的屏幕截图。 从状态栏访问帮助中心(Help Center) 我们为 Java 开发人员创建了一个帮助中心，这个帮助中心提供了各种有用信息和文档，方便Java开发者快速上手和学习关于VS Code Java的使用方法。以前，它有些隐藏并不容易访问。在最新发布中，我们通过在状态栏中添加了它的快捷方式，让它更方便访问。这是如何从状态栏访问帮助中心的演示。 Spring 功能更新 我们还有几个令人兴奋的新 Spring 功能。要使用以下功能，请安装 Spring Boot 插件包。 SpEL 语法高亮显示和验证 像 JPQL 语法高亮显示一样，SpEL 表达式现在在注解（如 @Value）或查询中也具有语法高亮显示和基本验证。 Spring 注解的内容辅助和查找引用支持 每个版本迭代后，使用 Java 源代码中的 Spring 注解都变得更快更容易。最新的 Spring Boot 工具增加了对以下内容的高级支持： @Profile（自动完成和查找配置文件名的引用） @Qualifier（自动完成，转到定义和查找限定符值的引用） @DependsOn（自动完成，转到定义的 bean 名称） @Resource（自动完成和转到定义的 bean 名称） @Value（自动完成和转到定义的类路径资源） 这里有内容辅助和查找引用的演示。 内容辅助 查找引用 安装 Java 插件包 要使用上述所有功能，请在 Visual Studio Code 上下载并安装Extension Pack for Java 。 如果您是一位Spring开发者，并且正在编写Spring Boot相关的程序，您也可以下载并安装Spring Boot插件包，获得与Spring Boot有关的专属开发体验 反馈与建议 2024 年，Visual Studio Code 上的 Java 会有很多激动人心的更新，一如既往，您的反馈和建议对我们非常重要，将有助于我们未来的产品塑造。有几种方法可以给我们留下反馈 填写中文问卷 在这个帖子下留言 在我们的GitHub repo上创建Issue 发送电子邮件到vscjfeedback@microsoft.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code Update – July 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 09:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the July update for Visual Studio Code for Java! This blog will cover the latest Gradle enhancements, user experience improvements and new Spring features, so let’s get started! Gradle enhancements HCR Support for Gradle Build Server HCR (Hot Code Replace) is an advanced feature that debugger supports in VS Code Java.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-visual-studio-code-update-july-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Faster with dotNetTips.com Spargine 8: August 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2024/01_08_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine 8 (v2024.8.8.1) released on August 1st, 2024, offers NuGet packages for .NET 8 and significant performance enhancements. New methods and benchmarks have been added to boost performance and reliability, informed by benchmark tests outlined in the 4th edition of Rock Your Code: Code &amp;amp; App Performance for Microsoft .NET. Community involvement for further improvements is encouraged.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/08/01/coding-faster-with-dotnettips-com-spargine-8-august-2024-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – August 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 20:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The August 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include improved Python discovery using python environment tools, inline variable values with the python debugger, and improvements to the VS Code native REPL. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-august-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Japanese LLMs with AWS Trainium: Innovators Showcase from the AWS LLM Development Support Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 19:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since its launch, the LLM Program has welcomed 15 diverse companies and organizations, each with a unique vision for how to use LLMs to drive progress in their respective industries. The program provides comprehensive support through guidance on securing high-performance compute infrastructure, technical assistance and troubleshooting for distributed training, cloud credits, and support for go-to-market. The program also facilitated collaborative knowledge-sharing sessions, where the leading LLM engineers came together to discuss the technical complexities and commercial considerations of their work.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use the ApplyGuardrail API with long-context inputs and streaming outputs in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 19:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications become more prevalent, maintaining responsible AI principles becomes essential. Without proper safeguards, large language models (LLMs) can potentially generate harmful, biased, or inappropriate content, posing risks to individuals and organizations. Applying guardrails helps mitigate these risks by enforcing policies and guidelines that align with ethical principles and legal requirements. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-the-applyguardrail-api-with-long-context-inputs-and-streaming-outputs-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing #help in F# Interactive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The &#39;#help&#39; directive in F# Interactive can now quickly access documentation instantly within the REPL.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/enhancing-help-in-fsi 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – July Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 16:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Summer’s almost gone! Don’t delay upgrading your tech skills. Our July digest has it all: a new Git starter kit, fresh courses, top projects you can work on, career tips, events, and free educational licenses. Dive in and level up!
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/31/jetbrains-academy-july-digest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming Fleet Operations with vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB Geospatial Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Efficient fleet management is essential for industries that rely on transportation, such as logistics, delivery services, and public transportation. vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB supports enabling developers to create sophisticated geo-enabled applications with ease. Organizations can streamline fleet operations, monitor vehicle locations in real-time,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/transforming-fleet-operations-with-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-geospatial-capabilities 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to compress out interior padding in a std::pair and why you don’t want to</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Context-sensitive layout means you get a different structure each time you use it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240731-00/?p=110069 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Quality: Leadership Strategies for Finding and Supporting Quality-Focused Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 13:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why is prioritizing code quality so important? Building successful software products starts with getting the right team on board, but as any technical recruiter or team lead will tell you, this is often easier said than done. One of the greatest challenges leaders face is balancing culture, competency, and potential in order to grow teams […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/07/leadership-code-quality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Terraform ‘merge’ Function</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the core strengths of Terraform is its rich set of built-in functions, which empower users to create flexible and reusable configurations. Among these functions, the Terraform merge function is particularly powerful, enabling the seamless combination of multiple maps or objects into a single, cohesive unit. This chapter delves into the nuances of the […] The article Using the Terraform ‘merge’ Function was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing a new Learn module: Create a copilot to help promote your podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Learn has always been a way to learn new skills and concepts and discover the power of Microsoft products with step-by-step guidance. Recently, there has been an increase of learn paths and modules that throw you further into the deep end allowing you to develop new skills by building an end-to-end solution or project.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/create-a-copilot-to-help-promote-your-podcast 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KotlinConf 2025 Tickets Are Now on Sale!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The countdown to KotlinConf 2025 has officially begun, and we’re excited to announce that tickets are now on sale for this premier event, which will take place from May 21–23, 2025, in Copenhagen, Denmark! Organized by JetBrains, this is the largest Kotlin event in the world. Starting today, you can secure your spot at KotlinConf […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/07/kotlinconf-2025-tickets-on-sale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Cancel an HTTP Request on Leaving a Blazor Component</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 06:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2024/31_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article explores how to cancel an HTTP request and the associated backend operation inside a Blazor component. After a brief introduction to the architecture for canceling backend operations, we will familiarize ourselves with cancellation tokens and how to utilize them to cancel an operation when the user navigates away. Let’s start. Setup a Blazor […] The post How to Cancel an HTTP Request on Leaving a Blazor Component appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critter Stack Roadmap for the Rest of 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 20:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a little bit since I’ve written any kind of update on the unofficial “Critter Stack” roadmap, with the last update in February. A ton of new, important strategic features have been added to especially Marten since then, with plenty of expansion of Wolverine to boot. Before jumping into what’s to come, let me … Continue reading Critter Stack Roadmap for the Rest of 2024 →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s coming next? Summer / Fall roadmap for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 19:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It feels like yesterday when we went live with v1.0+ of all our SDKs (Python, Java, and C#) at Microsoft Build. Since then, the Semantic Kernel team has been hard at work making Semantic Kernel even better. Now that we’ve made some progress,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/whats-coming-next-summer-fall-roadmap-for-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Amazon Q Business with AWS IAM Identity Center trusted identity propagation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 18:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business comes with rich API support to perform administrative tasks or to build an AI-assistant with customized user experience for your enterprise. With administrative APIs you can automate creating Q Business applications, set up data source connectors, build custom document enrichment, and configure guardrails. With conversation APIs, you can chat and manage conversations with Q Business AI assistant. Trusted identity propagation provides authorization based on user context, which enhances the privacy controls of Amazon Q Business.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Platform Gradle Plugin 2.0 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 17:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Version 2.0 of the IntelliJ Platform Gradle Plugin is now available! Previously called the Gradle IntelliJ Plugin, this updated plugin for the Gradle build system simplifies the configuration of environments for building, testing, verifying, and publishing plugins for IntelliJ-based IDEs. Redesigned and rewritten, it addresses community-reported issues and feature requests from previous versions. The path […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/07/intellij-platform-gradle-plugin-2-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance your media search experience using Amazon Q Business and Amazon Transcribe</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 17:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s digital landscape, the demand for audio and video content is skyrocketing. Organizations are increasingly using media to engage with their audiences in innovative ways. From product documentation in video format to podcasts replacing traditional blog posts, content creators are exploring diverse channels to reach a wider audience. The rise of virtual workplaces has […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-your-media-search-experience-using-amazon-q-business-and-amazon-transcribe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monks boosts processing speed by four times for real-time diffusion AI image generation using Amazon SageMaker and AWS Inferentia2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 17:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Benjamin Moody from Monks. Monks is the global, purely digital, unitary operating brand of S4Capital plc. With a legacy of innovation and specialized expertise, Monks combines an extraordinary range of global marketing and technology services to accelerate business possibilities and redefine how brands and businesses interact with the world. Its […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/monks-boosts-processing-speed-by-four-times-for-real-time-diffusion-ai-image-generation-using-amazon-sagemaker-and-aws-inferentia2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement web crawling in Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 15:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading artificial intelligence (AI) companies like AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Stability AI, and Amazon through a single API, along with a broad set of capabilities to build generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. With […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-web-crawling-in-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Teachers, Involved Students: Active Learning with the Capture the Flag Game</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 14:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, August 13, at 3:00 pm UTC for the livestream in the JetBrains Academy series for educators, Lazy Teachers, Involved Students: Active Learning with the Capture the Flag Game The relevance of traditional education and the necessity of an academic degree have long been debated in the tech industry. The rapid pace […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/07/30/lazy-teachers-involved-students-active-learning-with-the-capture-the-flag-game/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is no mystery over who wrote the Blue Screen of Death, despite what some may want you to believe</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            No real contradictions in anybody&#39;s story.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240730-00/?p=110062 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Scout Health Scores: Security Grading for Container Images in Your Docker Hub Repo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Docker team introduces Docker Scout health scores to help quickly evaluate image health and simplify software security for developers.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-scout-health-scores-security-grading-for-container-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intuit uses Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude to explain taxes in TurboTax to millions of consumer tax filers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Intuit is committed to providing its customers innovative solutions that simplify complex financial processes. Tax filing can be a challenge, with its ever-changing regulations and intricate nuances. That’s why the company empowers millions of individuals and small businesses to comprehend tax-related information effortlessly and file with full confidence that their taxes are done right. For the […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/intuit-uses-amazon-bedrock-and-anthropic-claude-to-explain-taxes-in-turbotax-to-millions-of-consumer-tax-filers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2024.2 Release Candidate is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 12:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2024.2 Release Candidate is available now! You can get this build via the Toolbox App or download it from our website. You can also download the build from inside GoLand by going to Settings | Appearance &amp;amp; Behavior | System Settings | Updates and selecting Check IDE updates for: Early Access Program. Download GoLand […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/07/30/goland-2024-2-release-candidate-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating source-only NuGet packages</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how you can create a NuGet package that contains source code (instead of dlls) which is then compiled into the target project
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-source-only-nuget-packages/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for Azure.AI.OpenAI and OpenAI v2 is coming</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft announced the official OpenAI library for .NET at the Build 2024 conference. This new SDK ensures that .NET developers have parity with other programming language libraries when accessing Azure OpenAI models. This means the new SDK will be able to support the latest OpenAI features and models as soon as they come out,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/support-for-azure-ai-openai-and-openai-v2-is-coming 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Calisthenics #1: Elevating Code Quality with 9 Powerful Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Object Calisthenics can revolutionize your coding practices. Learn 9 essential rules to elevate your software craftsmanship and produce cleaner, more maintainable code.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/object-calisthenics-9-rules-clean-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davide&#39;s Code and Architecture Notes - Web APIs vs REST APIs vs pseudo-REST APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2024/30_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When describing a web service, people often use the wrong terms. Are you really creating a REST API, or is it some sort of pseudo-REST?
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/architecture-notes/webapi-vs-rest-vs-pseudo-rest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Marten Faster Through Table Partitioning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 21:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s been a definite theme lately about increasing the performance and scalability of Marten, as evident (I hope) in my post last week describing new optimization options in Marten 7.25. Today I was able to push a follow up feature that got missed in that release that allows Marten users to utilize PostgreSQL table partitioning … Continue reading Making Marten Faster Through Table Partitioning →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/07/29/making-marten-faster-through-table-partitioning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI–powered Salesforce applications with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 21:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how native integrations between Salesforce and Amazon Web Services (AWS) enable you to Bring Your Own Large Language Models (BYO LLMs) from your AWS account to power generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications in Salesforce. Requests and responses between Salesforce and Amazon Bedrock pass through the Einstein Trust Layer, which promotes responsible AI use across Salesforce.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-powered-salesforce-applications-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transition your Amazon Forecast usage to Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 19:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Forecast is a fully managed service that uses statistical and machine learning (ML) algorithms to deliver highly accurate time series forecasts. Launched in August 2019, Forecast predates Amazon SageMaker Canvas, a popular low-code no-code AWS tool for building, customizing, and deploying ML models, including time series forecasting models. With SageMaker Canvas, you get faster […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transition-your-amazon-forecast-usage-to-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Functions Best Practices for Performance, Reliability and Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 19:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building Microservice and Serverless architectures demand different design patterns to be used that other traditional application architectures. Even the older SOA (Service Oriented Architecture) design has different demands than the newer Microservices and Serverless solutions do today. Due to these differences, there are different things to keep in mind when building Microservice and Serverless architectures […] The article Azure Functions Best Practices for Performance, Reliability and Security was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (July 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 19:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure SDKs release every month. This post includes the month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-july-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSVC Backend Updates in Visual Studio 2022 version 17.10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 19:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 17.10 brings new optimizations, intrinsics, features, and improvements to the MSVC backend. Check out the highlights below: Performance improvements and additional functionality for all architectures: Improved SLP vectorizer. Now it runs on more functions, recognizes more operations, and may choose to use larger vector widths if allowed by the appropriate /arch flag.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/msvc-backend-updates-in-visual-studio-2022-version-17-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Release Candidate Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 18:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 Release Candidate is now available for download! You can get the latest build from our website, through the free Toolbox App, or via snaps for Ubuntu. To use this build, you need an active IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate subscription. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 RC With the major release just around the corner, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/intellij-idea-2024-2-rc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect Amazon Q Business to Microsoft SharePoint Online using least privilege access controls</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 17:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is the generative artificial intelligence (AI) assistant that empowers employees with your company’s knowledge and data. Microsoft SharePoint Online is used by many organizations as a secure place to store, organize, share, and access their internal data. With generative AI, employees can get answers to their questions, summarize content, or generate insights […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/connect-amazon-q-business-to-microsoft-sharepoint-online-using-least-privilege-access-controls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve the productivity of your customer support and project management teams using Amazon Q Business and Atlassian Jira</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 17:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Effective customer support and project management are critical aspects of providing effective customer relationship management. Atlassian Jira, a platform for issue tracking and project management functions for software projects, has become an indispensable part of many organizations’ workflows to ensure success of the customer and the product. However, extracting valuable insights from the vast amount […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-the-productivity-of-your-customer-support-and-project-management-teams-using-amazon-q-business-and-atlassian-jira/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Hybrid Support in the Azure Quantum Development Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 17:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some quantum computers can do more than execute a static sequence of gates. The most advanced ones can perform mid-circuit measurements, conditionally execute gates, perform real-time classical computations and re-use qubits. If you want to experiment with these state-of-the-art capabilities, we have good news for you.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/qsharp/integrated-hybrid-support-in-the-azure-quantum-development-kit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily Create Bindings for .NET MAUI with Native Library Interop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to get started creating bindings with Native Library Interop by following this example binding native Chart libraries in a .NET MAUI application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/native-library-interop-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign VSIX packages with Sign CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 15:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now leverage Sign CLI for a more secure, modern way to sign your Visual Studio extensions. Signing your VSIX packages improves security, prevents tampering, and builds trust with your users. This integration makes it easier and more convenient to sign your packages than ever before!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/sign-vsix-packages-with-sign-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.33: GA Releases of Docker Debug and Docker Build Checks Plus Enhanced Configuration Integrity Checks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.33 is packed with powerful new features designed to elevate your container development experience. Docker Desktop 4.33 includes GA releases of Docker Debug and Docker Build checks, and significant UX improvements to the Configuration integrity check.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-33/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Docker Build Checks: Optimize Dockerfiles with Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out how the newly released Docker Build checks help your team learn and follow best practices for building container images.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-docker-build-checks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Dockerfiles with GenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We explore how to use an AI assistant to generate Dockerfiles for specific projects.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-create-dockerfiles-with-genai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why don’t Windows Imaging Component pixel format GUIDs continue their nice pattern?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Patterns are predictable, which is not always a good thing.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240729-00/?p=110054 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Entra External ID: Secure, scalable external identity management for your apps and resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 11:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unlock the potential of secure and efficient identity management with Microsoft Entra External ID. Focusing on two key scenarios, we show how External ID simplifies the process of managing external identities, including business partners, consumers, and customers. Dive in to discover how you can streamline identity management with straightforward, customizable solutions that cater to diverse end-user segments.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-identity-solutions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Resources for pytest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 08:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we’ll look at how PyCharm helps you when you’re working with pytest, and we will signpost you to a bunch of resources for learning pytest. While some of these resources were created by us here at JetBrains, others were crafted by the storytellers in the pytest community. Using pytest in PyCharm […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/07/learning-resources-for-pytest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Template Method Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 05:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2024/29_07_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will talk about a behavioral design pattern, the Template Method Pattern. We are going to see how this pattern helps deal with certain design problems and how to implement it in C#. If you want to read more about design patterns in C#, you can inspect our C# Design Patterns page. Let’s start. […] The post Template Method Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Performance with Copilot Slash Commands: Unleashing New Speed in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2024/28_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2024/28_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the article &amp;quot;Unleashing the Power of Copilot: Enhancing Visual Studio with New Slash Commands,&amp;quot; the author discusses utilizing Copilot to improve the performance of the open-source project Spargine. Detailed examples show how Copilot&#39;s recommendations resulted in significant speed improvements and the author&#39;s workflow for implementing changes. The article encourages developers to use Copilot for code enhancement.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/07/28/boosting-performance-with-copilot-slash-commands-unleashing-new-speed-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Architectures in DotNet – Dev Leader Weekly 54</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2024/27_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2024/27_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Plugin Architectures in DotNet – Dev Leader Weekly 54 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I plugin architecture in DotNet based on a presentation I did in Dallas! The post Plugin Architectures in DotNet – Dev Leader Weekly 54 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/07/27/plugin-architectures-in-dotnet-dev-leader-weekly-54/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Messaging in .NET With Redis Pub/Sub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2024/27_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_07_2024/27_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Redis is a popular choice for caching data, but its capabilities go far beyond that. One of its lesser-known features is Pub/Sub support. Redis channels offer an interesting approach for implementing real-time messaging in your .NET applications.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/simple-messaging-in-dotnet-with-redis-pubsub 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.6 Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the availability of TypeScript 5.6 Beta. To get started using the beta, you can get it through NuGet, or through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@beta Here’s a quick list of what’s new in TypeScript 5.6!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-6-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can I do if IMlangConvertCharset is unable to convert from code page 28591 directly to UTF-8?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can do the conversion in two steps using things you already have.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240726-00/?p=110048 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Java Still Relevant Nowadays?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 13:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the biggest challenges for technologies nowadays is keeping up to date with the latest developments, remaining relevant to the demands of modern business, and continuing to provide added value for users. The world is changing faster than ever before, and the pace of this change shows no signs of slowing. As a major […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/is-java-still-relevant-nowadays/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make it Happen – With Easter Eggs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 12:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever since the dawn of humanity, we’ve had a fascination with discovery. For Neanderthals, it was fire, for people of the Renaissance it was electricity, and now it’s funny cat gifs and Easter eggs hidden deep within videos. Despite clocking in at just 1 minute and 18 seconds, the “Make it happen. With code. | […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/07/26/make-it-happen-with-easter-eggs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Microsoft Edge? Try Grazie!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 09:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to share that Grazie, our AI writing companion for people in tech, is now available for Microsoft Edge users. This is one more step towards streamlining your non-coding tasks wherever you work. How to get started: Grazie is currently available as a plugin for JetBrains IDEs and as an extension for Microsoft […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2024/07/use-microsoft-edge-try-grazie/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LLM Prompt Injection Considerations With Tool Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses a pattern to prevent a class of prompt injection attacks in LLM-based solutions. It emphasizes the importance of building strong foundational patterns to mitigate risks and avoid potential pitfalls. By implementing this pattern, teams can enhance the security of their tool-based solutions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/llm-prompt-injection-considerations-for-tool-use 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The LINQ Where Method in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 05:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll focus on the use cases of the LINQ Where Method in C#. The LINQ Where Method offers a powerful tool that can manipulate data from various sources ranging from collections of objects in memory to relational database tables and XML files according to a specific criterion. It offers a simple, intuitive […] The post The LINQ Where Method in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Azure Tooling的更新 – 2024年6月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 02:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎阅读 Java on Azure 开发者工具6月份更新。在本次更新中，我们将介绍在 IntelliJ IDEA 中 Azure Toolkit 对 Azure Container Apps 提供的工作负载配置文件支持。我们希望您喜欢这些更新，并享受使用 Azure 工具包的流畅体验。请下载并安装 IntelliJ 的 Azure 工具包。让我们开始吧！ Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ 提升 对 Azure Container Apps 支持工作负荷配置文件 在 5 月份的更新中，我们宣布针对 IntelliJ IDEA 的 Azure 工具包已为具有灵活部署选项的 Azure 容器应用程序提供了支持。 在最新版本中，我们通过工作负载配置文件环境支持进一步增强了这种体验。工作负载配置文件决定了部署在环境中的容器应用程序可用的计算和内存资源量。通过这一增强功能，您可以在 IntelliJ IDEA 中轻松调整工作负载配置文件的最小和最大实例数。此外，您还可以灵活配置每个应用程序，使其运行在容器应用程序环境中最合适的工作负载配置文件上。下面是一个简短的演示。 反馈与建议 如果您感兴趣，请不要犹豫并尝试使用我们的产品吧!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-azure-tooling-update-june-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Azure Tooling Update – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 02:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_07_2024/26_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the June update of Java on Azure developer tools. In this update, we will introduce our Workload Profiles Support for Azure Container Apps in Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ IDEA. We hope you enjoy these updates and have a smooth experience with our Azure toolkit.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-azure-tooling-update-june-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker inference launches faster auto scaling for generative AI models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 21:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce a new capability in Amazon SageMaker inference that can help you reduce the time it takes for your generative artificial intelligence (AI) models to scale automatically. You can now use sub-minute metrics and significantly reduce overall scaling latency for generative AI models. With this enhancement, you can improve the […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-inference-launches-faster-auto-scaling-for-generative-ai-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Stimulus in your Rails apps with RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! The RubyMine team is constantly striving to provide support for new technologies for Ruby and Rails. One of the most exciting recent additions to Rails is undoubtedly Hotwire, so we’ve prepared an overview of this suite of frameworks and a tutorial on how to use the most important Turbo and Stimulus features in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/07/how-to-use-stimulus-in-your-rails-apps-with-rubymine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Azure Boards &#43; GitHub Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 19:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been a few months since our last update on the initiative to enhance the integration between Azure Boards and GitHub. We’re excited to share that many new features have been completed and are in the process of being rolled out.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/update-on-azure-boards-github-integration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find answers accurately and quickly using Amazon Q Business with the SharePoint Online connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 17:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a fully managed, generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered assistant that helps enterprises unlock the value of their data and knowledge. With Amazon Q, you can quickly find answers to questions, generate summaries and content, and complete tasks by using the information and expertise stored across your company’s various data sources and enterprise […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/find-answers-accurately-and-quickly-using-amazon-q-business-with-the-sharepoint-online-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate conversational AI agents with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 17:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As conversational artificial intelligence (AI) agents gain traction across industries, providing reliability and consistency is crucial for delivering seamless and trustworthy user experiences. However, the dynamic and conversational nature of these interactions makes traditional testing and evaluation methods challenging. Conversational AI agents also encompass multiple layers, from Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to function-calling mechanisms that […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-conversational-ai-agents-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node problem detection and recovery for AWS Neuron nodes within Amazon EKS clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 17:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the post, we introduce the AWS Neuron node problem detector and recovery DaemonSet for AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS). This component can quickly detect rare occurrences of issues when Neuron devices fail by tailing monitoring logs. It marks the worker nodes in a defective Neuron device as unhealthy, and promptly replaces them with new worker nodes. By accelerating the speed of issue detection and remediation, it increases the reliability of your ML training and reduces the wasted time and cost due to hardware failure.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Semantic Kernel for Java 1.2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 15:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello Java AI developers! We are announcing the release of Semantic Kernel for Java v1.2.0! Since our release of v1.0 this past May, we have been working to improve and expand the capabilities we provide. Today, we are thrilled to share the latest updates,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-semantic-kernel-for-java-1-2-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring your custom engine copilot from Azure OpenAI Studio to Microsoft Teams: now in public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 15:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure OpenAI now offers a Deploy to a Teams app option in public preview, providing a new way to connect enterprise data with custom engine copilots in Microsoft Teams.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/bring-your-custom-engine-copilot-from-azure-openai-studio-to-microsoft-teams-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In my Visual Studio project, I set my Conformance mode to permissive, but it’s still not permissive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Digging into what the compiler sees.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240725-00/?p=110045 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Ways CARIAD Configures Docker Business for Security and Compliance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 13:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out how CARIAD, an automotive software and technology company, configures Docker for security and compliance using Docker Single Sign-On, Image Access Management, and Windows Subsystem for Linux 2.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/3-ways-cariad-configures-docker-business-for-security-and-compliance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.38 Is Here With Support for Virtual Environments Created by Anaconda, Auto-Refresh for Log Files, Improved Proxy Setting Detection, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 12:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fleet 1.38 is now available! Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using the Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.38 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/07/fleet-1-38-is-here-with-support-for-virtual-environments-created-by-anaconda-auto-refresh-for-log-files-improved-proxy-setting-detection-and-much-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Numbers to Clarity: Using Math to Simplify Data-Heavy Product Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 09:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2024/25_07_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s world, data platforms are crucial for any organization. These platforms make data storage assets available and provide the necessary tools to work with data effectively. In this blog post, we’ll explore the inner workings of JetBrains’ data kitchen and the role that documentation plays in it. What is the Product Analytics Platform at […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/07/from-numbers-to-clarity-using-math-to-simplify-data-heavy-product-documentation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
