<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:27:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhance speech synthesis and video generation models with RLHF using audio and video segmentation in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to implement an audio and video segmentation solution using SageMaker Ground Truth. We guide you through deploying the necessary infrastructure using AWS CloudFormation, creating an internal labeling workforce, and setting up your first labeling job. By the end of this post, you will have a fully functional audio/video segmentation workflow that you can adapt for various use cases, from training speech synthesis models to improving video generation capabilities.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using responsible AI principles with Amazon Bedrock Batch Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a practical, cost-effective approach for incorporating responsible AI guardrails into Amazon Bedrock Batch Inference workflows. Although we use a call center’s transcript summarization as our primary example, the methods we discuss are broadly applicable to a variety of batch inference use cases where ethical considerations and data protection are a top priority.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-responsible-ai-principles-with-amazon-bedrock-batch-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing knowledge management: VW’s AI prototype journey with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            we’re excited to share the journey of the VW—an innovator in the automotive industry and Europe’s largest car maker—to enhance knowledge management by using generative AI, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Kendra to devise a solution based on Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) that makes internal information more easily accessible by its users. This solution efficiently handles documents that include both text and images, significantly enhancing VW&#39;s knowledge management capabilities within their production domain.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune large language models with Amazon SageMaker Autopilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fine-tuning foundation models (FMs) is a process that involves exposing a pre-trained FM to task-specific data and fine-tuning its parameters. It can then develop a deeper understanding and produce more accurate and relevant outputs for that particular domain. In this post, we show how to use an Amazon SageMaker Autopilot training job with the AutoMLV2 […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-large-language-models-with-amazon-sagemaker-autopilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect which menu my item was invoked from?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just give them all different IDs. But this might itself by an XY problem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241121-00/?p=110554 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are the Latest Docker Desktop Enterprise-Grade Performance Optimizations?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the latest enterprise-grade performance optimizations in Docker Desktop, including Docker VMM for Apple Silicon, synchronized file sharing, and expanded support for RHEL and Windows Arm, all designed to deliver faster, more reliable development workflows.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/what-are-the-latest-docker-desktop-enterprise-grade-performance-optimizations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making you more productive with Visual Studio v17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 12th update to Visual Studio 2022 is packed with lots of exciting new features that users have been asking for! Here are some of the awesome highlights from this release that are some of my personal favorites. For all the details, be sure to check out our release notes. Copy from the Error List […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/making-you-more-productive-with-visual-studio-v17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never rewrite code?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Is it a bad idea to rewrite code or an entire system? At some point, developers want to rewrite for various reasons. Often, it’s because we simply don’t understand the existing codebase or think it’s a tire fire. But is the benefit there? Sometimes, yes. Sometimes, no. It’s a pretty nuanced topic around cost/benefit. YouTube… Read More »Never rewrite code? The post Never rewrite code? appeared first on CodeOpinion.
Link to article: https://codeopinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the enhanced MSSQL Extension for Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL extension for Visual Studio Code is designed to support developers in building applications that use Azure SQL (including Azure SQL Database, Azure SQL Managed Instance, and SQL Server on Azure VMs), SQL Database in Fabric (Preview) or SQL Server as backend databases. With a comprehensive suite of features for connecting to databases, designing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/mssql-extension-visual-studio-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Microsoft AI Shell Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 17:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            During Microsoft Ignite 2024, Microsoft announced the public preview of AI Shell, a groundbreaking innovation that integrates artificial intelligence directly into command-line workflows. With this release, Microsoft aims to bridge the gap between traditional shell interactions and the growing capabilities of AI, enabling developers and IT professionals to work smarter and faster. What is Microsoft […] The article New Microsoft AI Shell Public Preview was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unify structured data in Amazon Aurora and unstructured data in Amazon S3 for insights using Amazon Q</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-intensive business landscape, organizations face the challenge of extracting valuable insights from diverse data sources scattered across their infrastructure. Whether it’s structured data in databases or unstructured content in document repositories, enterprises often struggle to efficiently query and use this wealth of information. In this post, we explore how you can use Amazon […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unify-structured-data-in-amazon-aurora-and-unstructured-data-in-amazon-s3-for-insights-using-amazon-q/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Q&amp;A email responses with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate automating the responses to email inquiries by using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon Simple Email Service (Amazon SES), both fully managed services. By linking user queries to relevant company domain information, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases offers personalized responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-qa-email-responses-with-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline RAG applications with intelligent metadata filtering using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore an innovative approach that uses LLMs on Amazon Bedrock to intelligently extract metadata filters from natural language queries. By combining the capabilities of LLM function calling and Pydantic data models, you can dynamically extract metadata from user queries. This approach can also enhance the quality of retrieved information and responses generated by the RAG applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-rag-applications-with-intelligent-metadata-filtering-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotnet scaffold – Next Generation Project Creation for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing a new command line tool dotnet scaffold, a new interactive way to create projects in .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-dotnet-scaffold 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding secure generative AI in mission-critical public safety applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how Mark43 uses Amazon Q Business to create a secure, generative AI-powered assistant that drives operational efficiency and improves community service. We explain how they embedded Amazon Q Business web experience in their web application with low code, so they could focus on creating a rich AI experience for their customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/embedding-secure-generative-ai-in-mission-critical-public-safety-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How FP8 boosts LLM training by 18% on Amazon SageMaker P5 instances</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LLM training has seen remarkable advances in recent years, with organizations pushing the boundaries of what’s possible in terms of model size, performance, and efficiency. In this post, we explore how FP8 optimization can significantly speed up large model training on Amazon SageMaker P5 instances.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-fp8-boosts-llm-training-by-18-on-amazon-sagemaker-p5-instances/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the new Linux-based Azure Cosmos DB Emulator (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the preview release of the new Linux-based Azure Cosmos DB Emulator! This latest version is built to provide faster startup times and broader platform compatibility, addressing one of the most requested features in the Azure Cosmos DB User Voice community. The emulator can now seamlessly run on Apple silicon and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-the-new-linux-based-azure-cosmos-db-emulator-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I determine whether Explorer is showing or hiding file extensions?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can ask, but maybe you&#39;re asking the wrong question.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241120-00/?p=110547 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy files across instances of Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transferring code files between different instances of Visual Studio has often been a tedious task. To simplify this process, Visual Studio 2022 now includes a feature that allows you to easily copy and paste code files and folders between instances using the Solution Explorer. This enhancement aims to streamline workflow and save time. Until now, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/copy-files-across-instances-of-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion Nova Improvements, Debug Servers, OpenCV Image Viewer, and Zephyr West Debugging in CLion 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 11:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CLion 2024.3 is now available. This latest version of the JetBrains IDE for C and C++ includes the following key features and updates: You can download CLion 2024.3 from the link below, via the Toolbox App, as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu, or via a patch update from version 2024.2. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/11/2024-3-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Go Apps with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 11:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We live in a world where things change at a rapid pace, and the latest and greatest quickly becomes outdated. The same goes for deploying applications to servers. You used to have to physically travel to a data center to deploy your changes. Later on, we moved to VMs. Then containers came along and changed […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/11/20/deploying-go-apps-with-kubernetes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally! Improved Blazor Server reconnection UX</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Caution! If you’ve built web apps with Blazor Server the following may cause distress! 😅 Attempting to reconnect to the server… Reconnection failed. Try reloading the page if you’re unable to reconnect. These are the standard Blazor error messages your users have likely complained about as they interact with your Blazor application. These errors occur because of the connected nature of Blazor server apps. A circuit runs on the server (for a given user interaction), and a SignalR (websocket) connection is maintained between the user’s browser and said circuit.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Shines at Microsoft Ignite 2024!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Ignite 2024 took over the Windy City this week, bringing with it new technological innovation and exciting product announcements aplenty! If you missed the first day of the show, don’t worry – we’ve got you covered with all the latest and greatest Azure Cosmos DB news. This year’s event saw great enthusiasm and attendance […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-shines-at-microsoft-ignite-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racing into the future: How AWS DeepRacer fueled my AI and ML journey</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 2018, I sat in the audience at AWS re:Invent as Andy Jassy announced AWS DeepRacer—a fully autonomous 1/18th scale race car driven by reinforcement learning. At the time, I knew little about AI or machine learning (ML). As an engineer transitioning from legacy networks to cloud technologies, I had never considered myself a developer. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/racing-into-the-future-how-aws-deepracer-fueled-my-ai-and-ml-journey/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Public Preview of AI Shell</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce the public preview of AI Shell.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/announcing-the-public-preview-of-ai-shell 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your guide to generative AI and ML at AWS re:Invent 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this attendee guide, we’re highlighting a few of our favorite sessions to give you a glimpse into what’s in store. To help you plan your agenda for this year’s re:Invent, here are some highlights of the generative AI and ML sessions. Visit the session catalog to learn about all our generative AI and ML sessions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/your-guide-to-generative-ai-and-ml-at-aws-reinvent-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new for Office Add-ins at Ignite 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Office Platform team has been busy working on improvements to the platform since we last reported. This blog covers the new features from the office-js team announced at Ignite 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/whats-new-for-office-add-ins-at-ignite-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize small language models on AWS with automotive terminology</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we guide you through the phases of customizing SLMs on AWS, with a specific focus on automotive terminology for diagnostics as a Q&amp;amp;A task. We begin with the data analysis phase and progress through the end-to-end process, covering fine-tuning, deployment, and evaluation. We compare a customized SLM with a general purpose LLM, using various metrics to assess vocabulary richness and overall accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/customize-small-language-models-on-aws-with-automotive-terminology/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate emails for task management using Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, and Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to create an automated email response solution using Amazon Bedrock and its features, including Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, and Amazon Bedrock Guardrails.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-emails-for-task-management-using-amazon-bedrock-agents-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-and-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate analysis and discovery of cancer biomarkers with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bedrock agents can streamline workflows and provide AI automation to boost productivity. In this post, we show you how agentic workflows with Amazon Bedrock Agents can help accelerate this journey for research scientists with a natural language interface. We define an example analysis pipeline, specifically for lung cancer survival with clinical, genomics, and imaging modalities of biomarkers. We showcase a variety of tools including database retrieval with Text2SQL, statistical models and visual charts with scientific libraries, biomedical literature search with public APIs and internal evidence, and medical image processing with Amazon SageMaker jobs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate building guardrails for Amazon Bedrock using test-driven development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Guardrails helps implement safeguards for generative AI applications based on specific use cases and responsible AI policies. Amazon Bedrock Guardrails assists in controlling the interaction between users and foundation models (FMs) by detecting and filtering out undesirable and potentially harmful content, while maintaining safety and privacy. In this post, we explore a solution that automates building guardrails using a test-driven development approach.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-building-guardrails-for-amazon-bedrock-using-test-driven-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the new Azure AI Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure AI Agent Service is designed to revolutionize the development and deployment of these AI agents, delivering an enterprise-ready solution tailored to meet the unique needs of modern organizations. Organizations are constantly seeking innovative ways to enhance operational efficiency and streamline workflows. Artificial Intelligence (AI) has emerged as a cornerstone of this transformation, with autonomous […] The article Introducing the new Azure AI Agent Service was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Windows 365 Link: The First Cloud PC Device for Windows 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has unveiled its first-ever Cloud PC device, the Windows 365 Link, a purpose-built tool designed to enhance the user experience for organizations leveraging Windows 365 Cloud PCs. This compact, fanless device is packed with features aimed at boosting productivity, ensuring security, and simplifying IT management. Here’s a breakdown of everything you need to know […] The article Introducing Windows 365 Link: The First Cloud PC Device for Windows 365 was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Kotlin Scripting 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: Kotlin scripting remains an essential part of the Kotlin infrastructure. We continue to support it in the experimental state, and we are concluding certain experiments and reducing the number of scripting-related technologies that we provide and actively develop. Kotlin scripting is the technology that enables executing Kotlin code as scripts without prior compilation or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/11/state-of-kotlin-scripting-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing LangChain integration for your SQL-based AI applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-driven world, the ability to seamlessly integrate various technologies is crucial for efficient data management and analysis. We’re excited to announce LangChain integration with Azure SQL Database and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric! LangChain, a powerful tool for building solutions with language models, can be effectively combined with these services to build AI-ready […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/langchain-with-sqlvectorstore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LangChain Integration for Vector Support for SQL-based AI applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LangChain Integration for Vector Support for Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric Microsoft SQL now supports native vector search capabilities in Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. We also released the langchain-sqlserver package, enabling the management of SQL Server as a Vectorstore in LangChain. In this step-by-step tutorial, we will show […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/langchain-with-sqlvectorstore-example 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VisualStudio.Extensibility 17.12: CodeLens support is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We continue to invest in the VisualStudio.Extensibility SDK to allow users like you to create extensions that run faster and smoother than ever before! VisualStudio.Extensibility helps you build extensions that run outside the main Visual Studio IDE process for improved performance and reliability, and can be installed without the need to restart Visual Studio. Additional […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visualstudio-extensibility-17-12-codelens-support-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Faster with JetBrains AI in PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PyCharm 2024.3 comes with many improvements to JetBrains AI to help you code faster. I’m going to walk you through some of these updates in this blog post. Natural language inline AI prompt You can now use JetBrains AI by typing straight into your editor in natural language without opening the AI Assistant tool window. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/11/code-faster-with-jetbrains-ai-in-pycharm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Microsoft 365 Agents SDK with Semantic Kernel for Enhanced Multichannel AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the landscape of AI continues to evolve, meeting users where they are is vital. We want to spotlight the newly released Microsoft 365 Agents SDK and its seamless integration with Semantic Kernel. This powerful combination empowers developers to create robust AI agents that operate across various channels where users are already engaged. Extend the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/leveraging-microsoft-365-agents-sdk-with-semantic-kernel-for-enhanced-multichannel-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Module Layout for sbt Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Try out the enhanced sbt integration with IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2024.3 We’re introducing a new mode that better represents the structure of sbt projects in IntelliJ IDEA by organizing main and test sources into separate modules. The improved layout resolves several issues with compilation and highlighting. It also allows using different compiler options for main […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2024/11/19/new-module-layout-for-sbt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A wrinkle in how Windows 95 setup bootstrapped its initial GUI step</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Getting access to the common controls that don&#39;t exist until Windows 95.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241119-00/?p=110543 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a new landing page and welcome tour for Microsoft developer portal!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft, we are dedicated to shaping a developer experience that is efficient, user-friendly, and tailored to your needs. With the new landing page and welcome tour, we’re excited to empower you to work more effectively and unlock new levels of productivity. Together, we’re building a platform that evolves with you. At Microsoft, we’re focused […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/introducing-a-new-landing-page-and-welcome-tour-for-microsoft-dev-box 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI apps faster and easier with SQL database in Fabric – now Public Preview!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The SQL Server and Azure SQL team has embarked on a mission to make building AI apps faster and easier than ever, announcing the Public Preview of SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. This new simple, autonomous and secure, and optimized for AI service will help you in the era of AI, where 1 billion new […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-ai-apps-faster-and-easier-with-sql-database-in-fabric-now-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2024.3 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 13:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The first EAP build of MPS 2024.3 is now ready for you to download and try! DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 EAP The new version includes numerous fixes and improvements. Here are the two major ones that deserve special attention: Icon handling Icons and images that use a path relative to the module are no longer copied […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2024/11/the-mps-2024-1-eap-has-started-2-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Code to Clarity With the Redesigned Structure Tool Window</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 13:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers usually spend more time reading existing code than writing new code. To understand the existing codebase of an application, developers spend a good amount of time looking at how various frameworks and libraries are configured and how different components interact with each other. While developing JetBrains AI Assistant, we enriched prompts with context extracted […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/from-code-to-clarity-with-the-redesigned-structure-tool-window/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Making .NET Configurations Easier and Safer with Spargine’s Config Class</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_24/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source set of assemblies and NuGet packages for .NET 8, developed for effective configuration management. The Config class simplifies local settings storage with customizable classes and XML serialization. It enhances application reliability.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/19/boost-your-net-projects-making-net-configurations-easier-and-safer-with-spargines-config-class/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Origin-Opener-Policy: preventing attacks from popups: Understanding cross-origin security headers - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe the vulnerabilities in window.opener and window.open() and how to protect yourself with Cross-Origin-Opener-Policy
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/understanding-security-headers-part-1-cross-origin-opener-policy-preventing-attacks-from-popups/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule Background Job using Quartz.NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 07:50:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_25/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You may have encountered a situation where you must do some backend job without user intervention. For example, in an IOT application, your application needs to receive frequently published data from devices or send scheduler values to devices. .NET provides background job libraries for such tasks. I will discuss one
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/schedule-background-job-using-quartz-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy logging management with Seq and ILogger in ASP.NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_26/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Seq is one of the best Log Sinks out there : it’s easy to install and configure, and can be added to an ASP.NET application with just a line of code.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/logging-with-ilogger-and-seq/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q3 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ⭐️ Community highlights JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2024: Kicking off our first event On November 7, we hosted the first-ever JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf, a virtual event dedicated entirely to plugin development for JetBrains products. The conference brought together JetBrains experts and plugin developers to explore a wide range of topics, including developing and launching […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/11/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q3-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build cost-effective RAG applications with Binary Embeddings in Amazon Titan Text Embeddings V2, Amazon OpenSearch Serverless, and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are happy to announce the availability of Binary Embeddings for Amazon Titan Text Embeddings V2 in Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless. This post summarizes the benefits of this new binary vector support and gives you information on how you can get started.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-cost-effective-rag-applications-with-binary-embeddings-in-amazon-titan-text-embeddings-v2-amazon-opensearch-serverless-and-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate cloud security vulnerability assessment and alerting using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates a proactive approach for security vulnerability assessment of your accounts and workloads, using Amazon GuardDuty, Amazon Bedrock, and other AWS serverless technologies. This approach aims to identify potential vulnerabilities proactively and provide your users with timely alerts and recommendations, avoiding reactive escalations and other damages.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-cloud-security-vulnerability-assessment-and-alerting-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DXC transforms data exploration for their oil and gas customers with LLM-powered tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how DXC and AWS collaborated to build an AI assistant using large language models (LLMs), enabling users to access and analyze different data types from a variety of data sources. The AI assistant is powered by an intelligent agent that routes user questions to specialized tools that are optimized for different data types such as text, tables, and domain-specific formats. It uses the LLM’s ability to understand natural language, write code, and reason about conversational context.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: Fujitsu Kozuchi AI Agent Powered by Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customer Case Study: Fujitsu Kozuchi AI Agent Powered by Semantic Kernel Japanese multinational Fujitsu, a pioneer of information and communications technology, has been transforming industries since 1935. With a workforce of 124,000 dedicated professionals across 50 countries, Fujitsu’s mission is to “make the world more sustainable by building trust in society through innovation.” After introducing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-fujitsu-kozuchi-ai-agent-powered-by-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How MSD uses Amazon Bedrock to translate natural language into SQL for complex healthcare databases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSD, a leading pharmaceutical company, collaborates with AWS to implement a powerful text-to-SQL generative AI solution using Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic&#39;s Claude 3.5 Sonnet model. This approach streamlines data extraction from complex healthcare databases like DE-SynPUF, enabling analysts to generate SQL queries from natural language questions. The solution addresses challenges such as coded columns, non-intuitive names, and ambiguous queries, significantly reducing query time and democratizing data access.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate AWS Resilience Hub findings in natural language using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:51:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post discusses a solution that combines AWS Resilience Hub and Amazon Bedrock to generate architectural findings in natural language. By using the capabilities of Resilience Hub and Amazon Bedrock, you can share findings with C-suite executives, engineers, managers, and other personas within your corporation to provide better visibility over maintaining a resilient architecture.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-aws-resilience-hub-findings-in-natural-language-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate and evaluate images in Amazon Bedrock with Amazon Titan Image Generator G1 v2 and Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to interact with the Amazon Titan Image Generator G1 v2 model on Amazon Bedrock to generate an image. Then, we show you how to use Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock to describe it, evaluate it with a score from 1–10, explain the reason behind the given score, and suggest improvements to the image.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-and-evaluate-images-in-amazon-bedrock-with-amazon-titan-image-generator-g1-v2-and-anthropic-claude-3-5-sonnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How InsuranceDekho transformed insurance agent interactions using Amazon Bedrock and generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how InsuranceDekho harnessed the power of generative AI using Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude to provide responses to customer queries on policy coverages, exclusions, and more. This let our customer care agents and POSPs confidently help our customers understand the policies without reaching out to insurance subject matter experts (SMEs) or memorizing complex plans while providing sales and after-sales services. The use of this solution has improved sales, cross-selling, and overall customer service experience.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending the Interaction Between AI Agents and Editors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We explore the interaction of AI agents and editors by mixing tool definitions with prompts using a simple Markdown-based canvas.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/extending-the-interaction-between-ai-agents-and-editors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s meet at Slush 2024 in Helsinki!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Meet with our JetBrains for Startups team at Slush 2024 in Helsinki on November 20–21! This November, our JetBrains team is returning for the third year in a row to the most founder-focused event on Earth. Join us at booth 7A2 to discuss how our tools can accelerate your startup’s growth, win exclusive swag, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/11/18/let-s-meet-at-slush-2024-in-helsinki/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your .NET Developer Productivity with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to get started with GitHub Copilot for .NET development for AI assisted development in Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/enhance-your-dotnet-developer-productivity-with-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of Managed DevOps Pools (MDP) for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 17:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce that Managed DevOps Pools for Azure DevOps is now generally available! This milestone marks a significant advancement in our mission to improve developer productivity in the CI/CD loop, reduce your cloud bill for ES infra and to reduce the toil associated with creating and maintaining custom CI/CD infrastructure for your […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/managed-devops-pools-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software is a team sport: Building the future of software development together</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft, we strive to build the world’s most beloved developer tools and services. Our vision is to empower every developer to transform their concepts into reality, from idea to code to cloud, at lightning speed. The Visual Studio family, Azure, GitHub, and GitHub Copilot empower developers around the world to do just that. Since […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//building-the-future-of-software-development-together 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 7.5 RC-1 is now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Availability of PowerShell 7.5 RC1
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/powershell-7-5-rc-1-is-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s Agentic Frameworks: AutoGen and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft’s agentic AI frameworks, Semantic Kernel and AutoGen are deeply collaborating to provide the best-in-class agentic developer experience. With Semantic Kernel’s enterprise ready AI capabilities, customers can already use and get support for building agent applications and, moving forward, we’ll align the multi-agent runtime in AutoGen (called autogen-core) with Semantic Kernel, allowing customers to create […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/autogen/microsofts-agentic-frameworks-autogen-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git tooling updates in Visual Studio 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the latest updates to Git tooling in Visual Studio, designed to enhance your development experience and streamline your workflow. These new features are in direct response to user feedback, ensuring that you have the tools you need to be more productive and efficient. For the full list, check out the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/git-tooling-updates-in-visual-studio-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The operations for reading and writing single elements for C&#43;&#43; standard library maps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Breaking down the options.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241118-00/?p=110535 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K2 Mode Becomes Stable</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 14:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3, K2 mode is out of Beta and is now Stable and ready for general use. K2 mode significantly improves code analysis stability, memory consumption efficiency, and the IDE’s overall performance, and it supports Kotlin 2.1 language features. Background K2 mode in IntelliJ IDEA was developed to address limitations in the previous […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/k2-mode-becomes-stable/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Case Studies: Preventing Critical Production Incidents with Moovit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Moovit – a popular commuter app serving 1.5 billion users in over 3,500 cities – has become a critical part of people’s daily transit since its inception in 2012. As with any large-scale application, the Moovit team has to maintain a clean and sustainable codebase to limit outages and ensure a smooth and effective service […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/11/qodana-case-studies-moovit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embeded languages in string values supported by Roslyn</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a recent post, I shared how to highlight C# code in string values. Roslyn provides more built-in highlighters / code-completions in string values. Most of the supported languages are available as constants of the StringSyntaxAttribute class. To indicate the language, you can use the lang or language comment or the [StringSyntax] attribute. The languages mentioned in this post are handled by Roslyn (VS,…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/embeded-languages-in-string-values-supported-by-roslyn.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: The JUnit Crew Presents the Latest Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 09:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode with JUnit team members to discover the most recent updates to the test automation framework. Date: November 27, 2024 Time: 3:00–4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract In this session, the JUnit team will introduce the recent 5.11 release’s new features, as well as […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/new-livestream-the-junit-crew-presents-the-latest-features/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Binding and Late Binding in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 07:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In C#, method binding refers to associating a method call with the method’s code definition. When we invoke a method, the program determines which specific method to execute. This process, known as “binding,” can occur at two different times: during compile-time (early binding) or runtime (late binding). By using early binding, we can use compile-time […] The post Early Binding and Late Binding in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core BFF using OpenID Connect and Vue.js</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 07:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article shows how to implement a secure web application using Vue.js and ASP.NET Core. The web application implements the backend for frontend security architecture (BFF) and deploys both technical stacks as one web application. HTTP only secure cookies are used to persist the session. OpenIddict is used as the identity provider and the token […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/11/18/asp-net-core-bff-using-openid-connect-and-vue-js/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Numeric Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2024/17_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2024/17_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine is an open-source project for .NET 8, offering assemblies and NuGet packages developed since .NET 2. It features the NumericExtensions class with various utility methods for numeric types, improving programming efficiency.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/17/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-numeric-extension-methods/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Tools Are Wrecking Junior Developers! – Dev Leader Weekly 70</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_11_2024/16_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_11_2024/16_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post AI Tools Are Wrecking Junior Developers! – Dev Leader Weekly 70 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss my take on AI tools and getting started as a software developer. The post AI Tools Are Wrecking Junior Developers! – Dev Leader Weekly 70 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/11/16/ai-tools-are-wrecking-junior-developers-dev-leader-weekly-70/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HybridCache in ASP.NET Core - New Caching Library</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_11_2024/16_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_11_2024/16_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HybridCache in .NET 9 combines fast in-memory caching with distributed caching, solving common problems like cache stampede while adding features like tag-based invalidation. This guide shows you how to use HybridCache in your applications, from basic setup to real-world usage patterns with Entity Framework Core and minimal APIs.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/hybrid-cache-in-aspnetcore-new-caching-library 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for addressing the core dimensions of responsible AI for Amazon Bedrock applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 19:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the core dimensions of responsible AI and explore considerations and strategies on how to address these dimensions for Amazon Bedrock applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/considerations-for-addressing-the-core-dimensions-of-responsible-ai-for-amazon-bedrock-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From RAG to fabric: Lessons learned from building real-world RAGs at GenAIIC – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post focuses on doing RAG on heterogeneous data formats. We first introduce routers, and how they can help managing diverse data sources. We then give tips on how to handle tabular data and will conclude with multimodal RAG, focusing specifically on solutions that handle both text and image data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/from-rag-to-fabric-lessons-learned-from-building-real-world-rags-at-genaiic-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Embed multimodal embeddings model is now available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Cohere Embed multimodal embeddings model is now generally available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. This model is the newest Cohere Embed 3 model, which is now multimodal and capable of generating embeddings from both text and images, enabling enterprises to unlock real value from their vast amounts of data that exist in image form. In this post, we discuss the benefits and capabilities of this new model with some examples.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GoDaddy built Lighthouse, an interaction analytics solution to generate insights on support interactions using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how GoDaddy’s Care &amp;amp; Services team, in close collaboration with the AWS GenAI Labs team, built Lighthouse—a generative AI solution powered by Amazon Bedrock. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that makes foundation models (FMs) from leading AI startups and Amazon available through an API, so you can choose from a wide range of FMs to find the model that is best suited for your use case.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allow users to talk and listen to your chatbot using Semantic Kernel Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Until now, Semantic Kernel Python only allowed for the development of text-based AI applications. However, this is no longer the case, as we have expanded its capabilities to include audio as one of the supported modalities. In this article, I will provide a detailed, step-by-step guide on how to create a chatbot that can both […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/allow-users-to-talk-and-listen-to-your-chatbot-using-semantic-kernel-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune multimodal models for vision and text use cases on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showcase how to fine-tune a text and vision model, such as Meta Llama 3.2, to better perform at visual question answering tasks. The Meta Llama 3.2 Vision Instruct models demonstrated impressive performance on the challenging DocVQA benchmark for visual question answering. By using the power of Amazon SageMaker JumpStart, we demonstrate the process of adapting these generative AI models to excel at understanding and responding to natural language questions about images.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s Agentic AI Frameworks: AutoGen and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft’s agentic AI frameworks, Semantic Kernel and AutoGen are deeply collaborating to provide the best-in-class agentic developer experience. With Semantic Kernel’s enterprise ready AI capabilities, customers can already use and get support for building agent applications and, moving forward, we’ll align the multi-agent runtime in AutoGen (called autogen-core) with Semantic Kernel, allowing customers to create […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/microsofts-agentic-ai-frameworks-autogen-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Audio in Semantic Kernel Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce the arrival of audio support in Semantic Kernel Python. This new audio functionality will enable you to create more interactive and accessible user experiences. In this blog post, I will detail the new interface, the existing connectors, and provide samples. Please continue reading for more information. Audio-to-Text The first feature […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/working-with-audio-in-semantic-kernel-python 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principal Financial Group uses QnABot on AWS and Amazon Q Business to enhance workforce productivity with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Principal used QnABot paired with Amazon Q Business and Amazon Bedrock to create Principal AI Generative Experience: a user-friendly, secure internal chatbot for faster access to information. Using generative AI, Principal’s employees can now focus on deeper human judgment based decisioning, instead of spending time scouring for answers from data sources manually.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/principal-financial-group-uses-qnabot-on-aws-and-amazon-q-business-to-enhance-workforce-productivity-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us at Microsoft Ignite: Unlock GitHub Copilot’s New Potential in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get ready for an exciting Microsoft Ignite breakout session where we’re unveiling the latest advancements in GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio! Join Dalia Abo Sheasha, Jessie Houghton, and Scott Hanselman as they dive into how GitHub Copilot is evolving to help developers work smarter, collaborate better, and achieve more. Here’s a little preview of what […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/join-us-at-microsoft-ignite-unlock-github-copilots-new-potential-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I put a non-copyable, non-movable, non-constructible object into a std::optional?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Taking advantage of the conversion operator.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241115-00/?p=110527 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Private Resources in Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A practical guide for developers on connecting to Azure resources with private endpoints through a VPN.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/accessing-private-resources-in-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub Copilot for Efficient Unit Test Creation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 04:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers, we know that writing comprehensive unit tests is crucial yet often tedious. GitHub Copilot Chat revolutionizes this process by serving as your intelligent testing companion right in your IDE. Let’s explore how to maximize its potential for efficient and thorough test generation. The Testing Challenge: A Common Developer Pain Point Every developer has […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-use-github-copilot-for-efficient-unit-test-creation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – November 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 22:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the November release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-november-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governing ML lifecycle at scale: Best practices to set up cost and usage visibility of ML workloads in multi-account environments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud costs can significantly impact your business operations. Gaining real-time visibility into infrastructure expenses, usage patterns, and cost drivers is essential. To allocate costs to cloud resources, a tagging strategy is essential. This post outlines steps you can take to implement a comprehensive tagging governance strategy across accounts, using AWS tools and services that provide visibility and control. By setting up automated policy enforcement and checks, you can achieve cost optimization across your machine learning (ML) environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate invoice processing with Streamlit and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through a step-by-step guide to automating invoice processing using Streamlit and Amazon Bedrock, addressing the challenge of handling invoices from multiple vendors with different formats. We show how to set up the environment, process invoices stored in Amazon S3, and deploy a user-friendly Streamlit application to review and interact with the processed data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-invoice-processing-with-streamlit-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling methods is easier and faster with C# 13 params collections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 18:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s take a look at C# 13&#39;s new params collections that make methods easier to use and allow new optimizations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/csharp13-calling-methods-is-easier-and-faster 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nullable Reference Types in F# 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read about latest F# 9 feature, Nullable Reference Types
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/nullable-reference-types-in-fsharp-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtered change notifications in Microsoft Graph callRecords API are now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 17:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce that you can now optionally filter change notifications for the callRecord GraphAPI by participant Entra Object IDs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/filtered-change-notifications-in-microsoft-graph-callrecords-api-are-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centralize model governance with SageMaker Model Registry Resource Access Manager sharing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 16:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently announced the general availability of cross-account sharing of Amazon SageMaker Model Registry using AWS Resource Access Manager (AWS RAM), making it easier to securely share and discover machine learning (ML) models across your AWS accounts. In this post, we will show you how to use this new cross-account model sharing feature to build your own centralized model governance capability, which is often needed for centralized model approval, deployment, auditing, and monitoring workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionize trip planning with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Location Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to build a generative AI-powered trip-planning service that revolutionizes the way travelers discover and explore destinations. By using advanced AI technology and Amazon Location Service, the trip planner lets users translate inspiration into personalized travel itineraries. This innovative service goes beyond traditional trip planning methods, offering real-time interaction through a chat-based interface and maintaining scalability, reliability, and data security through AWS native services.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify automotive damage processing with Amazon Bedrock and vector databases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores a solution that uses the power of AWS generative AI capabilities like Amazon Bedrock and OpenSearch vector search to perform damage appraisals for insurers, repair shops, and fleet managers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simplify-automotive-damage-processing-with-amazon-bedrock-and-vector-databases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Testcontainers Cloud Is a Game-Changer Compared to Docker-in-Docker for Testing Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn why Testcontainers Cloud is a transformative alternative to Docker-in-Docker that&#39;s reshaping container-based testing.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/testcontainers-cloud-vs-docker-in-docker-for-testing-scenarios/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving the puzzle of trying to put an object into a std::optional</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How do I set a value? Let me count the ways.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241114-00/?p=110521 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding prompt engineering: Unlock the creative potential of Stability AI models on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stability AI’s newest launch of Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large (SD3.5L) on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart enhances image generation, human anatomy rendering, and typography by producing more diverse outputs and adhering closely to user prompts, making it a significant upgrade over its predecessor. In this post, we explore advanced prompt engineering techniques that can enhance the performance of these models and facilitate the creation of compelling imagery through text-to-image transformations.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of Stability AI’s latest and most advanced text-to-image model, Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large, in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. In this post, we provide an implementation guide for subscribing to Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large in SageMaker JumpStart, deploying the model in Amazon SageMaker Studio, and generating images using text-to-image prompts.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-stable-diffusion-3-5-large-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster Time-to-Code in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA’s power and wide range of functionality can make it somewhat resource-hungry. Depending on the project you’re working with, the IDE has been known to lag, which can naturally be frustrating. Perhaps the most common scenario in which developers are required to wait is when opening a project. IntelliJ IDEA needs to load and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/11/faster-time-to-code-in-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Game Development in Rust with Bevy: Key Insights from Herbert Wolverson’s Livestream</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disclaimer: This article was created using JetBrains Grazie, an AI-based writing and communication companion. With its help, the core topics of this rich and nuanced livestream were conveniently distilled into a compact blog post format. Game development in Rust is gaining momentum, and Bevy, a modern game engine focusing on Rust, is at the forefront […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2024/11/14/unveiling-game-development-in-rust-with-bevy-key-insights-from-herbert-wolverson-s-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover DataGrip 2024.3: New AI Assistant Features and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DataGrip 2024.3 is here! This is the third major update of 2024. Let’s take a look at what it has to offer. For a detailed description of this update, please visit our What’s New page. AI Assistant Working with data Code editor Connectivity If you’re interested in upgrading to DataGrip 2024.3, or if you have […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2024/11/14/discover-datagrip-2024-3-new-ai-assistant-features-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline AI Prompting, Coding Assistance for the dataclass_transform Decorator (PEP 681), and More in PyCharm 2024.3!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code smarter, optimize performance, and stay focused on what matters most with the latest updates in PyCharm 2024.3. From enhanced support for AI Assistant and Jupyter notebooks to new features like no-code data filtering, there’s so much to explore. Learn about all the updates on our What’s New page, download the latest version from our […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/11/pycharm-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2024.3 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 11:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This release is a major update that includes support for PHP 8.4, xdebug_notify(), Pest 3.0, and Pest parallel and mutation testing, and more. If you’re using PhpStorm together with JetBrains AI Assistant, it also got updated with the new AI code completion model, new inline AI prompting, and more. Download PhpStorm 2024.3 PHP 8.4 support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2024/11/phpstorm-2024-3-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Code with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 11:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking to resolve code issues quickly? The new GitHub Copilot feature integrated into the lightbulb and error list in Visual Studio 2022 offers a valuable solution for developers. Whether you’re working in C# or C++, this feature will help you understand and address problems in your codebase more efficiently. The integration of GitHub Copilot into […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/fix-code-with-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 10:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2024.3 comes with a set of new features and inspections designed to streamline the developer workflow. For AI users, we’ve refined multiline code completion and added a brand-new inline prompts feature. Startup performance for large projects has also been significantly improved, and we’ve added support for some of the latest (and some upcoming) Go […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2024/11/14/goland-2024-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave’s Faster or Not!: Optimizing Base64 Decoding in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, the author explored faster data processing methods using Span in .NET, specifically for converting Base64 strings to byte arrays. The article aims to assist developers in making informed decisions.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/11/14/dotnetdaves-faster-or-not-optimizing-base64-decoding-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
