<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:09:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modernize ASP.NET MVC Razor UI with AWS Transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Transform is an agentic service that accelerates modernization, including .NET applications. With it, you can transform .NET Framework Windows applications to cross-platform .NET and reduce operating costs up to 40% by running on Linux. For ASP.NET web applications, AWS Transform can port the UI layer to ASP.NET Core. In this post, I’ll explain how […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-asp-net-mvc-razor-ui-with-aws-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why “Microservices” Debates Miss the Point</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 22:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DHH had a take on microservices in small teams that is getting a lot of attention. And while I agree with what he’s pointing out, all of these types of conversations miss what actually matters. This is not about microservices or a monolith or small teams. Now what’s implied here is microservices is much more… Read More »Why “Microservices” Debates Miss the Point The post Why “Microservices” Debates Miss the Point appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance by design: The essential guide for successful AI scaling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 21:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picture this: Your enterprise has just deployed its first generative AI application. The initial results are promising, but as you plan to scale across departments, critical questions emerge. How will you enforce consistent security, prevent model bias, and maintain control as AI applications multiply?
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/governance-by-design-the-essential-guide-for-successful-ai-scaling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Ergonomics: How the Azure Command Launcher for Java Improves GC Stability and Throughput on Azure VMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous blog we introduced Azure Command Launcher for Java (jaz) —a safe, resource-aware way to launch the JVM without hand-tuning dozens of flags. This follow-up shares performance results, focusing on
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/beyond-ergonomics-how-the-azure-command-launcher-for-java-improves-gc-stability-and-throughput-on-azure-vms 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tata Power CoE built a scalable AI-powered solar panel inspection solution with Amazon SageMaker AI and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Tata Power CoE and Oneture Technologies use AWS services to automate the inspection process end-to-end.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-tata-power-coe-built-a-scalable-ai-powered-solar-panel-inspection-solution-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking video understanding with TwelveLabs Marengo on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll show how the TwelveLabs Marengo embedding model, available on Amazon Bedrock, enhances video understanding through multimodal AI. We&#39;ll build a video semantic search and analysis solution using embeddings from the Marengo model with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless as the vector database, for semantic search capabilities that go beyond simple metadata matching to deliver intelligent content discovery.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-video-understanding-with-twelvelabs-marengo-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataGrip turns 10. Hidden gems of DataGrip.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking back Hello, friends! 10 years ago to this very day, DataGrip was born. That’s right, on December 16, 2016, the first-ever version of DataGrip was released! But the origins of DataGrip go back even further. We had already been working to create a database IDE for quite some time by then, and its codename […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/12/16/datagrip-turns-10-hidden-gems-of-datagrip/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; code editing tools for GitHub Copilot: now in Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In November, we introduced C++ code editing tools for GitHub Copilot as a Private Preview, focusing on partnering with customers to tackle one of the common, taxing challenges for C++ development: refactoring at s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-code-editing-tools-for-github-copilot-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft.Testing.Platform Now Fully Supported in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this year, we announced that all major .NET test frameworks now support Microsoft.Testing.Platform. The next logical step? Making sure it works seamlessly with your CI/CD pipelines. Today, we&#39;re announcing comprehensive Azure DevOps integration for Microsof
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/microsoft-testing-platform-azure-retry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin 2.3.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Kotlin 2.3.0 release is out! This version includes new language features, stable ones, and other features now enabled by default. This release also brings tooling updates, performance improvements for different platforms, and important fixes. Here are some additional highlights from this release: For the complete list of changes, refer to What’s new in Kotlin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/kotlin-2-3-0-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging, but Without the Drama (A Visual Studio 2026 Story)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It starts the way these things always start. A red build.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2026-debugging-with-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is the Windows clipboard taking the scenic route when converting from &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; to &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;OEM­TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our investigation of why the CF_OEM­TEXT clipboard format is not being created from CF_TEXT via Ansi­To­Oem led us to the realization that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251216-00/?p=111873 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and deploy voice AI apps using Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Voice is the next frontier of conversational AI. It is the most natural modality for people to chat and interact with another intelligent being. However, the voice AI software stack is complex, with many moving parts. Docker has emerged as one of the most useful tools for AI agent deployment. In this article, we&#39;ll explore...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/develop-deploy-voice-ai-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards integration with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A few months ago we introduced the Azure Boards integration with GitHub Copilot in private preview. The goal was simple: allow teams to take a work item from Azure Boards and send it directly to GitHub Copilot so the coding agent
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/github-copilot-for-azure-boards 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner now included with the Universal Blue family</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running large language models (LLMs) and other generative AI models can be a complex, frustrating process of managing dependencies, drivers, and environments. At Docker, we believe this should be as simple as docker model run. That&#39;s why we built Docker Model Runner, and today, we’re thrilled to announce a new collaboration with Universal Blue. Thanks...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-universal-blue/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs C&#43;&#43;: competition or evolution in systems programming for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C and C++ are the backbone of modern software. Operating systems, databases, game engines, and compilers all trace their roots to these languages. They give developers low-level control over memory, hardware, and performance. It’s a level of control that has defined decades of software development. However, the landscape has shifted, and the Rust vs. C++ […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/12/16/rust-vs-cpp-comparison-for-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents, Protocols, and Why We’re Not Playing Favorites</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past few weeks, after we announced ACP protocol support, I’ve gotten lots of messages asking something along these lines: “Microsoft just launched AgentHQ for GitHub and VS Code. So, does this mean JetBrains will drop ACP? Will you only support your own thing now?” The quick answer: We’re not picking sides. Here’s why – […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/agents-protocols-and-why-we-re-not-playing-favorites/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a .NET CLR profiler using C# and NativeAOT with Silhouette</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at how to create a simple .NET profiler. But instead of using C++, the profiler uses C# and NativeAOT with the Silhouette library
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-dotnet-profiler-using-csharp-with-silhouette/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating AI’s ability to perform scientific research tasks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces FrontierScience, a benchmark testing AI reasoning in physics, chemistry, and biology to measure progress toward real scientific research.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/frontierscience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring AI’s capability to accelerate biological research</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces a real-world evaluation framework to measure how AI can accelerate biological research in the wet lab. Using GPT-5 to optimize a molecular cloning protocol, the work explores both the promise and risks of AI-assisted experimentation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/accelerating-biological-research-in-the-wet-lab 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in .NET 10 and C# 14: Optimizations in log aggregation jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:55:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 is officially out, along with C# 14. Microsoft has released .NET 10 as Long-Term Support (LTS) as a successor to .NET 8. Like every version, it is not just an update but brings something new to the table. In this series, we will explore which aspects of software
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/new-in-net-10-and-c-14-optimizations-in-log-aggregation-jobs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt Noise Is Killing Your AI Accuracy: How to Optimize Context for Grounded Output</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 01:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The most common reason an AI system “hallucinates” in production isn’t that the model is dumb. It’s that we’re drowning it. In the last year, many teams have quietly adopted a pattern that looks sophisticated on paper: throw everything into the prompt. Policies, API schemas, examples, edge cases, brand voice, product specs, meeting notes, customer […] The article Prompt Noise Is Killing Your AI Accuracy: How to Optimize Context for Grounded Output was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[C# Tip] How to create and access custom C# Attributes by using Reflection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In C#, Attributes are a handy mechanism to attach metadata to your classes, methods, properties, etc. In this article, we will see how to create custom Attributes and access them at runtime using Reflection.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/csharptips/custom-csharp-attributes-reflection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new ChatGPT Images is here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new ChatGPT Images is powered by our flagship image generation model, delivering more precise edits, consistent details, and image generation up to 4× faster. The upgraded model is rolling out to all ChatGPT users today and is also available in the API as GPT-Image-1.5.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/new-chatgpt-images-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checkpointless training on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod: Production-scale training with faster fault recovery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce checkpointless training on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod, a paradigm shift in model training that reduces the need for traditional checkpointing by enabling peer-to-peer state recovery. Results from production-scale validation show 80–93% reduction in recovery time (from 15–30 minutes or more to under 2 minutes) and enables up to 95% training goodput on cluster sizes with thousands of AI accelerators.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/checkpointless-training-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-production-scale-training-with-faster-fault-recovery/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build declarative agents for Microsoft 365 Copilot with MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is revolutionizing AI by providing a universal integration standard for the external systems, unlocking unprecedented capabilities, transforming how AI models access and utilize real-time data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-declarative-agents-for-microsoft-365-copilot-with-mcp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive infrastructure for foundation model training with elastic training on SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker HyperPod now supports elastic training, enabling your machine learning (ML) workloads to automatically scale based on resource availability. In this post, we demonstrate how elastic training helps you maximize GPU utilization, reduce costs, and accelerate model development through dynamic resource adaptation, while maintain training quality and minimizing manual intervention.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/adaptive-infrastructure-for-foundation-model-training-with-elastic-training-on-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build iOS Widgets with .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog from Toine de Boer. I&#39;m a .NET developer primarily focused on .NET MAUI to ASP.NET backend services. Because I recently have worked a lot with Widgets and encountered many obstacles and very limited documentation in the initial phas
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/how-to-build-ios-widgets-with-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize agent workflows with advanced orchestration techniques using Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore two powerful orchestration patterns implemented with Strands Agents. Using a common set of travel planning tools, we demonstrate how different orchestration strategies can solve the same problem through distinct reasoning approaches,
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/customize-agent-workflows-with-advanced-orchestration-techniques-using-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operationalize generative AI workloads and scale to hundreds of use cases with Amazon Bedrock – Part 1: GenAIOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this first part of our two-part series, you&#39;ll learn how to evolve your existing DevOps architecture for generative AI workloads and implement GenAIOps practices. We&#39;ll showcase practical implementation strategies for different generative AI adoption levels, focusing on consuming foundation models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/operationalize-generative-ai-workloads-and-scale-to-hundreds-of-use-cases-with-amazon-bedrock-part-1-genaiops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying data loading best practices for ML training with Amazon S3 clients</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present practical techniques and recommendations for optimizing throughput in ML training workloads that read data directly from Amazon S3 general purpose buckets.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/applying-data-loading-best-practices-for-ml-training-with-amazon-s3-clients/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.11.1 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have rolled out 2025.11.1, the first update for the major 2025.11 version. This bug-fix resolves a number of issues, including: Bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements, so we recommend installing them promptly. See TeamCity 2025.11.1 Release Notes for the complete list of resolved issues. Why update? Staying up to date with minor […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/teamcity-2025-11-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes of the Visual Studio feedback system</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Here on the Visual Studio team, our top priority is making your coding experience smoother and more enjoyable. And that begins with truly listening to your feedback. We understand that sometimes sharing your thoughts can feel like tossing bug reports and suggestions into a black hole. It doesn’t feel good, and we get it. But here’s the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/behind-the-scenes-of-the-visual-studio-feedback-system 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misunderstanding what the Cricket Celebration Bowl is</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Apparently, late last week was an event known as the Cricket Celebration Bowl. I thought to myself, &amp;quot;The Cricket Celebration Bowl sounds like the name of the least popular item on the Panera menu.&amp;quot; And no, it&#39;s not a cricket match either.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251215-01/?p=111871 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Windows clipboard automatic text conversion algorithm is path-dependent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We closed last time with this table: To get First try
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251215-00/?p=111869 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Tame Your Flaky Tests in TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_12_2025/15_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Satish Subrahmanya, draft.dev. It’s 4:47 pm on a Friday. Your feature branch just passed all tests locally, and the code review went smoothly, so you hit the merge button. But then it happens: The CI build fails. The same test suite that passed five minutes ago is now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/how-to-tame-flaky-tests/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auth0 Changes The Game for AI Agents - Dev Leader Weekly 119</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss some of the awesome features Auth0 is bringing for building AI agents!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/14/auth0-changes-the-game-for-ai-agents-dev-leader-weekly-119 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-12-12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/14/weekly-recap-20251212 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private MCP Catalogs and the Path to Composable Enterprise AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most discussions about Model Context Protocol infrastructure ask how to govern thousands of AI tools and monitor which MCP servers are running. This question is table stakes but undershoots the possibilities. A better question is how we can unleash MCP to drive developer creativity from a trusted foundation. The first question produces a phone book...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/private-mcp-catalogs-oci-composable-enterprise-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Chronicles: When OpenAI’s Magic Meets a Messy User Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author expresses frustration with Sora&#39;s poor user experience and ongoing instability, emphasizing navigation difficulties, session issues, and prolonged outages. Despite Sora&#39;s impressive capabilities, the author argues that without prioritizing user experience and reliability, OpenAI risks losing the trust of professional creators. They urge the hiring of experienced UX designers and engineers.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/12/14/ux-chronicles-when-openais-magic-meets-a-messy-user-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New .slnx Solution Format (migration guide)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2025/13_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2025/13_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            See what changes in .slnx, how to convert your existing .sln, and what to watch out for in CI.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-new-slnx-solution-format-migration-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from AWS re:Invent: Supercharging Kiro with Docker Sandboxes and MCP Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the recent AWS re:Invent, Docker focused on a very real developer problem: how to run AI agents locally without giving them access to your machine, credentials, or filesystem. With AWS introducing Kiro, Docker demonstrated how Docker Sandboxes and MCP Toolkit allow developers to run agents inside isolated containers, keeping host environments and secrets out...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/aws-reinvent-kiro-docker-sandboxes-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a voice-driven AWS assistant with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a sophisticated voice-powered AWS operations assistant using Amazon Nova Sonic for speech processing and Strands Agents for multi-agent orchestration. This solution demonstrates how natural language voice interactions can transform cloud operations, making AWS services more accessible and operations more efficient.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-voice-driven-aws-assistant-with-amazon-nova-sonic/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving an ambiguity in the Windows clipboard automated text conversion table</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we encountered a mystery where the synthesis of CF_OEM­TEXT from CF_TEXT did not use Ansi­To­Oem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251212-05/?p=111862 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of Global Personal Access Tokens in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the new year, we’ll be retiring the Global Personal Access Token (PAT) type in Azure DevOps. Global PATs allow users to authenticate across all accessible organizations. While this can feel convenient, a single credential with broad reach creates a concentrated security risk — especially as a user’s access
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/retirement-of-global-personal-access-tokens-in-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is AI the New Insider Threat?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Insider threats have always been difficult to manage because they blur the line between trusted access and risky behavior. With generative AI, these risks aren&#39;t tied to malicious insiders misusing credentials or bypassing controls; they come from well-intentioned employees simply trying to get work done faster. Whether it&#39;s developers refactoring code, analysts summarizing long reports,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-insider-threat-shadow-ai-risk-controls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add MCP Servers to ChatGPT with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT is great at answering questions and generating code. But here&#39;s what it can&#39;t do: execute that code, query your actual database, create a GitHub repo with your project, or scrape live data from websites. It&#39;s like having a brilliant advisor who can only talk, never act. Docker MCP Toolkit changes this completely. Here&#39;s what...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/add-mcp-server-to-chatgpt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 3: Under Observation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously in this series: Two articles in, and our coding agent can already do quite a bit. It can explore projects, read and write code, execute shell commands, and run tests. Adding a definition of done (DoD) in our last article gave it the feedback loop it needed – the agent now iterates until all […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-3-under-observation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Qodana on Kubernetes: More Scalability, More Control</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As engineering teams scale, so do the demands on their tooling. Code quality checks that worked well for one repository or service often need a more resilient, automated, and infrastructure-native setup when development ecosystems grow. That’s exactly why we’re excited to introduce first-class Kubernetes support for Qodana, bringing fully automated deployments, lifecycle management, and future-ready […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/12/deploying-qodana-on-kubernetes-more-scalability-more-control/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: 4 Tools That Keep Systems Running</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference — the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and to contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/12/open-source-in-focus-4-tools-that-keep-systems-running/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBVA and OpenAI collaborate to transform global banking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BBVA is expanding its work with OpenAI through a multi-year AI transformation program, rolling out ChatGPT Enterprise to all 120,000 employees. Together, the companies will develop AI solutions that enhance customer interactions, streamline operations, and help build an AI-native banking experience.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bbva-collaboration-expansion 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BNY builds “AI for everyone, everywhere” with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BNY is using OpenAI technology to expand AI adoption enterprise-wide. Through its Eliza platform, 20,000+ employees are building AI agents that enhance efficiency and improve client outcomes.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bny 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Used Codex to Ship Sora for Android in 28 Days</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI shipped Sora for Android in 28 days using Codex. AI-assisted planning, translation, and parallel coding workflows helped a nimble team deliver rapid, reliable development.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/shipping-sora-for-android-with-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Harmonic Security improved their data-leakage detection system with low-latency fine-tuned models using Amazon SageMaker, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Nova Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how Harmonic Security used Amazon SageMaker AI, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Nova Pro to fine-tune a ModernBERT model, achieving low-latency, accurate, and scalable data leakage detection.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-harmonic-security-improved-their-data-leakage-detection-system-with-low-latency-fine-tuned-models-using-amazon-sagemaker-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-nova-pro/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Swisscom builds enterprise agentic AI for customer support and sales using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll show how Swisscom implemented Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to build and scale their enterprise AI agents for customer support and sales operations. As an early adopter of Amazon Bedrock in the AWS Europe Region (Zurich), Swisscom leads in enterprise AI implementation with their Chatbot Builder system and various AI initiatives. Their successful deployments include Conversational AI powered by Rasa and fine-tuned LLMs on Amazon SageMaker, and the Swisscom Swisscom myAI assistant, built to meet Swiss data protection standards.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying the various locale mismatch scenarios in Windows clipboard text format synthesis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So far, we&#39;ve learned that the conversion between Unicode and the 8-bit ANSI and OEM code pages is performed with the assistance of the CF_LOCALE clipboard format, which itself c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251211-37/?p=111858 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling MLflow for enterprise AI: What’s New in SageMaker AI with MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re announcing Amazon SageMaker AI with MLflow, now including a serverless capability that dynamically manages infrastructure provisioning, scaling, and operations for artificial intelligence and machine learning (AI/ML) development tasks. In this post, we explore how these new capabilities help you run large MLflow workloads—from generative AI agents to large language model (LLM) experimentation—with improved performance, automation, and security using SageMaker AI with MLflow.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scaling-mlflow-for-enterprise-ai-whats-new-in-sagemaker-ai-with-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Observability with Langfuse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how to integrate Langfuse observability with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to gain deep visibility into an AI agent&#39;s performance, debug issues faster, and optimize costs. We walk through a complete implementation using Strands agents deployed on AgentCore Runtime followed by step-by-step code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-agentcore-observability-with-langfuse/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Windows Terminal awesome with GitHub Copilot CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As someone who lives and breathes in the command line, I love making my terminal feel like home. Windows Terminal is full of personalization options that really allow for a custom experience. Additionally, I can stay within my terminal for my development with GitHub Copilot with the GitHub Copilot CLI. Let&#39;s walk through how you can trick out
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/making-windows-terminal-awesome-with-github-copilot-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner now supports vLLM on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Great news for Windows developers working with AI models: Docker Model Runner now supports vLLM on Docker Desktop for Windows with WSL2 and NVIDIA GPUs! Until now, vLLM support in Docker Model Runner was limited to Docker Engine on Linux. With this update, Windows developers can take advantage of vLLM&#39;s high-throughput inference capabilities directly through...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-vllm-windows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Way to Explore kotlinx-benchmark Results with Kotlin Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Benchmarking is an important part of writing efficient Kotlin code. The kotlinx-benchmark library helps you measure and compare performance across different implementations or hardware configurations. However, raw text results only take you so far. Sometimes you need to visualize your data, not just read it. That’s where Kotlin notebooks come in. Kotlin notebooks combine the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/a-better-way-to-explore-kotlinx-benchmark-results-with-kotlin-notebooks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire Integrations, Batteries Included</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aspire Integrations: Batteries included Modern applications depend on many external services: databases, caches, message brokers, storage layers, observability tools, and sometimes AI systems. Each of these brings its own rules for configuration, connection strings, environment variables, authentication, and deployment. Setting al
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspire-integrations-batteries-included 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy Plugin 2025.11 is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the holidays just around the corner and the year coming to a cheerful close, we’re ringing in the final JetBrains Academy plugin update of 2025, version 2025.11! This release focuses on the introduction of the standalone Hyperskill plugin, expands achievement-sharing to IDE-based courses, and brings a number of improvements and fixes to make your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/11/jetbrains-academy-plugin-2025-11-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Free From AI Vendor Lock-in: Integrating GitHub Models with Docker cagent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The landscape of AI development is rapidly evolving, and one of the most exciting developments in 2025 from Docker is the release of Docker cagent. cagent is Docker&#39;s open-source multi-agent runtime that orchestrates AI agents through declarative YAML configuration. Rather than managing Python environments, SDK versions, and orchestration logic, developers define agent behavior in a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/configure-cagent-github-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB vNext Emulator: Query and Observability Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure Cosmos DB Linux-based vNext emulator (preview) is a local version of the Azure Cosmos DB service that runs as a Docker container on Linux, macOS, and Windows. It provides a cost-effective way to develop and test applications locally without requiring an Azure
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-vnext-emulator-query-and-observability-enhancements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider and ReSharper 2025.3.0.4: Important Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another set of updates for the 2025.3 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. Rider 2025.3.0.4 Multi-agent experience in the AI Chat window: Junie and Claude Agent Claude Agent has become the first third-party AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/11/rider-and-resharper-2025-3-0-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing science and math with GPT-5.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2 is OpenAI’s strongest model yet for math and science, setting new state-of-the-art results on benchmarks like GPQA Diamond and FrontierMath. This post shows how those gains translate into real research progress, including solving an open theoretical problem and generating reliable mathematical proofs.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-2-for-science-and-math 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB : Becoming a Search-Native Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For years, “Database” and “Search systems&amp;quot; (think Elastic Search) lived in separate worlds. While both Databases and Search Systems operate in the same domain (storing, indexing and querying data), they prioritized different aspects. OLTP Databases prioritized Structured and Semi-structured data
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-becoming-a-search-native-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing revenue 300% by bringing AI to SMBs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Podium used OpenAI’s GPT-5 to build “Jerry,” an AI teammate driving 300% growth and transforming how Main Street businesses serve customers.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/podium 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2 is our most advanced frontier model for everyday professional work, with state-of-the-art reasoning, long-context understanding, coding, and vision. Use it in ChatGPT and the OpenAI API to power faster, more reliable agentic workflows.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten years</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI reflects on ten years of progress, from early research breakthroughs to widely used AI systems that reshaped what’s possible. We share lessons from the past decade and why we remain optimistic about building AGI that benefits all of humanity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/ten-years 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Walt Disney Company and OpenAI reach landmark agreement to bring beloved characters to Sora</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disney and OpenAI have reached an agreement to bring more than 200 Disney, Marvel, Pixar and Star Wars characters to Sora for fan-inspired short videos. The agreement emphasizes responsible AI in entertainment and includes Disney’s company-wide use of ChatGPT Enterprise and the OpenAI API.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/disney-sora-agreement 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update to GPT-5 System Card: GPT-5.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2 is the latest model family in the GPT-5 series. The comprehensive safety mitigation approach for these models is largely the same as that described in the GPT-5 System Card and GPT-5.1 System Card. Like OpenAI’s other models, the GPT-5.2 models were trained on diverse datasets, including information that is publicly available on the internet, information that we partner with third parties to access, and information that our users or human trainers and researchers provide or generate.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Availability of SharePoint Framework 1.22 - A Major Refresh of the Build &amp; Tooling Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 22:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce general availability of the SharePoint Framework (SPFx) 1.22 – with a focus on refreshing the build and toolchain areas. SharePoint Framework is the easiest and the most widely used model to build your enterprise solutions for Microsoft 365 with automatic single s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/general-availability-of-sharepoint-framework-1-22-a-major-refresh-of-the-build-tooling-experience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement automated smoke testing using Amazon Nova Act headless mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to implement automated smoke testing using Amazon Nova Act headless mode in CI/CD pipelines. We use SauceDemo, a sample ecommerce application, as our target for demonstration. We demonstrate setting up Amazon Nova Act for headless browser automation in CI/CD environments and creating smoke tests that validate key user workflows. We then show how to implement parallel execution to maximize testing efficiency, configure GitLab CI/CD for automatic test execution on every deployment, and apply best practices for maintainable and scalable test automation.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Laravel Support: A New Era for PhpStorm Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For years, PhpStorm has been the go-to IDE for PHP developers – powerful and deeply integrated with the language. But there was one thing many kept asking for: Laravel support out of the box. It should come with built-in — Amdadul Haq (@amdad121) July 30, 2025 Starting with PhpStorm 2025.3, Laravel support is now built […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/12/built-in-laravel-support-a-new-era-for-phpstorm-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2025 (version 1.107)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What&#39;s new in the Visual Studio Code November 2025 Release (1.107). Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/november-2025-(version-1.107) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2025 Insiders (version 1.107)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code November 2025 Release (1.107). Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/external-blogs/november-2025-insiders-version-1-107 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining your Git workflow with Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’re a .NET developer with a busy morning, and an Azure DevOps ticket drops: “Login endpoint 500s under load.” You’ve got to fix it, review a teammate’s feature branch, and keep your repo clean - all before lunch. Visual Studio’s Git tools turn this everyday Git workflow of creating topic branches, stashing changes, committing, a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/streamlining-your-git-workflow-with-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does Windows synthesize the &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;LOCALE&lt;/CODE&gt; clipboard format?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we finished with a nice table of now Windows synthesizes each of the three text clipboard formats from the other two. We saw that the CF_LOCALE clipboa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251210-00/?p=111856 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue Center, All Reports Tab, Improved Report Sharing, the Ability to Change User Roles, and More in Datalore 2025.6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The final Datalore release of the year is here, and it brings multiple improvements designed to make your day-to-day work smoother. Whether you’re trying to keep reports error-free, managing user roles, or setting up environments, Datalore 2025.6 adds new tools that will help you stay organized and productive. Issue center The issue center is available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/12/10/datalore-2025-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Backups in Git Repositories, the Ability to Share Reports With Preselected Values, Mobile Layout for Reports, and More in Datalore 2025.5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.5 is out with multiple new features and improvements, including a new Git integration for workspace backups, the ability to share reports with preselected values in dropdowns, date pickers, and other inputs, and support for new LLMs in AI Assistant. These updates are already available for Datalore Cloud users, and Datalore On-Premises users can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/12/10/datalore-2025-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Architectural Update: Introducing the New Search Everywhere API (Built for Remote Development)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Search Everywhere dialog is one of the most important entry points in the IntelliJ Platform. To future-proof this core feature and ensure its optimal performance in remote development, we have completely rewritten the underlying architecture, and we’re introducing a brand-new API for plugin developers. This is a critical update for anyone contributing custom results […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/12/major-architectural-update-introducing-the-new-search-everywhere-api-built-for-remote-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening cyber resilience as AI capabilities advance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is investing in stronger safeguards and defensive capabilities as AI models become more powerful in cybersecurity. We explain how we assess risk, limit misuse, and work with the security community to strengthen cyber resilience.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/strengthening-cyber-resilience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the TeamCity Operator for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running TeamCity in Kubernetes has always been possible, but it often required knowing your way around both systems pretty well. TeamCity is flexible and easy to tune, and Kubernetes provides excellent tools for running applications at scale. However, bringing the two together smoothly wasn’t always straightforward. The new TeamCity Operator is designed to change that. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/teamcity-kubernetes-operator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Strategy Pattern with Dependency Injection in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:24:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Selection logic is a prominent part of many applications. Whether you add a simple environment toggle, a UI mode decision, or apply a discount, you have to rely on user input. Sometimes, simply using an intuitive if-else or a switch case can work. However, when conditions are growing or a
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/using-strategy-pattern-with-dependency-injection-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-world reasoning: How Amazon Nova Lite 2.0 handles complex customer support scenarios</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post evaluates the reasoning capabilities of our latest offering in the Nova family, Amazon Nova Lite 2.0, using practical scenarios that test these critical dimensions. We compare its performance against other models in the Nova family—Lite 1.0, Micro, Pro 1.0, and Premier—to elucidate how the latest version advances reasoning quality and consistency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/real-world-reasoning-how-amazon-nova-lite-2-0-handles-complex-customer-support-scenarios/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Azure DevOps Server General Availability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that Azure DevOps Server is now generally available (GA)! This release marks the transition from the Release Candidate (RC) phase to full production readiness, delivering enterprise-grade DevOps capabilities fo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/announcing-azure-devops-server-general-availability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Joins the Agentic AI Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, the Linux Foundation launched the Agentic AI Foundation with three founding projects: Anthropic&#39;s Model Context Protocol (MCP), Block&#39;s goose agent framework, and OpenAI&#39;s AGENTS.md standard. The foundation brings together the companies building the infrastructure layer for agents: Anthropic, Block, OpenAI, Amazon, Google, Microsoft, Cloudflare, and Bloomberg, alongside key tooling and platform companies. Docker is...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-joins-the-agentic-ai-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sky’s the Limit: The Cloud9 × JetBrains Global Hackathon Is Live</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month, we announced that JetBrains is now the Official AI-Powered Coding Partner of Cloud9. The response from the community has been incredible, and today, we’re taking the next step in that journey. We’re excited to launch Sky’s the Limit, a global hackathon designed for developers, esports fans, analysts, and creators who want to push […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/09/sky-s-the-limit-the-cloud9-jetbrains-global-hackathon-is-live/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework December 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for December 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Update Overview .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of December 09, 2025. This update contains non-securi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-december-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue-green deployment in Azure Container Apps using Azure Developer CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Blue-green deployment in Azure Container Apps using Azure Developer CLI If you follow the Azure Developer CLI blog posts, you already know that Azure Container Apps (ACA) support in Azure Developer CLI (azd) is GA. We want azd to be production-ready—you should be a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-blue-green-aca-deployment 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Cross-Platform In-App Billing in .NET MAUI Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the discontinuation of the popular InAppBillingPlugin, many .NET MAUI developers have been looking for guidance on implementing in-app purchases in their applications. Today, we&#39;re sharing a comprehensive sample that demonstrates how to implement cross-platform billing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/cross-platform-billing-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Joins the Agentic Artificial Intelligence Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is joining the new Agentic Artificial Intelligence Foundation (AAIF) hosted by the Linux Foundation. The AAIF brings together leading organizations contributing to the next generation of open agentic technologies. The foundation launches with several key open-source projects – including MCP, goose, and AGENTS.md – which already form an emerging ecosystem for shared standards and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/09/jetbrains-joins-the-agentic-artificial-intelligence-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Previewing the JavaScript/TypeScript Modernizer for VS Code Insiders</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previewing the JavaScript/TypeScript Modernizer for VS Code Insiders Keeping JavaScript/TypeScript projects up-to-date can be a challenge, especially when it’s time to upgrade a bunch of npm packages or adopt the latest frameworks. We’ve heard from many JS/TS developers that modernizing an older app (upgrading de
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/jsts-modernizer-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Resource Leaks in Go: How GoLand Helps You Write Safer Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every Go application uses resources, such as files, network connections, HTTP responses, and database query results. But when a resource is left unclosed, it can cause a leak, which drains memory, exhausts system limits, introduces subtle bugs, and eventually brings even the most robust service to failure. Recently, we’ve introduced resource leak analysis in GoLand […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/12/09/preventing-resource-leaks-in-go-how-goland-helps-you-write-safer-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create AI-powered chat assistants for your enterprise with Amazon Quick Suite</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build chat agents in Amazon Quick Suite. We walk through a three-layer framework—identity, instructions, and knowledge—that transforms Quick Suite chat agents into intelligent enterprise AI assistants. In our example, we demonstrate how our chat agent guides feature discovery, use enterprise data to inform recommendations, and tailors solutions based on potential to impact and your team’s adoption readiness.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-ai-powered-chat-assistants-for-your-enterprise-with-amazon-quick-suite/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does Windows synthesize &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;UNICODE­TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; from &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; and vice versa?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we started our exploration of how Windows synthesizes text clipboard formats by looking at the conversion between CF_OEM­TEXT and CF_TEXT
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251209-00/?p=111854 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Your CI/CD Tool Helping or Hindering Performance?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every engineering leader would love to work with a team of elite performers who deploy 182x more frequently, recover from failures 2,293x faster, and achieve 127x faster lead times than low performers. (Yes, that’s the actual difference in performance of real teams from the 2024 DORA research report). But how do you improve your team’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/is-your-ci-cd-tool-helping-or-hindering-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperskill Gets Its Own Plugin Inside JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hyperskill is introducing its own free dedicated plugin inside JetBrains IDEs. This new plugin is built specifically for the Hyperskill learning experience and replaces the previous integration inside the JetBrains Academy plugin. Starting December 11, Hyperskill courses will be available exclusively through the new Hyperskill Academy plugin. The new Hyperskill Academy plugin provides a more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/09/hyperskill-gets-its-own-plugin-inside-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2025.3: Visualization Cells, Multi-Agent Support, Jupyter Improvements.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the 2025.3 release, DataSpell continues its mission to make data analysts more productive with the help of AI. In addition to improving DataSpell’s own AI agent, this release expands your options by introducing direct access to Claude Agent from the IDE – with more agents coming soon. DataSpell 2025.3 also includes major visualization workflow […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/12/dataspell-2025-3-visualization-cells-multi-agent-support-jupyter-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out the Zed editor on Windows for .NET and Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I try out Zed on Windows to see if it can replace my VS Code usages for quick edits of .NET projects and writing Markdown documents
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/trying-out-the-zed-editor-on-windows-for-dotnet-and-markdown/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the RubyMine Team on Reddit AMA Session</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The RubyMine team will be stopping by r/jetbrains on December 11 from 1–5 pm CET and doing an Ask Me Anything (AMA) thread. You’re invited to join us! This isn’t a product launch or a marketing campaign – it’s a chance to have an open conversation about RubyMine and the challenges you face as a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/12/join-the-rubymine-team-on-reddit-ama-session/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI co-founds Agentic AI Foundation, donates AGENTS.md</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI co-founds the Agentic AI Foundation under the Linux Foundation and donates AGENTS.md to support open, interoperable standards for safe agentic AI.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/agentic-ai-foundation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Microsoft Entra PowerShell v1.1.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to introduce Microsoft Entra PowerShell v1.1.0 available on PowerShell Gallery. The headline feature is No more version pinning to Microsoft Graph PowerShell v2.25.0. You can now use the latest Graph modules wi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/entrapowershell/announcing-microsoft-entra-powershell-v1-1-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entra PowerShell Now Supports Latest Microsoft Graph PowerShell Versions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve heard you and we’ve made it happen! One of the most requested changes from our community has been greater flexibility when working with Microsoft Graph PowerShell. Previously, Entra PowerShell pinned its dependency to Microsoft Graph PowerShell v2.25, which limited customers from leveraging
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/entrapowershell/entra-powershell-now-supports-latest-microsoft-graph-powershell-versions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching our first OpenAI Certifications courses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI’s new certifications and AI Foundations courses help people build real-world AI skills, boost career opportunities, and prepare for the future of work.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-certificate-courses 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing powerful AI to millions across Europe with Deutsche Telekom</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is collaborating with Deutsche Telekom to bring advanced, multilingual AI experiences to millions of people across Europe. ChatGPT Enterprise will also be deployed to help employees at Deutsche Telekom improve workflows and accelerate innovation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/deutsche-telekom-collaboration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI fluency at scale with ChatGPT Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Commonwealth Bank of Australia partners with OpenAI to roll out ChatGPT Enterprise to 50,000 employees, building AI fluency at scale to improve customer service and fraud response.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/commonwealth-bank-of-australia 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI appoints Denise Dresser as Chief Revenue Officer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Denise Dresser is joining as Chief Revenue Officer, overseeing OpenAI’s global revenue strategy across enterprise and customer success. She will help more businesses put AI to work in their day-to-day operations as OpenAI continues to scale.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-appoints-denise-dresser 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
