<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Now Available: Sort Geospatial Query Results by ST_Distance in Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB’s geospatial capabilities just got even better! We&#39;re excited to announce that you can now sort query results by distance using an ORDER BY ST_DISTANCE(...) clause in the NoSQL query language while leveraging a spatial index. Why is this important?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-available-sort-geospatial-query-results-by-st_distance-in-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Advisor for Azure Cosmos DB: Actionable insights to improve performance and cost</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL now features Query Advisor, designed to help you write faster and more efficient queries. Whether you’re optimizing for performance, cost, or scalability, Query Advisor provides actionable recommendations to help you get the most out of your data. Why Query Optimization Matters Azure Cosmos DB’
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/query-advisor-for-azure-cosmos-db-actionable-insights-to-improve-performance-and-cost 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repository pattern vs. Specification pattern: Which is more maintainable?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:33:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When talking about Domain-Driven Design (DDD), the repository pattern becomes a default choice for the data access layer. Another pattern is the Specification pattern that organizes code into smaller objects. The question raised here is which suits your project and which is more maintainable as your project scales? I will
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/repository-pattern-vs-specification-pattern-which-is-more-maintainable/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Experience for all Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agents took over VS Code in 2025. We released agent mode for VS Code, integration for the Copilot coding agent, and the new GitHub Copilot CLI. But Copilot is not the only agent game in town. There are now more coding agents than ever, including options from OpenAI and Anthropic.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/a-unified-experience-for-all-coding-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI: Azure Container Apps Dev-to-Prod Deployment with Layered Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how to implement &amp;quot;build once, deploy everywhere&amp;quot; patterns using Azure Container Apps with the new azd publish and layered infrastructure features in Azure Developer CLI v1.20.0. You&#39;ll learn how to deploy the same containerized application across multiple environments with proper separation of concerns.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-developer-cli-azure-container-apps-dev-to-prod-deployment-with-layered-infrastructure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterate faster with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime direct code deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock AgentCore is an agentic platform for building, deploying, and operating effective agents securely at scale. Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime is a fully managed service of Bedrock AgentCore, which provides low latency serverless environments to deploy agents and tools. It provides session isolation, supports multiple agent frameworks including popular open-source frameworks, and handles multimodal […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/iterate-faster-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime-direct-code-deployment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready for .NET Conf 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Conf 2025 is just one week away! Join us November 11-13 for this free, three-day virtual conference showcasing the latest advancements in the .NET platform, open-source projects, and developer tools - including the official release of .NET 10 and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/get-ready-for-dotnet-conf-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm Plugins You Might Not Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PhpStorm comes with a ton of built-in features, and you can add even more with plugins. They bring new languages, tools, and small improvements that make everyday coding smoother. Many of the best ones come from independent developers. One of them is Dmitrii Derepko, who built several handy tools for working with web projects and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/11/phpstorm-plugins-you-might-not-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JDConf 2026 Is Coming With Modern Solutions for an Agentic World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Technology is accelerating faster than ever, and developers are once again at the helm, shaping the future of applications, intelligence, and enterprise systems. With the rise of large language models (LLMs), agent-oriented architectures, and AI-driven development paradigms, Java developers find themselves in a uniquely po
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/jdconf-2026-is-coming-with-modern-solutions-for-an-agentic-world 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Entry Point: A Single Entry Point for Context-Aware Coding Assistance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern IDEs are powerful tools with many useful features. When we talk about developer productivity, one thing that comes to mind is mastering the IDE – learning its features, like refactorings, navigation, or code generation, and remembering how to invoke them. However, discovering all the relevant features of your IDE, and knowing when and how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/universal-entry-point-a-single-entry-point-for-context-aware-coding-assistance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Microsoft SoftCard for the Apple II: Getting two processors to share the same memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Z-80 SoftCard was a plug-in expansion card for the Apple II that added the ability to run CP/M software. According to Wikipedia, it was Microsoft&#39;s first hardware product and in 1980 was the single largest revenue source for the company. CP/M runs on an 8080 pr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251104-00/?p=111758 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming the Billion Dollar Mistake: Maarten Balliauw’s Guide to C# Nullable Reference Types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the most recent JetBrains.NET Days Online 2025 event, Maarten Balliauw delivered a comprehensive session on migrating existing codebases to use C# nullable reference types, a feature that’s been available since C# 8 but remains underutilized in many legacy projects. Through practical examples and migration strategies, Maarten demonstrated how to bring null safety to your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/04/maarten-balliauws-guide-to-csharp-nullable-reference-types/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering Distributed AI/ML at Scale with Azure and Anyscale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The path from prototype to production for AI/ML workloads is rarely straightforward. As data pipelines expand and model complexity grows, teams can find themselves spending more time orchestrating distributed compute than building the intelligence that powers their products. Scaling from a laptop experiment to a production-grade workload still
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/powering-distributed-aiml-at-scale-with-azure-and-anyscale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easier reflection with [UnsafeAccessorType] in .NET 10: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to work with [UnsafeAccessor] to do &#39;easier&#39; reflection and how to use .NET 10&#39;s [UnsafeAccessorType] with types you can&#39;t reference
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-9-easier-reflection-with-unsafeaccessortype/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I learned after speaking at my first Big International Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s easy to say ‘Public Speaking’. But there are lots of factors that you can (and should) consider when talking to an international audience, especially if English is not your first language.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/after-first-big-tech-conference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoMapper 15.1 and MediatR 13.1 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 22:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting a new policy of regular quarterly releases, today I pushed out new versions of AutoMapper and MediatR:AutoMapper 15.1.0 Release NotesMediatR 13.1.0 Release NotesThe previous versions restored netstandard2.0 support across the board. In these releases, I&#39;m including first-class support for
Link to article: https://www.jimmybogard.com/automapper-15-1-and-mediatr-13-1-released/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New developer resource page for Microsoft 365 interoperability and data portability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 20:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has long provided interoperability information, interfaces, and tools to help our vibrant ecosystem of partners integrate their products
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/new-developer-resource-page-for-microsoft-365-interoperability-and-data-portability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Switchboard, MD automates real-time call transcription in clinical contact centers with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we examine the specific challenges Switchboard, MD faced with scaling transcription accuracy and cost-effectiveness in clinical environments, their evaluation process for selecting the right transcription solution, and the technical architecture they implemented using Amazon Connect and Amazon Kinesis Video Streams. This post details the impressive results achieved and demonstrates how they were able to use this foundation to automate EMR matching and give healthcare staff more time to focus on patient care.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q3 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your quarterly dose of plugin dev news, tools, and tips from JetBrains. ⭐ Community Spotlight JetBrains Plugin Developer Conf 2025 Is Coming Up Soon 📅 November 5, 2025 | Online | FreeLearn how to build the next great JetBrains plugin! Join our annual free virtual event focused on developing plugins for JetBrains products. Explore topics […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/11/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q3-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring Your Own Key (BYOK) Is Coming Soon to JetBrains AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’ve always believed in giving developers the best possible tools to enhance productivity and creativity. Recently, you’ve shared important feedback about AI usage limits, transparency, and the freedom to choose which AI providers you use. We heard you loud and clear. That’s why we are working to introduce bring-your-own-key (BYOK) support for JetBrains […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/bring-your-own-key-byok-is-coming-soon-to-jetbrains-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does &lt;code&gt;SHFormat­Date­Time&lt;/code&gt; take an unaligned &lt;code&gt;FILETIME&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I noted some time ago Windows requires that pointers be aligned unless explicitly permitted to be unaligned. I gave as an example of a function that explicitly permits unaligned po
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251103-00/?p=111753 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Platform 2025.3: What Plugin Developers Should Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we approach the release of IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3, we would like to share key information about changes that may impact your plugin development process. This post addresses common questions from the developer community and provides guidance on maintaining compatibility with the latest IntelliJ Platform versions. No Immediate Upgrade Required If you built your plugin […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/11/intellij-platform-2025-3-what-plugin-developers-should-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Multimodal AI Models With Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most exciting advances in modern AI is multimodal support, the ability for models to understand and generate multiple types of input, such as text, images, or audio. With multimodal models, you’re no longer limited to typing prompts; you can show an image or play a sound, and the model can understand it....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-use-multimodel-ai-with-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Growth: Azure Cosmos DB Partner Acceleration Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Accelerate Your Growth: Azure Cosmos DB Partner Acceleration Program Unlock 360° Success with the Cosmos DB Engineering Team Are you ready to elevate your cloud data practice and drive innovation for your customers? The Azure Cosmos DB Partner Acceleration Program—spearheaded by the Cosmos DB Engineering
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/accelerate-your-growth-azure-cosmos-db-partner-acceleration-program 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Trust Leads and Speed Follows in Agentic Design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every developer recognises the trade-off. You can take the shortcut that delivers today but breaks tomorrow, or choose the slower approach that earns lasting confidence. This dilemma has become even more poignant with the widespread integration of AI agents into real workflows. Speed feels tempting, but speed without trust usually wastes more time than it […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/why-trust-leads-and-speed-follows-in-agentic-design/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a secure MCP server using OAuth DPoP and Duende identity provider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 06:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how an ASP.NET Core application can connect to a secure MCP server using OpenID Connect and OAuth. Both applications use Duende IdentityServer as the identity provider. The MCP server requires delegated DPoP access tokens. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/McpOidcOAuth Setup The UI application authenticates with the Duende IdentityServer using OpenID Connect. Upon successful authentication, a […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/11/03/implement-a-secure-mcp-server-using-oauth-dpop-and-duende-identity-provider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS and OpenAI announce multi-year strategic partnership</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and AWS have entered a multi-year, $38 billion partnership to scale advanced AI workloads. AWS will provide world-class infrastructure and compute capacity to power OpenAI’s next generation of models.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/aws-and-openai-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Better Apps with GitHub Copilot Custom Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2025/02_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 17:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2025/02_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Custom agents are here to customize and optimize how coding agents work on your code, here is my experiment with the WinForms agent.
Link to article: https://montemagno.com/building-better-apps-with-github-copilot-custom-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Programming Rule #2: Always Validate Method Parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2025/02_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_11_2025/02_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Parameter validation is crucial in programming, ensuring applications reject bad data before it causes issues. It safeguards data integrity, reduces bugs, and enhances developer satisfaction. The use of meaningful exceptions and tools like Spargine can standardize validation, while adopting strategies like nameof improves error messaging accuracy. Consistent validation fosters reliable APIs.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/11/02/defensive-programming-rule-2-always-validate-method-parameters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Experience, More Overwhelmed - Dev Leader Weekly 114</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2025/01_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2025/01_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to navigate feeling overwhelmed as a developer in a senior+ role.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/01/more-experience-more-overwhelmed-dev-leader-weekly-114 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-10-31</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2025/01_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 05:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2025/01_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/01/weekly-recap-20251031 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s New in EF Core 10: LeftJoin and RightJoin Operators in LINQ</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2025/01_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2025/01_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 finally adds proper LeftJoin and RightJoin methods to LINQ, replacing the complex GroupJoin + DefaultIfEmpty pattern with clean, readable code that does exactly what it says.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/whats-new-in-ef-core-10-leftjoin-and-rightjoin-operators-in-linq 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build reliable AI systems with Automated Reasoning on Amazon Bedrock – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 21:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enterprises in regulated industries often need mathematical certainty that every AI response complies with established policies and domain knowledge. Regulated industries can’t use traditional quality assurance methods that test only a statistical sample of AI outputs and make probabilistic assertions about compliance. When we launched Automated Reasoning checks in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails in preview at […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-reliable-ai-systems-with-automated-reasoning-on-amazon-bedrock-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Universe demo: From prompt to production with VS Code, GitHub Copilot and the Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At this year’s GitHub Universe, we set out to answer a simple question: What would it take to go from an idea to production in under 30 minutes – using only natural language, your editor, and AI? On stage, we built a cloud-native, intelligent app from scratch using
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/behind-the-universe-demo-with-vs-code-copilot-and-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>💫 Welcome to Aspire: Your stack, streamlined</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a new chapter for Aspire and a new home at aspire.dev. What started two years ago as an experiment to simplify distributed app development has become a thriving, community-driven, extensible, code-first pl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspirepolyglot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-region Expansion for Azure Deployments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why Financial Services Organizations Should Consider Expanding to Other Azure Regions for New Workloads As a Cloud Architect, I work closely with financial services organizations to help them unlock the full potential of Azure innovations. One of the most impactful strategies I r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/multi-region-expansion-for-azure-deployments 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Intelligence: Building AI that matches your business DNA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In 2024, we launched the Custom Model Program within the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to provide comprehensive support throughout every stage of model customization and optimization. Over the past two years, this program has delivered exceptional results by partnering with global enterprises and startups across diverse industries—including legal, financial services, healthcare and life sciences, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/custom-intelligence-building-ai-that-matches-your-business-dna/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clario streamlines clinical trial software configurations using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post builds upon our previous post discussing how Clario developed an AI solution powered by Amazon Bedrock to accelerate clinical trials. Since then, Clario has further enhanced their AI capabilities, focusing on innovative solutions that streamline the generation of software configurations and artifacts for clinical trials while delivering high-quality clinical evidence.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/clario-streamlines-clinical-trial-software-configurations-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Team at CppCon 2025: Trip Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another year and another CppCon is all wrapped up! Microsoft was pleased to once again be an exhibitor and to have several of our employees present sessions at the conference. Here are my major takeaways from the keynotes, sessions, conversations, and the general vibe. AI tooling is finding a footing with the C++ community. The ne
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/cppcon2025-trip-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock cross-Region inference for Claude Sonnet 4.5 and Haiku 4.5 in Japan and Australia</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            こんにちは, G’day. The recent launch of Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet 4.5 and Claude Haiku 4.5, now available on Amazon Bedrock, marks a significant leap forward in generative AI models. These state-of-the-art models excel at complex agentic tasks, coding, and enterprise workloads, offering enhanced capabilities to developers. Along with the new models, we are thrilled to announce that […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-cross-region-inference-for-claude-sonnet-4-5-and-haiku-4-5-in-japan-and-australia/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us at .NET Conf: Dive into the future of development with Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to invite you to one of the most exciting events in the .NET ecosystem: .NET Conf. It runs from November 11th through the 13th and you’re invited! This annual virtual conference is a must-attend for developers, architects, and enthusiasts looking t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/join-us-at-net-conf-dive-into-the-future-of-development-with-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: turn into a pumpkin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The English idiom turn into a pumpkin comes from the fairy tale story of Cinderella, in which the protagonist&#39;s ragged clothes are magically transformed into an elegant gown and a pumpkin is transformed into a carriage, allowing her to attend a royal ball. She is warned that the magic wears off at midnight, upon which her clot
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251031-00/?p=111750 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Doesn’t Have to Hurt</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you ever wish security would stop blocking the tools you need to do your job? Surprise: your security team wants the same. There you are, just trying to get your work done, when… You need an AI to translate documentation, but all the AI services are blocked by a security web monitoring tool. You...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/security-shadow-it-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Bones: A Pirate-Voiced Halloween Chatbot Powered by Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            My name is Mike Coleman, a staff solution architect at Docker. This year I decided to turn a Home Depot animatronic skeleton into an AI-powered, live, interactive Halloween chatbot. The result: kids walk up to Mr. Bones, a spooky skeleton in my yard, ask it questions, and it answers back — in full pirate voice...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/talking-skeleton-docker-llm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuning and Optimization of Speech-to-Text (STT), Text-to-Speech (TTS), and Custom Keyword Recognition in Azure Speech Services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Optimizing Speech-to-Text (STT) and Text-to-Speech (TTS) is essential for developers building voice-enabled applications, as it enhances recognition accuracy and overall user experience. Additionally, custom keyword recognition enables hands-free activation for voice assistants. This blog outlines: Method
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/azure-speech-to-text-optimization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce CAPTCHAs for AI agents browsing the web with Web Bot Auth (Preview) in Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI agents need to browse the web on your behalf. When your agent visits a website to gather information, complete a form, or verify data, it encounters the same defenses designed to stop unwanted bots: CAPTCHAs, rate limits, and outright blocks. Today, we are excited to share that AWS has a solution. Amazon Bedrock AgentCore […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/reduce-captchas-for-ai-agents-browsing-the-web-with-web-bot-auth-preview-in-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-browser/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failures Happen in Cloud, but how Azure Cosmos DB keeps your Applications Online</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The only thing that’s constant in distributed systems is failures. No cloud platform is immune to failures — from regional outages and transient network blips to human errors or hardware faults. What defines resiliency &amp;amp; reliability isn’t the absence of failure, but how systems anticipate, isolate, and recover from them. Here is a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/failures-happen-in-cloud-but-how-azure-cosmos-db-keeps-your-applications-online 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the azd extension to configure GitHub Copilot coding agent integration with Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This new azd extension makes it easy to use the GitHub Copilot coding agent with Azure Want Copilot to help you build apps in the cloud? This tool does all the boring setup work for you. Instead of spending hours figuring out permissions and security, you can get Copilot coding agent connected to your cloud resources i
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-copilot-coding-agent-config 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading C&#43;&#43; Projects to Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Visual Studio 2026 version 18.0 getting closer to General Availability (GA), we want to share with you how you can upgrade your projects from your current versions of Visual Studio and the Microsoft C++ (MSVC) Build Tools to the latest versions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/upgrading-c-projects-to-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Livestream recording] Maximizing TeamCity: New Features in Action and a Look Ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our latest livestream, TeamCity Solutions Engineers Ricardo Leite and Daniel Gallo hosted a livestream packed with exciting updates about TeamCity – from brand-new features already making life easier for CI/CD engineers, to a sneak peek at what’s next for 2026. If you missed it or just want a quick refresher, here are the key […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/10/livestream-recording-maximizing-teamcity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to build a XAML tree in code throws a &#34;No installed components were detected&#34; exception</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You might, for some reason, be building some XAML in code rather than markup. Starting with this XAML: &amp;lt;Grid.ColumnDefinitions&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Grid.ColumnDefinitions&amp;gt; Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251030-00/?p=111746 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Stargate to Michigan</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is expanding Stargate to Michigan with a new one-gigawatt campus that strengthens America’s AI infrastructure. The project will create jobs, drive investment, and support economic growth across the Midwest.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/expanding-stargate-to-michigan 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grazie’s Next Step: Built-In Language Intelligence for Your IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the last few years, Grazie has grown from a simple proofreading tool into a comprehensive writing assistant for developers, offering intelligent support across different contexts like code comments, documentation, and README files. Starting with the upcoming 2025.3 IDE versions, Grazie will become a native part of IntelliJ-based IDEs through the Natural Languages plugin, bringing […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/grazie/2025/10/grazie-s-next-step-built-in-language-intelligence-for-your-ide/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Framework (SPFx) roadmap update – October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We continue to be humbled by the incredible momentum of SharePoint Framework (SPFx) and the growth it is driving with our customers and partners. There are tens of millions of users across the world using custom SPFx solutions on a daily basis in Microsoft 365 – built by our customers and pa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/sharepoint-framework-spfx-roadmap-update-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio October Update – new models, memories, planning, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The October 2025 update for Visual Studio 2022 (v17.14) is now available. In this month, we are bringing you improvements to model choices, agentic flows, and chat thread management.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-october-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>theCUBE Research economic validation of Docker’s development platform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker&#39;s impact on agentic AI, security, developer productivity, costs, ROI. An independent study by theCUBE Research. To investigate Docker&#39;s impact on developer productivity, software supply chain security, agentic AI development, cost savings, and ROI, theCUBE Research asked nearly 400 enterprise IT &amp;amp; AppDev leaders from medium to large global enterprises. The industry context is that...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/thecube-research-economic-validation-of-docker-development-platform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Aardvark: OpenAI’s agentic security researcher</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces Aardvark, an AI-powered security researcher that autonomously finds, validates, and helps fix software vulnerabilities at scale. The system is in private beta—sign up to join early testing.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-aardvark 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v1.3 with exporting to HAR, LLM usage tracking, and enhanced permissions analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to announce the release of Dev Proxy v1.3.0! This update introduces two powerful new plugins: HAR file generation for universal debugging and LLM usage tracking for cost optimization, along with enhanced permissions analysis and improved OpenAPI spec generation for complex testing scenarios. In this version: New
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v1-3-with-exporting-to-har-llm-usage-tracking-and-enhanced-permissions-analysis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we built OWL, the new architecture behind our ChatGPT-based browser, Atlas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A deep dive into OWL, the new architecture powering ChatGPT Atlas—decoupling Chromium, enabling fast startup, rich UI, and agentic browsing with ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/building-chatgpt-atlas 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java OpenJDK October 2025 Patch &amp; Security Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 21:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello Java customers! We are happy to announce the latest July 2025 patch &amp;amp; security update release for the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK. Download and install the binaries today. OpenJDK 25.0.1 OpenJDK 21.0.9 OpenJDK 17.0.17 OpenJDK 11.0.29
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-openjdk-oct-2025-patch-security-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from IDCRL authentication to modern authentication in SharePoint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the next few months, Microsoft will be removing the legacy authentication protocol known as IDCRL (Identity Client Run Time Library) in SharePoint and force calls to rely on OpenID connect and OAuth Protocols. Since 2018, regular sign-in for services such as OneDrive and SharePoint has always relied on the more secure OpenID Connect and OAu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/migrating-from-idcrl-authentication-to-modern-authentication-in-sharepoint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Azure Front Door Outage Causing Widespread Service Disruptions Across Microsoft 365, Microsoft Azure, and the Azure Portal (October 29, 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting at approximately 16:00 UTC on October 29, 2025, Microsoft Azure began experiencing a significant outage affecting the Azure Front Door (AFD) service. This incident is resulting in latencies, timeouts, and connectivity failures across numerous Microsoft cloud products, including Microsoft 365 services and the Azure Portal. This article provides an overview of the ongoing outage, the confirmed root cause, its impact on Microsoft […] The article Major Azure Front Door Outage Causing Widespread Service Disruptions Across Microsoft 365, Microsoft Azure, and the Azure Portal (October 29, 2025) was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Becomes Cloud9’s Official AI-Powered Coding Partner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers love coding – it’s a passion we all share. But staying productive means taking time to recharge, and for many of us, that means playing video games. That’s why we’re excited to team up with the legendary Cloud9 Esports as their official AI-Powered Coding Partner. With this partnership, we’re bringing AI-powered coding to the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/10/29/jetbrains-becomes-cloud9s-official-ai-powered-coding-partner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put your AI to the Test with Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is changing how we build software, but it also introduces new challenges: how do you know if your AI application is giving the right answers and producing the right outcomes? Evaluations (often referred to simply as ‘evals’) provide a structured way to measure quality so you can trust your results. In this blog, we’ll introduce the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/put-your-ai-to-the-test-with-microsoft-extensions-ai-evaluation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New GitHub Copilot capabilities for C&#43;&#43; developers: Upgrade MSVC, improve build performance, and refactor C&#43;&#43; code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot;]GitHub Copilot app modernization for C++, GitHub Copilot build performance for Windows, and C++ code editing tools for GitHub Copilot will be available soon in Private Preview. Join the waitlist for Private Preview today.[/alert] Yesterday at GitHub Universe, Gi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/new-github-copilot-capabilities-for-c-developers-upgrade-msvc-improve-build-performance-and-refactor-c-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation of the previewImageUrl property for Insights items that reference file attachments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re deprecating the previewImageUrl property in the resourceVisualization complex type for
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-of-the-previewimageurl-property-for-insights-items-that-reference-file-attachments 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Dispatch in DDD</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What’s Double Dispatch? Well, before we get to what it is, there is a common belief in domain-driven design that you want to keep your domain pure, meaning no dependencies, no services, no distractions. I get it because you do not want that core logic coupled to infrastructure concerns like database calls. You want it… Read More »Double Dispatch in DDD The post Double Dispatch in DDD appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Distributed Systems: Jason Taylor Shows How .NET Aspire Makes the Complex Feel Effortless</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025, Jason Taylor, Microsoft MVP and Solutions Architect at Particular Software, delivered an engaging presentation that transforms how we think about building distributed systems. Through live coding and interactive polls with the audience, Taylor demonstrated how .NET Aspire can turn what’s traditionally been a complex, friction-filled process into something surprisingly […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/10/29/simplifying-distributed-systems-dotnet-aspire-jason-taylor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do when you have a crash in the runtime control flow guard check</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows Control Flow Guard (CFG) is a defense in depth feature which validates indirect call targets. The idea is that each module that is enabled for CFG provides a bitmap that describes which addresses in the module are intended to be targets of indirect calls. When CFG is enabled in a process, indirect function calls are checked against
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251029-00/?p=111738 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program Has Started</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re starting the MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program (EAP) today. You can download the first 2025.3 EAP release and try it out now! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 EAP Besides numerous bug fixes, this release brings three major improvements: Light and dark TextIcon options TextIcon’s layers can now be configured to apply to the light, dark, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/10/the-mps-2025-3-eap-has-started/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Order in the Mayhem: A Novel Concurrency Testing Tool that Improved the Kotlin Compiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve ever tried to track down a bug in concurrent programs, you know how chaotic and frustrating it can be: everything seems to work fine, then suddenly crashes, and you can’t quite pin down why – all while the bugs slip through. To bring order to this chaos, at JetBrains Research we built LitmusKt […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/10/litmuskt-concurrency-testing/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine Does More to Simplify Server Side Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just to set myself up with some pressure to perform, let me hype up a live stream on Wolverine I’m doing later this week! I’m doing a live stream on Thursday afternoon (U.S. friendly this time) entitled Vertical Slices the Critter Stack Way based on a fun, meandering talk I did for Houston DNUG and … Continue reading Wolverine Does More to Simplify Server Side Code →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing gpt-oss-safeguard</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces gpt-oss-safeguard—open-weight reasoning models for safety classification that let developers apply and iterate on custom policies.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-oss-safeguard 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Report: Performance and baseline evaluations of gpt-oss-safeguard-120b and gpt-oss-safeguard-20b</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            gpt-oss-safeguard-120b and gpt-oss-safeguard-20b are two open-weight reasoning models post-trained from the gpt-oss models and trained to reason from a provided policy in order to label content under that policy. In this report, we describe gpt-oss-safeguard’s capabilities and provide our baseline safety evaluations on the gpt-oss-safeguard models, using the underlying gpt-oss models as a baseline. For more information about the development and architecture of the underlying gpt-oss models, see the original gpt-oss model model card⁠.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
