<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 01:57:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>.NET Build 2024：引领AI与云原生应用开发的新篇章</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 01:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自.NET Team的.NET Announcements and Updates from Microsoft Build 2024 – .NET Blog。 在 Microsoft Build 2024 上，我们很高兴推出一系列旨在使 .NET 开发更快、更容易的新功能和工具。 探索 Microsoft Build 2024 上的 .NET 会议，了解新功能的实际效果，或者通过下载 .NET 9 Preview 4 亲自尝试。 以下是我们的更新和公告： 人工智能：用于构建AI应用的端到端方案、拥抱AI生态、与云服务深度集成。 .NET Aspire：用于构建云原生分布式应用程序，今天发布。 C# 13：加强了许多深受喜爱的 C# 功能，使它们更适合您。 性能：通过关键基准测试减少内存和执行时间。 .NET 库和框架的加强，包括 ASP.NET Core、Blazor、.NET MAUI 等。 让我们从如何使用 .NET 为开发人员改进 AI 开发开始。 .NET 与人工智能 .NET 为您提供了使用 AI 创建功能强大的应用程序的工具。您可以使用Semantic Kernel来编排 AI 插件，从而将 AI 功能无缝集成到您的应用程序中。您可以使用最先进的库（例如 OpenAI、Qdrant 和 Milvus）来增强应用程序的功能。您还可以使用 .NET Aspire 将应用程序部署到云端，确保最佳性能和可扩展性。 让我们更深入地了解这些内容。 AI基础知识 我们引入了一种新的 Tensor
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneak Peek of Strong Typed Identifiers in Marten</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 20:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you really need to have strong typed identifier support in Marten right now, here’s the long standing workaround. Some kind of support for “strong typed identifiers” has long been a feature request for Marten from our community. I’ve even been told by a few folks that they wouldn’t consider using Marten until it did … Continue reading Sneak Peek of Strong Typed Identifiers in Marten →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Performance of TLS 1.3 in Java JDK 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 20:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transport Layer Security (TLS) 1.3 is the latest version of the TLS protocol, built on the foundation of its predecessors, with significant improvements in terms of security, performance, and simplicity. TLS 1.3 is widely considered one of the most secure network protocols currently available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/improved-performance-of-tls-1-3-in-java-jdk-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Years Since Kubernetes Launched at DockerCon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 17:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reflecting on the monumental announcement of Kubernetes at DockerCon on June 10th, 2014, Docker CEO Scott Johnston celebrates its transformative impact on container orchestration and modern application development over the past decade, highlighting Docker&#39;s role in this pivotal industry shift.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/10-years-since-kubernetes-launched-at-dockercon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with UI testing .NET MAUI apps using Appium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A proven way to test your (mobile) apps is through UI testing. In this post we will learn how to get setup with UI testing for .NET MAUI apps using Appium.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-maui-ui-testing-appium 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosch widely adopts Visual Studio 2022 after experiencing performance improvements for C&#43;&#43; Linux cross-compilation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction The Bosch security camera team had been evaluating Visual Studio as a unified development setup for their team’s C++ development, which includes remote Linux C++ development for cross-compiling. While evaluating Visual Studio 2022, the team had a positive experience of using Visual Studio for their C++ development due to notable improvements over the years.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/bosch-widely-adopts-visual-studio-2022-after-experiencing-performance-improvements-for-c-linux-cross-compilation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code generation using Code Llama 70B and Mixtral 8x7B on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 14:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of machine learning and artificial intelligence (AI), large language models (LLMs) have emerged as powerful tools for a wide range of natural language processing (NLP) tasks, including code generation. Among these cutting-edge models, Code Llama 70B stands out as a true heavyweight, boasting an impressive 70 billion parameters. Developed by Meta […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/code-generation-using-code-llama-70b-and-mixtral-8x7b-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Azure Cosmos DB: A Comprehensive Guide from Prototype to Production</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 14:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past couple of years, we have collaborated with numerous customers to tackle performance, scaling, and cost issues that arise when transitioning their Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL API based applications to production. In many cases, these challenges stem from a lack of understanding of key Azure Cosmos DB concepts.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/mastering-azure-cosmos-db-a-comprehensive-guide-from-prototype-to-production 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I get the name of a SID, and what does it mean when the conversion fails?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most places will do it for you, or at least try.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240610-00/?p=109872 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing the Renovate configuration across multiple projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Renovate is a tool that helps you to keep your dependencies up-to-date. You can configure Renovate using a configuration file at the root of the repository. In this post, I describe how to share the Renovate configuration across multiple projects. Developers don&#39;t like to maintain the same configuration in multiple repositories. It&#39;s error-prone and time-consuming. By sharing the configuration, you can…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/sharing-the-renovate-configuration-across-multiple-projects.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allow your AI Agent to call Microsoft Graph APIs securely with Microsoft Entra ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover an exciting new plugin in the Chat Copilot sample app from the Semantic Kernel team. This plugin lets an AI Agent call Microsoft Graph APIs secured by Microsoft Entra ID using the On-Behalf-Of (OBO) flow.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/ai-agent-graph-api 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test &amp; Feedback Extension in Manifest V3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 06:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce a new update to the Azure DevOps Test and Feedback extension! This update brings essential implementation changes, upgrading from manifest version 2 to version 3. Following Google’s announcement of their Manifest V2 deprecation schedule, we have been actively working on our implementation of Manifest V3.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/test-feedback-extension-v3 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrying Failed HttpClient Requests in .NET Using Polly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 02:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we will explore the different approaches to retrying failed HttpClient requests using Polly. We will also discuss the advantages and disadvantages of each retry strategy, from simplest to most sophisticated. Let’s start. Reasons for HttpClient Request Failures We like to think of the Internet as a reliable data transmission medium. Sadly, this […] The post Retrying Failed HttpClient Requests in .NET Using Polly appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Generative AI &#43; RAG App in C# with Phi-3, ONNX, and SharpVector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2024/09_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2024/09_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By combining Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) with Generative AI, you can create a more intelligent and context aware AI solution that can more accurately generate text responses. I’ve previously written about building a generative AI application using C#, Phi-3 and the ONNX Runtime. This article will take the foundation covered in that article and add […] The article Build a Generative AI + RAG App in C# with Phi-3, ONNX, and SharpVector was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Performance: Enhancing Dictionary Performance with FrozenDictionary</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2024/09_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_06_2024/09_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The FrozenDictionary is a thread-safe, immutable, read-only dictionary optimized for fast lookups. It outperforms the Dictionary, reducing iteration and lookup times significantly.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/09/collection-performance-enhancing-dictionary-performance-with-frozendictionary/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG)?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 21:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Diagram: How Does RAG Work? The article What is Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG)? was originally published on Build5Nines. To stay up-to-date, Subscribe to the Build5Nines Newsletter.
Link to article: https://build5nines.com/what-is-retrieval-augmented-generation-rag/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DotNetDave Rocks On .NET Live: Performance Improvements in .NET 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 18:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On June 10th, 2024 at 9 AM PST, I&#39;ll be appearing on &amp;quot;On.NET Live&amp;quot; for the second time. We&#39;ll delve into code performance in .NET 8 through the Code Performance Game. Join the live show for an engaging session. For more details, visit https://youtu.be/4WX14dsnKsg.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/06/08/dotnetdave-rocks-on-net-live-performance-improvements-in-net-8/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Being Unkind To Yourself – Dev Leader Weekly 47</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post Stop Being Unkind To Yourself – Dev Leader Weekly 47 appeared first on Dev Leader.Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss why it&#39;s important to be kind to yourself as a software engineer looking to improve. The post Stop Being Unkind To Yourself – Dev Leader Weekly 47 appeared first on Dev Leader.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2024/06/08/stop-being-unkind-to-yourself-dev-leader-weekly-47/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use the LINQ ToDictionary Method in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 06:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, let’s describe how to use the LINQ ToDictionary() method in C#. We will start by defining this method and how it works. Then, we will proceed to show several ways of invoking it. Ultimately, we will discuss different situations where we can utilize the LINQ ToDictionary() method to transform data in our […] The post How to Use the LINQ ToDictionary Method in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caching in ASP.NET Core: Improving Application Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_06_2024/08_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Caching is one of the simplest techniques to significantly improve your application&#39;s performance. In this newsletter, we will explore how to implement caching in ASP.NET Core applications.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/caching-in-aspnetcore-improving-application-performance 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring GitHub Actions to Run Jobs on Specific Branches</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 21:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running jobs on specific branches with GitHub Actions is a common scenario implemented by DevOps and SRE professionals. This allows you to control which branches trigger specific jobs within your workflows. This can be important for maintaining efficient CI/CD processes, especially if you want tests to run on every branch while restricting deployment actions to […] The article Configuring GitHub Actions to Run Jobs on Specific Branches was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Essential Tips: Accelerate Prompt Flow Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 16:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post focusses on tips and tricks to accelerate from flow development through use of dev container &amp;amp; shell scripts.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/7-essential-tips-accelerate-prompt-flow-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the deal with std::type_identity?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you want to use a type without participating in type deduction.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240607-00/?p=109865 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Azure Tooling的更新 – 2024年5月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 11:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎阅读 Java on Azure 工具 5 月份更新。在本次更新中，我们将介绍 Java 在 Azure 上的容器应用程序的入门指南。希望您喜欢这些更新，并享受使用 Azure 工具包的流畅体验。请下载并安装 IntelliJ 的 Azure 工具包。让我们开始吧！ Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ 提升 Java 对 Azure Container Apps 上入门指南支持 在之前的更新中，我们宣布针对 IntelliJ 的 Azure 工具包已为具有灵活部署选项的 Azure 容器应用程序（Java on ACA）提供支持。对于刚刚接触 Azure 容器应用程序的 Java 开发人员，我们还提供了一份教程，帮助您快速入门。本指南将告诉您如何使用本地 Java 源代码构建微服务并将其部署到 Azure Container Apps，并提供分步说明。要使用该指南，请右键单击 “Azure”，然后在 Azure Explorer 中选择 “Getting Started”。然后，选择 “将第一个容器应用程序部署到 Azure（Deploy Your First Container App to Azure） ”继续。下面是一个简短的演示。 反馈与建议 如果您感兴趣，请不要犹豫并尝试使用我们的产品吧!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-azure-tooling-update-may-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Azure Tooling Update – May 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 10:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the May update of Java on Azure Tooling. In this update, we will introduce our getting started guide for Java on Azure Container Apps. We hope you enjoy these updates and have a smooth experience with our Azure toolkit.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-azure-tooling-update-may-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Serialize a PascalCase JSON.NET JObject to camelCase</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 06:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_06_2024/07_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’re going to learn how to serialize a PascalCase JObject to a camelCase format. We will do this in two ways by using the most familiar JSON library in the .NET ecosystem which is Newtonsoft.Json. Let’s begin. Overview of JObject Serialization in .NET Serializing JSON objects is a common practice in .NET […] The post How to Serialize a PascalCase JSON.NET JObject to camelCase appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.5 RC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 21:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the availability of the release candidate of TypeScript 5.5. To get started using the RC, you can get it through NuGet, or through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@rc Here’s a quick list of what’s new in TypeScript 5.5!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-5-rc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unified Development Environment is GA!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 20:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview We are proud to announce that the Unified Developer Experience for Finance and Operations apps (colloquially known as UDE) is now generally availablity for all customers. As you may know, UDE is both the next step in the app development experience for Finance and Operations,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/the-unified-development-environment-is-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the official OpenAI library for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The initial beta release of the official OpenAI library for .NET is now available.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/openai-dotnet-library 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware! Anti-patterns in Event-Driven Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 18:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Event-driven architecture has patterns and common practices that are solutions for various problems. The issue arises when you apply these patterns when you don’t have the problem they solve, or you can avoid having the problem in the first place. Here are some patterns and why the might become anti-patterns in a given context. YouTube… Read More »Beware! Anti-patterns in Event-Driven Architecture The post Beware! Anti-patterns in Event-Driven Architecture appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build RAG applications using Jina Embeddings v2 on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the Jina Embeddings v2 model, developed by Jina AI, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy with one click for running model inference. This state-of-the-art model supports an impressive 8,192-tokens context length. You can deploy this model with SageMaker JumpStart, a machine learning (ML) hub […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-rag-applications-using-jina-embeddings-v2-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Super Resolution: The First OS-Integrated AI-Based Super Resolution for Gaming</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the latest innovation in gaming graphics with Automatic super resolution (Auto SR)—the first OS-integrated AI super resolution (SR) technique where your games not only play smoother, but look stunning too! Ready for a quick visual challenge? Take a glance at these side-by-side images of Borderlands 3 played natively at 1440p versus one rendered at 720p but enhanced by AI-based Auto SR.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/autosr 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in Visual Studio Code – June 2024 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The June 2024 release of the Python and Jupyter extensions for Visual Studio Code are now available. This month&#39;s updates include an experimental Python REPL with Intellisense and syntax highlighting, and pytest improvements on the testing rewrite. Keep reading to learn more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-visual-studio-code-june-2024-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Your Own AI-Driven Code Analysis Chatbot for Developers with the GenAI Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We dive into a winning Docker AI/ML Hackathon submission, Code Explorer, which might spark project ideas for you.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-your-own-ai-driven-code-analysis-chatbot-genai-stack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification validates app compliance through annual pen testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn more about the Microsoft 365 Certification and how pen testing can help verify your app’s underlying security.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-validates-app-compliance-through-annual-pen-testing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can INI files be Unicode? Yes, they can, but it has to be your idea</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;ll only be Unicode if it&#39;s already Unicode.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240606-00/?p=109861 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop Kubernetes Operators in Java without Breaking a Sweat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 13:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover testing possibilities that let developers consider Java as the language of choice for Kubernetes-related projects.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/develop-kubernetes-operators-in-java-without-breaking-a-sweat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livestream – An Authentic Voice in Young Professionals: Why and How Educators Should Foster It</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 12:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us on Tuesday, June 18, at 3:00 pm UTC for the third livestream in the JetBrains Academy series for educators, An Authentic Voice in Young Professionals: Why and How Educators Should Foster It with Andrew Paul. Andrew has extensive teaching experience at various academic levels. He started his journey in education with Kainos, Queen’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2024/06/06/an-authentic-voice-in-young-professionals-why-and-how-educators-should-foster-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 10:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? A commonly used sorting algorithm known as Bogosort is also referred to as the ‘slow sort’. Because the algorithm works by generating all permutations of its input until it finds one that is sorted, makes it significantly inefficient and impractical for large data sets. Despite its impracticality, it’s often mentioned in computer […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/06/dotinsights-june-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Trial Periods Now Available for Plugins on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 10:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Selling your plugins on JetBrains Marketplace comes with numerous benefits. The platform handles licensing and billing, eliminating the need for a custom solution and simplifying the checkout process by taking care of payment processing and sales-related communications. JetBrains Marketplace allows you to fine-tune your offering, including volume and community discounts, as well as coupons with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2024/06/flexible-trial-periods-now-available-for-plugins-on-jetbrains-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Code Analysis for Spring: Run Analysis, Fix Critical Errors, Hit the Beach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fun fact: 72% of our JVM users use Spring in their applications, especially in industries like manufacturing and finance. Why? Spring makes programming with Java and Kotlin quicker, easier, and safer for everybody – but it also comes with unique challenges. Why is it so tricky to manage code quality in Spring? Spring has a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2024/06/static-code-analysis-for-spring-run-analysis-fix-critical-errors-hit-the-beach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bouncy Castle Cryptography Library for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 05:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cryptography remains an ever-important topic in building modern security-minded applications. Bouncy Castle is a cryptography library for .NET that allows users to build robust cryptography features. In this article, we will cover just a few important capabilities Bouncy Castle offers us and how to implement them. Let’s get started! What is Bouncy Castle? Bouncy Castle […] The post Bouncy Castle Cryptography Library for .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New LinkedIn Learning Course on Semantic Kernel Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 20:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today’s topic will cover a new LinkedIn Learning Course here: If you can code in .NET, you are an AI developer | LinkedIn Learning focused on Semantic Kernel Fundamentals. We are excited to welcome back José Luis Latorre Millás, an MVP for Microsoft focused on AI who worked on this to dive in further.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/new-linkedin-learning-course-on-semantic-kernel-fundamentals 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect email phishing attempts using Amazon Comprehend</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 19:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Phishing is the process of attempting to acquire sensitive information such as usernames, passwords and credit card details by masquerading as a trustworthy entity using email, telephone or text messages. There are many types of phishing based on the mode of communication and targeted victims. In an Email phishing attempt, an email is sent as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/detect-email-phishing-attempts-using-amazon-comprehend/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combat impersonation using Face Check with Microsoft Entra Verified ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 18:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post highlights the need for better identity verification methods to prevent fraud and impersonation. Microsoft Entra Verified ID&#39;s Face Check, showcased at Microsoft Build 2024, enhances security by comparing live selfies with trusted photos, effectively preventing unauthorized access and detecting spoofing techniques.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/verified-id-face-check 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSTest 3.4 is here with WinUI support and new analyzers!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSTest 3.4 is available. Learn all about the highlighted features and fixes that will make your testing experience always better.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-mstest-34 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating C&#43;&#43; header units into Office using MSVC (3/n)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 16:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview Recap: Where we were, what we’re doing now. Changes adopted in Word: Composing headers for reuse. Testing Details: The setup of the performance experiment. Opportunity for Improvement: Identifying a potential performance bottleneck. Upcoming Improvements to MSVC. What’s next for Office?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/integrating-c-header-units-into-office-using-msvc-3-n 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Skyflow creates technical content in days using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 15:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guest post is co-written with Manny Silva, Head of Documentation at Skyflow, Inc. Startups move quickly, and engineering is often prioritized over documentation. Unfortunately, this prioritization leads to release cycles that don’t match, where features release but documentation lags behind. This leads to increased support calls and unhappy customers. Skyflow is a data privacy […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-skyflow-creates-technical-content-in-days-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writerside’s First AI EAP Release is Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 14:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The first Writerside build with AI-powered features is now available as part of its Early Access Program. Read on the full story, or jump straight to the new features. No longer a threat, AI is a writer’s friend Just one year ago, tech writers felt threatened by the AI breakthrough and were worried their jobs […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/writerside/2024/06/writerside-s-first-ai-eap-release-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving our Azure marketplace images a makeover</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We previously announced the addition of new, optimized Azure VM image offers to help you create and test your applications faster and more easily on Azure VMs and the Microsoft Dev Box service. As we continue to evolve and optimize our offers,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/giving-our-visual-studio-azure-marketplace-images-a-makeover 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How 16-bit Windows cached INI files for performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Taking advantage of co-operative multitasking.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240605-00/?p=109852 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2024.2 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the first Rider 2024.2 Early Access Program (EAP) build just around the corner, we thought we’d give you an idea of what we’re working on for the next major update. The following is a list of our priorities for the next release. Note that these are the features we’re working on, however some might […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/05/rider-2024-2-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – June 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 08:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly is here! This month, we’re thrilled to welcome Tom Cools to share some of the interesting things he’s found of late in our Featured Content section. As always, we bring you the latest Java news, highlighting the key JEPs set to be available in Java 23. You’ll also […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/06/java-annotated-monthly-june-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and downloading a PDF or DOCX in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post shows how a PDF can be created from data in an ASP.NET Core backend and downloaded using an API. The data could be loaded from different locations and exported then as a PDF or a docx or whatever you require. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/AspNetCoreCreatePdf Why GemBox? There are many different tools to generate PDF all […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/06/05/creating-and-downloading-a-pdf-or-docx-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing ExecuteAsync() and StartAsync() Methods from the BackgroundService Class in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 05:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Due to the emerging significance of running background tasks, .NET Core has given us new ways of achieving it. BackgroundService is another tool in our toolbox with methods ExecuteAsync() and StartAsync() being the central components. In this article, we will compare these methods and demonstrate when and how to use them. We will first introduce […] The post Comparing ExecuteAsync() and StartAsync() Methods from the BackgroundService Class in .NET appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the Potential of Generative AI in Azure SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI is not just a technological advancement; it’s a paradigm shift that is redefining the landscape of customer interaction. Azure SQL Database stands at the forefront of this revolution, offering unparalleled opportunities to harness the power of “your data” in crafting state-of-the-art applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/unleashing-the-potential-of-generative-ai-in-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating One Billion MSAL.NET Downloads</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 22:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Celebrating the first billion downloads of the Microsoft Authentication Library for .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/msal-net-one-billion 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[security] Go 1.22.4-1 and 1.21.11-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 22:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft builds of the Go security patches released today, June 4, are now available for download. The new versions are: 1.22.4-1 1.21.11-1 For more information about the changes included in this release, take a look at the upstream Go announcement: [security] Go 1.22.4 and Go 1.21.11 are released.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/security-go-1-22-4-1-and-1-21-11-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline custom model creation and deployment for Amazon Bedrock with Provisioned Throughput using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 17:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As customers seek to incorporate their corpus of knowledge into their generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications, or to build domain-specific models, their data science teams often want to conduct A/B testing and have repeatable experiments. In this post, we discuss a solution that uses infrastructure as code (IaC) to define the process of retrieving and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-custom-model-creation-and-deployment-for-amazon-bedrock-with-provisioned-throughput-using-terraform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A beginner’s guide to mapping arrays in EF Core 8</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            EF Core 8 introduces support for mapping typed arrays of simple values to database columns so the semantics of the mapping can be used in the SQL generated from LINQ queries.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/array-mapping-in-ef-core-8 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost productivity with video conferencing transcripts and summaries with the Amazon Chime SDK Meeting Summarizer solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 16:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Businesses today heavily rely on video conferencing platforms for effective communication, collaboration, and decision-making. However, despite the convenience these platforms offer, there are persistent challenges in seamlessly integrating them into existing workflows. One of the major pain points is the lack of comprehensive tools to automate the process of joining meetings, recording discussions, and extracting […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-productivity-with-video-conferencing-transcripts-and-summaries-with-the-amazon-chime-sdk-meeting-summarizer-solution/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing UNISTR and || operator in Azure SQL Database – preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that the UNISTR intrinsic function and ANSI SQL concatenation operator (||) are now available in public preview in Azure SQL Database. The UNISTR function allows you to escape Unicode characters, making it easier to work with international text.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/announcing-unistr-and-ansi-sql-concatenation-operator-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize ASP.NET Web Forms applications in-place using DotVVM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 15:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was co-authored by Alok Bhatnagar, Technical Account Manager, AWS, and Tomáš Herceg, founder of DotVVM, an open-source framework that simplifies creating line-of-business web applications for .NET developers. Since the genesis of the .NET Framework, ASP.NET Web Forms has been a popular choice for building websites. Even to this day, there are thousands of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/dotnet/modernize-asp-net-web-forms-applications-in-place-using-dotvvm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Fluid DevTools to debug your web app</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 15:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A guide to using the Fluid DevTools browser extension to inspect and manipulate Fluid data structures and containers.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/use-fluid-devtools-to-debug-your-web-app 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions: Get Current Branch Name for Git Repo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 14:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to get the current branch name in GitHub Actions can be useful for workflows that trigger off of multiple branches of a GitHub repository. The reason this can be useful is that the branch name may be important to mark or tag the code release in some way (i.e. tag a docker image), or […] The article GitHub Actions: Get Current Branch Name for Git Repo was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Global­Lock max out at 255 locks?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Because that&#39;s how many bits were available for reporting the lock count.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240604-00/?p=109847 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Announces SOC 2 Type 2 Attestation &amp; ISO 27001 Certification</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 13:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker demonstrates commitment to security by achieving SOC 2 Type 2 attestation and ISO 27001 certification.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-announces-soc-2-type-2-attestation-iso-27001-certification/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Hands-On with Visual Studio and Azure: Live at Microsoft HQ this August!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio LIVE! Microsoft HQ 2024 August 5-9 | Microsoft Conference Center, Redmond, WA Join the Ultimate Developer Celebration! Who’s ready to connect with fellow developers and Visual Studio Product Managers this August at the Microsoft Campus in Redmond? Visual Studio Live!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/get-hands-on-with-visual-studio-and-azure-live-at-microsoft-hq-this-august 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Pipelines Pulse, Issue #2: Drag, Drop, Deploy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 10:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine you could click your way through a pipeline configuration. How much easier would that be? Guess what: Now you can define dependencies between jobs in TeamCity Pipelines with a simple drag and drop. Just click on the job that you’d like to connect with another one – and voilà! In case you prefer the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/06/teamcity-pipelines-pulse-issue2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditionally skipping a trigger job in GitLab based on a previous job</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe the approaches I explored to conditionally skip a trigger job in GitLab based on a previous job using dynamic pipelines
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/conditionally-skipping-a-trigger-job-in-gitlab-based-on-a-previous-job/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tarsier Studios Brings Little Nightmares to Life With JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 08:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we have Tristan Louet and Meghan Corso from Tarsier Studios with us. Meghan is actively involved in advancing Unreal Engine support in JetBrains Rider and ReSharper C++, while Tristan leads the core technology team, focusing on plugins, reusable solutions, infrastructure, and methodologies. This special interview will give you a firsthand insight into their experiences […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/06/04/how-tarsier-studios-brings-little-nightmares-to-life-with-jetbrains-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Testing Processes with Contract Testing and Pact in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Optimize your .NET development workflow with contract testing and Pact. Explore the transformative impact of contract testing on testing cycles, reliability, and integration. Unlock the potential of seamless software development.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/contract-testing-net-software-development-pact/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Exception.HResult property in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 08:24:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since launching support for showing parsed HRESULT on the elmah.io UI, we have received a few questions about HRESULTs in general. While I understand that HRESULTs is probably not on everyone&#39;s radar, I think a general understanding will help with debugging. In this post, I&#39;ll asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/understanding-the-exception-hresult-property-in-c/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Mock IConfiguration.GetValue in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 05:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll take a closer look at how we can mock IConfiguration.GetValue when writing unit tests in ASP.NET Core. Let’s start! Mock IConfiguration.GetValue in ASP.NET Core Before we start mocking, we need a class that utilizes IConfiguration: public class FinanceService(IConfiguration configuration) : IFinanceService { public double CalculateTotalAmount(double hours) { var hourlyRate = configuration.GetValue(&amp;quot;FinanceSettings:HourlyRate&amp;quot;); […] The post How to Mock IConfiguration.GetValue in ASP.NET Core appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
