<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:53:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the new year with the first Early Access Program (EAP) build for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1! This is your chance to get an exclusive first look at the upcoming features and improvements designed to make your coding workflow more efficient than ever. You can download this version from our website, update directly from […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HCLTech’s AWS powered AutoWise Companion: A seamless experience for informed automotive buyer decisions with data-driven design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces HCLTech’s AutoWise Companion, a transformative generative AI solution designed to enhance customers’ vehicle purchasing journey. In this post, we analyze the current industry challenges and guide readers through the AutoWise Companion solution functional flow and architecture design using built-in AWS services and open source tools. Additionally, we discuss the design from security and responsible AI perspectives, demonstrating how you can apply this solution to a wider range of industry scenarios.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating risk: AWS backbone network traffic prediction using GraphStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can use our enterprise graph machine learning (GML) framework GraphStorm to solve prediction challenges on large-scale complex networks inspired by our practices of exploring GML to mitigate the AWS backbone network congestion risk.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mitigating-risk-aws-backbone-network-traffic-prediction-using-graphstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does Get­User­Default­Geo­Name choose between ISO 3166-1 and UN M.49 codes?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Clarifying the behavior.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250115-59/?p=110769 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips and Tricks for Adopting GitHub Copilot at Scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction​ Adopting GitHub Copilot at scale can be a game-changer for many development teams (especially large or distributed teams). This blog post provides best practices, actionable tips, and tricks to ensure a successful adoption of GitHub Copilot to ensure successful adoption at scale, foster engagement, and maximize the return on investment (ROI). 1. Raise Awareness […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/adopting-github-copilot-at-scale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program (EAP) for CLion 2025.1 has officially launched. The first EAP build, 251.14649.40, is here to provide an early look at some of the improvements coming in the next major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/01/2025-1-eap-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? The Y2K bug, or “Millennium Bug,” was a programming issue caused by storing years with only two digits (e.g., “1999” as “99”) to save memory. As 2000 approached, systems risked interpreting “00” as 1900, leading to potential errors in calculations and data processing. Fears of disruptions in critical systems like banking and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/15/dotinsights-january-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify AI Development with the Model Context Protocol and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started using the Model Context Protocol to experiment with AI capabilities using Docker Desktop.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/simplify-ai-development-with-the-model-context-protocol-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user delegated access token management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article looks at managing user delegated access tokens for a downstream API in an ASP.NET Core web application. There are many ways of implementing this, all with advantages and disadvantages. The tokens are requested from an OpenID Connect server using the recommended standards. In this blog, the UI access token from the application authentication […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/01/15/asp-net-core-user-delegated-access-token-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI Explained: A Philosophical Framework for Understanding AI Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine an AI-powered world where assistance goes beyond tasks — where intelligent agents debate, learn and collaborate with the wisdom of history’s greatest minds. What if Socrates, Plato, and Aristotle could step into the digital age, engaging in vibrant discussions and offering their timeless perspectives. In this article, I’ll delve into how AI agents can […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/agentic-philosophers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Semantic Kernel AI Connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI Connectors in Semantic Kernel are components that facilitate communication between the Kernel’s core functionalities and various AI services. They abstract the intricate details of service-specific protocols, allowing developers to seamlessly interact with AI services for tasks like text generation, chat interactions, and more. Using AI Connectors in Semantic Kernel Developers utilize AI connectors […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/understanding-semantic-kernel-ai-connectors 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework January 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 21:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for January 2025. Let’s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what’s new in these releases: Security Improvements .NET updates .NET Framework updates Security improvements This month you will find several CVEs that have been fixed this month: […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/net-and-net-framework-january-2025-servicing-releases-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement RAG while meeting data residency requirements using AWS hybrid and edge services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 18:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to extend Amazon Bedrock Agents to hybrid and edge services such as AWS Outposts and AWS Local Zones to build distributed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) applications with on-premises data for improved model outcomes. With Outposts, we also cover a reference pattern for a fully local RAG application that requires both the foundation model (FM) and data sources to reside on premises.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking complex problem-solving with multi-agent collaboration on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The research team at AWS has worked extensively on building and evaluating the multi-agent collaboration (MAC) framework so customers can orchestrate multiple AI agents on Amazon Bedrock Agents. In this post, we explore the concept of multi-agent collaboration (MAC) and its benefits, as well as the key components of our MAC framework. We also go deeper into our evaluation methodology and present insights from our studies.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-complex-problem-solving-with-multi-agent-collaboration-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us at VS Live! 2025 Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join Your Favorite Speakers at VS Live! Las Vegas With the new year here, many developers are looking for the best ways to stay ahead in a rapidly evolving tech landscape. That’s why Visual Studio Live! Las Vegas, March 10-14, 2025, is a must-attend event! Stay ahead of the curve with the latest enhancements in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/vs-live-2025-las-vegas 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Storage—A look back and a look forward</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Storage has evolved to bolster the evolution of Microsoft AI and enterprise cloud onboarding with multiple innovations. The post Azure Storage—A look back and a look forward appeared first on Microsoft Azure Blog.
Link to article: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/azure-storage-a-look-back-and-a-look-forward/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Conversation: Call for Proposals for Azure Cosmos DB Conf 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you passionate about Azure Cosmos DB? Do you have insights, experiences, or innovations that the developer community would love to hear? Now is your chance to shine at the Azure Cosmos DB Conference 2025 – a free, virtual developer event co-organized by Microsoft and the vibrant Azure Cosmos DB community. Mark your calendar for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/join-the-conversation-call-for-proposals-for-azure-cosmos-db-conf-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: The walk-on topic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just walk on in with your topic.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250114-00/?p=110762 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Powerful Devs Conference &#43; Hack Together 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 14:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to invite you to participate in this year’s Powerful Devs Conference + Hackathon, commencing on February 12, 2025. The conference will be followed by a two-week Hack Together, ending on February 28, 2025. Join us to unleash your creativity and build innovation solutions!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-powerful-devs-conference-and-hack-together-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Factory Pattern: Solving JSON Deserialization Challenges in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to implement the Static Factory Pattern in .NET while handling JSON serialization challenges. Discover practical solutions using System.Text.Json with example implementations and best practices
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/static-factory-pattern-json-serialization-dotnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading compilation options and the C# version in source generators: Creating a source generator - Part 12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to read details of a target project from a source generator, such as assembly name, the current configuration, or the c# version
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/creating-a-source-generator-part-12-reading-compilation-options-and-csharp-version-in-source-generators/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Records, Structs, and Classes in C#: When to Use What?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 07:48:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# provides a few ways to define types—records, structures, and classes. Each has its own qualities and limitations. In this blog post, I will discuss each construct and help you identify which one to use in your project.
What is a class in C#?
A class defines reference types,
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/comparing-records-structs-and-classes-in-c-when-to-use-what/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmos DB Embeddings Generator Sample</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever since our first preview announcement for vector indexing and support for DiskANN and then again when we announced the GA for these features, customers have been asking us to make it easier to generate Azure OpenAI embeddings on their data in Azure Cosmos DB. So we did just that and created the Azure Cosmos […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/embeddings-generator-sample 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Logging in ASP.NET: how to automatically log all incoming HTTP requests (and its downsides!)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aren’t you tired of adding manual logs to your HTTP APIs to log HTTP requests and responses? By using a built-in middleware in ASP.NET, you will be able to centralize logs management and have a clear view of all the incoming HTTP requests.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/httplogging-asp-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BQA streamlines education quality reporting using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Education and Training Quality Authority (BQA) plays a critical role in improving the quality of education and training services in the Kingdom Bahrain. BQA reviews the performance of all education and training institutions, including schools, universities, and vocational institutes, thereby promoting the professional advancement of the nation’s human capital. In this post, we explore how BQA used the power of Amazon Bedrock, Amazon SageMaker JumpStart, and other AWS services to streamline the overall reporting workflow.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting team innovation, productivity, and knowledge sharing with Amazon Q Business – Web experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how MuleSoft introduced a generative AI-powered assistant using Amazon Q Business to enhance their internal Cloud Central dashboard. This individualized portal shows assets owned, costs and usage, and well-architected recommendations to over 100 engineers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boosting-team-innovation-productivity-and-knowledge-sharing-with-amazon-q-business-web-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simplified overview of ways to add or update elements in a std::map</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            And using it to find missing opportunities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250113-00/?p=110757 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Gordon: An AI Agent for Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We share our experiments creating a Docker AI Agent, named Gordon, which can help new users learn about our tools and products and help power users get things done faster.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/meet-gordon-an-ai-agent-for-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing CodeCanvas 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we enter 2025, we hope you had an amazing holiday season filled with joy, relaxation, and plenty of inspiration for the year ahead! CodeCanvas 2024.3, last year’s final release, went live just before the holidays. To avoid adding to the busy year-end rush, we delayed the announcement until now, ensuring it gets the attention […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/codecanvas/2025/01/introducing-codecanvas-2024-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Files vs. A Server with an SMB Share: Key Takeaways from MS Cloud IT Pro Podcast Episode 367</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MS Cloud IT Pro Podcast episode 367, hosted by Ben Segink and Scott Hoag, dives deep into a crucial IT topic: choosing between Azure Files and a traditional server with an SMB share for file storage in the cloud. This episode is essential for IT professionals navigating cloud migration strategies and balancing infrastructure needs. […] The article Azure Files vs. A Server with an SMB Share: Key Takeaways from MS Cloud IT Pro Podcast Episode 367 was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Change Signature in C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Change Signature allows you to modify a function’s parameters, including reordering, adding, removing, or altering them across various locations. Previously, the Change Signature feature in Visual Studio involved multiple clicks and nested pop-up windows. In Visual Studio 2022 version 17.12, we’ve reduced the number of clicks and eliminated these nested steps to streamline the process. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/enhanced-change-signature-in-c 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your .NET HttpClient with HSTS Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HTTP Strict Transport Security (HSTS) is a security feature that indicates a client to only connect to a website over HTTPS. Websites can set the Strict-Transport-Security header to inform the client to always use HTTPS. ASP.NET Core can easily set the header, but there is no built-in feature to enable HSTS for an HttpClient. In this post, I describe how to create an HttpClient that supports HSTS,…
Link to article: https://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Perform Snapshot Testing With Verify in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to discuss how to perform snapshot testing on objects using the Verify library. Testing is an important part of our software development pipeline. As developers, we often rely on familiar testing approaches like unit testing, where we assert the behavior of individual components of an application, and integration testing, […] The post How to Perform Snapshot Testing With Verify in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop the Leaks: Properly Disposing Objects in .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article highlights the persistent issue of failing to call Dispose() on disposable objects in .NET projects, which leads to memory leaks and system instability. The author recommends using IDisposableAnalyzers and memory profilers to detect these issues, alongside custom extension methods for easier disposal management, advocating for proactive solutions to maintain application performance.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/01/13/stop-the-leaks-properly-disposing-objects-in-net/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine 3.6: Modular Monolith and Vertical Slice Architecture Goodies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wolverine 3.6 just went out tonight as a big release with bug fixes and quite a few significant features to improve Wolverine‘s usability for modular monolith architectures and to further improve Wolverine’s already outstanding usability for vertical slice architecture. Highlights: And of course, the full list of closed issues addressed by this release. As a little … Continue reading Wolverine 3.6: Modular Monolith and Vertical Slice Architecture Goodies →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How and Why To Learn In Public - Dev Leader Weekly 78</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss how to and why you should learn in public as a developer!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/01/11/how-and-why-to-learn-in-public-dev-leader-weekly-78 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Token Usage with Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing in my recent series of posts about calling LLMs with C# using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI NuGet package, in this post I want to discuss how to track the cost of your API calls to AI models. Each AI provider will have its own pricing structure for the various models it offers. For example, here are pricing pages for Azure OpenAI service, OpenAI&#39;s own API, Anthropic&#39;s API, Google Gemini API, DeepSeek API, Amazon Bedrock, and xAI Grok.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with LLMs in .NET using Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2025/11_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft.Extensions.AI provides a unified interface for integrating LLMs into .NET applications, allowing developers to switch between providers like Ollama, Azure, or OpenAI without changing application code. Through practical examples of chat completion, article summarization, and smart categorization, this article demonstrates how to leverage the library&#39;s features while running LLMs locally using Ollama.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/working-with-llms-in-dotnet-using-microsoft-extensions-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Azure Networking Outage in East US 2 Affecting VMs, App Service, and More! (Started January 8, 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On January 8, 2025, Microsoft Azure started experiencing a significant networking outage in the East US 2 region. This outage has impacted a broad range of Azure services (including Azure App Service, VMs, and more!) causing disruptions for businesses relying on these services for critical workloads. As of the time I’m writing this, the issue […] The article Major Azure Networking Outage in East US 2 Affecting VMs, App Service, and More!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Patterns for Building Resilient Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When the CrowdStrike incident happened, I was alarmed and notified of a degrading performance in parts of our system. That’s because we were indirectly impacted. I will provide some thoughts about how specific design patterns allow you to build resilient systems, allowing you to keep your system alive and online. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where… Read More »Design Patterns for Building Resilient Systems The post Design Patterns for Building Resilient Systems appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does inadvertently passing a std::string instead of a char const* to a variadic function crash on x86-32 but not x86-64?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Looking at the calling convention and the small string optimization.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250110-00/?p=110744 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Public Preview of Apple Identity Provider Support for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the public preview of &amp;quot;Sign in with Apple&amp;quot; support for Microsoft Entra External ID. This feature allows users to sign up and sign in to applications using their Apple ID. Apple joins Google and Facebook as pre-configured social identity providers, supporting Single Sign-On (SSO) through the OAuth framework.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/openid-connect-social-identity-provider-apple 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LLMOps in restricted networks and addressing continuous evaluation long run constraints</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we&#39;ll explore the challenges we faced in establishing LLMOps and continuous evaluation within a pipeline using Azure Machine Learning, particularly when dealing with long runs and a restricted Bring-Your-Own (BYO) network.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/llmops-in-restricted-networks-and-continuous-evaluation-long-run-constraints 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>通过 .NET Aspire 使用本地 AI 模型</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2025/10_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Aaron Powell的Using Local AI models with .NET Aspire 使用本地 AI 模型是在您自己的计算机上进行实验的一个很好的方法，它无需将资源部署到云中。在本文中，我们将了解如何使用.NET Aspire 和 Ollama 在本地运行 AI 模型，同时使用 Microsoft.Extensions.AI 抽象使其在部署时过渡到云托管模型。 在 .NET Aspire 中设置 Ollama 我们需要某种方法来从 .NET Aspire 应用程序中使用 Ollama，最简单的方法就是使用 .NET Aspire 社区工具包中的 Ollama 托管集成。您可以通过 Visual Studio 工具、VS Code 工具或 .NET CLI 从 NuGet 安装 Ollama 托管集成。让我们看一下如何通过命令行将 Ollama 托管集成安装到我们的应用程序主机项目中： dotnet add package CommunityToolkit.Aspire.Hosting.Ollama 安装 Ollama 托管集成后，您可以在 Program.cs […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e9%80%9a%e8%bf%87-net-aspire-%e4%bd%bf%e7%94%a8%e6%9c%ac%e5%9c%b0-ai-%e6%a8%a1%e5%9e%8b 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering AI Agents with Tools via OpenAPI: A Hands-On Guide with Microsoft Semantic Kernel Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 22:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today the Semantic Kernel team is happy to welcome back our guest author, Akshay Kokane. We will turn it over to him to dive into his recent Medium article on Semantic Kernel. As we advance towards an Agentic Approach in the AI world, I would like to share my insights on how Semantic Kernel can […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/empowering-ai-agents-with-tools-via-openapi-a-hands-on-guide-with-microsoft-semantic-kernel-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Essentials: Building Basics with Microsoft Copilot Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 22:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Exploring the Essentials: Building Basics with Microsoft Copilot Studio Don’t know how to start with building an agent in Microsoft Copilot Studio? We’ve got you covered! In our AI in Action: Building with Copilot Studio series on the Power Platform YouTube channel, we have several episodes that guide you through how to get started in […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/exploring-the-essentials-building-basics-with-microsoft-copilot-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 21:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has announced the retirement of Azure CDN services from the azureedge.net domain by January 15, 2025, driven by Edgio’s (formerly Limelight Networks) business closure. This domain underpins Azure CDN services, .NET installations, and content delivery for various Azure and Microsoft services. The shift requires developers and DevOps teams to update configurations, pipelines, and deployment […] The article Retirement of AzureEdge.net DNS: Edg.io Business Closure and What You Need to Know was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an Amazon Bedrock based digital lending solution on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 20:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we propose a solution using DigitalDhan, a generative AI-based solution to automate customer onboarding and digital lending. The proposed solution uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to automate services related to KYC verification, credit and risk assessment, and notification. Financial institutions can use this solution to help automate the customer onboarding, KYC verification, credit decisioning, credit underwriting, and notification processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-amazon-bedrock-based-digital-lending-solution-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI-powered malware analysis using Amazon Bedrock with Deep Instinct</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Deep Instinct’s generative AI-powered malware analysis tool, DIANNA, uses Amazon Bedrock to revolutionize cybersecurity by providing rapid, in-depth analysis of known and unknown threats, enhancing the capabilities of AWS System and Organization Controls (SOC) teams and addressing key challenges in the evolving threat landscape.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-ai-powered-malware-analysis-using-amazon-bedrock-with-deep-instinct/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email your conversations from Amazon Q</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As organizations navigate the complexities of the digital realm, generative AI has emerged as a transformative force, empowering enterprises to enhance productivity, streamline workflows, and drive innovation. To maximize the value of insights generated by generative AI, it is crucial to provide simple ways for users to preserve and share these insights using commonly used tools such as email. This post explores how you can integrate Amazon Q Business with Amazon SES to email conversations to specified email addresses.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code update – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 17:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re kicking off the new year with exciting updates to Teams Toolkit for Visual Studio Code including a refreshed user interface for getting started and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/teams-toolkit-for-visual-studio-code-update-january-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MWA pattern: Strangler Fig</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 13:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Author’s Note: After announcing the Modern Web App (MWA) pattern (https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/introducing-the-modern-web-app-mwa-pattern-for-java), we now focus on one of its many pattens – the Strangler Fig pattern. This pattern incrementally modernizes a legacy Java application by “strangling” targeted areas and replacing them with new microservices or minimal web apps. We’ll explore an example showing how to integrate […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/mwa-pattern-strangler-fig 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incident Update: Docker Desktop for Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker has identified and provided a temporary workaround for an issue preventing Docker Desktop from starting on some macOS systems, with a permanent fix currently in development.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/incident-update-docker-desktop-for-mac/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock cost-effective AI inference using Amazon Bedrock serverless capabilities with an Amazon SageMaker trained model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 22:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies such as AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Mistral AI, Stability AI, and Amazon through a single API, along with a broad set of capabilities to build generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. In this post, I’ll show you how to use Amazon Bedrock—with its fully managed, on-demand API—with your Amazon SageMaker trained or fine-tuned model.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Dockerize a Django App: Step-by-Step Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We show how to create a Docker container for your Django application, which gives you a standardized environment and makes it easier to get up and running and be more productive.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-dockerize-django-app/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server Native Vector Search for .NET Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It seems that the majority of developers naturally believe this field of software development belongs to mathematics and Python developers, who originally started building the first solutions. However, .NET and C# provide a great foundation for building almost any kind of application on any platform in a highly professional way. In this post, we will […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/sql-server-native-vector-search-for-net-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a RAG-Based Smart Memory Application with Azure SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Project Mission The way people work and manage information is changing rapidly in our digital age. More and more people are struggling to keep track of all the online resources they use daily. They need a better way to save, organize, and retrieve important information from websites, articles, and other online sources. This is especially […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/building-a-rag-based-smart-memory-application-with-azure-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term real-world data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/01/data-cleaning-in-data-science/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside STL: Waiting for a std::atomic&lt;std::shared_ptr&lt;T&gt;&gt; to change, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Waiting on a single pointer, but checking for two.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250108-00/?p=110732 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Efficiency with Docker for AI and Cloud-Native Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker helps you deliver secure, efficient applications by providing consistent environments and building on best practices that let you discover and resolve issues earlier in the software development life cycle (SDLC).
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/unlocking-efficiency-with-docker-for-ai-and-cloud-native-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Developer CLI: Accelerate App &amp; Infrastructure Deployment on Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As developers and organizations increasingly adopt cloud solutions, streamlining the deployment of applications and infrastructure becomes a critical part of achieving efficiency and scalability. Microsoft’s Azure Developer CLI (azd) addresses this by providing an integrated, open-source command-line tool that accelerates the journey from local development to Azure deployment. Whether you’re a solo developer or part […] The article Introduction to Azure Developer CLI: Accelerate App &amp;amp; Infrastructure Deployment on Microsoft Azure was originally published on Build5Nines.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The start of the new year is the perfect time to share our plans for JetBrains Rider 2025.1. These plans are subject to change based on available resources, evolving development priorities, and shifts in the .NET landscape. Some features and improvements may be postponed to a later release date. With that in mind, let’s dive […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/01/08/rider-2025-1-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Plan Support for GitHub Copilot Available on JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, developers! Welcome to our very first blog post dedicated to GitHub Copilot Plugin for JetBrains IDEs in 2025. We are excited to share that the new Free Plan for GitHub Copilot has been available for everyone on JetBrains IDEs! Whether you use IntelliJ IDEA (Ultimate, Community, Educational), PyCharm(Professional, Community, Educational), WebStorm, PhpStorm, Rider, or […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/free-plan-support-for-github-copilot-available-on-jetbrains-ides 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2025/08_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new year has arrived, and we’re kicking it off with another handpicked selection of must-read tutorials and the latest news you won’t want to miss. This issue starts with an amazing featured content section with Donald Raab. Settle in and scroll your way to some fresh knowledge! Featured Content Greetings, Java Annotated Monthly readers! […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/01/java-annotated-monthly-january-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
