<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 22:21:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Function Calling Model Available in .NET for Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 22:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce release of the new function-calling model that is available in Semantic Kernel v1.20. The new model incorporates the best parts of the existing function-calling model, such as ease of use, and improves on it by making it more extensible and reusable. using Microsoft.SemanticKernel; IKernelBuilder builder = Kernel.CreateBuilder(); // Register OpenAI […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/new-function-calling-model-available-in-net-for-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build RAG-based generative AI applications in AWS using Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 17:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP with Amazon Bedrock to provide a RAG experience for your generative AI applications on AWS by bringing company-specific, unstructured user file data to Amazon Bedrock in a straightforward, fast, and secure way.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-rag-based-generative-ai-applications-in-aws-using-amazon-fsx-for-netapp-ontap-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observability in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many of you have asked similar questions: How do I obtain the rendered prompt that Semantic Kernel sends to the AI service? How do I monitor the token usage of my application? How do I gain insights into Semantic Kernel’s operations during runtime? These are all excellent questions! They fundamentally belong to the same class […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/observability-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2024.3 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for CLion 2024.3 is officially launched. The first EAP build 243.12818.61 is now available, giving you an early glimpse into the enhancements we’ll include in the upcoming major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/09/2024-3-eap-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack Introduces Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the new YouTrack 2024.3 release, one of the most hotly anticipated functionalities in the YouTrack roadmap – apps – goes live! Apps help teams customize YouTrack to fit their specific needs, improving project management, reporting, automation, and integration with other tools. You can now use and create apps to extend YouTrack’s functionality and add […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/youtrack/2024/09/youtrack-introduces-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for AWS DeepComposer ending soon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS DeepComposer was first introduced during AWS re:Invent 2019 as a fun way for developers to compose music by using generative AI. AWS DeepComposer was the world’s first machine learning (ML)-enabled keyboard for developers to get hands-on—literally—with a musical keyboard and the latest ML techniques to compose their own music. After careful consideration, we have […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/support-for-aws-deepcomposer-ending-soon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserve access and explore alternatives for Amazon Lookout for Equipment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we discuss how you can maintain access to Lookout for Equipment after it is closed to new customers and some alternatives to Lookout for Equipment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/preserve-access-and-explore-alternatives-for-amazon-lookout-for-equipment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability (GA) of Microsoft Entra External ID extension for Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 15:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the new Microsoft Entra External ID extension for Visual Studio Code, now Generally Available (GA), created to simplify CIAM integration in your development process. See how this extension provides a smooth experience for setting up External ID applications from within VS Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/external-id-vs-code-extension-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 23 and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 15:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            New and updated Java language features, core API, and the JVM – Java 23 packs it all – for new Java developers to senior developers. IntelliJ IDEA 2024.2 is ready with its support for Java 23 features. Keeping pace with new Java version releases could be difficult – what changed, why, and how to use […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/java-23-and-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a GraphQL Client in .NET with JetBrains Rider and StrawberryShake</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 14:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many teams are using GraphQL for their API needs, thanks to its powerful query language and flexibility. Unlike traditional REST APIs, GraphQL lets you fetch the data you need in a single request, making your applications more efficient and responsive. However, it can be daunting getting started creating schemas, writing queries, and integrating GraphQL into […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2024/09/17/building-a-graphql-client-in-net-with-jetbrains-rider-and-strawberryshake/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It rather involved being on the other side of this airtight hatchway: Posting completions to somebody else’s I/O completion port</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have gained access to it, then that was the problem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240917-00/?p=110276 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for Web Developers: Getting Started with the Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Docker empowers web developers by providing efficient, scalable, and collaborative containerization tools that streamline development workflows, ensure consistency across environments, and enhance productivity for building, testing, and deploying web applications.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-for-web-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RubyMine 2024.3 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone! We’re starting the RubyMine 2024.3 Early Access Program today. In this blog post, we’ll inform you about the upcoming features and updates in this release cycle. What’s coming in RubyMine 2024.3? AI Assistant For RubyMine 2024.3, we’re working on several Ruby-specific AI features, focusing on context improvements for AI-powered unit test generation, explanation […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2024/09/the-rubymine-2024-3-early-access-program-is-open/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run .NET apps natively on Arm64 devices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you developing .NET applications for Arm-based processors? Do you want to take advantage of the performance and power efficiency of running your apps natively on Arm64 devices? If so, you’ll be happy to hear that Visual Studio 2022 17.11 has a new feature that makes it easier than ever to do just that. Visual […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-to-run-net-apps-natively-on-arm64-devices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing MAX_PATH issues in GitLab</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how you can enable Git&#39;s long-path support in a GitLab job to override Window&#39;s MAX_PATH limitations which can cause git clone failures
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/fixing-max_path-issues-in-gitlab/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Existing Code through TDD: A Password Case Study</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 08:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Week 4 of our Summer Craft Book, which Yann Courtel and I created, we focus on Test-Driven Development with the exercise below.The Initial ChallengeIn this exercise, our task was to create a program that validates a password following Test-Driven Development cycles based on the following criteria:At
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/evolving-existing-code-through-tdd-a-password-validator-case-study/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET User Secrets Demystified: Practical Usage and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 08:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to effectively use .NET User Secrets to secure sensitive data in your development process. This comprehensive guide covers initialization, management, and best practices.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/net-user-secrets-demystified-practical-usage-and-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Remote Development Challenges With CodeCanvas: A CDE Orchestration Tool by JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 07:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the public release of CodeCanvas, JetBrains’ new platform for orchestrating cloud development environments (CDEs). To better understand CodeCanvas and why it is important for JetBrains’ remote development strategy, let’s dive a bit into history and context. Remote development trend Many companies still rely on local development, a method that has several […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2024/09/17/introducing-codecanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Azure DevOps Security with GHAS Code Scanning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 07:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Debjyoti Ganguly shares insights on the security benefits and configuration of GHAS Code Scanning with Azure DevOps. Boosting Azure DevOps Security with GHAS Code Scanning Code scanning, a pipeline-based tool available in GitHub Advanced Security, is designed to detect code vulnerabilities and bugs within the source code of ADO (Azure DevOps) repositories. Utilizing CodeQL as […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/boosting-azure-devops-security-with-ghas-code-scanning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR-Cas9 guide RNA efficiency prediction with efficiently tuned models in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeat (CRISPR) technology holds the promise to revolutionize gene editing technologies, which is transformative to the way we understand and treat diseases. This technique is based in a natural mechanism found in bacteria that allows a protein coupled to a single guide RNA (gRNA) strand to locate and make […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/crispr-cas9-guide-rna-efficiency-prediction-with-efficiently-tuned-models-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve RAG performance using Cohere Rerank</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 19:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use Cohere Rerank to improve search efficiency and accuracy in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-rag-performance-using-cohere-rerank/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure by Design for AI: Building Resilient Systems from the Ground Up</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dive into the “Secure by Design” approach essential for AI systems, focusing on embedding security features from the start to fortify AI against emerging threats.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/secure-by-design-for-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on Win32 carets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Assorted notes and musings.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240916-00/?p=110272 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the behavior of the XAML Designer with abstract base classes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 13:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 introduced a new XAML designer for building WPF apps, with a goal of increasing the performance and reliability of the designer. The new designer can quickly open a XAML file by using WPF’s built-in parser and display. This new design has a nuanced behavior when the root XAML element derives from an […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/understanding-the-behavior-of-the-xaml-designer-with-abstract-base-classes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Livestream: Developing Spring Boot Applications With Joy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 12:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join us for a new IntelliJ IDEA Livestream episode, where we will explore how to build modern Spring Boot applications using IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate with Siva Reddy. Date: September 26, 2024 Time: 3:00 pm – 4:00 pm UTC REGISTER FOR THE LIVESTREAM Session abstract Spring Boot is the most popular application framework in the Java […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/new-livestream-java-22-and-intellij-ideanew-livestream/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for a ManualResetEventSlim to be set asynchronously</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ManualResetEventSlim represents a thread synchronization event that, when signaled, must be reset manually. This is a common synchronization primitive. However, it doesn&#39;t expose a method to wait asynchronously. Hopefully, it&#39;s not too complicated to create an extension method using ThreadPool.RegisterWaitForSingleObject and TaskCompletionSource. static class Extensions { public static Task WaitAsync(this…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/waiting-for-a-manualreseteventslim-to-be-set-asynchronously.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Ways To Use Jupyter Notebooks inside PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 10:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Jupyter notebooks allow you to tell stories by creating and sharing data, equations, and visualizations sequentially, with a supporting narrative as you go through the notebook. Jupyter notebooks in PyCharm Professional provide functionality above and beyond that of browser-based Jupyter notebooks, such as code completion, dynamic plots, and quick statistics, to help you explore and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2024/09/7-ways-to-use-jupyter-notebooks-inside-pycharm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Elasticsearch with .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 04:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to use Elasticsearch in .NET Aspire. Elasticsearch is setup to use HTTPS with the dotnet developer certificates and and simple client can be implemented to query the data. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/keycloak-backchannel Setup Two services are setup to run in .NET Aspire. The first service is the official Elasticsearch docker container and deployed […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2024/09/16/using-elasticsearch-with-net-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediator Design Pattern in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 02:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we are going to talk about a popular design pattern, the Mediator Pattern. We will see how this pattern helps address some design problems and how to implement it in C#. Let’s start. What is The Mediator Design Pattern? Mediator is a behavioral design pattern that promotes loose coupling by eliminating chaotic […] The post Mediator Design Pattern in C# appeared first on Code Maze.
Link to article: https://code-maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Unleashing the Power of Spargine’s Array Extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2024/15_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2024/15_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spargine, an open-source .NET 8 toolset, offers a variety of extension methods for arrays. The project&#39;s author emphasizes the benefits of enhanced performance and reliability. Community involvement is sought for further improvements and contributions. Detailed benchmark results are available on GitHub, and users are encouraged to provide feedback and suggestions. Contact dotnetdave@live.com for inquiries or contributions.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2024/09/15/boost-your-net-projects-unleashing-the-power-of-spargines-array-extensions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire: A Game-Changer for Cloud-Native Development?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_09_2024/14_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_09_2024/14_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Aspire promises to revolutionize cloud-native development for .NET applications, but does it live up to the hype? In this hands-on review, I&#39;ll share my experience migrating a real project to Aspire, exploring its strengths, limitations, and potential impact on how we build distributed systems.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/dotnet-aspire-a-game-changer-for-cloud-native-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock AWS Cost and Usage insights with generative AI powered by Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 18:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a solution that uses generative artificial intelligence (AI) to generate a SQL query from a user’s question in natural language. This solution can simplify the process of querying CUR data stored in an Amazon Athena database using SQL query generation, running the query on Athena, and representing it on a web portal for ease of understanding.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-aws-cost-and-usage-insights-with-generative-ai-powered-by-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline workflow orchestration of a system of enterprise APIs using chaining with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 18:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how chaining domain-specific agents using Amazon Bedrock Agents can transform a system of complex API interactions into streamlined, adaptive workflows, empowering your business to operate with agility and precision.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-workflow-orchestration-of-a-system-of-enterprise-apis-using-chaining-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build ultra-low latency multimodal generative AI applications using sticky session routing in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 18:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explained how the new sticky routing feature in Amazon SageMaker allows you to achieve ultra-low latency and enhance your end-user experience when serving multi-modal models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-ultra-low-latency-multimodal-generative-ai-applications-using-sticky-session-routing-in-amazon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the fail-fast crashes coming from the power management system</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding why it decided to fail fast.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240913-00/?p=110257 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code Update – August 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 10:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the August update for Visual Studio Code for Java! In this blog, we will cover important Gradle updates, more user experience improvements, and an improved getting started experience, let’s get started! Gradle Updates Adding Gradle for Java into Extension Pack for Java Some of our users might have noticed that recently […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-visual-studio-code-update-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Htmx for Spring Boot Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 09:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting a new project can be both exciting and challenging at the same time. Choosing what technologies will help you deliver your solution comes with the cost associated with those choices. Each additional technology can bring issues and dependencies that can lead to incremental decreases in progress that can grind your project to a stop. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/introduction-to-htmx-for-spring-boot-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Azure Tooling的更新 – 2024年8月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 08:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎阅读 Java on Azure 开发者工具8月份更新。在本次更新中，我们将介绍在 IntelliJ IDEA 中 Azure Toolkit 对 Azure App Service 提供托管身份支持（Managed Identity），以及宣布 Java 在 Azure 容器应用程序体验上正式发布。我们希望您喜欢这些更新，并享受使用 Azure 工具包的流畅体验。请下载并安装 IntelliJ 的 Azure 工具包。让我们开始吧！ Azure Toolkit for IntelliJ 提升 在Azure App Service上支持Managed Identity 托管身份是 Azure 中的一项功能，可简化应用程序的凭证管理。有关详细信息，请访问这篇文档。 在最新版本中，我们在工具包中为 Azure Web 应用程序添加了托管身份支持。该功能为开发人员提供了使用托管身份进行身份验证和访问 Azure 存储等 Azure 资源的灵活性，而无需直接管理凭据。它有助于降低凭证暴露的风险，并简化各种服务的安全集成。在我们的工具包中将 Java 应用程序部署到 Azure 应用服务时，系统会提示您分配角色以访问 Azure 资源。下面是一个简短的演示。 宣布 Java体验在Azure Container […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-azure-tooling-update-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Azure Tooling Update – August 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 07:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi everyone, welcome to the August update of Java on Azure developer tools. In this update, we will introduce our Managed Identity Support for Azure App Service in Azure toolkit, and General Availability of Java experiences on Azure Container Apps. We hope you enjoy these updates and have a smooth experience with our Azure toolkit. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-on-azure-tooling-update-august-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java on Visual Studio Code的更新 – 2024年8月</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 03:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            大家好，欢迎来到 Visual Studio Code for Java 八月更新！在这篇博客中，我们将涵盖重要Gradle 更新、更多用户体验改进以及更好的入门体验，马上开始吧！ Gradle 更新 将 Gradle for Java 添加到 Java 插件包中 一些用户可能已经注意到，最近在 Java 插件包中添加了一个名为“Gradle for Java”的插件，我们想介绍一下这一改动背后的故事。 Gradle for Java 插件是一个专门为 Visual Studio Code 提供 Gradle 支持的工具。长期以来，我们已经在这个插件中陆续了加入新功能，包括 Gradle 的构建服务器。不过，由于它是一个独立的插件，很多 Gradle / Java 开发者很难发现它。因此，我们收集了关于该扩展的反馈，最终决定在最近的版本中将其添加到 Java 插件包中。 然而，在将其添加到插件包之前，我们发现该插件的架构需要一些改进。具体来说，该插件会启动多个 JVM 进程来提供不同的功能，这会占用过多的计算资源。因此，我们决定进行一些优化——简单来说，我们将这些不同的 JVM 进程合并为一个，从而减少了 JVM 进程的数量，并显著降低了使用该扩展时的内存消耗。以下是不同项目大小下的内存消耗对比。 中型项目 大型项目 我们希望您喜欢我们在该扩展中提供的 Gradle 功能，如果有任何问题，请随时通过提交问题告诉我们！ 将“调试测试”委托给 Gradle 在我们之前的博客中，我们提到支持将测试委托给 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java-ch/java-on-visual-studio-code-2024-08 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a RAG-based QnA application using Llama3 models from SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 22:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a step-by-step guide for creating an enterprise ready RAG application such as a question answering bot. We use the Llama3-8B FM for text generation and the BGE Large EN v1.5 text embedding model for generating embeddings from Amazon SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-rag-based-qna-application-using-llama3-models-from-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best prompting practices for using Meta Llama 3 with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 22:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into the best practices and techniques for prompting Meta Llama 3 using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to generate high-quality, relevant outputs. We discuss how to use system prompts and few-shot examples, and how to optimize inference parameters, so you can get the most out of Meta Llama 3.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-prompting-practices-for-using-meta-llama-3-with-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Visual Studio Build Insights 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 20:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the latest Visual Studio 2022 17.12 Build Insights features. These updates provide developers with greater control and accuracy when diagnosing and optimizing C++ builds directly within Visual Studio. Download Visual Studio 2022 17.12 Preview We extend our thanks to the developer community, particularly our game studio partners, for providing invaluable […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/build-insights-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How healthcare payers and plans can empower members with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 19:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how generative artificial intelligence (AI) can help health insurance plan members get the information they need. The solution presented in this post not only enhances the member experience by providing a more intuitive and user-friendly interface, but also has the potential to reduce call volumes and operational costs for healthcare payers and plans.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-healthcare-payers-and-plans-can-empower-members-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling production-grade generative AI: New capabilities lower costs, streamline production, and boost security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 18:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative AI moves from proofs of concept (POCs) to production, we’re seeing a massive shift in how businesses and consumers interact with data, information—and each other. In what we consider “Act 1” of the generative AI story, we saw previously unimaginable amounts of data and compute create models that showcase the power of generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enabling-production-grade-generative-ai-new-capabilities-lower-costs-streamline-production-and-boost-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing new Ollama Connector for Local Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 17:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing new Ollama Connector for Local Models As a long-awaited feature we are happy to bring a dedicated Ollama Connector. In the core implementation of this connector, we are also using the Ollama Sharp library which allows you to manipulate some native Ollama APIs as well as using it with our connector for breaking glass […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/introducing-new-ollama-connector-for-local-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Asset Packs for .NET &amp; .NET MAUI Android Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing a new way to build and deploy Android Asset Packs using .NET for Android and .NET MAUI. If your app has allot of AndroidAsset items this feature will make your life easier.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/android-asset-packs-in-dotnet-android 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Team at CppCon 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 17:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             As always our team will be at CppCon this year with a host of presentations. Many of us will also be present at our team’s booth in the main hall for the first four days of the conference. Come say hi and let us know if you have any questions about our talks, products, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/microsoft-c-team-at-cppcon-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Network security controls</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Microsoft 365 Certification verifies network security controls are in place for your application.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-network-security-controls 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet Plugins – Now With Сustom Keymaps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            About a month ago, we launched a mechanism for publishing your color theme as a plugin. With the recent updates, we are extending Fleet plugin applicability even further by allowing you to publish your custom keymaps. You can now map Fleet actions to specific key combinations to streamline your development experience and share the resulting […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2024/09/fleet-plugins-now-with-sustom-keymaps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Thomson Reuters’ language model research with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the journey that Thomson Reuters took to enable cutting-edge research in training domain-adapted large language models (LLMs) using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod, an Amazon Web Services (AWS) feature focused on providing purpose-built infrastructure for distributed training at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scaling-thomson-reuters-language-model-research-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DiskANN for Azure Cosmos DB Now in Open Public Preview!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that the DiskANN vector index is now in open public preview in Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL! This means that anyone who enrolls an Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL resource in the Vector Search Public Preview now automatically gets access to the most powerful and scalable vector index on the planet. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/diskann-for-azure-cosmos-db-now-in-open-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling IP Access Control Policy for Azure Portal: A Necessity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing IP access control policies is essential for maintaining a secure Azure environment. These policies allow you to restrict access to your resources based on specific IP addresses, adding an extra layer of security to prevent unauthorized access. To avoid disruptions when accessing your Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB or Apache Cassandra API accounts through […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/enabling-ip-access-control-policy-for-azure-portal-a-necessity 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I tell whether two programs will share drive letter mappings?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can compare the authentication IDs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240912-00/?p=110251 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create With Kotlin Multiplatform and Win a Trip to KotlinConf 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To all students and recent graduates: The Kotlin Foundation is excited to announce the launch of the Kotlin Multiplatform Contest! Showcase your creativity and coding skills by building a cross-platform project using Kotlin Multiplatform and win a trip to KotlinConf 2025, the largest Kotlin event of the year. Take part Kotlin Multiplatform allows you to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2024/09/kotlin-multiplatform-contest/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing SharePoint Framework 1.20 release candidate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce release candidate for the upcoming SharePoint Framework 1.20. This time focus is primarily on the Microsoft Viva platform capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-sharepoint-framework-1-20-release-candidate 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Upgraded Docker Plans: Simpler, More Value, Better Development and Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker announces significant upgrades to its subscription plans, delivering more value, flexibility, and tools for customers of all sizes.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/november-2024-updated-plans-announcement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Improvements in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Take an in-depth tour through hundreds of performance improvements in .NET 9.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/performance-improvements-in-net-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the New TeamCity Plugin for IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release of the updated TeamCity plugin for IntelliJ IDEA! 🎉 You can now download it directly from JetBrains Marketplace. Using the plugin, you can trigger TeamCity builds directly from within your IDE and test any changes before committing them to the version control system. Why get the new plugin? This […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2024/09/new-teamcity-plugin-intellij-idea/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 08:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Early Access Program for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 is officially underway! The first EAP build is now available, offering you an early look at the first portion of improvements introduced for the next major release. You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/09/intellij-idea-2024-3-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Background Tasks With The IHostedLifecycleService Interface</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 06:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this article, we’ll describe the IHostedLifecycleService interface. We’ll see how it extends the IHostedService interface and enables finer control over the hosted service lifecycle. Finally, we’ll show some practical use cases for the IHostedLifecycleService interface. Let’s get started. What Is the IHostedService Interface The IHostedService interface is a powerful feature in .NET that enables […] The post Manage Background Tasks With The IHostedLifecycleService Interface appeared first on Code Maze.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Sourcing 101: Terminology &amp; Concepts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 22:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is event sourcing? Many terms are often used that can be pretty confusing. I will explain the core concepts and, specifically, Event Sourcing terminology so you can better understand what it is and what some of the benefits might be. YouTube Check out my YouTube channel, where I post all kinds of content accompanying my posts,… Read More »Event Sourcing 101: Terminology &amp;amp; Concepts The post Event Sourcing 101: Terminology &amp;amp; Concepts appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 9 Release Candidate 1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Try out the latest features in .NET 9 Release Candidate 1 across the .NET SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, SignalR, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-9-release-candidate-1-is-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of purpose-built accelerators for financial services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 19:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we aim to provide business leaders with a non-technical overview of purpose-built accelerators (PBAs) and their role within the financial services industry (FSI).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-review-of-purpose-built-accelerators-for-financial-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly detection in streaming time series data with online learning using Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 19:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a robust real-time anomaly detection solution for streaming time series data using Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink and other AWS managed services.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/anomaly-detection-in-streaming-time-series-data-with-online-learning-using-amazon-managed-service-for-apache-flink/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI-powered technology operations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 19:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we describe how AWS generative AI solutions (including Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Q Developer, and Amazon Q Business) can further enhance TechOps productivity, reduce time to resolve issues, enhance customer experience, standardize operating procedures, and augment knowledge bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generative-ai-powered-technology-operations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing MLOps for Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 18:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we review the guidance for optimizing MLOps for Sustainability on AWS, providing service-specific practices to understand and reduce the environmental impact of these workloads.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-mlops-for-sustainability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Models and .NET: Building Generative AI apps for engineers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you&#39;ll learn how to use AI models on GitHub.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-github-models-and-dotnet-to-build-generative-ai-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure AI Inference Connector for Azure AI Studio Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction With the latest launch of the Azure AI Inference SDK for Azure AI Studio Models Catalog, we are happy to announce that we have also made available our dedicated Azure AI Inference Semantic Kernel Connector. This connector is specially designed on top of the published Azure AI Inference SDK and is targeted to allow […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/introducing-azure-ai-inference-connector-for-azure-ai-studio-models 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAP for Vector Support Refresh – Introducing Vector type</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not even 6 months ago we started the Early Adopter Preview vector data support in Azure SQL, and we got great feedback and a lot of enthusiasm about the feature. Developers are excited to be able to easily build AI-enabled solution using an enterprise ready, secure, scalable and proven platform like Azure SQL, without the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/eap-for-vector-support-refresh-introducing-vector-type 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize your UWP app with preview UWP support for .NET 9 and Native AOT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re introducing the initial preview UWP (Universal Windows Platform) support for .NET 9, providing a path for existing UWP developers to modernize their apps with the latest .NET and Native AOT. Are you a UWP app developer considering migrating to Windows App SDK and WinUI 3? Or wanting to leverage the latest releases of .NET […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ifdef-windows/preview-uwp-support-for-dotnet-9-native-aot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling complex generative AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we take a closer look at Amazon Bedrock Agents. They empower you to build intelligent and context-aware generative AI applications, streamlining complex workflows and delivering natural, conversational user experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enabling-complex-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing large payloads in Fluid Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn about three Fluid Framework features which can be used to work around large payload scenarios: Grouped Batching, Batch Compression, and Compressed Batch Chunking.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/optimizing-large-payloads-in-fluid-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the string being copied from a mysterious pointer to invalid memory, revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reflections on an older topic.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240911-00/?p=110247 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next: The WebStorm 2024.3 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In August of this year, we released WebStorm 2024.2, our second major update for 2024. Thank you to everyone who is already using it and providing feedback. With August now behind us, we’d like to announce what we’ve got planned for the next release of WebStorm, which is scheduled for the middle of November, with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/webstorm/2024/09/what-s-next-the-webstorm-2024-3-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix C&#43;&#43; warnings and errors with Copilot: Introducing AI-Assisted Code Fixes in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stuck on an unfamiliar build error? Want to resolve your code errors quickly? Copilot is now integrated into Visual Studio error workflows to assist you with understanding and resolving C++ errors and warnings. To access this new feature, you will need an active Copilot subscription and the latest 17.11 GA version of Visual Studio. How […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/fix-c-warnings-and-errors-with-copilot-introducing-ai-assisted-code-fixes-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search scoping helps you find what you’re looking for</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’re working on a large and complex solution, you might find yourself overwhelmed by the number of results when you use code search in Visual Studio. You might be looking for a specific class, method, or variable, but end up scrolling through pages of irrelevant matches. Wouldn’t it be nice if you could narrow […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/search-scoping-helps-you-find-what-youre-looking-for 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2024.3 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 07:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The second major release of CLion this year, 2024.2, introduced many improvements and advanced features. These include full line code completion for С++ that runs locally, Zephyr West support, and updates to the new CLion Nova language engine. If you still haven’t tried CLion 2024.2, download and try it today. DOWNLOAD CLION 2024.2 We’ve begun […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2024/09/2024-3-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomics England uses Amazon SageMaker to predict cancer subtypes and patient survival from multi-modal data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we detail our collaboration in creating two proof of concept (PoC) exercises around multi-modal machine learning for survival analysis and cancer sub-typing, using genomic (gene expression, mutation and copy number variant data) and imaging (histopathology slides) data. We provide insights on interpretability, robustness, and best practices of architecting complex ML workflows on AWS with Amazon SageMaker. These multi-modal pipelines are being used on the Genomics England cancer cohort to enhance our understanding of cancer biomarkers and biology.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolverine meets RavenDb</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hey, did you know that JasperFx Software offers both consulting services and support plans for the “Critter Stack” tools? Or for architectural or test automation help with any old server side .NET application. One of the other things we do is to build out custom features that our customers need in the “Critter Stack” — like the … Continue reading Wolverine meets RavenDb →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2024/09/10/wolverine-meets-ravendb/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmaps for Microsoft Dev Box and Azure Deployment Environments are now live!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have just published the roadmaps for Microsoft Dev Box and Azure Deployment Environments! These roadmaps showcase our plans and upcoming features for both services, reflecting our commitment to enhancing your experience developing in the cloud. Your feedback is invaluable to us. We’ve built these roadmaps in a direct response to some feedback we’ve heard […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/roadmaps-for-microsoft-dev-box-and-azure-deployment-environments-are-now-live 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Build Your First Blazor Hybrid App!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn all about the Blazor Hybrid workshop that you can follow yourself or teach to others!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-blazor-hybrid-workshop 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Data API Preview in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the preview of the Data API for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB. The Data API provides a flexible and powerful way to interact with your database through HTTP-based API calls. What is the Data API The Data API for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB allows you work with your […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-the-data-api-preview-in-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase your Microsoft Teams app’s visibility and adoption with asynchronous link unfurling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to leverage link unfurling for your Microsoft Teams app, now enhanced with asynchronous capabilities.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/how-asynchronous-link-unfurling-increases-your-microsoft-teams-apps-visibility-and-adoption 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add enhanced flexibility to your apps with custom claims on Native Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how the custom claims feature, now available in public preview for Native Authentication on Microsoft Entra External ID, enhances your app&#39;s authentication process. This new capability allows you to tailor app behavior, based on specific user data, by allowing apps to dynamically add custom claims to authentication tokens via a custom claims provider during user sign-up or sign-in.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/custom-claims-on-native-auth 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the Resource Compiler have a separate preprocessor or doesn’t it?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It did, but now it doesn&#39;t.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20240910-00/?p=110243 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break for Async User-Unhandled exceptions in the Visual Studio Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Before .NET 9, the debugger was unable to track exceptions thrown from user-code async methods into non-user code framework methods, such as ASP.NET middleware. We are pleased to announce that you will now start seeing the debugger stop for these user-unhandled exceptions in your ASP.NET applications, as well as anywhere else this might happen! Summary […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/break-for-async-user-unhandled-exceptions-in-the-visual-studio-debugger 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing breaking changes in public APIs with PublicApiGenerator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how you can use the PublicApiGenerator project to document your public API and build a snapshot unit test to prevent breaking changes
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/preventing-breaking-changes-in-public-apis-with-publicapigenerator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caching Strategies in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 08:28:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2024/10_09_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Decreasing response time is one of the key measures towards improving the user experience of an application. Caching techniques and other practices can help your .NET application perform well with low effort. With caching, you can keep frequently accessed delay-prone data in a fast, accessible location. This can improve your asd
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/caching-strategies-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
