<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:10:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Supply Chain Paradox: When “Hardened” Images Become a Vendor Lock-in Trap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The market for pre-hardened container images is experiencing explosive growth as security-conscious organizations pursue the ultimate efficiency: instant security with minimal operational overhead. The value proposition is undeniably compelling—hardened images with minimal dependencies promise security &amp;quot;out of the box,&amp;quot; enabling teams to focus on building and shipping applications rather than constantly revisiting low-level configuration management....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hardened-container-images-security-vendor-lock-in/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Copilot Studio Agent Academy: Your Mission Starts Now</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to Copilot Studio Agent Academy Whether you&#39;re just starting your journey with AI agents or looking to sharpen your skills in Microsoft Copilot Studio, we&#39;ve got your mission briefing ready and it&#39;s time to suit up! We&#39;re thrilled to introduce Copilot Studio Agent Academy, a new, self-paced curricu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-copilot-studio-agent-academy 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Reduced API Response Time by 70% in a Large .NET Project</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 08:33:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Slow APIs hurt users&#39; experience and the owners&#39; pocket. Users become disappointed, and the server costs more if APIs are not up to standard in large projects. I also faced a similar issue in my project. However, I cut down the performance overhead marginally. This article breaks down
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/penhow-i-reduced-api-response-time-by-70-in-a-large-net-project/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify access control and auditing for Amazon SageMaker Studio using trusted identity propagation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to enable and use trusted identity propagation in Amazon SageMaker Studio, which allows organizations to simplify access management by granting permissions to existing AWS IAM Identity Center identities. The solution demonstrates how to implement fine-grained access controls based on a physical user&#39;s identity, maintain detailed audit logs across supported AWS services, and support long-running user background sessions for training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simplify-access-control-and-auditing-for-amazon-sagemaker-studio-using-trusted-identity-propagation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Data Wrangler powered Notebook Results Table</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have ever found yourself rewriting the last line of a notebook cell repeatedly just to get an overview of your data, you&#39;re not alone. In VS Code the default output for Pandas DataFrames is a static, truncated HTML table and it often fails to answer essential questions, such as: Do we have rogue blank values somewhere we di
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/data-wrangler-results-table 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (August 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-august-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Context Protocol (MCP) is Now Generally Available in Visual Studio 🎉</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that MCP support is now GA in Visual Studio—unlocking richer, real-time context from your entire development stack and expanding the power of Agent Mode like never before. Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open standard that makes it easy for AI agents to connect with external tools and services—think of it
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/mcp-is-now-generally-available-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking document information localization with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock, specifically Amazon Nova Pro, to achieve high-accuracy document field localization while dramatically simplifying implementation. We show how these models can precisely locate and interpret document fields with minimal frontend effort, reducing processing errors and manual intervention.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/benchmarking-document-information-localization-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Infosys built a generative AI solution to process oil and gas drilling data with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We built an advanced RAG solution using Amazon Bedrock leveraging Infosys Topaz™ AI capabilities, tailored for the oil and gas sector. This solution excels in handling multimodal data sources, seamlessly processing text, diagrams, and numerical data while maintaining context and relationships between different data elements. In this post, we provide insights on the solution and walk you through different approaches and architecture patterns explored, like different chunking, multi-vector retrieval, and hybrid search during the development.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-OSS - A C# Guide with Ollama</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-OSS is OpenAI&#39;s first open-weight model since GPT-2, and it&#39;s a game-changer for developers who want powerful AI without the cloud dependency. You get two flavors - gpt-oss-120b and gpt-oss-20b - both delivering solid performance on coding, math, and tool use while keeping your data completely private. The 20B model is especially interesti
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/gpt-oss-csharp-ollama 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Proxy 4: The Next Leap in C&#43;&#43; Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Proxy 4 is here! After years of innovation and sustained use in the Windows OS codebase (since 2022), Proxy has matured from a bold experiment into a production-grade, modern C++ library for runtime polymorphism. The theory behind Proxy is original, and its design is now proven at scale. We are excited to invite the broader C++ community to jo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/announcing-proxy-4-the-next-leap-in-c-polymorphism 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline NGINX Configuration with Docker Desktop Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker periodically highlights blog posts featuring use cases and success stories from Docker partners and practitioners. This story was contributed by Dylen Turnbull and Timo Stark. With over 29 years in enterprise and open-source software development, Dylen Turnbull has held roles at Symantec, Veritas, F5 Networks, and most recently as a Developer Advocate for NGINX....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/streamline-nginx-configuration-with-docker-desktop-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents with Docker MCP Toolkit: A Developer’s Real-World Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI agents in the real world often involves more than just making model calls — it requires integrating with external tools, handling complex workflows, and ensuring the solution can scale in production. In this post, we’ll walk through a real-world developer setup for creating an agent using the Docker MCP Toolkit. To make things...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-ai-agent-developer-setup/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline employee training with an intelligent chatbot powered by Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to design and implement custom plugins for Amazon Q Business to create an intelligent chatbot that streamlines employee training by retrieving answers from training materials. The solution implements secure API access using Amazon Cognito for user authentication and authorization, processes multiple document formats, and includes features like RAG-enhanced responses and email escalation capabilities through custom plugins.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-employee-training-with-an-intelligent-chatbot-powered-by-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 7: Non-modifying trackers, second try</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we tried to add non-modifying trackers to our tracking pointers implementation. I noted at the end that our attempt was wrong. The problem is in the code we
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250819-00/?p=111488 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting an xUnit test project to TUnit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I discuss the new TUnit testing framework, why I ported one of my libraries to use it instead of xUnit and related issues I had to deal with
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/converting-an-xunit-project-to-tunit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operations that Span Multiple Event Streams with the Critter Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s just say that Marten incurs some serious benefits to being on top of PostgreSQL and its very strong support for transactional integrity as opposed to some of the high profile commercial Event Sourcing tools who are spending a lot of time and energy on their “Dynamic Consistency Boundary” concept because they lack the ACID … Continue reading Operations that Span Multiple Event Streams with the Critter Stack →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Machine Reboots with VM Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 22:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One confusion around all of our extensions is: how are reboots handled? This varies by extension, but only VM Applications provide the option on how to handle them. It does this via the &amp;quot;scriptBehaviorAfterReboot&amp;quot; prop
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/handling-machine-reboots-with-vm-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a travel planning agentic workflow with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 20:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a travel planning solution using AI agents. The agent uses Amazon Nova, which offers an optimal balance of performance and cost compared to other commercial LLMs. By combining accurate but cost-efficient Amazon Nova models with LangGraph orchestration capabilities, we create a practical travel assistant that can handle complex planning tasks while keeping operational costs manageable for production deployments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-travel-planning-agentic-workflow-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) - August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the August 2025 edition of the Azure Developer CLI (azd) release blog! This post covers releases 1.18.1 and 1.18.2. To share your feedback and questions, join the August release discussion on GitHub. This month brings important bug fixes, documentation improvements
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-august-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Next Edit Suggestions in JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the latest release of JetBrains AI Assistant, we’ve introduced a long-awaited feature – next edit suggestions. These new suggestions are now available in Beta across JetBrains IDEs for Java, Kotlin, and Python. Next edit suggestions offer intelligent recommendations for edits across your entire file – not just the next line of code. The new feature […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/08/introducing-next-edit-suggestions-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SQL and databases in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 14:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out our recent livestream from August 14 on How to Work With SQL and Databases in JetBrains IDEs. In this demo session, we showed how to write SQL queries and work with databases in any JetBrains IDE and explored a range of use cases for embedded database functionality, from simple queries to more advanced […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datagrip/2025/08/18/using-sql-and-databases-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 6: Non-modifying trackers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s add non-modifying trackers to our tracking pointers implementation. That is, a tracking pointer that gives you only read-only access to the tracked object. The idea is that tracking point
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250818-00/?p=111486 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Windows Known Folders in C# with SHGetKnownFolderPath</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows has a list of well-known folders such as Documents, Pictures, Music, etc. You can access most of these folders using the Environment.GetFolderPath method in C#. Here&#39;s an example: Environment.GetFolderPath(Environment.SpecialFolder.MyDocuments); However, this list is limited to the folders defined in the Environment.SpecialFolder enumeration. If you need to access other well-known folders, such as…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/accessing-windows-known-folders-in-csharp-with-shgetknownfolderpath.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Python 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 11:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Michael Kennedy, the founder of Talk Python and a PSF Fellow. Welcome to the highlights, trends, and key actions from the eighth annual Python Developers Survey. This survey is conducted as a collaborative effort between the Python Software Foundation and JetBrains’ PyCharm team. My name is Michael Kennedy, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/08/the-state-of-python-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps for Startups: CI/CD from the Ground Up</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 10:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The benefits of DevOps are not limited to large enterprises. For startups, DevOps can offer the agility you need to keep responding and adapting to market demands, while maintaining the quality users now expect. Why DevOps Matters for Startups As a startup, you’re probably feeling the pressure to get your product or service to market […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/08/devops-for-startups/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset Cookies and force new sign-in using ASP.NET Core Identity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 05:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post looks at implementing a cookie reset in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende identity server which federates to Entra ID. Sometimes cookies need to be reset for end users due to size problems, or unknown remote authentication server errors. The cookies can be cleared and a new sign in can be forced. Code: […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/08/18/reset-cookies-and-force-new-sign-in-using-asp-net-core-identity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with DoorDash’s CPO, Mariana Garavaglia</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how DoorDash is scaling AI adoption to empower employees to build, learn, and innovate faster in a conversation with Chief People Officer Mariana Garavaglia.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/doordash-mariana-garavaglia 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Chronicles: Why Streaming Apps Still Suck—and Why That Should Terrify Tech Teams</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2025/17_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_08_2025/17_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Major streaming platforms like Netflix and Amazon Prime Video are failing to prioritize user experience, leading to frustration for users. Issues such as misleading content promotion, disruptive ads, disorganized content, and technical malfunctions highlight a disconnect between companies and their audience. Executives must engage with their products to improve usability and user satisfaction.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/08/17/ux-chronicles-why-streaming-apps-still-suck-and-why-that-should-terrify-tech-teams/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-08-15</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2025/16_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 06:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2025/16_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Like what you read or watched from the recap? I&#39;d love if you helped share on Reddit or Daily.dev so others can see!
Weekly Recap FORGET The Generic Resume Fluff! Focus On Impact As A Developer!
Is this resume a bit too fluffy? Let&#39;s see if we can identify some opportunities for this senior software engineer to REALLY showcase all of the awesome impactful work that they&#39;ve done!
Does This Developer Intern Resume Stand A Chance?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Generative AI Applications With GitHub Models and .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2025/16_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2025/16_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how to integrate AI into your .NET applications in under an hour using GitHub Models and .NET Aspire 9.4. I&#39;ll walk you through building a simple AI-powered blog analyzer that automatically categorizes your content.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/building-generative-ai-applications-with-github-models-and-dotnet-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need Some Feedback on Near Term Wolverine Work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 19:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            That’s supposed to be a play on a Wolverine as Winnie the Pooh in his “thinking spot” I’m wrestling a little bit with whether the new features and changes coming into Wolverine very soon are worthy of a 5.0 release even though 4.0 was just a couple months ago. I’d love any and all feedback … Continue reading Need Some Feedback on Near Term Wolverine Work →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker @ Black Hat 2025: CVEs have everyone’s attention, here’s the path forward</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CVEs dominated the conversation at Black Hat 2025. Across sessions, booth discussions, and hallway chatter, it was clear that teams are feeling the pressure to manage vulnerabilities at scale. While scanning remains an important tool, the focus is shifting toward removing security debt before it enters the software supply chain. Hardened images, compliance-ready tooling, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-black-hat-2025-secure-software-supply-chain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway: Transforming enterprise AI agent tool development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, a fully managed service that revolutionizes how enterprises connect AI agents with tools and services by providing a centralized tool server with unified interface for agent-tool communication. The service offers key capabilities including Security Guard, Translation, Composition, Target extensibility, Infrastructure Manager, and Semantic Tool Selection, while implementing sophisticated dual-sided security architecture for both inbound and outbound connections.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway-transforming-enterprise-ai-agent-tool-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a scalable containerized web application on AWS using the MERN stack with Amazon Q Developer – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a traditional SDLC, a lot of time is spent in the different phases researching approaches that can deliver on requirements: iterating over design changes, writing, testing and reviewing code, and configuring infrastructure. In this post, you learned about the experience and saw productivity gains you can realize by using Amazon Q Developer as a coding assistant to build a scalable MERN stack web application on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Salesforce’s model endpoints with Amazon SageMaker AI inference components</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how the Salesforce AI Platform team optimized GPU utilization, improved resource efficiency and achieved cost savings using Amazon SageMaker AI, specifically inference components.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-salesforces-model-endpoints-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-inference-components/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practitioner’s view on how Docker enables security by default and makes developers work better</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post was written by Docker Captains, experienced professionals recognized for their expertise with Docker. It shares their firsthand, real-world experiences using Docker in their own work or within the organizations they lead. Docker Captains are technical experts and passionate community builders who drive Docker’s ecosystem forward. As active contributors and advocates, they share...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-docker-enables-security-by-default/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a RAG chat-based assistant on Amazon EKS Auto Mode and NVIDIA NIMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the implementation of a practical RAG chat-based assistant using a comprehensive stack of modern technologies. The solution uses NVIDIA NIMs for both LLM inference and text embedding services, with the NIM Operator handling their deployment and management. The architecture incorporates Amazon OpenSearch Serverless to store and query high-dimensional vector embeddings for similarity search.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-rag-chat-based-assistant-on-amazon-eks-auto-mode-and-nvidia-nims/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Identity: Securing agentic AI at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Identity, a comprehensive identity and access management service purpose-built for AI agents that enables secure access to AWS resources and third-party tools. The service provides robust identity management features including agent identity directory, agent authorizer, resource credential provider, and resource token vault to help organizations deploy AI agents securely at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-identity-securing-agentic-ai-at-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 5: Copying our tracking pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our previous attempt to create a tracking pointer class had the perhaps-undesirable property that copying a const tracking pointer is not permitted. This requirement arose because copying a tracking p
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250815-00/?p=111484 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking about trying or upgrading to Datalore Cloud? This August, you can save 30%.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 10:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve recently started a trial or are thinking about trying Datalore, and a Cloud plan is on your radar, now is a good time to consider it. Until the end of August, new users and teams currently using a trial version of Datalore can get 30% off their first payment when subscribing to the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/08/15/save-30/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.44: Smarter AI Modeling, Platform Stability, and Streamlined Kubernetes Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 20:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Docker Desktop 4.44, we’ve focused on delivering enhanced reliability, tighter AI modeling controls, and simplified tool integrations so you can build on your terms. Docker Model Runner Enhancements Inspectable Model Runner Workflows Now you can inspect AI inference requests and responses directly from Docker Model Runner (DMR), helping you troubleshoot and debug model behavior...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-44/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the blog post Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock, we demonstrated how to build a scalable IDP pipeline using Anthropic foundation models on Amazon Bedrock. Although that approach delivered robust performance, the introduction of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation brings a new level of efficiency and flexibility to IDP solutions. This post explores how Amazon Bedrock Data Automation enhances document processing capabilities and streamlines the automation journey.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiteboard to cloud in minutes using Amazon Q, Amazon Bedrock Data Automation, and Model Context Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share the Amazon Bedrock Data Automation Model Context Protocol (MCP) server, for seamless integration between Amazon Q and your enterprise data. In this post, you will learn how to use the Amazon Bedrock Data Automation MCP server to securely integrate with AWS Services, use Bedrock Data Automation operations as callable MCP tools, and build a conversational development experience with Amazon Q.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/whiteboard-to-cloud-in-minutes-using-amazon-q-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-model-context-protocol/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing agentic Retrieval Augmented Generation to Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how Amazon Q Business is transforming enterprise data interaction through Agentic Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bringing-agentic-retrieval-augmented-generation-to-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5 for Microsoft Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI announced GPT-5 last week in &amp;quot;GPT-5 and the new era of work&amp;quot;. Working with OpenAI, we rolled out GPT-5 support the day it launched, making sure you can use and build with it and integrate it into your applications immediately. We&#39;ve got you covered with a dev-focused rundo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/gpt-5-for-microsoft-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the NuGet MCP Server Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month, we announced support for building custom MCP servers with .NET and publishing them to NuGet. Building on that foundation, today we&#39;re announcing the official NuGet MCP Server, which enables you to integrate real-time NuGet package information
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/nuget-mcp-server-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering students with disabilities: University Startups’ generative AI solution for personalized student pathways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            University Startups, headquartered in Bethesda, MD, was founded in 2020 to empower high school students to expand their education beyond a traditional curriculum. University Startups is focused on special education and related services in school districts throughout the US. In this post, we explain how University Startups uses generative AI technology on AWS to enable students to design a specific plan for their future either in education or the work force.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The GitHub Prompt Injection Data Heist</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 3 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that validate the critical vulnerabilities threatening AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker MCP Toolkit provides enterprise-grade protection. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) promised to revolutionize how AI agents interact with developer tools, making GitHub repositories, Slack channels, and databases...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-github-prompt-injection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations with Amazon Nova understanding models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to prompt Amazon Nova understanding models to cite sources in responses. Further, we will also walk through how we can evaluate the responses (and citations) for accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/citations-with-amazon-nova-understanding-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data encryption with customer-managed key (CMK) for Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB vCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Built-in security for every configuration Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB vCore is designed with security as a foundational principle. Regardless of how your cluster is configured—whether it&#39;s a sing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/data-encryption-with-customer-managed-key-cmk-for-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-vcore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 4: Using a circular doubly linked list</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our previous attempt to create a tracking pointer class had the downside of incurring a potential memory allocation when a tracking pointer is copied or moved. We can get rid of this allocation by mak
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250814-00/?p=111482 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Quarter, New Qodana 2025.2 Release Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 13:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following the recent rollout of our new Insights dashboard, Native mode, Self-Hosted Lite version, SSO functionality, and Visual Studio plugin, our Qodana 2025.2 update promises another round of improvements and extensions. Take a look at what we’ve been doing as we focus on providing greater access to code quality and security in your organization, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/08/qodana-2025-2-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Context Protocol (MCP) for GitHub Copilot in Xcode is Now Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 13:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Model Context Protocol (MCP) support with GitHub Copilot is now generally available for Xcode! Developers can now enable GitHub Copilot with MCP in Xcode to enhance coding intelligence and context awareness. What&#39;s new With MCP support in Xcode, developers can now connect Copilot to both local and remote MCP servers that follow the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/mcp-for-ghc-in-xcode-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2025.07.1 Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 12:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TeamCity On-Premises 2025.07.1, the first bug-fix for the recently released TeamCity 2025.07, is ready to be installed on your On-Premises servers. This update addresses a significant number of issues, including: Bug-fix updates also include performance and security improvements, so we recommend installing them promptly. See TeamCity 2025.07.1 Release Notes for the complete list of resolved […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/08/teamcity-2025-07-1-bug-fix/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Codebase Awareness in Visual Studio Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Smarter Code Search in Visual Studio: From BM25 to Semantic Search In our lat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/improving-codebase-awareness-in-visual-studio-chat 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Performance Improvements in ReSharper 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 10:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2025.2 release of ReSharper introduces a number of performance and responsiveness improvements across several key areas. This post outlines the most notable updates, including out-of-process support, improved solution startup, faster refactorings, and better Razor/Blazor handling. Out-of-Process mode Public Preview ReSharper 2025.2 is the first stable release to support running ReSharper out of process (OOP) […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/14/resharper-performance-improvements-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2025.2 Are Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 10:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ReSharper and the .NET tools 2025.2 are available for download. This release introduces the public preview of ReSharper’s Out-of-Process mode, adds support for the latest C# 14 and C++26 features, and brings a range of improvements for performance, refactorings, and inspections. If you’d like to try out what’s coming in the next stable release, you […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/14/resharper-and-the-net-tools-2025-2-are-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.2 Is Here with Junie, In-IDE OpenTelemetry, Game Dev Upgrades, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider 2025.2 delivers a big step forward in intelligent development tooling, bringing AI deeper into your workflow with Junie – our AI coding agent – along with runtime observability through the new OpenTelemetry plugin, a reworked Monitoring tool window, and improved debugging across platforms. Let’s take a closer look at what’s new. Meet Junie, your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/08/14/rider-2025-2-is-here-with-junie-in-ide-opentelemetry-game-dev-upgrades-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Fuzz Testing in CLion</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 09:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fuzz testing is an effective technique for identifying bugs that are difficult to detect using unit tests or static analysis alone. This article will show you how to perform fuzz testing in CLion, analyze the results, and debug a tested function. We’ll use CI Fuzz, a fuzz testing tool developed by Code Intelligence, a company […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/08/fuzz-testing-in-clion/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizable and Extensible Evaluation of a GenAI Application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction You have built out a generative AI application. Now are you wondering how to assess that your application is returning quality results? Have you considered using Azure AI Foundry to evaluate your application? If you are wondering how to start programmatically evaluating your application in a way that is both adaptable an
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/customizable-extensible-evaluations-of-genai-application 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Redmond to San Diego: VS Live! Highlights, Session Examples, and What’s Next</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s something special about hosting developers at Microsoft HQ — and this year’s Visual Studio Live! Redmond reminded me why I love these events. The energy in every room was electric. From the moment the first session kicked off, developers leaned in, asked smart, challenging questions, and took every opportunity to connect with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/from-redmond-to-san-diego-vs-live-highlights-session-examples-and-whats-next 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securely launch and scale your agents and tools on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 21:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime simplifies the deployment and management of AI agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/securely-launch-and-scale-your-agents-and-tools-on-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PwC and AWS Build Responsible AI with Automated Reasoning on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 19:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents how AWS and PwC are developing new reasoning checks that combine deep industry expertise with Automated Reasoning checks in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails to support innovation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pwc-and-aws-build-responsible-ai-with-automated-reasoning-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI: From Dev to Prod with Azure DevOps Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 18:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building on our previous post about implementing dev-to-prod promotion with GitHub Actions, this follow-up demonstrates the same &amp;quot;build once, deploy everywhere&amp;quot; pattern using Azure DevOps Pipelines. You&#39;ll learn how to leverage Azure Dev
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-developer-cli-from-dev-to-prod-with-azure-devops-pipelines 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GPT-5 Launch Broke the AI Internet (And Not in a Good Way)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What That Means for Devs and AI App Companies When GPT-5 dropped, OpenAI killed off a bunch of older APIs without much warning. A whole lot of apps face-planted overnight. If your app hard-codes itself to one provider, one API shape, or one model, this is the nightmare scenario. This is also different from losing...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/gpt5-api-deprecation-ai-app-failure/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon scaled Rufus by building multi-node inference using AWS Trainium chips and vLLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, Amazon shares how they developed a multi-node inference solution for Rufus, their generative AI shopping assistant, using Amazon Trainium chips and vLLM to serve large language models at scale. The solution combines a leader/follower orchestration model, hybrid parallelism strategies, and a multi-node inference unit abstraction layer built on Amazon ECS to deploy models across multiple nodes while maintaining high performance and reliability.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-scaled-rufus-by-building-multi-node-inference-using-aws-trainium-chips-and-vllm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent financial analysis agent with LangGraph and Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes an approach of combining three powerful technologies to illustrate an architecture that you can adapt and build upon for your specific financial analysis needs: LangGraph for workflow orchestration, Strands Agents for structured reasoning, and Model Context Protocol (MCP) for tool integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-financial-analysis-agent-with-langgraph-and-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory: Building context-aware agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory, a fully managed service that enables AI agents to maintain both immediate and long-term knowledge, transforming one-off conversations into continuous, evolving relationships between users and AI agents. The service eliminates complex memory infrastructure management while providing full control over what AI agents remember, offering powerful capabilities for maintaining both short-term working memory and long-term intelligent memory across sessions.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational natural language interface for Amazon Athena queries using Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore an innovative solution that uses Amazon Bedrock Agents, powered by Amazon Nova Lite, to create a conversational interface for Athena queries. We use AWS Cost and Usage Reports (AWS CUR) as an example, but this solution can be adapted for other databases you query using Athena. This approach democratizes data access while preserving the powerful analytical capabilities of Athena, so you can interact with your data using natural language.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – August Digest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your August learning boost is here – with free tools, career-launching courses, practical advice from the JetBrains Academy team, and your shot at winning a MacBook Pro.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/08/13/jetbrains-academy-august/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps OAuth Client Secrets Now Shown Only Once</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re making an important change to how Azure DevOps displays OAuth client secrets to align with industry best practices and improve our overall security posture. Starting September, newly generated client secrets will be shown only once at the time of creation. After that, they will no longer be retrievable via the UI or
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-oauth-client-secrets-now-shown-only-once 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerToys 0.93 is here: faster Command Palette, new dashboard UX and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/powertoys-0-93-is-here-faster-command-palette-new-dashboard-ux-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simpler, More Transparent Model for AI Quotas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 15:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR: Starting August 18, 2025, we’re rolling out a new AI quota model that makes AI subscriptions easier to understand and manage, while also letting you seamlessly extend your usage beyond your included quota with transparent pricing in real currency. The initial rollout will apply to individuals and organizations, with AI Enterprise updates to follow. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/08/a-simpler-more-transparent-model-for-ai-quotas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Managed Instance for Apache Cassandra v5.0 Generally Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 14:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-managed-instance-for-apache-cassandra-v5-0-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on creating a tracking pointer class, part 3: Using a &lt;code&gt;std::vector&lt;/code&gt;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we tried to build our &amp;quot;tracking pointers&amp;quot; out of nodes in a std::list, but we found that the std::list was not expressive enough to support the operations we needed.¹ So instea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250813-00/?p=111459 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning-Fast Python: Mastering the uv Package Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 13:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out our recent livestream from August 7 on uv, a next-generation Python package manager revolutionizing Python development with speeds 10-100x faster than pip. Released just last year and written in Rust, uv replaces long-standing Python dependency management challenges with a single, lightning-fast tool that just works. Join us as we demonstrate uv‘s game-changing capabilities […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/08/lightning-fast-python-mastering-the-uv-package-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.0-1 Microsoft build now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 12:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-0-1-microsoft-build-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Transactions? Let Spring Debugger Do the Heavy Lifting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 10:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Framework’s declarative transaction management is incredibly powerful, allowing developers to simply add the @Transactional annotation to a method and let Spring handle the transaction details. However, misconfigurations or misunderstandings of how transactions work can lead to frustrating database transaction handling issues. Debugging these problems often means sifting through a lot of AOP proxy code, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/08/debugging-transactions-let-spring-debugger-do-the-heavy-lifting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodee’s Kotlin Roundup: 2.2.20-Beta2, Kotlin LSP Update, Shipaton 2025, and a New Face on the Foundation Board</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Kodee here – your ever-cheerful tour guide through the ever-bustling streets of Kotlin-land. Summer may be the season for vacations, but we’re not slowing down! Let’s take a stroll through the latest news. What else to read YouTube highlights Check out some of the most popular videos on our Kotlin YouTube channel: And these are […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/08/kodee-kotlin-roundup-july-25-edition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
