<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 18:34:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Prioritize OSS Bugs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_07_2025/20_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 18:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_07_2025/20_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I just got back from a week long vacation with the family, and I was as rested and relaxed as I can ever be, at least before I picked up a head cold on the last day. Today though, it’s time to start catching up on OSS bug reports that have come in in the … Continue reading How I Prioritize OSS Bugs →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.com/2025/07/20/how-i-prioritize-oss-bugs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Effortlessly Randomize Collections with CollectionRandomizer in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_07_2025/20_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_07_2025/20_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CollectionRandomizer is a new utility class for .NET that simplifies working with randomized collections. It supports infinite looping and automatic reshuffling, making it ideal for dynamic UI components and rotating messages. This lightweight, thread-safe class is production-ready and streamlines the process of retrieving random items efficiently.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/20/boost-your-net-projects-effortlessly-randomize-collections-with-collectionrandomizer-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-07-18</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2025/19_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 06:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2025/19_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://devleader.ca/2025/07/19/weekly-recap-20250718 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDF Reporting in .NET With HTML Templates and PuppeteerSharp (and it&#39;s free)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2025/19_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_07_2025/19_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generate PDF reports in .NET using HTML templates and a headless browser. We&#39;ll explore Handlebars.NET and PuppeteerSharp, compare alternatives, and analyze performance tradeoffs.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/pdf-reporting-in-dotnet-with-html-templates-and-puppeteersharp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build real-time travel recommendations using AI agents on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build a generative AI solution using Amazon Bedrock that creates bespoke holiday packages by combining customer profiles and preferences with real-time pricing data. We demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases for travel information, Amazon Bedrock Agents for real-time flight details, and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless for efficient package search and retrieval.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-real-time-travel-recommendations-using-ai-agents-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a full stack voice AI agent with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to create an AI-powered call center agent for a fictional company called AnyTelco. The agent, named Telly, can handle customer inquiries about plans and services while accessing real-time customer data using custom tools implemented with the Model Context Protocol (MCP) framework.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-a-full-stack-voice-ai-agent-with-amazon-nova-sonic/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage multi-tenant Amazon Bedrock costs using application inference profiles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how to implement a robust monitoring solution for multi-tenant AI deployments using a feature of Amazon Bedrock called application inference profiles. We demonstrate how to create a system that enables granular usage tracking, accurate cost allocation, and dynamic resource management across complex multi-tenant environments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-multi-tenant-amazon-bedrock-costs-using-application-inference-profiles/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the invalid instruction exception on an instruction that should never have executed</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The image processing folks added specialized AVX2 versions of their code, but found that it was crashing with an illegal instruction exception. The code went something like this: void SwizzleAVX2(uint32_t* source, uint32_t* destination, uint32_t count) { ⟦ do stuff using AVX-only instructions ⟧ ⟦ such as _mm256_cv
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250718-00/?p=111390 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 Beta: EAP Closure and Our New Approach to Release Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 13:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Beta version of IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 is now available, marking the end of our Early Access Program for this release cycle. Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 Beta Thank you to everyone who used the EAP builds, shared feedback, and helped shape this release. As we mentioned in the EAP opening post, we have moved away […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/intellij-idea-2025-2-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reworked Terminal Becomes the Default in 2025.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 12:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting from 2025.2, the default terminal implementation is now the reworked terminal. To create this new implementation, the classic terminal was rewritten almost from scratch to provide the technical foundation for new terminal features like visual separation of executed commands, AI integration, and the ability to work seamlessly in remote development scenarios. Functionally, it is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/07/the-reworked-terminal-becomes-the-default-in-2025-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Model Promotion with dstoolkit-mlops-v2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In a recent engagement, our team of Data Scientists and Software Engineers, developed a series of custom AI models to meet our customer&#39;s specific use case. While doing so, consideration was given to how best to allow Data Scientists the freedom to quickly experiment and iterate on model development, while also incorpora
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/ai-model-promotion-with-dstoolkit-v2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A $50 million fund to build with communities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is launching an initial $50 million fund that supports nonprofit and community organizations, informed by the independent OpenAI Nonprofit Commission report.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/50-million-fund-to-build-with-communities 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating generative AI models with Amazon Nova LLM-as-a-Judge on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 22:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Evaluating the performance of large language models (LLMs) goes beyond statistical metrics like perplexity or bilingual evaluation understudy (BLEU) scores. For most real-world generative AI scenarios, it’s crucial to understand whether a model is producing better outputs than a baseline or an earlier iteration. This is especially important for applications such as summarization, content generation, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluating-generative-ai-models-with-amazon-nova-llm-as-a-judge-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building cost-effective RAG applications with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon S3 Vectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 22:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to integrate Amazon S3 Vectors with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases for RAG applications. You&#39;ll learn a practical approach to scale your knowledge bases to handle millions of documents while maintaining retrieval quality and using S3 Vectors cost-effective storage.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-cost-effective-rag-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-and-amazon-s3-vectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing on-demand deployment with customized Amazon Nova models on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 19:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through the custom model on-demand deployment workflow for Amazon Bedrock and provide step-by-step implementation guides using both the AWS Management Console and APIs or AWS SDKs. We also discuss best practices and considerations for deploying customized Amazon Nova models on Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implementing-on-demand-deployment-with-customized-amazon-nova-models-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Compiling: Two Shirts Every Veteran Software Engineer Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 17:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The new t-shirt designs celebrate seasoned software engineers surviving industry challenges like Y2K and IE6. The Vintage Tech Emblem Tee and Embroidered Patch Edition embody resilience and experience, emphasizing their importance in producing reliable code. These shirts serve as a declaration of enduring value in a technology-driven world.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/17/still-compiling-two-shirts-every-veteran-software-engineer-needs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build reliable Go applications: Configuring Azure Cosmos DB Go SDK for real-world scenarios</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 16:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building applications that interact with databases, developers frequently encounter scenarios where default SDK configurations don&#39;t align with their specific operational requirements. They need to customize SDK behavior to address real-world challenges like network instability, performance bottlenecks, debugging complexity, monitoring re
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/build-reliable-go-applications-configuring-azure-cosmos-db-go-sdk-for-real-world-scenarios 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ktor 3.2.2 Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Ktor 3.2.2 patch release brings a critical fix for Android D8 compatibility, along with some minor enhancements and bug fixes. 🚀 Get started Ready to explore Ktor 3.2.2? Start building your next project today with our interactive project generator at start.ktor.io. Your feedback and contributions are always welcome! 🔗 Get Started With Ktor | […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/07/ktor-3-2-0-is-now-available-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If the Window Runtime PropertyValue is for boxing non-inspectables, why is there a PropertyValue.CreateInspectable?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Windows Runtime provides a class named Property­Value which is a helper class for boxing non-inspectables. &amp;quot;Boxing&amp;quot; means taking a value type and wrapping inside an object so it can be used as an object type, and in the Windows Runtime, &amp;quot;objects&amp;quot; are represented by the IInspectable interface. There are
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250717-00/?p=111388 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoFiber v3 &#43; Testcontainers: Production-like Local Dev with Air</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 13:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Intro Local development can be challenging when apps rely on external services like databases or queues, leading to brittle scripts and inconsistent environments. Fiber v3 and Testcontainers solve this by making real service dependencies part of your app’s lifecycle, fully managed, reproducible, and developer-friendly. With the upcoming v3 release, Fiber is introducing a powerful new...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/go-local-dev-fiber-v3-testcontainers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking to Build: Fuzzing the Kotlin Compiler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we care about Kotlin compiler quality. One powerful way to test it? Fuzzing, an approach that feeds programs unexpected, often random, inputs to uncover bugs that traditional tests may miss. It may sound chaotic, but it works, especially for complex software like compilers. In a previous post, our colleagues introduced kotlinx.fuzz, a powerful […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2025/07/fuzzing-the-kotlin-compiler/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building enterprise-scale RAG applications with Amazon S3 Vectors and DeepSeek R1 on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 12:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are adopting large language models (LLMs), such as DeepSeek R1, to transform business processes, enhance customer experiences, and drive innovation at unprecedented speed. However, standalone LLMs have key limitations such as hallucinations, outdated knowledge, and no access to proprietary data. Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) addresses these gaps by combining semantic search with generative AI, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-enterprise-scale-rag-applications-with-amazon-s3-vectors-and-deepseek-r1-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qodana Cloud vs. Self-Hosted Lite: Which Is Best for Your Team?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Onboarding development teams with new tools can be difficult. People disagree about what’s best, and different organizations have different pains, needs, and regulations. Which option is the best for you? How do you find consensus in your team? How much control do you need over your data? There are many considerations, and it can feel […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/07/cloud-vs-self-hosted-lite/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA Moves to the Unified Distribution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the next step for IntelliJ IDEA: we are moving to a single, unified distribution. And yes, before you ask, our commitment to open source remains as strong as ever. There will be just one IntelliJ IDEA installer, replacing the separate downloads for Community Edition and Ultimate Edition. In this new […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/intellij-idea-unified-distribution-plan/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT agent System Card</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT agent System Card: OpenAI’s agentic model unites research, browser automation, and code tools with safeguards under the Preparedness Framework.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/chatgpt-agent-system-card 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing ChatGPT agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing ChatGPT agent: it thinks and acts, using tools to complete tasks like research, bookings, and slideshows—all with your guidance.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-chatgpt-agent 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent bio bug bounty call</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI invites researchers to its Bio Bug Bounty. Test the ChatGPT agent’s safety with a universal jailbreak prompt and win up to $25,000.
Link to article: https://openai.com/bio-bug-bounty 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command GitHub&#39;s Coding Agent from VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VS Code&#39;s integration with GitHub Copilot Coding Agent allows you to delegate tasks to the agent and let it handle them in the background. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/command-github&#39;s-coding-agent-from-vs-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI nonprofit jam</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At OpenAI, we build tools to help people solve hard problems—including nonprofits working on the frontlines of their communities. The OpenAI Academy is teaming up with the Walton Family Foundation, Emerson Collective, and a network of local nonprofit organizations to host the Nonprofit Jam—a one-day, nationwide event bringing together more than 1,000 nonprofit leaders across 10 locations.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/openai-nonprofit-jam 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement from the OpenAI Board of Directors on the Nonprofit Commission Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Board of Directors thanks the members of the independent OpenAI Nonprofit Commission for their extensive work and engagement.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/nonprofit-commission-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accenture scales video analysis with Amazon Nova and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 22:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was written with Ilan Geller, Kamal Mannar, Debasmita Ghosh, and Nakul Aggarwal of Accenture. Video highlights offer a powerful way to boost audience engagement and extend content value for content publishers. These short, high-impact clips capture key moments that drive viewer retention, amplify reach across social media, reinforce brand identity, and open new […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accenture-scales-video-analysis-with-amazon-nova-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Microsoft MCP Servers to Accelerate Your Development Workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 19:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve been talking a lot about the Model Context Protocol (MCP) lately, including recent blog posts and sessions at Microsoft Build. In this post, I&#39;d like to share some top tips for how you can use MCP servers we&#39;ve been building to improve yo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//10-microsoft-mcp-servers-to-accelerate-your-development-workflow 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy conversational agents with Vonage and Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 18:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how developers can integrate Amazon Nova Sonic with the Vonage communications service to build responsive, natural-sounding voice experiences in real time. By combining the Vonage Voice API with the low-latency and expressive speech capabilities of Amazon Nova Sonic, businesses can deploy AI voice agents that deliver more human-like interactions than traditional voice interfaces. These agents can be used as customer support, virtual assistants, and more.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring your own agents into Microsoft 365 Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Custom Engine Agents now generally available—build and integrate your own AI into the flow of work Microsoft 365 Copilot is redefining how people interact with AI—embedding it directly into the flow of work as the intuitive, natural interface for agents: the ‘UI for AI’ As Copilot becomes the interface for
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/bring-your-own-agents-into-microsoft-365-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Agentic AI Era at JetBrains Is Here</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Seamless in-IDE coding and async development with Junie Software development has been significantly influenced by AI coding agents taking over more repetitive tasks, generating code faster and getting more done with less effort. It’s nice to have access to a fast coding agent or an in-IDE AI assistant, but in real-world scenarios, intelligence and trustworthiness […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/junie/2025/07/the-agentic-ai-era-at-jetbrains-is-here/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling customers to deliver production-ready AI agents at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, I’m excited to share how we’re bringing this vision to life with new capabilities that address the fundamental aspects of building and deploying agents at scale. These innovations will help you move beyond experiments to production-ready agent systems that can be trusted with your most critical business processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enabling-customers-to-deliver-production-ready-ai-agents-at-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and LangChain4j: A Partnership for Secure, Enterprise-Grade Java AI Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/microsoft-and-langchain4j-a-partnership-for-secure-enterprise-grade-java-ai-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Models, Big Impact: Why JetBrains is Betting on Focal LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At AI Summit London 2025, Kris Kang, Head of Product for AI at JetBrains, gave a talk that questioned a common belief in AI development: that bigger means better. The industry has focused heavily on massive, general-purpose language models. These models offer impressive capabilities, but the cost of building and running them at scale is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/07/small-models-big-impact-why-jetbrains-is-betting-on-focal-llms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fundamental Failure-Mode Theorem: Systems lie about their proper functioning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I have on occasion referred to Le Chatelier&#39;s Principle for complex systems, as presented by John Gall in the book Systemantics: &amp;quot;Every complex system r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250716-00/?p=111383 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of AI in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is no longer a distant idea. It’s already here and changing how we build software. As it advances, new questions emerge about its impact. How deeply will AI be woven into software development? What new opportunities will emerge for companies building AI-powered tools? Perhaps most importantly, how will developers and AI collaborate over the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/07/the-future-of-ai-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering Local AI Together: Docker Model Runner on Hugging Face</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 12:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Docker, we always believe in the power of community and collaboration. It reminds me of what Robert Axelrod said in The Evolution of Cooperation: “The key to doing well lies not in overcoming others, but in eliciting their cooperation.” And what better place for Docker Model Runner to foster this cooperation than at Hugging...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-on-hugging-face/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Import From ZIP, Python Update, Collapsible Sections in Notebooks, and More in Datalore 2025.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 11:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 2025.3 release of Datalore delivers multiple long-awaited features, including a new way to import workspaces, default values for text fields, and tools for organizing assets like collapsible sections and report folders. Read on to learn more. These updates are already available for Datalore Cloud users, and Datalore On-Premises users can get them by updating […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/07/16/workspace-import-from-zip-python-update-collapsible-sections-in-notebooks-and-more-in-datalore-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Better Agents: What’s New in Koog 0.3.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 07:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released Koog 0.3.0, which comes with many updates that make building, running, and managing intelligent agents easier. This version focuses on durability, speed, observability, and smoother integration with real-world systems. If you’ve been exploring how to develop your own intelligent agent that can handle complex workflows, the new and updated Koog could be […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/07/building-better-agents-what-s-new-in-koog-0-3-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Day the Software Community Died: Let’s Stop Coding in Isolation and Start Creating Community—And Software—People Truly Love</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author reflects on the vital role of the software community in shaping their career as an engineer, emphasizing its decline post-COVID-19. They highlight the diminishing local user groups and conferences, attributing this to a lack of appreciation from younger developers and reduced corporate support, particularly from Microsoft. A call to action urges developers to engage, companies to invest, and veterans to mentor, reinforcing the importance of community in fostering quality software.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases now supports Amazon OpenSearch Service Managed Cluster as vector store</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 22:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases has extended its vector store options by enabling support for Amazon OpenSearch Service managed clusters, further strengthening its capabilities as a fully managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) solution. This enhancement builds on the core functionality of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases , which is designed to seamlessly connect foundation models (FMs) with internal data sources. This post provides a comprehensive, step-by-step guide on integrating an Amazon Bedrock knowledge base with an OpenSearch Service managed cluster as its vector store.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor agents built on Amazon Bedrock with Datadog LLM Observability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 22:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a new integration between Datadog LLM Observability and Amazon Bedrock Agents that helps monitor agentic applications built on Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we&#39;ll explore how Datadog&#39;s LLM Observability provides the visibility and control needed to successfully monitor, operate, and debug production-grade agentic applications built on Amazon Bedrock Agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/monitor-agents-built-on-amazon-bedrock-with-datadog-llm-observability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PayU built a secure enterprise AI assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 21:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PayU offers a full-stack digital financial services system that serves the financial needs of merchants, banks, and consumers through technology. In this post, we explain how we equipped the PayU team with an enterprise AI solution and democratized AI access using Amazon Bedrock, without compromising on data residency requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-payu-built-a-secure-enterprise-ai-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your First MCP Server with .NET and Publishing to NuGet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want to extend AI assistants with custom capabilities? In this post, we&#39;ll show you how to build a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server using .NET 10 and publish it to NuGet — making your AI tools discoverable and reusable by the entire .NET community. We&#39;ll also show you some new features we&#39;ve added to .NET 10 and NuGet to support this, and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mcp-server-dotnet-nuget-quickstart 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to Warning Suppressions in Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Code Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 18:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft C++ Code Analysis is a powerful static analysis tool integrated into Visual Studio that helps you identify and fix potential issues in your C++ code. Large projects require effective management of analysis warnings to maintain code quality and you sometimes need to suppress warnings, but must do so in a clear and auditable way.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/updates-to-warning-suppressions-in-microsoft-c-code-analysis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Platform API and SDKs: From UX-First to API-First</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Historically, Power Platform has empowered administrators through the Power Platform Admin Center (PPAC). This UX-first experience offered a seamless, intuitive interface for managing environments, automating everyday tasks, and discovering new capabilities within the platform. Today, we’re taking a bold step forward. We’re tran
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/power-platform-api-and-sdks-from-ux-first-to-api-first 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension concerns when replacing the OS disk</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One confusing area regarding extensions on Azure VMs is - what happens when the OS disk is swapped out? Well, in that case the extensions will run again. Is this the desired behavior? Well, we don&#39;t know. There are many types of extensions. Some handle monitoring and security, so those you&#39;ll probably want to keep. Some install applications
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/extension-concerns-when-replacing-the-os-disk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 6 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the sixth preview release of .NET 10 with enhancements across the .NET Runtime, SDK, libraries, C#, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more. Check out the full release notes linked below and get started today. [cta-button align=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Download .NET 10 Preview 6&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;https://get.d
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-6 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perhaps not a recommended usage for an emergency power outlet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is not uncommon for Microsoft employees who are aficionados of arcade video games to set up a unit in free play mode in a public space for anyone to play. For example, the Habitrail in the Building 16-18 complex
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250715-00/?p=111381 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge generative AI workflows with NVIDIA DGX Cloud on AWS and Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 13:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Andrew Liu, Chelsea Isaac, Zoey Zhang, and Charlie Huang from NVIDIA. DGX Cloud on Amazon Web Services (AWS) represents a significant leap forward in democratizing access to high-performance AI infrastructure. By combining NVIDIA GPU expertise with AWS scalable cloud services, organizations can accelerate their time-to-train, reduce operational complexity, and unlock […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/supercharge-generative-ai-workflows-with-nvidia-dgx-cloud-on-aws-and-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate generative AI inference with NVIDIA Dynamo and Amazon EKS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 13:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces NVIDIA Dynamo and explains how to set it up on Amazon EKS for automated scaling and streamlined Kubernetes operations. We provide a hands-on walkthrough, which uses the NVIDIA Dynamo blueprint on the AI on EKS GitHub repo by AWS Labs to provision the infrastructure, configure monitoring, and install the NVIDIA Dynamo operator.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-generative-ai-inference-with-nvidia-dynamo-and-amazon-eks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS doubles investment in AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, marking two years of customer success</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 12:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, AWS announces a $100 million additional investment in its AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, marking two years of successful customer collaborations across industries from financial services to healthcare. The investment comes as AI evolves toward more autonomous, agentic systems, with the center already helping thousands of customers drive millions in productivity gains and transform customer experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-doubles-investment-in-aws-generative-ai-innovation-center-marking-two-years-of-customer-success/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Debugger: Working With Dynamic Database Connections Just Got Simpler</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 12:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While building Spring Boot applications, you can leverage Testcontainers to spin up any required services, such as a database or messaging broker, as Docker containers at application startup. This enables a ready-to-code setup, minimizing environment friction so you can focus on delivering high-quality, maintainable code. For database-driven development, IntelliJ IDEA provides enterprise-grade, professional-level tooling out […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/07/spring-debugger-working-with-dynamic-database-connections-just-got-simpler/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 10:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? Because of C#’s ability to use verbatim strings, you can use reserved keywords as variable names by prefixing them with the @ symbol. For example, var @class = new Class(); is a perfectly valid statement to make an instance of the Class class. But keep in mind – just because you could […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/15/dotinsights-july-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 14 extension members; AKA extension everything: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I look at the C#14 extension members feature. I show how to convert extension methods to the new syntax and how to add new types of extension.
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-3-csharp-14-extensions-members/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Claude Code Subagents for Complex Development Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 08:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Claude Code subagents create specialized AI teams for complex development. Complete guide with prompts, examples, and best practices.
Link to article: https://goatreview.com/how-to-use-claude-code-subagents-tutorial/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesser-known C# features that can simplify your code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 08:27:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# is a robust OOP language that provides the foundation for building almost every application with .NET. As a C# developer, you are likely familiar with its fundamentals. However, like any legacy technology, it holds more depth to explore and enhance your code&#39;s maintainability and beauty. In this
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/lesser-known-c-features-that-can-simplify-your-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual freedom by design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT is designed to be useful, trustworthy, and adaptable—so you can make it your own.
Link to article: https://openai.com/global-affairs/intellectual-freedom-by-design 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your EWS migration with AI and GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you running apps on Exchange Web Services (EWS)? With EWS support ending in October 2026, this is the perfect time to modernize. We’re excited to announce a new hands-on tutorial that helps you accelerate migrations from EWS to Microsoft Graph, using AI tools you already have access to. This tutorial
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/supercharge-your-ews-migration-with-ai-and-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI-driven policy creation for vehicle data collection and automation using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Sonatus partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to develop a natural language interface to generate data collection and automation policies using generative AI. This innovation aims to reduce the policy generation process from days to minutes while making it accessible to both engineers and non-experts alike. In this post, we explore how we built this system using Sonatus’s Collector AI and Amazon Bedrock. We discuss the background, challenges, and high-level solution architecture.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rapid7 automates vulnerability risk scores with ML pipelines using Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Rapid7 implemented end-to-end automation for the training, validation, and deployment of ML models that predict CVSS vectors. Rapid7 customers have the information they need to accurately understand their risk and prioritize remediation measures.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-rapid7-automates-vulnerability-risk-scores-with-ml-pipelines-using-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build secure RAG applications with AWS serverless data lakes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a secure RAG application using serverless data lake architecture, an important data strategy to support generative AI development. We use Amazon Web Services (AWS) services including Amazon S3, Amazon DynamoDB, AWS Lambda, and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases to create a comprehensive solution supporting unstructured data assets which can be extended to structured data. The post covers how to implement fine-grained access controls for your enterprise data and design metadata-driven retrieval systems that respect security boundaries.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Testing: Using Docker Model Runner with Microcks for Dynamic Mock APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The non-deterministic nature of LLMs makes them ideal for generating dynamic, rich test data, perfect for validating app behavior and ensuring consistent, high-quality user experiences. Today, we’ll walk you through how to use Docker’s Model Runner with Microcks to generate dynamic mock APIs for testing your applications. Microcks is a powerful CNCF tool that allows...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-powered-mock-apis-for-testing-with-docker-and-microcks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Cosmos DB in Microsoft Fabric (Preview) with New Capabilities!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to unveil the open Public Preview of Cosmos DB in Microsoft Fabric, now available to all users! Since our initial announcement at Microsoft Build 2025, we’ve introduced an array of powerful new features to enhance your data workflows.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-cosmos-db-in-microsoft-fabric-preview-with-new-capabilities 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Code Quality at Scale with AI-Powered Code Reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 15:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft, we are constantly looking for ways to improve developer productivity and code quality. One of our most impactful innovations in this space is AI-powered code review assistant — an AI tool that augments pull request (PR) reviews. This AI Assistant started as an internal experiment and now has scaled to suppor
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/enhancing-code-quality-at-scale-with-ai-powered-code-reviews 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025 — Call for Speakers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 14:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Streaming worldwide 8 – 9 October 2025 Have you cracked a performance bottleneck?Built something clever with AI agents?Discovered a design pattern the .NET world should know? Share it with thousands of developers at JetBrains .NET Days Online 2025 – a free, community-driven event broadcast live around the globe. Submit your talk on Sessionize → TL;DR […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/07/14/jetbrains-net-days-online-2025-call-for-speakers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is a &lt;CODE&gt;std::&lt;WBR&gt;chrono::&lt;WBR&gt;high_&lt;WBR&gt;resolution_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt;, but no &lt;CODE&gt;low_&lt;WBR&gt;resolution_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The C++ standard provides a std::chrono::high_resolution_clock which provides the implementation&#39;s clock with the smallest tick period. This gives you the best resolution available to the implementation. But what if you don&#39;t need the best resolution available to the implementation? For examp
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250714-00/?p=111375 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Full Cross-Platform Support for the mssql-python Driver</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 11:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/announcing-full-cross-platform-support-for-the-mssql-python-driver 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Release of the MPS 2025.2 Early Access Program Is Ready</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 05:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today marks another milestone on our journey to MPS 2025.2. You can now download the second build of the MPS 2025.2 EAP and try it out! DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.2 EAP It comes with bug fixes and improvements, such as: Java source and target compatibility was raised to Java 21. VCS libraries are now part of […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/07/the-second-release-mps-2025-2-eap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
