<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:10:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Auth0 Changes The Game for AI Agents - Dev Leader Weekly 119</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss some of the awesome features Auth0 is bringing for building AI agents!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/14/auth0-changes-the-game-for-ai-agents-dev-leader-weekly-119 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-12-12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/12/14/weekly-recap-20251212 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private MCP Catalogs and the Path to Composable Enterprise AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most discussions about Model Context Protocol infrastructure ask how to govern thousands of AI tools and monitor which MCP servers are running. This question is table stakes but undershoots the possibilities. A better question is how we can unleash MCP to drive developer creativity from a trusted foundation. The first question produces a phone book...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/private-mcp-catalogs-oci-composable-enterprise-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Chronicles: When OpenAI’s Magic Meets a Messy User Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author expresses frustration with Sora&#39;s poor user experience and ongoing instability, emphasizing navigation difficulties, session issues, and prolonged outages. Despite Sora&#39;s impressive capabilities, the author argues that without prioritizing user experience and reliability, OpenAI risks losing the trust of professional creators. They urge the hiring of experienced UX designers and engineers.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/12/14/ux-chronicles-when-openais-magic-meets-a-messy-user-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New .slnx Solution Format (migration guide)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2025/13_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_12_2025/13_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            See what changes in .slnx, how to convert your existing .sln, and what to watch out for in CI.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-new-slnx-solution-format-migration-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from AWS re:Invent: Supercharging Kiro with Docker Sandboxes and MCP Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the recent AWS re:Invent, Docker focused on a very real developer problem: how to run AI agents locally without giving them access to your machine, credentials, or filesystem. With AWS introducing Kiro, Docker demonstrated how Docker Sandboxes and MCP Toolkit allow developers to run agents inside isolated containers, keeping host environments and secrets out...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/aws-reinvent-kiro-docker-sandboxes-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a voice-driven AWS assistant with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a sophisticated voice-powered AWS operations assistant using Amazon Nova Sonic for speech processing and Strands Agents for multi-agent orchestration. This solution demonstrates how natural language voice interactions can transform cloud operations, making AWS services more accessible and operations more efficient.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-voice-driven-aws-assistant-with-amazon-nova-sonic/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving an ambiguity in the Windows clipboard automated text conversion table</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we encountered a mystery where the synthesis of CF_OEM­TEXT from CF_TEXT did not use Ansi­To­Oem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251212-05/?p=111862 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement of Global Personal Access Tokens in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the new year, we’ll be retiring the Global Personal Access Token (PAT) type in Azure DevOps. Global PATs allow users to authenticate across all accessible organizations. While this can feel convenient, a single credential with broad reach creates a concentrated security risk — especially as a user’s access
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/retirement-of-global-personal-access-tokens-in-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is AI the New Insider Threat?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Insider threats have always been difficult to manage because they blur the line between trusted access and risky behavior. With generative AI, these risks aren&#39;t tied to malicious insiders misusing credentials or bypassing controls; they come from well-intentioned employees simply trying to get work done faster. Whether it&#39;s developers refactoring code, analysts summarizing long reports,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-insider-threat-shadow-ai-risk-controls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add MCP Servers to ChatGPT with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT is great at answering questions and generating code. But here&#39;s what it can&#39;t do: execute that code, query your actual database, create a GitHub repo with your project, or scrape live data from websites. It&#39;s like having a brilliant advisor who can only talk, never act. Docker MCP Toolkit changes this completely. Here&#39;s what...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/add-mcp-server-to-chatgpt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 3: Under Observation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously in this series: Two articles in, and our coding agent can already do quite a bit. It can explore projects, read and write code, execute shell commands, and run tests. Adding a definition of done (DoD) in our last article gave it the feedback loop it needed – the agent now iterates until all […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-3-under-observation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Qodana on Kubernetes: More Scalability, More Control</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As engineering teams scale, so do the demands on their tooling. Code quality checks that worked well for one repository or service often need a more resilient, automated, and infrastructure-native setup when development ecosystems grow. That’s exactly why we’re excited to introduce first-class Kubernetes support for Qodana, bringing fully automated deployments, lifecycle management, and future-ready […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/12/deploying-qodana-on-kubernetes-more-scalability-more-control/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: 4 Tools That Keep Systems Running</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference — the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and to contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/12/open-source-in-focus-4-tools-that-keep-systems-running/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBVA and OpenAI collaborate to transform global banking</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BBVA is expanding its work with OpenAI through a multi-year AI transformation program, rolling out ChatGPT Enterprise to all 120,000 employees. Together, the companies will develop AI solutions that enhance customer interactions, streamline operations, and help build an AI-native banking experience.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bbva-collaboration-expansion 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BNY builds “AI for everyone, everywhere” with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BNY is using OpenAI technology to expand AI adoption enterprise-wide. Through its Eliza platform, 20,000+ employees are building AI agents that enhance efficiency and improve client outcomes.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bny 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Used Codex to Ship Sora for Android in 28 Days</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI shipped Sora for Android in 28 days using Codex. AI-assisted planning, translation, and parallel coding workflows helped a nimble team deliver rapid, reliable development.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/shipping-sora-for-android-with-codex 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Harmonic Security improved their data-leakage detection system with low-latency fine-tuned models using Amazon SageMaker, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Nova Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how Harmonic Security used Amazon SageMaker AI, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Nova Pro to fine-tune a ModernBERT model, achieving low-latency, accurate, and scalable data leakage detection.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-harmonic-security-improved-their-data-leakage-detection-system-with-low-latency-fine-tuned-models-using-amazon-sagemaker-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-nova-pro/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Swisscom builds enterprise agentic AI for customer support and sales using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll show how Swisscom implemented Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to build and scale their enterprise AI agents for customer support and sales operations. As an early adopter of Amazon Bedrock in the AWS Europe Region (Zurich), Swisscom leads in enterprise AI implementation with their Chatbot Builder system and various AI initiatives. Their successful deployments include Conversational AI powered by Rasa and fine-tuned LLMs on Amazon SageMaker, and the Swisscom Swisscom myAI assistant, built to meet Swiss data protection standards.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying the various locale mismatch scenarios in Windows clipboard text format synthesis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So far, we&#39;ve learned that the conversion between Unicode and the 8-bit ANSI and OEM code pages is performed with the assistance of the CF_LOCALE clipboard format, which itself c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251211-37/?p=111858 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling MLflow for enterprise AI: What’s New in SageMaker AI with MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re announcing Amazon SageMaker AI with MLflow, now including a serverless capability that dynamically manages infrastructure provisioning, scaling, and operations for artificial intelligence and machine learning (AI/ML) development tasks. In this post, we explore how these new capabilities help you run large MLflow workloads—from generative AI agents to large language model (LLM) experimentation—with improved performance, automation, and security using SageMaker AI with MLflow.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scaling-mlflow-for-enterprise-ai-whats-new-in-sagemaker-ai-with-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Observability with Langfuse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how to integrate Langfuse observability with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to gain deep visibility into an AI agent&#39;s performance, debug issues faster, and optimize costs. We walk through a complete implementation using Strands agents deployed on AgentCore Runtime followed by step-by-step code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-agentcore-observability-with-langfuse/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Windows Terminal awesome with GitHub Copilot CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As someone who lives and breathes in the command line, I love making my terminal feel like home. Windows Terminal is full of personalization options that really allow for a custom experience. Additionally, I can stay within my terminal for my development with GitHub Copilot with the GitHub Copilot CLI. Let&#39;s walk through how you can trick out
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/making-windows-terminal-awesome-with-github-copilot-cli 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner now supports vLLM on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Great news for Windows developers working with AI models: Docker Model Runner now supports vLLM on Docker Desktop for Windows with WSL2 and NVIDIA GPUs! Until now, vLLM support in Docker Model Runner was limited to Docker Engine on Linux. With this update, Windows developers can take advantage of vLLM&#39;s high-throughput inference capabilities directly through...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-vllm-windows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Way to Explore kotlinx-benchmark Results with Kotlin Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Benchmarking is an important part of writing efficient Kotlin code. The kotlinx-benchmark library helps you measure and compare performance across different implementations or hardware configurations. However, raw text results only take you so far. Sometimes you need to visualize your data, not just read it. That’s where Kotlin notebooks come in. Kotlin notebooks combine the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/a-better-way-to-explore-kotlinx-benchmark-results-with-kotlin-notebooks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire Integrations, Batteries Included</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Aspire Integrations: Batteries included Modern applications depend on many external services: databases, caches, message brokers, storage layers, observability tools, and sometimes AI systems. Each of these brings its own rules for configuration, connection strings, environment variables, authentication, and deployment. Setting al
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspire-integrations-batteries-included 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy Plugin 2025.11 is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the holidays just around the corner and the year coming to a cheerful close, we’re ringing in the final JetBrains Academy plugin update of 2025, version 2025.11! This release focuses on the introduction of the standalone Hyperskill plugin, expands achievement-sharing to IDE-based courses, and brings a number of improvements and fixes to make your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/11/jetbrains-academy-plugin-2025-11-is-now-available/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Free From AI Vendor Lock-in: Integrating GitHub Models with Docker cagent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The landscape of AI development is rapidly evolving, and one of the most exciting developments in 2025 from Docker is the release of Docker cagent. cagent is Docker&#39;s open-source multi-agent runtime that orchestrates AI agents through declarative YAML configuration. Rather than managing Python environments, SDK versions, and orchestration logic, developers define agent behavior in a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/configure-cagent-github-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB vNext Emulator: Query and Observability Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure Cosmos DB Linux-based vNext emulator (preview) is a local version of the Azure Cosmos DB service that runs as a Docker container on Linux, macOS, and Windows. It provides a cost-effective way to develop and test applications locally without requiring an Azure
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-vnext-emulator-query-and-observability-enhancements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rider and ReSharper 2025.3.0.4: Important Updates Released</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another set of updates for the 2025.3 versions of ReSharper and Rider has just been released. This release contains important bug-fixes as well as feature updates. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. Rider 2025.3.0.4 Multi-agent experience in the AI Chat window: Junie and Claude Agent Claude Agent has become the first third-party AI […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/12/11/rider-and-resharper-2025-3-0-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing science and math with GPT-5.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2 is OpenAI’s strongest model yet for math and science, setting new state-of-the-art results on benchmarks like GPQA Diamond and FrontierMath. This post shows how those gains translate into real research progress, including solving an open theoretical problem and generating reliable mathematical proofs.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-2-for-science-and-math 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB : Becoming a Search-Native Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For years, “Database” and “Search systems&amp;quot; (think Elastic Search) lived in separate worlds. While both Databases and Search Systems operate in the same domain (storing, indexing and querying data), they prioritized different aspects. OLTP Databases prioritized Structured and Semi-structured data
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-becoming-a-search-native-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing revenue 300% by bringing AI to SMBs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Podium used OpenAI’s GPT-5 to build “Jerry,” an AI teammate driving 300% growth and transforming how Main Street businesses serve customers.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/podium 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GPT-5.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2 is our most advanced frontier model for everyday professional work, with state-of-the-art reasoning, long-context understanding, coding, and vision. Use it in ChatGPT and the OpenAI API to power faster, more reliable agentic workflows.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten years</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI reflects on ten years of progress, from early research breakthroughs to widely used AI systems that reshaped what’s possible. We share lessons from the past decade and why we remain optimistic about building AGI that benefits all of humanity.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/ten-years 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Walt Disney Company and OpenAI reach landmark agreement to bring beloved characters to Sora</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Disney and OpenAI have reached an agreement to bring more than 200 Disney, Marvel, Pixar and Star Wars characters to Sora for fan-inspired short videos. The agreement emphasizes responsible AI in entertainment and includes Disney’s company-wide use of ChatGPT Enterprise and the OpenAI API.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/disney-sora-agreement 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update to GPT-5 System Card: GPT-5.2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GPT-5.2 is the latest model family in the GPT-5 series. The comprehensive safety mitigation approach for these models is largely the same as that described in the GPT-5 System Card and GPT-5.1 System Card. Like OpenAI’s other models, the GPT-5.2 models were trained on diverse datasets, including information that is publicly available on the internet, information that we partner with third parties to access, and information that our users or human trainers and researchers provide or generate.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Availability of SharePoint Framework 1.22 - A Major Refresh of the Build &amp; Tooling Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 22:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce general availability of the SharePoint Framework (SPFx) 1.22 – with a focus on refreshing the build and toolchain areas. SharePoint Framework is the easiest and the most widely used model to build your enterprise solutions for Microsoft 365 with automatic single s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/general-availability-of-sharepoint-framework-1-22-a-major-refresh-of-the-build-tooling-experience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement automated smoke testing using Amazon Nova Act headless mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to implement automated smoke testing using Amazon Nova Act headless mode in CI/CD pipelines. We use SauceDemo, a sample ecommerce application, as our target for demonstration. We demonstrate setting up Amazon Nova Act for headless browser automation in CI/CD environments and creating smoke tests that validate key user workflows. We then show how to implement parallel execution to maximize testing efficiency, configure GitLab CI/CD for automatic test execution on every deployment, and apply best practices for maintainable and scalable test automation.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Laravel Support: A New Era for PhpStorm Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For years, PhpStorm has been the go-to IDE for PHP developers – powerful and deeply integrated with the language. But there was one thing many kept asking for: Laravel support out of the box. It should come with built-in — Amdadul Haq (@amdad121) July 30, 2025 Starting with PhpStorm 2025.3, Laravel support is now built […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/12/built-in-laravel-support-a-new-era-for-phpstorm-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2025 (version 1.107)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What&#39;s new in the Visual Studio Code November 2025 Release (1.107). Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/november-2025-(version-1.107) 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2025 Insiders (version 1.107)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn what is new in the Visual Studio Code November 2025 Release (1.107). Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/external-blogs/november-2025-insiders-version-1-107 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining your Git workflow with Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’re a .NET developer with a busy morning, and an Azure DevOps ticket drops: “Login endpoint 500s under load.” You’ve got to fix it, review a teammate’s feature branch, and keep your repo clean - all before lunch. Visual Studio’s Git tools turn this everyday Git workflow of creating topic branches, stashing changes, committing, a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/streamlining-your-git-workflow-with-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does Windows synthesize the &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;LOCALE&lt;/CODE&gt; clipboard format?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we finished with a nice table of now Windows synthesizes each of the three text clipboard formats from the other two. We saw that the CF_LOCALE clipboa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251210-00/?p=111856 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue Center, All Reports Tab, Improved Report Sharing, the Ability to Change User Roles, and More in Datalore 2025.6</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The final Datalore release of the year is here, and it brings multiple improvements designed to make your day-to-day work smoother. Whether you’re trying to keep reports error-free, managing user roles, or setting up environments, Datalore 2025.6 adds new tools that will help you stay organized and productive. Issue center The issue center is available […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/12/10/datalore-2025-6/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Backups in Git Repositories, the Ability to Share Reports With Preselected Values, Mobile Layout for Reports, and More in Datalore 2025.5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Datalore 2025.5 is out with multiple new features and improvements, including a new Git integration for workspace backups, the ability to share reports with preselected values in dropdowns, date pickers, and other inputs, and support for new LLMs in AI Assistant. These updates are already available for Datalore Cloud users, and Datalore On-Premises users can […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2025/12/10/datalore-2025-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Architectural Update: Introducing the New Search Everywhere API (Built for Remote Development)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Search Everywhere dialog is one of the most important entry points in the IntelliJ Platform. To future-proof this core feature and ensure its optimal performance in remote development, we have completely rewritten the underlying architecture, and we’re introducing a brand-new API for plugin developers. This is a critical update for anyone contributing custom results […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/12/major-architectural-update-introducing-the-new-search-everywhere-api-built-for-remote-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening cyber resilience as AI capabilities advance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is investing in stronger safeguards and defensive capabilities as AI models become more powerful in cybersecurity. We explain how we assess risk, limit misuse, and work with the security community to strengthen cyber resilience.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/strengthening-cyber-resilience 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the TeamCity Operator for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running TeamCity in Kubernetes has always been possible, but it often required knowing your way around both systems pretty well. TeamCity is flexible and easy to tune, and Kubernetes provides excellent tools for running applications at scale. However, bringing the two together smoothly wasn’t always straightforward. The new TeamCity Operator is designed to change that. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/teamcity-kubernetes-operator/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Strategy Pattern with Dependency Injection in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:24:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2025/10_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Selection logic is a prominent part of many applications. Whether you add a simple environment toggle, a UI mode decision, or apply a discount, you have to rely on user input. Sometimes, simply using an intuitive if-else or a switch case can work. However, when conditions are growing or a
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/using-strategy-pattern-with-dependency-injection-in-asp-net-core/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-world reasoning: How Amazon Nova Lite 2.0 handles complex customer support scenarios</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post evaluates the reasoning capabilities of our latest offering in the Nova family, Amazon Nova Lite 2.0, using practical scenarios that test these critical dimensions. We compare its performance against other models in the Nova family—Lite 1.0, Micro, Pro 1.0, and Premier—to elucidate how the latest version advances reasoning quality and consistency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/real-world-reasoning-how-amazon-nova-lite-2-0-handles-complex-customer-support-scenarios/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Azure DevOps Server General Availability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce that Azure DevOps Server is now generally available (GA)! This release marks the transition from the Release Candidate (RC) phase to full production readiness, delivering enterprise-grade DevOps capabilities fo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/announcing-azure-devops-server-general-availability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Joins the Agentic AI Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, the Linux Foundation launched the Agentic AI Foundation with three founding projects: Anthropic&#39;s Model Context Protocol (MCP), Block&#39;s goose agent framework, and OpenAI&#39;s AGENTS.md standard. The foundation brings together the companies building the infrastructure layer for agents: Anthropic, Block, OpenAI, Amazon, Google, Microsoft, Cloudflare, and Bloomberg, alongside key tooling and platform companies. Docker is...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-joins-the-agentic-ai-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sky’s the Limit: The Cloud9 × JetBrains Global Hackathon Is Live</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month, we announced that JetBrains is now the Official AI-Powered Coding Partner of Cloud9. The response from the community has been incredible, and today, we’re taking the next step in that journey. We’re excited to launch Sky’s the Limit, a global hackathon designed for developers, esports fans, analysts, and creators who want to push […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/09/sky-s-the-limit-the-cloud9-jetbrains-global-hackathon-is-live/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework December 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for December 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Update Overview .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of December 09, 2025. This update contains non-securi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-december-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue-green deployment in Azure Container Apps using Azure Developer CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Blue-green deployment in Azure Container Apps using Azure Developer CLI If you follow the Azure Developer CLI blog posts, you already know that Azure Container Apps (ACA) support in Azure Developer CLI (azd) is GA. We want azd to be production-ready—you should be a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-blue-green-aca-deployment 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Cross-Platform In-App Billing in .NET MAUI Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the discontinuation of the popular InAppBillingPlugin, many .NET MAUI developers have been looking for guidance on implementing in-app purchases in their applications. Today, we&#39;re sharing a comprehensive sample that demonstrates how to implement cross-platform billing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/cross-platform-billing-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Joins the Agentic Artificial Intelligence Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            JetBrains is joining the new Agentic Artificial Intelligence Foundation (AAIF) hosted by the Linux Foundation. The AAIF brings together leading organizations contributing to the next generation of open agentic technologies. The foundation launches with several key open-source projects – including MCP, goose, and AGENTS.md – which already form an emerging ecosystem for shared standards and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/12/09/jetbrains-joins-the-agentic-artificial-intelligence-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Previewing the JavaScript/TypeScript Modernizer for VS Code Insiders</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previewing the JavaScript/TypeScript Modernizer for VS Code Insiders Keeping JavaScript/TypeScript projects up-to-date can be a challenge, especially when it’s time to upgrade a bunch of npm packages or adopt the latest frameworks. We’ve heard from many JS/TS developers that modernizing an older app (upgrading de
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/jsts-modernizer-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Resource Leaks in Go: How GoLand Helps You Write Safer Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every Go application uses resources, such as files, network connections, HTTP responses, and database query results. But when a resource is left unclosed, it can cause a leak, which drains memory, exhausts system limits, introduces subtle bugs, and eventually brings even the most robust service to failure. Recently, we’ve introduced resource leak analysis in GoLand […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/12/09/preventing-resource-leaks-in-go-how-goland-helps-you-write-safer-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create AI-powered chat assistants for your enterprise with Amazon Quick Suite</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build chat agents in Amazon Quick Suite. We walk through a three-layer framework—identity, instructions, and knowledge—that transforms Quick Suite chat agents into intelligent enterprise AI assistants. In our example, we demonstrate how our chat agent guides feature discovery, use enterprise data to inform recommendations, and tailors solutions based on potential to impact and your team’s adoption readiness.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-ai-powered-chat-assistants-for-your-enterprise-with-amazon-quick-suite/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does Windows synthesize &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;UNICODE­TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; from &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; and vice versa?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we started our exploration of how Windows synthesizes text clipboard formats by looking at the conversion between CF_OEM­TEXT and CF_TEXT
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251209-00/?p=111854 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Your CI/CD Tool Helping or Hindering Performance?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every engineering leader would love to work with a team of elite performers who deploy 182x more frequently, recover from failures 2,293x faster, and achieve 127x faster lead times than low performers. (Yes, that’s the actual difference in performance of real teams from the 2024 DORA research report). But how do you improve your team’s […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2025/12/is-your-ci-cd-tool-helping-or-hindering-performance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperskill Gets Its Own Plugin Inside JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hyperskill is introducing its own free dedicated plugin inside JetBrains IDEs. This new plugin is built specifically for the Hyperskill learning experience and replaces the previous integration inside the JetBrains Academy plugin. Starting December 11, Hyperskill courses will be available exclusively through the new Hyperskill Academy plugin. The new Hyperskill Academy plugin provides a more […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/12/09/hyperskill-gets-its-own-plugin-inside-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSpell 2025.3: Visualization Cells, Multi-Agent Support, Jupyter Improvements.</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the 2025.3 release, DataSpell continues its mission to make data analysts more productive with the help of AI. In addition to improving DataSpell’s own AI agent, this release expands your options by introducing direct access to Claude Agent from the IDE – with more agents coming soon. DataSpell 2025.3 also includes major visualization workflow […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dataspell/2025/12/dataspell-2025-3-visualization-cells-multi-agent-support-jupyter-improvements/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out the Zed editor on Windows for .NET and Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I try out Zed on Windows to see if it can replace my VS Code usages for quick edits of .NET projects and writing Markdown documents
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/trying-out-the-zed-editor-on-windows-for-dotnet-and-markdown/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the RubyMine Team on Reddit AMA Session</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The RubyMine team will be stopping by r/jetbrains on December 11 from 1–5 pm CET and doing an Ask Me Anything (AMA) thread. You’re invited to join us! This isn’t a product launch or a marketing campaign – it’s a chance to have an open conversation about RubyMine and the challenges you face as a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/12/join-the-rubymine-team-on-reddit-ama-session/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI co-founds Agentic AI Foundation, donates AGENTS.md</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI co-founds the Agentic AI Foundation under the Linux Foundation and donates AGENTS.md to support open, interoperable standards for safe agentic AI.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/agentic-ai-foundation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Microsoft Entra PowerShell v1.1.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to introduce Microsoft Entra PowerShell v1.1.0 available on PowerShell Gallery. The headline feature is No more version pinning to Microsoft Graph PowerShell v2.25.0. You can now use the latest Graph modules wi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/entrapowershell/announcing-microsoft-entra-powershell-v1-1-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entra PowerShell Now Supports Latest Microsoft Graph PowerShell Versions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve heard you and we’ve made it happen! One of the most requested changes from our community has been greater flexibility when working with Microsoft Graph PowerShell. Previously, Entra PowerShell pinned its dependency to Microsoft Graph PowerShell v2.25, which limited customers from leveraging
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/entrapowershell/entra-powershell-now-supports-latest-microsoft-graph-powershell-versions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching our first OpenAI Certifications courses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how OpenAI’s new certifications and AI Foundations courses help people build real-world AI skills, boost career opportunities, and prepare for the future of work.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-certificate-courses 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing powerful AI to millions across Europe with Deutsche Telekom</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is collaborating with Deutsche Telekom to bring advanced, multilingual AI experiences to millions of people across Europe. ChatGPT Enterprise will also be deployed to help employees at Deutsche Telekom improve workflows and accelerate innovation.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/deutsche-telekom-collaboration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI fluency at scale with ChatGPT Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Commonwealth Bank of Australia partners with OpenAI to roll out ChatGPT Enterprise to 50,000 employees, building AI fluency at scale to improve customer service and fraud response.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/commonwealth-bank-of-australia 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI appoints Denise Dresser as Chief Revenue Officer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Denise Dresser is joining as Chief Revenue Officer, overseeing OpenAI’s global revenue strategy across enterprise and customer success. She will help more businesses put AI to work in their day-to-day operations as OpenAI continues to scale.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-appoints-denise-dresser 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term data retention up to 10 years: Announcing Private Preview of Azure Backup for Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Backup for Azure Cosmos DB is a new option that lets you securely protect and recover your Azure Cosmos DB data for compliance, audit, and ransomware protection scenarios. It leverages Azure Backup’s vault isolation and Azure Cosmos DB’s native backup streams to deliver scalable, long-term data protection that meets regulatory requir
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/cosmos-db-ltr-immutability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Learn MCP Server Elevates Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you tried asking GitHub Copilot about Aspire 13 or the new Agent Framework and found it either hallucinated an answer or told you that those things didn’t exist? This happens because the model used was trained before those things did exist, so it doesn’t know how to answer or help you. As you continue to innovate and move at the speed
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/microsoft-learn-mcp-server-elevates-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregates in DDD: Model Rules, Not Relationships</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a recent video I did about Domain-Driven Design Misconceptions, there was a comment that turned into a great thread that I want to highlight. Specifically, somebody left a comment about their problem with Aggregates in DDD. Their example: if you have a chat, it has millions of messages. If you have a user, it… Read More »Aggregates in DDD: Model Rules, Not Relationships The post Aggregates in DDD: Model Rules, Not Relationships appeared first on CodeOpinion.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Networking Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As with every release, we publish a blog post about the new and interesting changes and additions in .NET networking space. This time, we are writing about HTTP improvements, new web sockets APIs, security
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-networking-improvements 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host Your Node.js MCP Server on Azure Functions in 3 Simple Steps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI agents with the Model Context Protocol (MCP) is powerful, but when it comes to hosting your MCP server in production, you need a solution that&#39;s reliable, scalable, and cost-effective. What if you could deploy your regular Node.js MCP server to a serverless platform that handles scaling automatically while you only pay for what you
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/host-your-node-js-mcp-server-on-azure-functions-in-3-simple-steps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AWS delivers generative AI to the public sector in weeks, not years</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Experts at the Generative AI Innovation Center share several strategies to help organizations excel with generative AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-aws-delivers-generative-ai-to-the-public-sector-in-weeks-not-years/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2025.3 – Unified IDE, Jupyter notebooks in remote development, uv as default, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that PyCharm 2025.3 is here! This release continues our mission to make PyCharm the most powerful Python IDE for web, data, and AI/ML development. It marks the migration of Community users to the unified PyCharm and brings full support for Jupyter notebooks in remote development, uv as the default environment manager, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/12/pycharm-2025-3-unified-ide-jupyter-notebooks-in-remote-development-uv-as-default-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S&amp;P Global Data integration expands Amazon Quick Research capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are pleased to announce a new integration between Amazon Quick Research and S&amp;amp;P Global. This integration brings both S&amp;amp;P Global Energy news, research, and insights and S&amp;amp;P Global Market Intelligence data to Quick Research customers in one deep research agent. In this post, we explore S&amp;amp;P Global’s data sets and the solution architecture of the integration with Quick Research.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/sp-global-data-integration-expands-amazon-quick-research-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline AI agent tool interactions: Connect API Gateway to AgentCore Gateway with MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AgentCore Gateway now supports API GatewayAs organizations explore the possibilities of agentic applications, they continue to navigate challenges of using enterprise data as context in invocation requests to large language models (LLMs) in a manner that is secure and aligned with enterprise policies. This post covers these new capabilities and shows how to implement them.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-ai-agent-tool-interactions-connect-api-gateway-to-agentcore-gateway-with-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an intelligent insurance underwriter agent powered by Amazon Nova 2 Lite and Amazon Quick Suite</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build an intelligent insurance underwriting agent that addresses three critical challenges: unifying siloed data across CRM systems and databases, providing explainable and auditable AI decisions for regulatory compliance, and enabling automated fraud detection with consistent underwriting rules. The solution combines Amazon Nova 2 Lite for transparent risk assessment, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore for managed MCP server infrastructure, and Amazon Quick Suite for natural language interactions—delivering a production-ready system that underwriters can deploy in under 30 minutes .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python is First Class in Aspire 13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Aspire 13, Python has been elevated to a first-class citizen alongside .NET and JavaScript, transforming Aspire into a truly polyglot application platform. The new Aspire.Hosting.Python package provides comprehensive support for developing, debugging, and deploying Python applications within distributed syst
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/python-is-first-class-in-aspire-13 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does Windows synthesize &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;OEM­TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; from &lt;CODE&gt;CF_&lt;WBR&gt;TEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; and vice versa?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows has three built-in text formats for the clipboard: CF_UNICODE­TEXT: UTF-16 text. CF_TEXT: 8-bit text in ANSI code page. CF_OEM­TEXT: 8-bit text in OEM code page. If you don&#39;t provide all three formats, then the system
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251208-00/?p=111849 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Fleet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Fleet started as our attempt to explore a new generation of JetBrains IDEs, developed in parallel with those based on the IntelliJ Platform. Over time, we learned that having two general-purpose IDE families created confusion and diluted our focus. Rebuilding the full capabilities of IntelliJ-based IDEs inside Fleet did not create enough value, and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/fleet/2025/12/the-future-of-fleet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Compose to Kubernetes to Cloud: Designing and Operating Infrastructure with Kanvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker has long been the simplest way to run containers. Developers start with a docker-compose.yml file, run docker compose up, and get things running fast. As teams grow and workloads expand into Kubernetes and integrate into cloud services, simplicity fades. Kubernetes has become the operating system of the cloud, but your clusters rarely live in...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/compose-to-kubernetes-to-cloud-kanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm 2025.3 Is Now Out</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to PhpStorm 2025.3! This release brings native Claude Agent integration, out-of-the-box Laravel support, support for PHP 8.5, improvements in generics, a new Islands theme, and more. Download PhpStorm 2025.3 PHP PHP 8.5 support PhpStorm 2025.3 supports all of the changes introduced in the recently released PHP 8.5. As usual, you can try new features by setting […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/12/phpstorm-2025-3-is-now-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Made Simple: A Guide for JVM Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was written by an external contributor. Kubernetes is a container orchestration system for deploying, scaling, and managing containerized applications. If you build services on the Java virtual machine (JVM), you likely know that most microservices run on Kubernetes. Kubernetes has become the de facto standard for running containerized microservices at scale. However, Kubernetes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/12/kubernetes-made-simple-a-guide-for-jvm-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junie Now Integrated Into the AI Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we’re always listening closely to our users, ensuring that the products we ship provide a consistent and intuitive user experience. One area for improvement that we both noticed is the presence of two separate UIs – one for Junie, the coding agent by JetBrains, and one for the JetBrains AI chat. We’ve now […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/12/junie-now-integrated-into-the-ai-chat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLand 2025.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GoLand 2025.3 brings a set of powerful upgrades designed to help you write cleaner and more efficient code. This release introduces on-the-fly resource leak detection, bundled Terraform support, smoother single-file editing, updates to golangci-lint integration, and performance boosts everywhere in the IDE. Early resource leak detection GoLand now helps you catch resource leaks – situations […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/12/08/goland-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.3 Is Here, and It’s Epic: Faster Language Engine, Unique Constexpr Debugger, DAP Support, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is one of our largest updates ever, featuring advanced capabilities and refinements to deliver a smoother workflow. CLion 2025.3 represents one of our most ambitious releases yet. Beyond the extensive feature additions and workflow improvements, this version marks a fundamental shift in how we approach C and C++ language support – prioritizing speed and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2025/12/2025-3-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyMine 2025.3: Multi-Agent AI Chat, Rails-Aware MCP Server, Faster Multi-Module Projects Startup, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RubyMine 2025.3 is out! This blog post briefly goes over the highlights of the latest release. For a detailed description, check out our What’s New page. You can get the new build from our website or via the free Toolbox App. AI Assistant Multi-agent experience: Junie and Claude Agent With the addition of Claude Agent, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ruby/2025/12/rubymine-2025-3-multi-agent-ai-chat-rails-aware-mcp-server-faster-multi-module-projects-startup-and-more/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 Is Out Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 has arrived! This version brings significant updates designed to streamline your productivity and help you confidently adopt the latest innovations across the Java ecosystem. You can download this latest release from our website or update to it directly from inside the IDE, via the free Toolbox App, or using snap packages for […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-2025-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Overload Ambiguity with Collection Expressions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OverloadResolutionPriority allows you to specify which method overload should be preferred by the compiler when multiple overloads are applicable. This can be useful in scenarios where you have multiple methods with types that can be implicitly converted to each other, and you want to control which overload is chosen. I&#39;ve found this feature particularly useful when having existing overloads that take…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/resolving-overload-ambiguity-with-collection-expressions.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Scala Plugin 2025.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scala 3 Support Scala 3.8 introduces several significant changes, including a new into modifier, the standard library now being compiled with Scala 3, and the minimum required JDK version being updated to 17. Given that the next Scala version, 3.9 LTS, will focus on stabilization, it was important for us to support these new changes […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2025/12/08/scala-plugin-2025-3-is-out/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unified IntelliJ IDEA: More Free Features, a Better Experience, Smoother Flow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IntelliJ IDEA is now a unified product! As we announced back in July, starting from this release (2025.3), there is one IntelliJ IDEA, replacing the separate IntelliJ IDEA Community Edition and IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate to keep things simple and convenient. All the functionality of the Community Edition remains free for non-commercial and commercial use. We’re […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/12/intellij-idea-unified-release/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Islands Theme – The New Default Look for JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_24/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Islands theme is now the default look across JetBrains IDEs starting with version 2025.3.This update is more than a visual refresh. It’s our commitment to creating a soft, balanced environment designed to support focus and comfort throughout your workflow. We began introducing the new theme earlier this year, gathering feedback, conducting research, and testing it hands-on with developers […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/platform/2025/12/meet-the-islands-theme-the-new-default-look-for-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instacart and OpenAI partner on AI shopping experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_25/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Instacart are deepening their longstanding partnership by bringing the first fully integrated grocery shopping and Instant Checkout payment app to ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/instacart-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of enterprise AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_26/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Key findings from OpenAI’s enterprise data show accelerating AI adoption, deeper integration, and measurable productivity gains across industries in 2025.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/the-state-of-enterprise-ai-2025-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
