<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:34:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Streamline AI operations with the Multi-Provider Generative AI Gateway reference architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the Multi-Provider Generative AI Gateway reference architecture, which provides guidance for deploying LiteLLM into an AWS environment to streamline the management and governance of production generative AI workloads across multiple model providers. This centralized gateway solution addresses common enterprise challenges including provider fragmentation, decentralized governance, operational complexity, and cost management by offering a unified interface that supports Amazon Bedrock, Amazon SageMaker AI, and external providers while maintaining comprehensive security, monitoring, and control capabilities.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview 3 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview 3 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.OData.Core 9.0.0 Preview 3
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-odata-net-odl-9-preview-3-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignite 2025: A Developer’s Guide to Building Agents for Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ignite 2025 brought many innovations for developers building agents for Microsoft 365. From new capabilities in Declarative Agents and Custom Engine Agents to the introduction of Microsoft Agent 365, the platform now enables organizations to arch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/ignite-2025-a-developers-guide-to-building-agents-for-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Docker Hardened Images Patches Vulnerabilities in 24 hours</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 19, 2025, the Golang project published two Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVEs) affecting the widely-used golang.org/x/crypto/ssh package. While neither vulnerability received a critical CVSS score, both presented real risks to applications using SSH functionality in Go-based containers. CVE-2025-58181 affects SSH servers parsing GSSAPI authentication requests. The vulnerability allows attackers to trigger unbounded memory...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-docker-hardened-images-patch-cves-in-24-hours/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy geospatial agents with Foursquare Spatial H3 Hub and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you&#39;ll learn how to deploy geospatial AI agents that can answer complex spatial questions in minutes instead of months. By combining Foursquare Spatial H3 Hub&#39;s analysis-ready geospatial data with reasoning models deployed on Amazon SageMaker AI, you can build agents that enable nontechnical domain experts to perform sophisticated spatial analysis through natural language queries—without requiring geographic information system (GIS) expertise or custom data engineering pipelines.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Wipro PARI accelerates PLC code generation using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Wipro implemented advanced prompt engineering techniques, custom validation logic, and automated code rectification to streamline the development of industrial automation code at scale using Amazon Bedrock. We walk through the architecture along with the key use cases, explain core components and workflows, and share real-world results that show the transformative impact on manufacturing operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-wipro-pari-accelerates-plc-code-generation-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Hype: How to Use AI to Actually Increase Your Productivity as a Dev</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I started incorporating AI tools into my workflow, I was first frustrated. I didn&#39;t get the 5x or 10x gains others raved about on social. In fact, it slowed me down. But I persisted. Partly because I see it as my professional duty as a software engineer to be as productive as possible, partly...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-developer-productivity-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot 4: Leaner, Safer Apps and a New Kotlin Baseline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Spring Boot 4.0 has officially landed. At JetBrains, we’ve been tracking the updates since the first milestones to ensure that IntelliJ IDEA delivers a smooth and reliable development experience. While many of the core capabilities come directly from Spring Framework 7, Spring Boot remains the adoption enabler that brings everything together: sensible defaults, consistent configuration, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/spring-boot-4/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2.5. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. Here are the most notable updates: To find out more details about the issues resolved, please refer to […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-2025-2-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSD explores applying generative Al to improve the deviation management process using AWS services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post has explores how MSD is harnessing the power of generative AI and databases to optimize and transform its manufacturing deviation management process. By creating an accurate and multifaceted knowledge base of past events, deviations, and findings, the company aims to significantly reduce the time and effort required for each new case while maintaining the highest standards of quality and compliance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/msd-explores-applying-generative-al-to-improve-the-deviation-management-process-using-aws-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating genomics variant interpretation with AWS HealthOmics and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we show you how agentic workflows can accelerate the processing and interpretation of genomics pipelines at scale with a natural language interface. We demonstrate a comprehensive genomic variant interpreter agent that combines automated data processing with intelligent analysis to address the entire workflow from raw VCF file ingestion to conversational query interfaces.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-genomics-variant-interpretation-with-aws-healthomics-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rufus scales conversational shopping experiences to millions of Amazon customers with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Our team at Amazon builds Rufus, an AI-powered shopping assistant which delivers intelligent, conversational experiences to delight our customers. More than 250 million customers have used Rufus this year. Monthly users are up 140% YoY and interactions are up 210% YoY. Additionally, customers that use Rufus during a shopping journey are 60% more likely to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-rufus-scales-conversational-shopping-experiences-to-millions-of-amazon-customers-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinventing how .NET Builds and Ships (Again)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After I wrote my last post on how .NET builds and ships, I was cautiously optimistic that I wouldn&#39;t be writing another one. Or at least not another one about how we build and ship. That problem was done and dusted. .NET had done it! We&#39;d struck a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/reinventing-how-dotnet-builds-and-ships-again 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs: What’s New and What’s Next</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Build 2025, we introduced the Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs to help developers bring grounded AI into their solutions without rebuilding indexes or compromising security. The response has been encouraging, and your fee
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-copilot-apis-whats-new-and-whats-next 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop Faster with VS Code for the Web – Azure: Your Browser-Based Dev Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers can now move from idea to Azure-ready code in minutes with VS Code for the Web – Azure. This browser-based environment removes setup time, reduces friction, and gives you immediate access to pre-configured run
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/get-started-with-vs-code-for-the-web 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Complexity to Simplicity: Intelligent JVM Optimizations on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As cloud-native architectures scale across thousands of containers and virtual machines, Java performance tuning has become more distributed, complex, and error-prone than ever. As highlighted in our public preview announcement, traditional JVM optimization relied on ex
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/from-complexity-to-simplicity-intelligent-jvm-optimizations-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Public Preview of Azure Command Launcher for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the Public Preview of the Azure Command Launcher for Java, a new tool that helps developers, SREs, and infrastructure teams standardize and automate JVM configuration on Azure. The goal is to simplify tuning practices and reduce resource waste across Java workloads.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/announcing-the-public-preview-of-azure-command-launcher-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundry Local comes to Android—plus on-device speech, on-prem support, and a simpler SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re introducing a powerful new way to bring AI directly to your mobile apps: Foundry Local on Android. Starting now, you can build Android applications that run AI on-device—no cloud round trips required. Sign up for the gated preview here: https://aka.m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/foundry-local-comes-to-android 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Care Access achieved 86% data processing cost reductions and 66% faster data processing with Amazon Bedrock prompt caching</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how healthcare organizations can securely implement prompt caching technology to streamline medical record processing while maintaining compliance requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-care-access-achieved-86-data-processing-cost-reductions-and-66-faster-data-processing-with-amazon-bedrock-prompt-caching/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Updates and Fixes for ReSharper and Rider 2025.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A second set of updates and bug fixes for the 2025.3 release of ReSharper and Rider has just been made public. Let’s take a look at what’s been improved. ReSharper 2025.3.0.2 For the full list of issues resolved in this build, please refer to our issue tracker. Rider 2025.3.0.2 For the full list of issues we’ve resolved in this […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/20/resharper-rider-2025-3-0-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: Dynamic Data Masking for Azure Cosmos DB (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today marks a big step forward with the public preview of Dynamic Data Masking (DDM) for Azure Cosmos DB. This feature helps organizations protect sensitive data without requiring changes to application logic or database interactions. What is Dynamic Data Masking? Dynamic Data Masking (DDM) is a server-side, policy-driven
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-dynamic-data-masking-for-azure-cosmos-db-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Azure SRE Agent with Azure Cosmos DB: Smarter Diagnostics for Your Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/use-azure-sre-agent-with-azure-cosmos-db-smarter-diagnostics-for-your-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Private Preview: Safe Account Key rotation using Account Key Usage Metadata</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Account Key Usage Metadata is a new security and observability feature that helps Azure Cosmos DB customers avoid service disruptions during key rotations. It provides visibility when each account key was last used
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-private-preview-safe-account-key-rotation-using-account-key-usage-metadata 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and Foxconn collaborate to strengthen U.S. manufacturing across the AI supply chain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Foxconn are collaborating to design and manufacture next-generation AI infrastructure hardware in the U.S. The partnership will develop multiple generations of data-center systems, strengthen U.S. supply chains, and build key components domestically to accelerate advanced AI infrastructure.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-and-foxconn-collaborate 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner Integrates vLLM for High-Throughput Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Expanding Docker Model Runner’s Capabilities Today, we’re excited to announce that Docker Model Runner now integrates the vLLM inference engine and safetensors models, unlocking high-throughput AI inference with the same Docker tooling you already use. When we first introduced Docker Model Runner, our goal was to make it simple for developers to run and experiment...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-integrates-vllm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn AI-Assisted Programming With Junie: Free Courses From JetBrains Academy and Nebius</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For over 25 years, JetBrains has been driven by a desire to make developers more productive and enhance the developer experience by providing smarter, more efficient tools. JetBrains Academy advances this mission by empowering learners to study computer science and gain hands-on experience with the professional tools they’ll use in their future careers. AI is […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/11/20/learn-ai-assisted-programming-with-junie-free-courses-from-jetbrains-academy-and-nebius/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps to GitHub migration Playbook: Unlocking Agentic DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure DevOps or GitHub Enterprise ? Today, in the Microsoft ecosystem, two Software Development Lifecycle management platforms coexist: - Azure DevOps is designed from the ground up for enterprise with advanced planning features through Azure Boards, build and release automation with Azure Pipelines, and a unique
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/azure-devops-to-github-migration-playbook-unlocking-agentic-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping 1,000 small businesses build with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is partnering with DoorDash, SCORE, and local organizations to help 1,000 small businesses build with AI. The Small Business AI Jam gives Main Street business owners hands-on tools and training to compete and grow.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/small-business-ai-jam 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early experiments in accelerating science with GPT-5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI introduces the first research cases showing how GPT-5 accelerates scientific progress across math, physics, biology, and computer science. Explore how AI and researchers collaborate to generate proofs, uncover new insights, and reshape the pace of discovery.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/accelerating-science-gpt-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Guardrails expands support for code domain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 22:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Guardrails now extends its safety controls to protect code generation across twelve programming languages, addressing critical security challenges in AI-assisted software development. In this post, we explore how to configure content filters, prompt attack detection, denied topics, and sensitive information filters to safeguard against threats like prompt injection, data exfiltration, and malicious code generation while maintaining developer productivity .
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-guardrails-expands-support-for-code-domain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the AWS Well-Architected Responsible AI Lens</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re announcing the AWS Well-Architected Responsible AI Lens—a set of thoughtful questions and corresponding best practices that help builders address responsible AI concerns throughout development and operation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/announcing-the-aws-well-architected-responsible-ai-lens/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon uses AI agents to support compliance screening of billions of transactions per day</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon&#39;s AI-powered Amazon Compliance Screening system tackles complex compliance challenges through autonomous agents that analyze, reason through, and resolve cases with precision. This blog post explores how Amazon’s Compliance team built its AI-powered investigation system through a series of AI agents built on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-uses-ai-agents-to-support-compliance-screening-of-billions-of-transactions-per-day/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignite 2025 - What&#39;s new for Office Add-ins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog outlines the new and exciting features now available in the Office Add-ins ecosystem for Ignite 2025. Continue reading for platform updates, developer experience improvements, and store enhancements. Copilot Agents work with office.js to read and write document content, enabling powerful workflows At Build earlier this yea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/ignite-2025-whats-new-for-office-add-ins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge Your Test Coverage with GitHub Copilot Testing for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing high-quality unit tests is critical for reliable software, but it’s often time-consuming and repetitive. What if GitHub Copilot could take care of that for you? Today we’re thrilled to announce GitHub Copilot testing for .NET is now available in Visual Studio Insiders. This new capability brings AI-powered unit test gen
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/github-copilot-testing-for-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the azd AI agent extension: Publish Microsoft Foundry agents directly from your development environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the new azd AI agent extension: Publish Microsoft Foundry agents directly from your development environment If you&#39;ve ever built an AI agent, you know the real challenge is more than writing the code, it&#39;s the complex dance of provisioning resources, managing models, and securely deploying everything to the cloud. We tho
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-foundry-agent-extension 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Agent 365 Interoperability for Smart, Secure Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday we launched Agent 365 - Microsoft’s enterprise control plane for AI agents, designed to make agents secure, compliant, and ready for large-scale deployment within organizations. Agents enabled with Agent 365 have a unique identi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-agent-365-interoperability-for-smart-secure-productivity 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I joined Docker: security at the center of the software supply chain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mark Lechner, Docker’s CISO, shares his vision for a future where Docker not only powers the software supply chain, but actively safeguards it. Cybersecurity has reached a turning point. The most significant threats no longer exploit isolated systems; they move through the connections between them. The modern attack surface includes every dependency, every container, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-i-joined-docker-security-at-the-center-of-the-software-supply-chain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an agentic solution with Amazon Nova, Snowflake, and LangGraph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we cover how you can use tools from Snowflake AI Data Cloud and Amazon Web Services (AWS) to build generative AI solutions that organizations can use to make data-driven decisions, increase operational efficiency, and ultimately gain a competitive edge.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-agentic-solution-with-amazon-nova-snowflake-and-langgraph/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) Nov 2025 - Container Apps (GA), Layered Provisioning (Beta), Extension Framework, and Aspire 13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the November 2025 edition of the Azure Developer CLI (azd) release blog! This post covers releases 1.20.1 through 1.21.2. To share your feedback and questions, join the November release discussion on GitHub. Highlights: Az
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-november-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Spectrum fine-tuning to improve FM training efficiency on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post you will learn how to use Spectrum to optimize resource use and shorten training times without sacrificing quality, as well as how to implement Spectrum fine-tuning with Amazon SageMaker AI training jobs. We will also discuss the tradeoff between QLoRA and Spectrum fine-tuning, showing that while QLoRA is more resource efficient, Spectrum results in higher performance overall.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-spectrum-fine-tuning-to-improve-fm-training-efficiency-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is &lt;code&gt;Write­Process­Memory&lt;/code&gt; faster than shared memory for transferring data between two processes?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Say you need to transfer a large amount of data between two processes. One way is to use shared memory. Is that the fastest way to do it? Can you do any better? One argument against shared memory is that the sender will have to copy the data into the shared memory block, and the recipient will have to copy it out, resulting in two e
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251119-00/?p=111800 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announced at Ignite 2025: Azure DocumentDB, MCP Toolkit, Fleet Analytics, and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announced-at-ignite-2025-azure-documentdb-mcp-toolkit-fleet-analytics-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Update .NET on Wsl or Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:37:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever year or so, a new version of .NET ships, and I need to upgrade the .NET SDK version on my machines. Not just the Windows machines, but also the WSL Ubuntu bits that live on those same machines. First, determine what version of dotnet you already have using this:
1 2
dotnet --version
10.0.100-rc.1.25451.107
Yep, I need to update that. But how? Surely there must be a simple way to do it using just the command line.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Must-Have MCP Servers (and How to Use Them)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The era of AI agents has arrived, and with it, a new standard for how they connect to tools: the Model Context Protocol (MCP). MCP unlocks powerful, flexible workflows by letting agents tap into external tools and systems. But with thousands of MCP servers (including remote ones) now available, it’s easy to ask: Where do...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/top-mcp-servers-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerToys 0.96 is here: endpoints for Advanced Paste, metadata support for PowerRename and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/powertoys-0-96-is-here-endpoints-for-advanced-paste-metadata-support-for-powerrename-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening our safety ecosystem with external testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI works with independent experts to evaluate frontier AI systems. Third-party testing strengthens safety, validates safeguards, and increases transparency in how we assess model capabilities and risks.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/strengthening-safety-with-external-testing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How evals drive the next chapter in AI for businesses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how evals help businesses define, measure, and improve AI performance—reducing risk, boosting productivity, and driving strategic advantage.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/evals-drive-next-chapter-of-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and Target team up on new AI-powered experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Target are partnering to bring a new Target app to ChatGPT, offering personalized shopping and faster checkout. Target will also expand its use of ChatGPT Enterprise to boost productivity and guest experiences.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/target-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A free version of ChatGPT built for teachers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT for Teachers is a secure workspace with education‑grade privacy and admin controls. Free for verified U.S. K–12 educators through June 2027.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/chatgpt-for-teachers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building more with GPT-5.1-Codex-Max</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing GPT-5.1-Codex-Max, a faster, more intelligent agentic coding model for Codex. The model is designed for long-running, project-scale work with enhanced reasoning and token efficiency.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-1-codex-max 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5.1-Codex-Max System Card</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This system card outlines the comprehensive safety measures implemented for GPT‑5.1-CodexMax. It details both model-level mitigations, such as specialized safety training for harmful tasks and prompt injections, and product-level mitigations like agent sandboxing and configurable network access.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-1-codex-max-system-card 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Access Terms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Teacher Access Terms outline how verified educators may use ChatGPT for Teachers, covering eligibility, account management, and data privacy requirements.
Link to article: https://openai.com/policies/education-terms 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing tic-tac-toe to life with AWS AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RoboTic-Tac-Toe is an interactive game where two physical robots move around a tic-tac-toe board, with both the gameplay and robots’ movements orchestrated by LLMs. Players can control the robots using natural language commands, directing them to place their markers on the game board. In this post, we explore the architecture and prompt engineering techniques used to reason about a tic-tac-toe game and decide the next best game strategy and movement plan for the current player.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New T-SQL AI Features are now in Public Preview for Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the start of this year, we released a new set of T-SQL AI features for embedding your relational data for AI applications. Today, we have brought those features to Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. This post will help you get started usi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/ai-functions-public-preview-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A step-by-step guide to modernizing .NET applications with GitHub Copilot agent mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Upgrading an old .NET app doesn’t have to mean chasing broken builds and cryptic errors. Yet for many developers, a simple version bump turns into hours of dependency conflicts and manual fixes. Modernization isn’t just about staying current. Older frameworks can introduce security risks, slow performance, and block cloud adoptio
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/modernizing-dotnet-with-github-copilot-agent-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker &#43; Unsloth: Build Custom Models, Faster</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building and Running Custom Models Is Still Hard Running AI models locally is still hard. Even as open-source LLMs grow more capable, actually getting them to run on your machine, with the right dependencies, remains slow, fragile, and inconsistent. There’s two sides to this challenge: Model creation and optimization: making fine-tuning and quantization efficient. Model...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-unsloth-build-custom-models-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperPod enhances ML infrastructure with security and storage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post introduces two major enhancements to Amazon SageMaker HyperPod that strengthen security and storage capabilities for large-scale machine learning infrastructure. The new features include customer managed key (CMK) support for encrypting EBS volumes with organization-controlled encryption keys, and Amazon EBS CSI driver integration that enables dynamic storage management for Kubernetes volumes in AI workloads.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/hyperpod-enhances-ml-infrastructure-with-security-and-storage/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps and GitHub Repositories — Next Steps in the Path to Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In May, we talked about the evolution of GitHub Copilot from a coding assistant into an AI powered peer programmer. Since then, GitHub has taken a major step forward - becoming an open platform for agentic devel
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-and-github-repositories-next-steps-in-the-path-to-agentic-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating generative AI applications with a platform engineering approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, I will illustrate how applying platform engineering principles to generative AI unlocks faster time-to-value, cost control, and scalable innovation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-generative-ai-applications-with-a-platform-engineering-approach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Microsoft Teams SDK (Formerly the Teams AI Library)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;UPDATE November 17: We&#39;re excited to announce that the Teams AI Library is now called the Microsoft Teams SDK.&amp;quot;]The Teams SDK, now generally available in C# and JavaScript and in public preview for Python, remains a developer’s one-stop-shop to build anything, including conversational agents, for Micros
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-the-updated-teams-ai-library-and-mcp-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spend Less Time Upgrading, More Time Coding in Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the past, moving to the next major version of Visual Studio could take hours, sometimes days, to recreate your dev environment the way you like it. Visual Studio 2026 makes it easier than ever to stay current with the latest productivity features, performance improvements, and security fixes all without disrupting your flow. With the new Vi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/spend-less-time-upgrading-more-time-coding-in-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Innovation to Enterprise Trust with Microsoft Agent 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The bridge between agent innovation and enterprise readiness While teams can build an agent in just a few days, deployin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/from-innovation-to-enterprise-trust-with-microsoft-agent-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: GitHub Copilot Chat GA and New Public Previews for Edit Data, Data-tier Application, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code continues to evolve, delivering features that make SQL development more integrated, more consistent, and more developer-friendly. In version v1.37.0, we’re announcing the Public Preview of Edit Data,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-copilot-ga-edit-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 3 Pro Is Now Available in JetBrains IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest AI model from Google, Gemini 3 Pro, is now live in JetBrains IDEs. From day one, it powers AI Chat and soon will be available in Junie, our coding agent, giving you smarter reasoning, stronger instruction following, and seamless integration into your workflow. What’s new Gemini 3 Pro shows clear improvements that matter […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/gemini-3-pro-is-now-available-in-jetbrains-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Major New Agentic Capabilities for GitHub Copilot in JetBrains and Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot is taking a major step forward with expanded, deeply integrated support for JetBrains and Eclipse — bringing a new generation of agentic, intelligent capabilities directly into your favorite Java IDEs. This release strengthens Copilot’s cross-IDE experience, unifies agentic workflows, and unlocks m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/new-agentic-capabilities-for-github-copilot-in-jetbrains-and-eclipse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public preview of vector indexing in Azure SQL DB, Azure SQL MI, and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to share that DiskANN vector indexing is now in public preview across Azure SQL Database, Azure SQL Managed Instance, and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. DiskANN is a cutting-edge algorithm for efficient vector similarity search, making it ideal for powering recommendation systems
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/public-preview-of-vector-indexing-in-azure-sql-db-azure-sql-mi-and-sql-database-in-microsoft-fabric 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Generally Available: Azure Cosmos DB Fleet Pools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce two updates to Azure Cosmos DB fleets: Fleet pools – now generally available Fleet analytics – now in public preview Azure Cosmos DB fleets enables developers to build scalable, isolated, and cost-effective multi-tenant or Software as a Service (SaaS) applications. Today,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-generally-available-azure-cosmos-db-fleet-pool 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Release of MPS 2025.3 Early Access Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting today, you can download the second EAP release for MPS 2025.3 and try all the latest updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2025.3 EAP 2 This release includes several noteworthy improvements: JavaDoc language overhaul The JavaDoc language has been completely migrated to use the jetbrains.mps.lang.text language for text representation and editing. This change should have minimal impact […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/mps/2025/11/the-mps-2025-3-eap2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch a Chat UI Agent with Docker and the Vercel AI SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running a Chat UI Agent doesn’t have to involve a complicated setup. By combining Docker with the Vercel AI SDK, it’s possible to build and launch a conversational interface in a clean, reproducible way. Docker ensures that the environment is consistent across machines, while the Vercel AI SDK provides the tools for handling streaming responses...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/launch-chat-ui-agent-docker-vercel-ai-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping Decision‑Makers Say Yes to Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the fourth post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/helping-decision-makers-say-yes-to-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source in Focus: Projects We’re Proud to Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At JetBrains, we love seeing the developer community grow and thrive. That’s why we support open-source projects that make a real difference — the ones that help developers learn, build, and create better software together. We’re proud to back open-source maintainers with free licenses and to contribute to initiatives that strengthen the ecosystem and the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2025/11/18/open-source-in-focus-projects-we-re-proud-to-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Companies complaining .NET moves too fast should just pay for post-EOL support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe a solution to .NET &amp;quot;releasing too quickly&amp;quot;: just pay for support of older versions, such as HeroDevs&#39; Never Ending Support for .NET 6
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/companies-using-dotnet-need-to-suck-it-up-and-pay-for-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Read Models with EF Core Projections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 08:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can&#39;t really argue against the importance of performance in any application. Even if the system is not time-critical, efficient and time-saving operations are cornerstones of the system. Data fetching is the primary step for improving the performance of most applications. If you use Entity Framework Core (EF
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/building-read-models-with-ef-core-projections/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intuit and OpenAI join forces on new AI-powered experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Intuit have entered a $100M+ multi-year partnership to launch Intuit app experiences in ChatGPT and expand Intuit’s use of OpenAI’s frontier models to power personalized financial tools.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/intuit-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing MSVC AddressSanitizer for ARM64 targets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announceÂ AddressSanitizerÂ (ASan) support for the Microsoft C++ (MSVC) Build Tools forÂ ARM64 targets.Â ASan is a runtime memory error detector thatÂ
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/introducing-msvc-addresssanitizer-for-arm64-targets 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your complete guide to Amazon Quick Suite at AWS re:Invent 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, re:Invent will be held in Las Vegas, Nevada, from December 1 to December 5, 2025, and this guide will help you navigate our comprehensive session catalog and plan your week. The sessions cater to business and technology leaders, product and engineering teams, and data and analytics teams interested in incorporating agentic AI capabilities across their teams and organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/your-complete-guide-to-amazon-quick-suite-at-aws-reinvent-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate enterprise solutions with agentic AI-powered consulting: Introducing AWS Professional Service Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m excited to announce AWS Professional Services now offers specialized AI agents including the AWS Professional Services Delivery Agent. This represents a transformation to the consulting experience that embeds intelligent agents throughout the consulting life cycle to deliver better value for customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-enterprise-solutions-with-agentic-ai-powered-consulting-introducing-aws-professional-service-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Claude: Transforming business with agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Claude are enabling enterprises like Cox Automotive and Druva to deploy production-ready agentic AI systems that deliver measurable business value, with results including up to 63% autonomous issue resolution and 58% faster response times. We examine the technical foundation combining Claude&#39;s frontier AI capabilities with AgentCore&#39;s enterprise-grade infrastructure that allows organizations to focus on agent logic rather than building complex operational systems from scratch.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing C# 14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# 14 ships with .NET 10. The highlight is new extension members, but there&#39;s a lot more features that make your life as a developer more productive. And, we&#39;ve added new features that enable some of the performance improvements you can experience in .NET 10. Read on for a tour of all the new features, and find links to dive de
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-csharp-14 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing F# 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            F# 10 is now shipping with .NET 10 and Visual Studio 2026. This version is a refinement release focused on clarity, consistency, and performance, bringing small but meaningful improvements that make your everyday code more legible and robust. You can get F# 10 today in a few ways:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-fsharp-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect that Windows is running in S-Mode, redux</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Igor Levicki asked for a plain C version of the sample code to detect whether Windows is running in S-Mode. I didn&#39;t write one for two reasons. First, I didn&#39;t realize that so many people still tried to use COM from plain C. A
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251117-00/?p=111795 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Features in Rider</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rider provides robust support for working with databases directly within the IDE – powered by DataGrip! Rider and DataGrip smooth development workflows by allowing you to manage and interact with a variety of database systems. This integration enhances productivity for developers who frequently work with data. Database projects and connectivity There has long been support […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/17/database-features-in-rider/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize GUID creation performance in .NET applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Many .NET projects use well-known GUIDs as identifiers for activities, interop scenarios, database keys, and other purposes. It&#39;s common to see code like new Guid(&amp;quot;01234567-8901-2345-6789-012345678901&amp;quot;) throughout applications. While this approach is readable and straightforward, it comes with a hidden performance cost that can impact application startup time. This is a micro-optimization that primarily…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/optimize-guid-creation-performance-in-dotnet-applications.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Prepare for the Future of Programming</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Start a start-up? Scratch that. Call your mom. Go back to school? Don’t go back to school. Learn to code? Don’t learn to code. Forget coding. Only prompt engineering matters now. Actually, I heard it’s overrated. You think we’re gonna be prompting in 5 years? 2 years? Nonsense. All this hype is being blown so […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/education/2025/11/17/how-to-prepare-for-the-future-of-programming/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Your Calendars! Qodana Events in November</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As 2025 starts racing to a close, the JetBrains Qodana team is ending the year with a series of events dedicated to what matters most in modern software development: secure workflows, high-quality code, and practical tooling that empowers developers to ship with confidence. Whether you’re working in security engineering, backend development, DevOps, or AI-powered applications, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2025/11/mark-your-calendars-qodana-events-in-november/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI named Emerging Leader in Generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI has been named an Emerging Leader in Gartner’s 2025 Innovation Guide for Generative AI Model Providers. The recognition reflects our enterprise momentum, with over 1 million companies building with ChatGPT.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/gartner-2025-emerging-leader 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement forgot your password using swiyu, ASP.NET Core Identity and Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post show to implement a “Forgot your password” flow using the Swiss Digital identity and trust infrastructure, (swiyu) in an ASP.NET Core web application using ASP.NET Core Identity and Duende IdentityServer. The generic containers from swiyu are used to integrate the Swiss E-ID and the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations standards. .NET Aspire is used […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/11/17/implement-forgot-your-password-using-swiyu-asp-net-core-identity-and-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Diffusion Models Could Change Developer Workflows in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers spend much of their time editing, refactoring, and debugging rather than producing entirely new code. Code creation tends to involve non-sequential back-and-forth refinement rather than typing out a complete function in one uninterrupted sequence. You might sketch a part, adjust parameters, skip ahead, then revisit earlier sections to refine them. Diffusion models, and in […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2025/11/why-diffusion-models-could-change-developer-workflows-in-2026/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Programming Rule #4: Safe and Efficient Type Casting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_11_2025/16_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_11_2025/16_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article emphasizes defensive programming by highlighting safe type compatibility checks in .NET. It advises using the &#39;is&#39; keyword to prevent InvalidCastException and warns against unnecessary type casts that clutter code and affect performance. The open-source project Spargine aids developers with tools for better validation and logging, promoting cleaner, more resilient applications.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/11/16/defensive-programming-rule-4-safe-and-efficient-type-casting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is My Developer Career JUST Maintenance?! - Dev Leader Weekly 116</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss just how much of our developer careers are maintaining software systems.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/15/is-my-developer-career-just-maintenance-dev-leader-weekly-116 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-11-14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/15/weekly-recap-20251114 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Is Heading to VSLive! Orlando</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Next week we’ll be in Orlando, Florida for Visual Studio Live!, and if you work with .NET, we’d like to meet you. You’ll find the JetBrains booth (#118) in the conference expo area throughout the week. Stop by to: We’ll also have special offers available for those who visit the booth.
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/15/jetbrains-is-heading-to-vslive-orlando/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring C# File-based Apps in .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2025/15_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With .NET 10, Microsoft introduced file-based apps, which give you the ability to write C# code in a single .cs file and run it directly, without any project or solution files. This feature finally makes C# approachable for quick scripts and utilities
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/exploring-csharp-file-based-apps-in-dotnet-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a biomedical research agent with Biomni tools and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a production-ready biomedical research agent by integrating Biomni&#39;s specialized tools with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, enabling researchers to access over 30 biomedical databases through a secure, scalable infrastructure. The implementation showcases how to transform research prototypes into enterprise-grade systems with persistent memory, semantic tool discovery, and comprehensive observability for scientific reproducibility .
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-biomedical-research-agent-with-biomni-tools-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your web apps hands-free with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Graphical user interfaces have carried the torch for decades, but today’s users increasingly expect to talk to their applications. In this post we show how we added a true voice-first experience to a reference application—the Smart Todo App—turning routine task management into a fluid, hands-free conversation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/make-your-web-apps-hands-free-with-amazon-nova-sonic/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the power of generative AI: Druva’s multi-agent copilot for streamlined data protection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI is transforming the way businesses interact with their customers and revolutionizing conversational interfaces for complex IT operations. Druva, a leading provider of data security solutions, is at the forefront of this transformation. In collaboration with Amazon Web Services (AWS), Druva is developing a cutting-edge generative AI-powered multi-agent copilot that aims to redefine the customer experience in data security and cyber resilience.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/harnessing-the-power-of-generative-ai-druvas-multi-agent-copilot-for-streamlined-data-protection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Trial – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            First steps: Run your first secure, production-ready image Container base images form the foundation of your application security. When those foundations contain vulnerabilities, every service built on top inherits the same risk. Docker Hardened Images addresses this at the source. These are continuously-maintained, minimal base images designed for security: stripped of unnecessary packages, patched proactively,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-trial-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.3 💚 Spring 7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Major Spring Framework releases don’t come around often – and when they do, they tend to reshape how we build applications for years to come. Spring Framework 7 is one of those releases. It simplifies many aspects of development, cleans up some long-standing pain points, and introduces features that previously required custom annotations or boilerplate-heavy […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/intellij-idea-2025-3-spring-7/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I can use &lt;CODE&gt;WM_&lt;WBR&gt;COPY&lt;WBR&gt;DATA&lt;/CODE&gt; to send a block of data to another window, but how does it send data back?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The WM_COPY­DATA message can be used to send a blob of data from one window to another. The window manager does the work of copying the data from the sending process to the receiving process, but how does the receiving process send data back? If the only information that needs to come back is a success/failure,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251114-00/?p=111792 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure MCP Server Now Built-In with Visual Studio 2026: A New Era for Agentic Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing cloud resources often means juggling multiple tools, writing custom scripts, and switching contexts between your IDE and cloud management portals. These extra steps slow development and make it harder to build intelligent, secure applications efficiently. We’re excited to announce that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/azure-mcp-server-now-built-in-with-visual-studio-2026-a-new-era-for-agentic-workflows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Great AI Productivity Divide: Why Are Some Developers 5x Faster?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered developer tools claim to boost your productivity, doing everything from intelligent auto-complete to (https://openai.com/index/introducing-codex/). But the productivity gains users report have been something of a mixed bag. Some groups claim to get 3-5x (or more), productivity boosts, while other devs claim to get no benefit at all—or even losses of up to 19%. I...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-productivity-divide-developers-5x-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial Videos: Setting up GitHub Copilot for your Company</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide shares a series of videos that walk you through setting up GitHub and GitHub Copilot end-to-end for your company. These are especially useful for organizations starting from scratch who want to leverage GitHub Copilot and are looking to get started. These videos were recorded as of October 2025.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/tutorial-videos-setting-up-github-copilot-for-your-company 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing OpenAI for Ireland</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI launches OpenAI for Ireland, partnering with the Irish Government, Dogpatch Labs and Patch to help SMEs, founders and young builders use AI to innovate, boost productivity and build the next generation of Irish tech startups.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/openai-for-ireland 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
