<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:51:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced fine-tuning techniques for multi-agent orchestration: Patterns from Amazon at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how fine-tuning enabled a 33% reduction in dangerous medication errors (Amazon Pharmacy), engineering 80% human effort reduction (Amazon Global Engineering Services), and content quality assessments improving 77% to 96% accuracy (Amazon A+). This post details the techniques behind these outcomes: from foundational methods like Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) (instruction tuning), and Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO), to Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) for human alignment, to cutting-edge reasoning optimizations such as Grouped-based Reinforcement Learning from Policy Optimization (GRPO), Direct Advantage Policy Optimization (DAPO), and Group Sequence Policy Optimization (GSPO) purpose-built for agentic systems.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Palo Alto Networks enhanced device security infra log analysis with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Palo Alto Networks’ Device Security team wanted to detect early warning signs of potential production issues to provide more time to SMEs to react to these emerging problems. They partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to develop an automated log classification pipeline powered by Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we discuss how Amazon Bedrock, through Anthropic’ s Claude Haiku model, and Amazon Titan Text Embeddings work together to automatically classify and analyze log data.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From beginner to champion: A student’s journey through the AWS AI League ASEAN finals</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS AI League, launched by Amazon Web Services (AWS), expanded its reach to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) last year, welcoming student participants from Singapore, Indonesia, Malaysia, Thailand, Vietnam, and the Philippines. In this blog post, you’ll hear directly from the AWS AI League champion, Blix D. Foryasen, as he shares his reflection on the challenges, breakthroughs, and key lessons discovered throughout the competition.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy AI agents on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore using GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use a GitHub Actions workflow to automate the deployment of AI agents on AgentCore Runtime. This approach delivers a scalable solution with enterprise-level security controls, providing complete continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) automation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-ai-agents-on-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-using-github-actions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making (Very) Small LLMs Smarter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, I’m Philippe, and I am a Principal Solutions Architect helping customers with their usage of Docker. I started getting seriously interested in generative AI about two years ago. What interests me most is the ability to run language models (LLMs) directly on my laptop (For work, I have a MacBook Pro M2 max, but...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-small-llms-smarter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Building Your First Serverless HTTP API on Azure with Azure Functions &amp; FastAPI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This post is Part 1 of the series Serverless Application Development with Azure Functions and Az
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/building-your-first-serverless-http-api-on-azure-with-azure-functions-fastapi 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update your Kotlin projects for Android Gradle Plugin 9.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Android Gradle plugin 9.0 is now available, and it includes two major changes that will affect existing Kotlin projects: This post provides some details about these changes and points you to the resources that you’ll need to update your existing projects. You’ll also need to update tools and plugins that depend on AGP to their […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/update-your-projects-for-agp9/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate Small Language Model Function Calling using the Azure AI Evaluation SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In recent years, Small Language Models (SLMs) have become increasingly important. SLMs are language models with far fewer parameters and use significantly fewer resources than their Large Language Model (LLM) counterparts, while still achieving comparable performance in specific tasks. SLMs are ideal for environments wh
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/slm-function-calling-with-azure-ai-evaluation-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GPT-5.2 Availability in Azure for U.S. Government Secret and Top Secret Clouds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that GPT-5.2, Azure OpenAI’s newest frontier reasoning model, is available in Microsoft Azure for U.S. Government Secret and Top Secret cloud environments. This release marks another significant milestone in our mission to b
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/advancing-ai-capabilities-in-azure-for-u-s-government-secret-and-top-secret-clouds 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Amazon AMET Payments team accelerates test case generation with Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how we overcame the limitations of single-agent AI systems through a human-centric approach, implemented structured outputs to significantly reduce hallucinations and built a scalable solution now positioned for expansion across the AMET QA team and later across other QA teams in International Emerging Stores and Payments (IESP) Org.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-the-amazon-amet-payments-team-accelerates-test-case-generation-with-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI-powered business reporting solution with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces generative AI guided business reporting—with a focus on writing achievements &amp;amp; challenges about your business—providing a smart, practical solution that helps simplify and accelerate internal communication and reporting.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-generative-ai-powered-business-reporting-solution-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguard generative AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can address these challenges by adding centralized safeguards to a custom multi-provider generative AI gateway using Amazon Bedrock Guardrails.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/safeguard-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale creative asset discovery with Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings unified vector search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we describe how you can use Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings to retrieve specific video segments. We also review a real-world use case in which Nova Multimodal Embeddings achieved a recall success rate of 96.7% and a high-precision recall of 73.3% (returning the target content in the top two results) when tested against a library of 170 gaming creative assets. The model also demonstrates strong cross-language capabilities with minimal performance degradation across multiple languages.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When programs assume that the system will never change, episode 4: Stealing strings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer had a program that automated a workflow, and one of the steps was to run a console program that came with Windows, and that console program printed a confirmation prompt &amp;quot;Are you sure (Y/N)?&amp;quot;. They wanted to programmatically say Yes, but since the customer had employees around the world, they couldn&#39;t hard code the lette
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260115-00/?p=111988 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permission-Aware RAG: End-to-End Testing with the SpiceDB Testcontainer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We use GenAI in every facet of technology now - internal knowledge bases, customer support systems, and code review bots, to name just a few use cases. And in nearly every one of these, someone eventually asks: What stops the model from returning something the user shouldn’t see?” This is a roadblock that companies building...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/rag-permission-testing-testcontainers-spicedb/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCode with Docker Model Runner for Private AI Coding</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered coding assistants are becoming a core part of modern development workflows. At the same time, many teams are increasingly concerned about where their code goes, how it’s processed, and who has access to it. By combining OpenCode with Docker Model Runner, you can build a powerful AI-assisted coding experience while keeping full control over...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/opencode-docker-model-runner-private-ai-coding/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Microsoft Entra PowerShell v1.2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to introduce Microsoft Entra PowerShell v1.2.0, a major update that delivers full support for Agent Identity Blueprints, expanded application configuration capabilities, and modernized invitation APIs aligned with Microsoft Graph
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/entrapowershell/announcing-microsoft-entra-powershell-v1-2-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot Memories</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you wasting time reviewing code for nits on code standards, project preferences, or important contribution guidelines?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/copilot-memories 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TransformConf: a New Conference on AI in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TransformConf, a new event focused on how AI is transforming software development, is coming in 2026! Save the date: September 15–16, London, UK. Early bird tickets are already available! AI is revolutionizing software development – that much barely needs saying. AI is already a daily tool for 85% of developers, and 68% expect AI proficiency […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2026/01/15/transformconf-a-new-conference-on-ai-in-software-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala 3.8 Support in the Scala Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello everyone, As I write these words, the Scala compiler team is wrapping up the Scala 3.8 release. It’s the last major release before a feature freeze. The next one, 3.9, will be the new Long-Term Support version. The compiler team decided that most of the work between 3.8 and 3.9 will go into stabilization, […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2026/01/15/scala-38-support-in-the-scala-plugin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Conf 2026 — Call for Proposals Is Now Open</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 08:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every production system has a story behind it. The scaling limit you didn’
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-conf-2026-call-for-proposals-is-open 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing in Merge Labs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is investing in Merge Labs to support new brain computer interfaces that bridge biological and artificial intelligence to maximize human ability, agency, and experience.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/investing-in-merge-labs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building docfind: Fast Client-Side Search with Rust and WebAssembly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How we built docfind, a high-performance client-side search engine using Rust and WebAssembly, and how GitHub Copilot accelerated development. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/building-docfind:-fast-client-side-search-with-rust-and-webassembly 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening the U.S. AI supply chain through domestic manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI launches a new RFP to strengthen the U.S. AI supply chain by accelerating domestic manufacturing, creating jobs, and scaling AI infrastructure.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/strengthening-the-us-ai-supply-chain 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AutoScout24 built a Bot Factory to standardize AI agent development with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the architecture that AutoScout24 used to build their standardized AI development framework, enabling rapid deployment of secure and scalable AI agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-autoscout24-built-a-bot-factory-to-standardize-ai-agent-development-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform AI development with new Amazon SageMaker AI model customization and large-scale training capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how new serverless model customization capabilities, elastic training, checkpointless training, and serverless MLflow work together to accelerate your AI development from months to days.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transform-ai-development-with-new-amazon-sagemaker-ai-model-customization-and-large-scale-training-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safer Docker Hub Pulls via a Sonatype-Protected Proxy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why a “protected repo”? Modern teams depend on public container images, yet most environments lack a single, auditable control point for what gets pulled and when. This often leads to three operational challenges: Inconsistent or improvised base images that drift across teams and pipelines. Exposure to new CVEs when tags remain unchanged but upstream content...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/safer-docker-hub-pulls-via-a-sonatype-protected-proxy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot Studio Extension for Visual Studio Code Is Now Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you build agents with the Copilot Studio extension for Visual Studio Code, you already know the fastest way to iterate is to treat your agent like software: version it, review changes, and promote it through environments with confidence. Today, the Microsoft Copilot Studio extension fo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/copilot-studio-extension-for-visual-studio-code-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Agent Academy: Operative</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this year, we launched Agent Academy: Recruit, a foundational learning path designed to help makers and developers get started with building agents in Copilot Studio. The response exceeded our expectations. Since launch, thousands of learners have worked through the Recruit
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-agent-academy-operative 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Aspire to a Python RAG Application</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adding Aspire to a Python RAG Application Imagine you&#39;re developing a RAG (Retrieval Augmented Generation) application with a Python backend, TypeScript frontend, and a few different Azure services. Your local development setup requires multiple terminal windows, hardcoded ports scattered across config files, and a deployment proc
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/adding-aspire-to-a-python-rag-application 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clipping the focus item when looking for its on-screen location, part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we clipped the focus item to the accessible parent so that we considered only the visible portion of the item. But we found that this failed to clip some items, such as it
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260114-00/?p=111986 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI partners with Cerebras</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI partners with Cerebras to add 750MW of high-speed AI compute, reducing inference latency and making ChatGPT faster for real-time AI workloads.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/cerebras-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Global Project Configuration: One Place to Manage All Your Qodana Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Global Project Configuration is a new feature that helps Qodana users manage linter settings across an entire organization or team – all from one location. Until now, maintaining consistent code quality rules meant updating configuration profiles in every individual repository. Whether you were approving new licenses, adjusting rule severity, or defining custom patterns for hardcoded […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/qodana/2026/01/introducing-global-project-configuration-one-place-to-manage-all-your-qodana-rules/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in .NET 10 and C# 14: Enhancements in APIs Request/Response Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:53:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2026/14_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 is officially out, along with C# 14. Microsoft has released .NET 10 as Long-Term Support (LTS) as a successor to .NET 8. Like every version, it is not just an update but brings something new to the table. In this series, we will explore which aspects of software
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/new-in-net-10-and-c-14-enhancements-in-apis-request-response-pipeline/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Amazon Bedrock cross-Region inference: Geographic and global</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 23:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the security considerations and best practices for implementing Amazon Bedrock cross-Region inference profiles. Whether you&#39;re building a generative AI application or need to meet specific regional compliance requirements, this guide will help you understand the secure architecture of Amazon Bedrock CRIS and how to properly configure your implementation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/securing-amazon-bedrock-cross-region-inference-geographic-and-global/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework January 2026 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for January 2026. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Update Overview .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of January 09, 2026. This update contains non-security
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-january-2026-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights Into China’s Developer Landscape: Key Trends From the JetBrains Developer Ecosystem Survey 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every year, thousands of developers take part in the JetBrains Developer Ecosystem Survey, helping us map the evolving landscape of software development worldwide. Published in eight languages with data from 20 geographical regions, the survey includes China – a fast-evolving market that shares many global characteristics while retaining distinct traits of its own. For example, Java […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2026/01/insights-into-china-s-developer-landscape-key-trends/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clipping the focus item when looking for its on-screen location, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we clipped the focus item to the containing window so that we considered only the visible portion of the item. But we found that some programs use a dummy 0×0 window as their win
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260113-00/?p=111984 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose Multiplatform 1.10.0: Unified @Preview, Navigation 3, and Stable Compose Hot Reload</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Multiplatform 1.10.0 has been released! We’re continually developing our multiplatform APIs and expanding support for Jetpack libraries commonly used on Android. Here are the highlights of this release: Get Started with Compose Multiplatform For a complete overview of the changes, check out What’s new in Compose Multiplatform 1.10.0 or the release notes on GitHub. […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/compose-multiplatform-1-10-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to Compose Hot Reload 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Compose Hot Reload has just been promoted to stable with our 1.0.0 release. We worked hard to build a technology that is easy to use and well-integrated into existing tools while also requiring zero configuration from users. The tool is bundled with Compose Multiplatform, starting from version 1.10 (see our dedicated release blog post). While […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/the-journey-to-compose-hot-reload-1-0-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering Real-Time Gaming Experiences with Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Scenario: When Every Millisecond Counts in Gaming Imagine millions of players logging in at the exact moment a new game season launches. Leaderboards light up, achievements tally, and in-game shops buzz with transactions. In these high-stakes moments, speed and reliability aren’t opt
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/powering-real-time-gaming-experiences-with-azure-cosmos-db-for-nosql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2026.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re now working on our next major release, which we plan to deliver in March. In our latest stable version (v2025.3), we introduced many features and enhancements, so for the next release, we’ve decided to focus on maintenance and bug fixes rather than introducing new functionality. With that in mind, we’ve prioritized the following areas […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2026/01/2026-1-roadmap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Windows File Explorer replacement, File Pilot, is awesome</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I describe my experience with the Windows File Explorer replacement, File Pilot. It&#39;s blazingly fast, feature rich, and has hotkeys everywhere
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/windows-explorer-replacement-filepilot-is-awesome/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents in Kotlin – Part 4: Delegation and Sub-Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 08:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2026/13_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Previously in this series: In the previous installment, we saw how to set up tracing, which brings us to two new questions: What should we experiment with based on the information this tool provides? And what parts of our agent could we improve using its observations? The first idea we had was to experiment with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/ai/2026/01/building-ai-agents-in-kotlin-part-4-delegation-and-sub-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2025 in Kotlin: Puzzles, Prizes, and Community</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you to everyone who participated in Advent of Code 2025 in Kotlin! Once again, it was a joy to see so many of you sharing solutions, cheering each other on in Slack, and keeping the holiday coding spirit alive. This year, we kicked things off with five days of livestreams on December 1–5, with […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2026/01/advent-of-code-2025-in-kotlin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Android Widgets with .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest blog from Toine de Boer. This blog takes a look at the Android side of the interactive widget created in the previous blog on iOS Widgets. Android is gen
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/how-to-build-android-widgets-with-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Troubleshoot Builds With TeamCity Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was brought to you by Damaso Sanoja, draft.dev. If you’re spending your mornings debugging Jenkins pipeline failures, waiting for builds that should take minutes but stretch into hours, or scrambling to identify which plugin update broke your deployment process, you’re not alone. These daily troubleshooting battles with legacy CI/CD systems drain engineering time […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2026/01/how-to-troubleshoot-teamcity-builds-using-dashboards/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAANG Interview Tips - Dev Leader Weekly 122</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss my tips for prepping for FAANG interviews!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/01/12/faang-interview-tips-dev-leader-weekly-122 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire for JavaScript developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Remember when Aspire was just for .NET folks? Yeah, those days are over. With Aspire 13, JavaScript and TypeScript developers get to join the party—and I&#39;m not talking about some half-baked afterthought integration. This is first-class, full-featured support for orchestrating your JavaScript apps in distributed systems. [alert typ
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspire-for-javascript-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Synchronize .NET&#39;s Virtual Monorepo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In our previous post &amp;quot;Reinventing how .NET Builds and Ships&amp;quot;, Matt covered our recent overhaul of .NET&#39;s building and shipping processes. A key part of this multi-year effort, which we called Unified Build, is the introduction of the Vi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/how-we-synchronize-dotnets-virtual-monorepo 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Omada Health scaled patient care by fine-tuning Llama models on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Sunaina Kavi, AI/ML Product Manager at Omada Health. Omada Health, a longtime innovator in virtual healthcare delivery, launched a new nutrition experience in 2025, featuring OmadaSpark, an AI agent trained with robust clinical input that delivers real-time motivational interviewing and nutrition education. It was built on AWS. OmadaSpark was designed […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-omada-health-scaled-patient-care-by-fine-tuning-llama-models-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2026-01-09</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2026/01/12/weekly-recap-20260109 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clipping the focus item when looking for its on-screen location</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we used Active Accessibility to locate the focus item, but I noted that there was a quirk. The quirk is that the focus item might be clipped. For example, if you ta
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260112-00/?p=111980 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing Backwards With Go</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from John Arundel, a Go writer and teacher who runs a free email course for Go learners. His book The Power of Go: Tests is a love letter to test-driven development in Go. Have you ever tried programming backwards? If not, you’re in for a treat! You won’t even need […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2026/01/12/dancing-backwards-with-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Level of Authentication (LoA) with ASP.NET Core Identity and Duende</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 06:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_01_2026/12_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to implement an application which requires a user to authenticate using passkeys. The identity provider returns three claims to prove the authentication level (loa), the identity level, (loi) and the amr claim showing the used authentication method. Code: https://github.com/swiss-ssi-group/swiyu-passkeys-idp-loi-loa Blogs in this series: The amr claim and the loa claim returns […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2026/01/12/implementing-level-of-authentication-loa-with-asp-net-core-identity-and-duende/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File I/O Performance: Picking the Fastest Weapon in Your Arsenal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2026/11_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_01_2026/11_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article provides insights on the fastest file I/O methods for .NET 10, emphasizing benchmarks with 1 MB payloads.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2026/01/11/file-i-o-performance-picking-the-fastest-weapon-in-your-arsenal/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossmodal search with Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2026/10_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2026/10_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings addresses the challenges of crossmodal search through a practical ecommerce use case. We examine the technical limitations of traditional approaches and demonstrate how Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings enables retrieval across text, images, and other modalities. You learn how to implement a crossmodal search system by generating embeddings, handling queries, and measuring performance. We provide working code examples and share how to add these capabilities to your applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Message Ordering from First Principles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2026/10_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_01_2026/10_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Per-aggregate ordering is what we really want. But queues with competing consumers make it surprisingly easy to break. This article shows how the “fix” naturally evolves into a saga.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/solving-message-ordering-from-first-principles 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating LLM inference with post-training weight and activation using AWQ and GPTQ on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Quantized models can be seamlessly deployed on Amazon SageMaker AI using a few lines of code. In this post, we explore why quantization matters—how it enables lower-cost inference, supports deployment on resource-constrained hardware, and reduces both the financial and environmental impact of modern LLMs, while preserving most of their original performance. We also take a deep dive into the principles behind PTQ and demonstrate how to quantize the model of your choice and deploy it on Amazon SageMaker.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Is a Developer Experience Problem, Rooted in Our Foundations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For more than a decade, the industry has tried to improve software security by pushing it closer to developers. We moved scanners into CI, added security checks to pull requests, and asked teams to respond faster to an ever-growing stream of vulnerabilities. And yet, the underlying problems have not gone away. The issue is not...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/security-is-a-developer-experience-problem-rooted-in-our-foundations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Beekeeper optimized user personalization with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Beekeeper’s automated leaderboard approach and human feedback loop system for dynamic LLM and prompt pair selection addresses the key challenges organizations face in navigating the rapidly evolving landscape of language models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-beekeeper-optimized-user-personalization-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis with Text and Audio Using AWS Generative AI Services: Approaches, Challenges, and Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post, developed through a strategic scientific partnership between AWS and the Instituto de Ciência e Tecnologia Itaú (ICTi), P&amp;amp;D hub maintained by Itaú Unibanco, the largest private bank in Latin America, explores the technical aspects of sentiment analysis for both text and audio. We present experiments comparing multiple machine learning (ML) models and services, discuss the trade-offs and pitfalls of each approach, and highlight how AWS services can be orchestrated to build robust, end-to-end solutions.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecting TrueLook’s AI-powered construction safety system on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides a detailed architectural overview of how TrueLook built its AI-powered safety monitoring system using SageMaker AI, highlighting key technical decisions, pipeline design patterns, and MLOps best practices. You will gain valuable insights into designing scalable computer vision solutions on AWS, particularly around model training workflows, automated pipeline creation, and production deployment strategies for real-time inference.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/architecting-truelooks-ai-powered-construction-safety-system-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Active Accessibility to find out where the focus item is</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we learned how to use Active Accessibility to find the caret, but what if the focus is not on an edit control? In that case, we want to find the focus object. GUITHREA
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260109-00/?p=111976 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a Free Market Fire Department System Beats the Archaic Public Model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By a devoted advocate for individual choice
Introduction: Fire Protection, Reimagined 🚒 In a nation that prizes personal responsibility, it’s time to ask whether a single, taxpayer-funded fire department model still serves us best. A market of competing fire protection providers would let every household choose the coverage, response times, and perks that match their unique risk profile and budget. What’s more, it would allow individuals and households to prioritize how they want to spend their money, rather than leaving it up to big government and its known inefficiencies.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Real Users Into a Product Team Gathering – A JetBrains Research Story</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In product development, assumptions about how people will use a tool don’t always align with the practical reality. Last spring, during a gathering of our Junie team, we set out to bridge that gap by trying something new. We ran two hands-on user workshops – one online and another in our Belgrade office. For the […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/research/2026/01/bringing-real-users-into-a-product-team-gathering-a-jetbrains-research-story/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and SoftBank Group partner with SB Energy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and SoftBank Group partner with SB Energy to develop multi-gigawatt AI data center campuses, including a 1.2 GW Texas facility supporting the Stargate initiative.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/stargate-sb-energy-partnership 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datadog uses Codex for system-level code review</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2026/09_01_2026_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI and Datadog brand graphic with the OpenAI wordmark on the left, the Datadog logo on the right, and a central abstract brown fur-like texture panel on a white background.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/datadog 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
