<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 20:04:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Rocks Austin .NET User Group November 2025 Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 20:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The dotNetDave No Rest for the Wicked World Tour will visit Austin on November 20, 2025, where I will present a session titled &amp;quot;Röck Yoür Cöde.&amp;quot; This session addresses critical issues in memory management related to disposable types in .NET, offering practical techniques to enhance application performance and prevent slowdowns and leaks.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/11/10/dotnetdave-rocks-austin-net-user-group-november-2025-meeting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune VLMs for multipage document-to-JSON with SageMaker AI and SWIFT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate that fine-tuning VLMs provides a powerful and flexible approach to automate and significantly enhance document understanding capabilities. We also demonstrate that using focused fine-tuning allows smaller, multi-modal models to compete effectively with much larger counterparts (98% accuracy with Qwen2.5 VL 3B).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-vlms-for-multipage-document-to-json-with-sagemaker-ai-and-swift/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Clario automates clinical research analysis using generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Clario has used Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services to build an AI-powered solution that automates and improves the analysis of COA interviews.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-clario-automates-clinical-research-analysis-using-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did Windows 3.1 distinguish two different programs that happened to share the same executable name?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I described the purpose of the icons in the moricons.dll and progman.exe icon libraries, along with a list of which programs Windows automatically associated the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251110-00/?p=111779 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Define the Future of Development – Take the Docker State of Application Development Survey 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the fourth annual Docker State of Application Development survey! Please help us better understand and serve the application development community with just 20 minutes of your time. We want to know where you’re focused, what you’re working on, and what is most important to you. Your thoughts and feedback will help us build...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/state-of-application-development-survey-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust vs. Python: Finding the right balance between speed and simplicity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post was brought to you by Damaso Sanoja, draft.dev. Deciding whether to use Python or Rust isn’t just a syntax choice; it’s a career bet. According to the StackOverflow Developer Survey, Python dominates in accessibility, with 66.4% of people learning to code choosing it as their entry point. Python usage skyrocketed from 32% […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/rust/2025/11/10/rust-vs-python-finding-the-right-balance-between-speed-and-simplicity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Advanced High Availability Features in Azure Cosmos DB SDKs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB is engineered from the ground up to deliver high availability, low latency, throughput, and consistency guarantees for globally distributed applications. As mission-critical systems increasingly rely on Cosmos DB for performance at scale, understanding and configuring advanced high availability feature
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/configuring-advanced-high-availability-features-in-azure-cosmos-db-sdks 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 14 Extension Members: Enhancing Polyfill Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C# has long supported extension methods, allowing developers to add new methods to existing types without modifying the original type. However, this capability was limited to instance methods. With C# 14, the language introduces extension members, significantly expanding what you can extend. You can now add extension properties and extension static methods to existing types. This enhancement is…
Link to article: https://www.meziantou.net/csharp-14-extension-members-enhancing-polyfill-libraries.htm?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=syndication 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Go Ecosystem in 2025: Key Trends in Frameworks, Tools, and Developer Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 09:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Go turns 16 this year. To celebrate this milestone, we have taken a closer look at the latest Developer Ecosystem Survey results and examined the evolution of the Go ecosystem over the past five years. According to JetBrains Data Playground, 2.2 million professional developers use Go as their primary programming language – twice as many […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2025/11/10/go-language-trends-ecosystem-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement MFA using swiyu, the Swiss E-ID with Duende IdentityServer, ASP.NET Core Identity and .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The post shows how to use the Swiss Digital identity and trust infrastructure, (swiyu) as an MFA method in an ASP.NET Core web application using ASP.NET Core Identity and Duende IdentityServer. The generic containers from swiyu are used to integrate the Swiss E-ID and the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations standards. Code: https://github.com/swiss-ssi-group/swiyu-idp-mfa-aspire-aspnetcore Blogs in this […]
Link to article: https://damienbod.com/2025/11/10/implement-mfa-using-swiyu-the-swiss-e-id-with-duende-identityserver-asp-net-core-identity-and-net-aspire/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free ChatGPT for transitioning U.S. servicemembers and veterans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenAI is offering U.S. servicemembers and veterans within 12 months of retirement or separation a free year of ChatGPT Plus to support their transition to civilian life. The tools can help with resumes, interviews, education, and planning for what’s next.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/chatgpt-for-veterans 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Programming Rule #3: Validate Your Enums (Every Time)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2025/09_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_11_2025/09_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enums enhance code readability but can lead to errors if not validated, as any integer can be cast as an Enum, including invalid values. Validating Enum inputs prevents silent data corruption, ensures meaningful defaults, and avoids processing impossible states. Always validate at method boundaries and define a zero value as &amp;quot;unknown.&amp;quot;
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/11/09/defensive-programming-rule-3-validate-your-enums-every-time/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vibe Coding 2.0 - Dev Leader Weekly 115</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2025/08_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2025/08_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to another issue of Dev Leader Weekly! In this issue, I discuss the vibes. And they are indeed immaculate.
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/08/vibe-coding-20-dev-leader-weekly-115 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap - 2025-11-07</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2025/08_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2025/08_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check out this week from Dev Leader! Here&#39;s a list including articles and videos on software engineering, career development, and programming in C#!
Link to article: https://www.devleader.ca/2025/11/08/weekly-recap-20251107 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Idempotent Consumer Pattern in .NET (And Why You Need It)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2025/08_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_11_2025/08_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Distributed systems don&#39;t fail cleanly: they retry, duplicate, and occasionally fail. This article shows how to design resilient message handlers in .NET using broker-level idempotency and the Idempotent Consumer pattern, so your system stays consistent no matter how many times a message is delivered.
Link to article: https://www.milanjovanovic.tech/blog/the-idempotent-consumer-pattern-in-dotnet-and-why-you-need-it 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows MIDI Services and the 10-MIDI driver limit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 22:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The USB MIDI 1.0 specification was released in the late 90s around the same time that PCs were starting to move from rectangular beige boxes to things like fake-silvered bulbous plastic shapes. At this point, some of the code in Windows to support USB MIDI 1.0 has become intergenerational – it&#39;s certainly older than my teenagers here at h
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/windows-midi-services-and-the-10-midi-driver-limit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratizing AI: How Thomson Reuters Open Arena supports no-code AI for every professional with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how TR addressed key business use cases with Open Arena, a highly scalable and flexible no-code AI solution powered by Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services such as Amazon OpenSearch Service, Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3), Amazon DynamoDB, and AWS Lambda. We&#39;ll explain how TR used AWS services to build this solution, including how the architecture was designed, the use cases it solves, and the business profiles that use it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing structured output for Custom Model Import in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the addition of structured output to Custom Model Import. Structured output constrains a model&#39;s generation process in real time so that every token it produces conforms to a schema you define. Rather than relying on prompt-engineering tricks or brittle post-processing scripts, you can now generate structured outputs directly at inference time.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-structured-output-for-custom-model-import-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.4-2 and 1.24.10-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-4-2-and-1-24-10-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelePeer supercharges its agentic AI platform with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reducing latency by 50% and scaling intelligent CX for SMBs This article was co-authored by Sergey Galchenko, Chief Technology Officer, IntelePeer, and Subhash Ramamoorthi, Director, IntelePeer AI Hub. Don’t miss: Discover how IntelePeer enhances agent intelligence and powers their multi-agent
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/intelepeer-supercharges-its-agentic-ai-platform-with-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Restructuring the tree</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve been looking at non-recursive algorithms for deleting the nodes of a binary tree. The previous algorithm performed a postorder traversal, cleverly repurposing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251107-00/?p=111774 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most DevSecOps Advice Is Useless without Context—Here’s What Actually Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generic DevSecOps advice may sound good on paper, but it often fails in practice because it ignores team context, workflow, and environment-specific needs. Overloaded controls, broad policies, and misapplied tools disrupt the flow of development. And once flow breaks, security measures are the first to get bypassed. The way forward isn&#39;t more rules but smarter...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/context-aware-devsecops-what-works/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding prompt injections: a frontier security challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Prompt injections are a frontier security challenge for AI systems. Learn how these attacks work and how OpenAI is advancing research, training models, and building safeguards for users.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/prompt-injections 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notion’s rebuild for agentic AI: How GPT‑5 helped unlock autonomous workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Notion rebuilt its AI architecture with GPT-5 to create autonomous agents that reason, act, and adapt across workflows. Learn how this shift unlocked smarter, faster, and more flexible productivity in Notion 3.0.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/notion 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patterns for Building a Scalable Multi-Agent System</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction LLMs are enabling a new generation of multi-agent systems that tackle complex, multi-step tasks. Moving from prototype to production is hard—especially when orchestrating dozens or hundreds of specialized agents. Commercial viability depends on intentional design, scalability, latency control, and predictable outcomes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/multi-agent-systems-at-scale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Real-Time Analytics to AI: Your Azure Cosmos DB &amp; DocumentDB Agenda for Microsoft Ignite 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 21:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Ignite 2025 is your opportunity to explore how Azure Cosmos DB, Cosmos DB in Microsoft Fabric, and DocumentDB power the next ge
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmosdb-documentdb-agenda-microsoft-ignite-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting recent MIDI issues in Windows 11 (and Windows 10)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 21:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you are on Windows 11 (or Windows 10 for the UAD issue) and recently had either of these two issues, please read on: You use a Universal Audio (UAD) device and found that all or most of your MIDI devices are no longer recognized in your DAW in Windows 11 or Windows 10 You have a new MIDI 2.0 (UMP Data Format – mo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/troubleshooting-recent-midi-issues-in-windows-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic MCPs with Docker: Stop Hardcoding Your Agents’ World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MCP protocol is almost one year old and during that time, developers have built thousands of new MCP servers. Thinking back to MCP demos from six months ago, most developers were using one or two local MCP servers, each contributing just a handful of tools. Six months later and we have access to thousands...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/dynamic-mcps-stop-hardcoding-your-agents-world/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform your MCP architecture: Unite MCP servers through AgentCore Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this year, we introduced Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, a fully managed service that serves as a centralized MCP tool server, providing a unified interface where agents can discover, access, and invoke tools. Today, we&#39;re extending support for existing MCP servers as a new target type in AgentCore Gateway. With this capability, you can group multiple task-specific MCP servers aligned to agent goals behind a single, manageable MCP gateway interface. This reduces the operational complexity of maintaining separate gateways, while providing the same centralized tool and authentication management that existed for REST APIs and AWS Lambda functions.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Synthesizing the parent pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we looked at a way to delete a binary tree non-recursively, assuming that we had parent pointers. But nodes in a classical binary tree does not remember t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251106-00/?p=111771 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Pilot to Practice: How BBVA Is Scaling AI Across the Organization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BBVA is reimagining how employees work with ChatGPT Enterprise, embedding AI into everyday operations. The bank has saved hours per week per employee, created 20,000+ Custom GPTs, and achieved up to 80% efficiency gains.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/bbva-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Critter Stack Gets Even Better at Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 02:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            My internal code name for one of the new features I’m describing is “multi-stage tracked sessions” which somehow got me thinking of the ZZ Top song “Stages” and their Afterburner album because the sound track for getting this work done this week. Not ZZ Top’s best stuff, but there’s still some bangers on it, or … Continue reading The Critter Stack Gets Even Better at Testing →
Link to article: https://jeremydmiller.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI progress and recommendations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is advancing fast. We have the chance to shape its progress—toward discovery, safety, and a better future for everyone.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/ai-progress-and-recommendations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Teen Safety Blueprint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover OpenAI’s Teen Safety Blueprint—a roadmap for building AI responsibly with safeguards, age-appropriate design, and collaboration to protect and empower young people online.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/introducing-the-teen-safety-blueprint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source AI Editor: Second Milestone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ghost text suggestions are now open source as part of the Copilot Chat extension - the second milestone in making VS Code an open source AI editor. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/open-source-ai-editor:-second-milestone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for AI in Visual Studio (November)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to share our public roadmap, which outlines the next steps in evolving Visual Studio with AI-powered agentic experiences. With every month, we aim to deliver smarter, faster, and more intuitive tools that enhance your coding experience. Disclaimer: The items outlined here represent ongoing work for the month. They
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/roadmap-for-ai-in-visual-studio-november 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Copilot Studio uses .NET and WebAssembly for performance and innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot Studio is at the forefront of conversational AI and automation, empowering organizations to build, customize, and manage intelligent copilots and bots for a wide range of enterprise scenarios. As the platform has evolved, so too have the t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/copilot-studio-dotnet-wasm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Search increased ML training twofold using AWS Batch for Amazon SageMaker Training jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Amazon Search optimized GPU instance utilization by leveraging AWS Batch for SageMaker Training jobs. This managed solution enabled us to orchestrate machine learning (ML) training workloads on GPU-accelerated instance families like P5, P4, and others. We will also provide a step-by-step walkthrough of the use case implementation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-search-increased-ml-training-twofold-using-aws-batch-for-amazon-sagemaker-training-jobs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rider 2025.3 Release Candidate Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The next big release for Rider is just around the corner! If you’re eager to get a sneak peek, you can download the Release Candidate version of Rider 2025.3 from our website right now. Here are the feature highlights of the Rider 2025.3 RC build: If you encounter any issues when using the Rider 2025.3 […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/05/the-rider-2025-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper, .NET Tools, and ReSharper C&#43;&#43; 2025.3 Release Candidates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get a preview of all the latest features and improvements set to be shipped with the next major ReSharper by downloading the Release Candidate builds that have just landed. The ReSharper 2025.3 Release Candidate For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to the issue tracker. dotTrace, dotMemory, dotCover and dotPeek […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/05/the-resharper-dotnet-tools-2025-3-release-candidate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Traversal with parent pointers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a challenge, a colleague of mine told me to find a non-recursive constant-space algorithm for deleting a binary tree.¹ After a moment&#39;s thought, I was able to come up with an algorithm. It is often the case that solving a problem is easier once you are told that a solution exists. When I asked the Internet for a non-recu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251105-00/?p=111765 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | November 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Did you know? C# includes a feature called “expression-bodied members“, which allows you to define one-line methods, properties, constructors, and destructors in a very concise way. Welcome to dotInsights by JetBrains! This newsletter is the home for recent .NET and software development related information. 🔗 Links Here’s the latest from the developer community. 🔦 From […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/05/dotinsights-november-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – November 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This edition is packed with insightful, practical, and curiosity-fueling reads. From hands-on advice to thought-provoking pieces, we’ve gathered a nice selection of stories that will help you stay sharp and inspired in the tech world. We’re also happy to have Josh Long as our featured content author this month! Expect some top-notch insights and a […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/java-annotated-monthly-november-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Available: Sort Geospatial Query Results by ST_Distance in Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB’s geospatial capabilities just got even better! We&#39;re excited to announce that you can now sort query results by distance using an ORDER BY ST_DISTANCE(...) clause in the NoSQL query language while leveraging a spatial index. [video width=&amp;quot;1920
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-available-sort-geospatial-query-results-by-st_distance-in-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Advisor for Azure Cosmos DB: Actionable insights to improve performance and cost</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL now features Query Advisor, designed to help you write faster and more efficient queries. Whether you’re optimizing for performance, cost, or scalability, Query Advisor provides actionable recommendations to help you get the most out of your data. Why Query Optimization Matters Azure Cosmos DB’
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/query-advisor-for-azure-cosmos-db-actionable-insights-to-improve-performance-and-cost 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Kotlin Adoption in Your Company</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Guest post by Urs Peter, Senior Software Engineer and JetBrains-certified Kotlin Trainer. For readers who’d like a more structured way to build Kotlin skills, Urs also leads the Kotlin Upskill Program at Xebia Academy. This is the third post in The Ultimate Guide to Successfully Adopting Kotlin in a Java-Dominated Environment, a series that follows how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/kotlin/2025/11/growing-kotlin-adoption-in-your-company-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Smart Performance Hacks For Faster Python Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post from Dido Grigorov, a deep learning engineer and Python programmer with 17 years of experience in the field. In the rapidly evolving domain of software development, Python has established itself as a premier language, renowned for its simplicity, readability, and versatility. It underpins a vast range of applications, from web […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2025/11/10-smart-performance-hacks-for-faster-python-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repository pattern vs. Specification pattern: Which is more maintainable?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:33:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When talking about Domain-Driven Design (DDD), the repository pattern becomes a default choice for the data access layer. Another pattern is the Specification pattern that organizes code into smaller objects. The question raised here is which suits your project and which is more maintainable as your project scales? I will
Link to article: https://blog.elmah.io/repository-pattern-vs-specification-pattern-which-is-more-maintainable/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 million business customers putting AI to work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            More than 1 million business customers around the world now use OpenAI. Across healthcare, life sciences, financial services, and more, ChatGPT and our APIs are driving a new era of intelligent, AI-powered work.
Link to article: https://openai.com/index/1-million-businesses-putting-ai-to-work 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Experience for all Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agents took over VS Code in 2025. We released agent mode for VS Code, integration for the Copilot coding agent, and the new GitHub Copilot CLI. But Copilot is not the only agent game in town. There are now more coding agents than ever, including options from OpenAI and Anthropic.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/a-unified-experience-for-all-coding-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI: Azure Container Apps Dev-to-Prod Deployment with Layered Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how to implement &amp;quot;build once, deploy everywhere&amp;quot; patterns using Azure Container Apps with the new azd publish and layered infrastructure features in Azure Developer CLI v1.20.0. You&#39;ll learn how to deploy the same containerized application across multiple environments with proper separation of concerns.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-developer-cli-azure-container-apps-dev-to-prod-deployment-with-layered-infrastructure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterate faster with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime direct code deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock AgentCore is an agentic platform for building, deploying, and operating effective agents securely at scale. Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime is a fully managed service of Bedrock AgentCore, which provides low latency serverless environments to deploy agents and tools. It provides session isolation, supports multiple agent frameworks including popular open-source frameworks, and handles multimodal […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/iterate-faster-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime-direct-code-deployment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready for .NET Conf 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Conf 2025 is just one week away! Join us November 11-13 for this free, three-day virtual conference showcasing the latest advancements in the .NET platform, open-source projects, and developer tools - including the official release of .NET 10 and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/get-ready-for-dotnet-conf-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpStorm Plugins You Might Not Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PhpStorm comes with a ton of built-in features, and you can add even more with plugins. They bring new languages, tools, and small improvements that make everyday coding smoother. Many of the best ones come from independent developers. One of them is Dmitrii Derepko, who built several handy tools for working with web projects and […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/2025/11/phpstorm-plugins-you-might-not-know/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JDConf 2026 Is Coming With Modern Solutions for an Agentic World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Technology is accelerating faster than ever, and developers are once again at the helm, shaping the future of applications, intelligence, and enterprise systems. With the rise of large language models (LLMs), agent-oriented architectures, and AI-driven development paradigms, Java developers find themselves in a uniquely po
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/jdconf-2026-is-coming-with-modern-solutions-for-an-agentic-world 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Entry Point: A Single Entry Point for Context-Aware Coding Assistance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern IDEs are powerful tools with many useful features. When we talk about developer productivity, one thing that comes to mind is mastering the IDE – learning its features, like refactorings, navigation, or code generation, and remembering how to invoke them. However, discovering all the relevant features of your IDE, and knowing when and how […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2025/11/universal-entry-point-a-single-entry-point-for-context-aware-coding-assistance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Microsoft SoftCard for the Apple II: Getting two processors to share the same memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Z-80 SoftCard was a plug-in expansion card for the Apple II that added the ability to run CP/M software. According to Wikipedia, it was Microsoft&#39;s first hardware product and in 1980 was the single largest revenue source for the company. CP/M runs on an 8080 pr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251104-00/?p=111758 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming the Billion Dollar Mistake: Maarten Balliauw’s Guide to C# Nullable Reference Types</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the most recent JetBrains.NET Days Online 2025 event, Maarten Balliauw delivered a comprehensive session on migrating existing codebases to use C# nullable reference types, a feature that’s been available since C# 8 but remains underutilized in many legacy projects. Through practical examples and migration strategies, Maarten demonstrated how to bring null safety to your […]
Link to article: https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2025/11/04/maarten-balliauws-guide-to-csharp-nullable-reference-types/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering Distributed AI/ML at Scale with Azure and Anyscale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The path from prototype to production for AI/ML workloads is rarely straightforward. As data pipelines expand and model complexity grows, teams can find themselves spending more time orchestrating distributed compute than building the intelligence that powers their products. Scaling from a laptop experiment to a production-grade workload still
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/powering-distributed-aiml-at-scale-with-azure-and-anyscale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easier reflection with [UnsafeAccessorType] in .NET 10: Exploring the .NET 10 preview - Part 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I show how to work with [UnsafeAccessor] to do &#39;easier&#39; reflection and how to use .NET 10&#39;s [UnsafeAccessorType] with types you can&#39;t reference
Link to article: https://andrewlock.net/exploring-dotnet-10-preview-features-9-easier-reflection-with-unsafeaccessortype/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I learned after speaking at my first Big International Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s easy to say ‘Public Speaking’. But there are lots of factors that you can (and should) consider when talking to an international audience, especially if English is not your first language.
Link to article: https://www.code4it.dev/blog/after-first-big-tech-conference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
