<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:37:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Governing ML lifecycle at scale: Best practices to set up cost and usage visibility of ML workloads in multi-account environments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud costs can significantly impact your business operations. Gaining real-time visibility into infrastructure expenses, usage patterns, and cost drivers is essential. To allocate costs to cloud resources, a tagging strategy is essential. This post outlines steps you can take to implement a comprehensive tagging governance strategy across accounts, using AWS tools and services that provide visibility and control. By setting up automated policy enforcement and checks, you can achieve cost optimization across your machine learning (ML) environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate invoice processing with Streamlit and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through a step-by-step guide to automating invoice processing using Streamlit and Amazon Bedrock, addressing the challenge of handling invoices from multiple vendors with different formats. We show how to set up the environment, process invoices stored in Amazon S3, and deploy a user-friendly Streamlit application to review and interact with the processed data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-invoice-processing-with-streamlit-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centralize model governance with SageMaker Model Registry Resource Access Manager sharing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 16:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently announced the general availability of cross-account sharing of Amazon SageMaker Model Registry using AWS Resource Access Manager (AWS RAM), making it easier to securely share and discover machine learning (ML) models across your AWS accounts. In this post, we will show you how to use this new cross-account model sharing feature to build your own centralized model governance capability, which is often needed for centralized model approval, deployment, auditing, and monitoring workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionize trip planning with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Location Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to build a generative AI-powered trip-planning service that revolutionizes the way travelers discover and explore destinations. By using advanced AI technology and Amazon Location Service, the trip planner lets users translate inspiration into personalized travel itineraries. This innovative service goes beyond traditional trip planning methods, offering real-time interaction through a chat-based interface and maintaining scalability, reliability, and data security through AWS native services.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify automotive damage processing with Amazon Bedrock and vector databases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores a solution that uses the power of AWS generative AI capabilities like Amazon Bedrock and OpenSearch vector search to perform damage appraisals for insurers, repair shops, and fleet managers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simplify-automotive-damage-processing-with-amazon-bedrock-and-vector-databases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding prompt engineering: Unlock the creative potential of Stability AI models on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stability AI’s newest launch of Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large (SD3.5L) on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart enhances image generation, human anatomy rendering, and typography by producing more diverse outputs and adhering closely to user prompts, making it a significant upgrade over its predecessor. In this post, we explore advanced prompt engineering techniques that can enhance the performance of these models and facilitate the creation of compelling imagery through text-to-image transformations.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of Stability AI’s latest and most advanced text-to-image model, Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large, in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. In this post, we provide an implementation guide for subscribing to Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large in SageMaker JumpStart, deploying the model in Amazon SageMaker Studio, and generating images using text-to-image prompts.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-stable-diffusion-3-5-large-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve governance of models with Amazon SageMaker unified Model Cards and Model Registry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 20:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now register machine learning (ML) models in Amazon SageMaker Model Registry with Amazon SageMaker Model Cards, making it straightforward to manage governance information for specific model versions directly in SageMaker Model Registry in just a few clicks. In this post, we discuss a new feature that supports the integration of model cards with the model registry. We discuss the solution architecture and best practices for managing model cards with a registered model version, and walk through how to set up, operationalize, and govern your models using the integration in the model registry.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribe, translate, and summarize live streams in your browser with AWS AI and generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the approach behind building an AWS AI-powered Chrome extension that aims to revolutionize the live streaming experience by providing real-time transcription, translation, and summarization capabilities directly within your browser.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transcribe-translate-and-summarize-live-streams-in-your-browser-with-aws-ai-and-generative-ai-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your financial statement analysis with Amazon Bedrock and generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy a generative AI application that can accelerate your financial statement analysis on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-your-financial-statement-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock-and-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual content processing using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon A2I</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post outlines a custom multilingual document extraction and content assessment framework using a combination of Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock and Amazon A2I to incorporate human-in-the-loop capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multilingual-content-processing-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-a2i/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a reverse image search engine with Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings in Amazon Bedrock and AWS managed services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to extract key objects from image queries using Amazon Rekognition and build a reverse image search engine using Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings from Amazon Bedrock in combination with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless Service.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-reverse-image-search-engine-with-amazon-titan-multimodal-embeddings-in-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-managed-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI for agriculture: How Agmatix is improving agriculture with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes how Agmatix, a pioneering Agtech company powering R&amp;amp;D for input companies and digital agronomic solutions, uses Amazon Bedrock and AWS fully featured services to enhance the research process and development of higher-yielding seeds and sustainable molecules for global agriculture.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generative-ai-for-agriculture-how-agmatix-is-improving-agriculture-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate financial industry-specific insights using generative AI and in-context fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we demonstrate prompt engineering techniques to generate accurate and relevant analysis of tabular data using industry-specific language. This is done by providing large language models (LLMs) in-context sample data with features and labels in the prompt. The results are similar to fine-tuning LLMs without the complexities of fine-tuning models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-financial-industry-specific-insights-using-generative-ai-and-in-context-fine-tuning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliver personalized marketing with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Bedrock Developer Experience, and Amazon Personalize that allow marketers to save time and deliver efficient personalized advertising using a generative AI enhanced solution. Our solution is a marketing agent that shows how Amazon Personalize can effectively segment target customers based on relevant characteristics and behaviors. Additionally, by using Amazon Bedrock Agents and foundation models (FMs), our tool generates personalized creative content specifically tailored to each purpose.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Meta Llama 3.2 text generation models for generative AI inference using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 17:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to fine-tune Meta’s latest Llama 3.2 text generation models, Llama 3.2 1B and 3B, using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart for domain-specific applications. By using the pre-built solutions available in SageMaker JumpStart and the customizable Meta Llama 3.2 models, you can unlock the models’ enhanced reasoning, code generation, and instruction-following capabilities to tailor them for your unique use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-meta-llama-3-2-text-generation-models-for-generative-ai-inference-using-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights with the Amazon Q Business Microsoft Teams connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 17:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Teams is an enterprise collaboration tool that allows you to build a unified workspace for real-time collaboration and communication, meetings, and file and application sharing. You can exchange and store valuable organizational knowledge within Microsoft Teams. Microsoft Teams data is often siloed across different teams, channels, and chats, making it difficult to get a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-with-the-amazon-q-business-microsoft-teams-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
