<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:09:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent healthcare forms analysis with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore using the Anthropic Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock large language model (LLM). Amazon Bedrock provides access to several LLMs, such as Anthropic Claude 3, which can be used to generate semi-structured data relevant to the healthcare industry. This can be particularly useful for creating various healthcare-related forms, such as patient intake forms, insurance claim forms, or medical history questionnaires.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/intelligent-healthcare-forms-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harness the power of AI and ML using Splunk and Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For organizations looking beyond the use of out-of-the-box Splunk AI/ML features, this post explores how Amazon SageMaker Canvas, a no-code ML development service, can be used in conjunction with data collected in Splunk to drive actionable insights. We also demonstrate how to use the generative AI capabilities of SageMaker Canvas to speed up your data exploration and help you build better ML models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/harness-the-power-of-ai-and-ml-using-splunk-and-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Deltek uses Amazon Bedrock for question and answering on government solicitation documents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides an overview of a custom solution developed by the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) for Deltek, a globally recognized standard for project-based businesses in both government contracting and professional services. Deltek serves over 30,000 clients with industry-specific software and information solutions. In this collaboration, the AWS GenAIIC team created a RAG-based solution for Deltek to enable Q&amp;amp;A on single and multiple government solicitation documents. The solution uses AWS services including Amazon Textract, Amazon OpenSearch Service, and Amazon Bedrock.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights from Box with the Amazon Q Box connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Seamless access to content and insights is crucial for delivering exceptional customer experiences and driving successful business outcomes. Box, a leading cloud content management platform, serves as a central repository for diverse digital assets and documents in many organizations. An enterprise Box account typically contains a wealth of materials, including documents, presentations, knowledge articles, and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-from-box-with-the-amazon-q-box-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Twilio generated SQL using Looker Modeling Language data with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As one of the largest AWS customers, Twilio engages with data, artificial intelligence (AI), and machine learning (ML) services to run their daily workloads. This post highlights how Twilio enabled natural language-driven data exploration of business intelligence (BI) data with RAG and Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-twilio-generated-sql-using-looker-modeling-language-data-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve AI assistant response accuracy using Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock and a reranking model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 18:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI chatbots and virtual assistants have become increasingly popular in recent years thanks the breakthroughs of large language models (LLMs). Trained on a large volume of datasets, these models incorporate memory components in their architectural design, allowing them to understand and comprehend textual context. Most common use cases for chatbot assistants focus on a few […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-ai-assistant-response-accuracy-using-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-and-a-reranking-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate the machine learning model approval process with Amazon SageMaker Model Registry and Amazon SageMaker Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 18:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2024/07_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post illustrates how to use common architecture principles to transition from a manual monitoring process to one that is automated. You can use these principles and existing AWS services such as Amazon SageMaker Model Registry and Amazon SageMaker Pipelines to deliver innovative solutions to your customers while maintaining compliance for your ML workloads.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-the-machine-learning-model-approval-process-with-amazon-sagemaker-model-registry-and-amazon-sagemaker-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build custom generative AI applications powered by Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 19:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With last month’s blog, I started a series of posts that highlight the key factors that are driving customers to choose Amazon Bedrock. I explored how Bedrock enables customers to build a secure, compliant foundation for generative AI applications. Now I’d like to turn to a slightly more technical, but equally important differentiator for Bedrock—the multiple techniques that you can use to customize models and meet your specific business needs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Bedrock to generate, evaluate, and understand code in your software development pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 15:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative artificial intelligence (AI) models have opened up new possibilities for automating and enhancing software development workflows. Specifically, the emergent capability for generative models to produce code based on natural language prompts has opened many doors to how developers and DevOps professionals approach their work and improve their efficiency. In this post, we provide an […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-bedrock-to-generate-evaluate-and-understand-code-in-your-software-development-pipeline/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inference AudioCraft MusicGen models using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2024/06_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Music generation models have emerged as powerful tools that transform natural language text into musical compositions. Originating from advancements in artificial intelligence (AI) and deep learning, these models are designed to understand and translate descriptive text into coherent, aesthetically pleasing music. Their ability to democratize music production allows individuals without formal training to create high-quality […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/inference-audiocraft-musicgen-models-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
