<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 21:57:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unleash the power of generative AI with Amazon Q Business: How CCoEs can scale cloud governance best practices and drive innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 21:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Hearst, one of the nation’s largest global, diversified information, services, and media companies, overcame these challenges by creating a self-service generative AI conversational assistant for business units seeking guidance from their CCoE.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleash-the-power-of-generative-ai-with-amazon-q-business-how-ccoes-can-scale-cloud-governance-best-practices-and-drive-innovation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate foundation models into your code with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 17:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The rise of large language models (LLMs) and foundation models (FMs) has revolutionized the field of natural language processing (NLP) and artificial intelligence (AI). These powerful models, trained on vast amounts of data, can generate human-like text, answer questions, and even engage in creative writing tasks. However, training and deploying such models from scratch is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-foundation-models-into-your-code-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and deploy a UI for your generative AI applications with AWS and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS provides a powerful set of tools and services that simplify the process of building and deploying generative AI applications, even for those with limited experience in frontend and backend development. In this post, we explore a practical solution that uses Streamlit, a Python library for building interactive data applications, and AWS services like Amazon Elastic Container Service (Amazon ECS), Amazon Cognito, and the AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK) to create a user-friendly generative AI application with authentication and deployment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unearth insights from audio transcripts generated by Amazon Transcribe using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2024/06_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we examine how to create business value through speech analytics with some examples focused on the following: 1) automatically summarizing, categorizing, and analyzing marketing content such as podcasts, recorded interviews, or videos, and creating new marketing materials based on those assets, 2) automatically extracting key points, summaries, and sentiment from a recorded meeting (such as an earnings call), and 3) transcribing and analyzing contact center calls to improve customer experience.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and lessons for fine-tuning Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 21:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the best practices and lessons learned for fine-tuning Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku on Amazon Bedrock. We discuss the important components of fine-tuning, including use case definition, data preparation, model customization, and performance evaluation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-and-lessons-for-fine-tuning-anthropics-claude-3-haiku-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track, allocate, and manage your generative AI cost and usage with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 19:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock has launched a capability that organizations can use to tag on-demand models and monitor associated costs. Organizations can now label all Amazon Bedrock models with AWS cost allocation tags, aligning usage to specific organizational taxonomies such as cost centers, business units, and applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/track-allocate-and-manage-your-generative-ai-cost-and-usage-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance environmental sustainability in clinical trials using AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to use AWS to support a decentralized clinical trial across the four main pillars of a decentralized clinical trial (virtual trials, personalized patient engagement, patient-centric trial design, and centralized data management). By exploring these AWS powered alternatives, we aim to demonstrate how organizations can drive progress towards more environmentally friendly clinical research practices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advance-environmental-sustainability-in-clinical-trials-using-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Q to find answers on Google Drive in an enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post covers the steps to configure the Amazon Q Business Google Drive connector, including authentication setup and verifying the secure indexing of your Google Drive content.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-q-to-find-answers-on-google-drive-in-an-enterprise/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Druva used Amazon Bedrock to address foundation model complexity when building Dru, Druva’s backup AI copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_11_2024/01_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Druva enables cyber, data, and operational resilience for thousands of enterprises, and is trusted by 60 of the Fortune 500. In this post, we show how Druva approached natural language querying (NLQ)—asking questions in English and getting tabular data as answers—using Amazon Bedrock, the challenges they faced, sample prompts, and key learnings.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-druva-used-amazon-bedrock-to-address-foundation-model-complexity-when-building-dru-druvas-backup-ai-copilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a generative AI–powered custom Google Chat application using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS offers powerful generative AI services, including Amazon Bedrock, which allows organizations to create tailored use cases such as AI chat-based assistants that give answers based on knowledge contained in the customers’ documents, and much more. Many businesses want to integrate these cutting-edge AI capabilities with their existing collaboration tools, such as Google Chat, to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-generative-ai-powered-custom-google-chat-application-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights from Gmail using the Gmail connector for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A number of organizations use Gmail for their business email needs. Gmail for business is part of Google Workspace, which provides a set of productivity and collaboration tools like Google Drive, Gmail, and Google Calendar. Google Drive supports storing documents such as Emails contain a wealth of information found in different places, such as within […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-from-gmail-using-the-gmail-connector-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate custom labeling workflows in Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth without using AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2024/31_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth enables the creation of high-quality, large-scale training datasets, essential for fine-tuning across a wide range of applications, including large language models (LLMs) and generative AI. By integrating human annotators with machine learning, SageMaker Ground Truth significantly reduces the cost and time required for data labeling. Whether it’s annotating images, videos, or […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-custom-labeling-workflows-in-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-without-using-aws-lambda/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
