<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:25:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scaling medical content review at Flo Health using Amazon Bedrock (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2026/08_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2026/08_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This two-part series explores Flo Health&#39;s journey with generative AI for medical content verification. Part 1 examines our proof of concept (PoC), including the initial solution, capabilities, and early results. Part 2 covers focusing on scaling challenges and real-world implementation. Each article stands alone while collectively showing how AI transforms medical content management at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scaling-medical-content-review-at-flo-health-using-amazon-bedrock-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect and redact personally identifiable information using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2026/08_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2026/08_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows an automated PII detection and redaction solution using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Amazon Bedrock Guardrails through a use case of processing text and image content in high volumes of incoming emails and attachments. The solution features a complete email processing workflow with a React-based user interface for authorized personnel to more securely manage and review redacted email communications and attachments. We walk through the step-by-step solution implementation procedures used to deploy this solution.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed meets scale: Load testing SageMakerAI endpoints with Observe.AI’s testing tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2026/08_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_01_2026/08_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Observe.ai developed the One Load Audit Framework (OLAF), which integrates with SageMaker to identify bottlenecks and performance issues in ML services, offering latency and throughput measurements under both static and dynamic data loads. In this blog post, you will learn how to use the OLAF utility to test and validate your SageMaker endpoint.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/speed-meets-scale-load-testing-sagemakerai-endpoints-with-observe-ais-testing-tool/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
