<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 16:02:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mixtral 8x22B is now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 16:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the Mixtral-8x22B large language model (LLM), developed by Mistral AI, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy with one click for running inference. You can try out this model with SageMaker JumpStart, a machine learning (ML) hub that provides access to algorithms and models so you […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mixtral-8x22b-is-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Generative AI prompt chaining workflows with human in the loop</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 15:51:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_05_2024/17_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While Generative AI can create highly realistic content, including text, images, and videos, it can also generate outputs that appear plausible but are verifiably incorrect. Incorporating human judgment is crucial, especially in complex and high-risk decision-making scenarios. This involves building a human-in-the-loop process where humans play an active role in decision making alongside the AI system. In this blog post, you will learn about prompt chaining, how to break a complex task into multiple tasks to use prompt chaining with an LLM in a specific order, and how to involve a human to review the response generated by the LLM.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How LotteON built a personalized recommendation system using Amazon SageMaker and MLOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2024/16_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with HyeKyung Yang, Jieun Lim, and SeungBum Shim from LotteON. LotteON aims to be a platform that not only sells products, but also provides a personalized recommendation experience tailored to your preferred lifestyle. LotteON operates various specialty stores, including fashion, beauty, luxury, and kids, and strives to provide a personalized shopping […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-lotteon-built-a-personalized-recommendation-system-using-amazon-sagemaker-and-mlops/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless exam generator application from your own lecture content using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Crafting new questions for exams and quizzes can be tedious and time-consuming for educators. The time required varies based on factors like subject matter, question types, experience level, and class level. Multiple-choice questions require substantial time to generate quality distractors and ensure a single unambiguous answer, and composing effective true-false questions demands careful effort to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-exam-generator-application-from-your-own-lecture-content-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate NLP inference with ONNX Runtime on AWS Graviton processors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ONNX is an open source machine learning (ML) framework that provides interoperability across a wide range of frameworks, operating systems, and hardware platforms. ONNX Runtime is the runtime engine used for model inference and training with ONNX. AWS Graviton3 processors are optimized for ML workloads, including support for bfloat16, Scalable Vector Extension (SVE), and Matrix […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-nlp-inference-with-onnx-runtime-on-aws-graviton-processors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn how Amazon Ads created a generative AI-powered image generation capability using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2024/15_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Ads helps advertisers and brands achieve their business goals by developing innovative solutions that reach millions of Amazon customers at every stage of their journey. At Amazon Ads, we believe that what makes advertising effective is delivering relevant ads in the right context and at the right moment within the consumer buying journey. With that […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/learn-how-amazon-ads-created-a-generative-ai-powered-image-generation-capability-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAG architecture with Voyage AI embedding models on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart and Anthropic Claude 3 models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 19:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide an overview of the state-of-the-art embedding models by Voyage AI and show a RAG implementation with Voyage AI’s text embedding model on Amazon SageMaker Jumpstart, Anthropic’s Claude 3 model on Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon OpenSearch Service. Voyage AI’s embedding models are the preferred embedding models for Anthropic. In addition to general-purpose embedding models, Voyage AI offers domain-specific embedding models that are tuned to a particular domain.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporate offline and online human – machine workflows into your generative AI applications on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 17:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recent advances in artificial intelligence have led to the emergence of generative AI that can produce human-like novel content such as images, text, and audio. These models are pre-trained on massive datasets and, to sometimes fine-tuned with smaller sets of more task specific data. An important aspect of developing effective generative AI application is Reinforcement […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/incorporate-offline-and-online-human-machine-workflows-into-your-generative-ai-applications-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications with Amazon Titan Text Premier, Amazon Bedrock, and AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 17:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Titan Text Premier, the latest addition to the Amazon Titan family of large language models (LLMs), is now generally available in Amazon Bedrock. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading artificial intelligence (AI) companies like AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Stability AI, and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-titan-text-premier-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of generative AI techniques for clinical report summarization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 19:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a comparison of results obtained by two such techniques: zero-shot and few-shot prompting. We also explore the utility of the RAG prompt engineering technique as it applies to the task of summarization. Evaluating LLMs is an undervalued part of the machine learning (ML) pipeline.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluation-of-generative-ai-techniques-for-clinical-report-summarization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
