<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 17:47:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Command R and R&#43; are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 17:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is co-written with Pradeep Prabhakaran from Cohere. Today, we are excited to announce that Cohere Command R and R+ foundation models are available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. Command R/R+ are the state-of-the-art retrieval augmented generation (RAG)-optimized models designed to tackle enterprise-grade workloads. In this post, we walk through how […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cohere-command-r-and-r-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing large language model training with Arcee and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 15:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_04_2024/29_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post by Mark McQuade, Malikeh Ehghaghi, and Shamane Siri from Arcee. In recent years, large language models (LLMs) have gained attention for their effectiveness, leading various industries to adapt general LLMs to their data for improved results, making efficient training and hardware availability crucial. At Arcee, we focus primarily on enhancing […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-large-language-model-training-with-arcee-and-aws-trainium/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databricks DBRX is now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 19:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the DBRX model, an open, general-purpose large language model (LLM) developed by Databricks, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy with one click for running inference. The DBRX LLM employs a fine-grained mixture-of-experts (MoE) architecture, pre-trained on 12 trillion tokens of carefully curated data and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/databricks-dbrx-is-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases in Amazon Bedrock now simplifies asking questions on a single document</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 19:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_04_2024/26_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At AWS re:Invent 2023, we announced the general availability of Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock. With Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, you can securely connect foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock to your company data for fully managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). In previous posts, we covered new capabilities like hybrid search support, metadata filtering […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/knowledge-bases-in-amazon-bedrock-now-simplifies-asking-questions-on-a-single-document/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a Hugging Face (PyAnnote) speaker diarization model on Amazon SageMaker as an asynchronous endpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 17:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Speaker diarization, an essential process in audio analysis, segments an audio file based on speaker identity. This post delves into integrating Hugging Face’s PyAnnote for speaker diarization with Amazon SageMaker asynchronous endpoints. We provide a comprehensive guide on how to deploy speaker segmentation and clustering solutions using SageMaker on the AWS Cloud.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-a-hugging-face-pyannote-speaker-diarization-model-on-amazon-sagemaker-as-an-asynchronous-endpoint/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate the text summarization capabilities of LLMs for enhanced decision-making on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_04_2024/25_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations across industries are using automatic text summarization to more efficiently handle vast amounts of information and make better decisions. In the financial sector, investment banks condense earnings reports down to key takeaways to rapidly analyze quarterly performance. Media companies use summarization to monitor news and social media so journalists can quickly write stories on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-the-text-summarization-capabilities-of-llms-for-enhanced-decision-making-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance conversational AI with advanced routing techniques with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Conversational artificial intelligence (AI) assistants are engineered to provide precise, real-time responses through intelligent routing of queries to the most suitable AI functions. With AWS generative AI services like Amazon Bedrock, developers can create systems that expertly manage and respond to user requests. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-conversational-ai-with-advanced-routing-techniques-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve LLM performance with human and AI feedback on Amazon SageMaker for Amazon Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Amazon EU Design and Construction (Amazon D&amp;amp;C) team is the engineering team designing and constructing Amazon warehouses. The team navigates a large volume of documents and locates the right information to make sure the warehouse design meets the highest standards. In the post A generative AI-powered solution on Amazon SageMaker to help Amazon EU […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-llm-performance-with-human-and-ai-feedback-on-amazon-sagemaker-for-amazon-engineering/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve accuracy of Amazon Rekognition Face Search with user vectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In various industries, such as financial services, telecommunications, and healthcare, customers use a digital identity process, which usually involves several steps to verify end-users during online onboarding or step-up authentication. An example of one step that can be used is face search, which can help determine whether a new end-user’s face matches those associated with […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-accuracy-of-amazon-rekognition-face-search-with-user-vectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate ML workflows with Amazon SageMaker Studio Local Mode and Docker support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 19:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce two new capabilities in Amazon SageMaker Studio that will accelerate iterative development for machine learning (ML) practitioners: Local Mode and Docker support. ML model development often involves slow iteration cycles as developers switch between coding, training, and deployment. Each step requires waiting for remote compute resources to start up, which […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-ml-workflows-with-amazon-sagemaker-studio-local-mode-and-docker-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significant new capabilities make it easier to use Amazon Bedrock to build and scale generative AI applications – and achieve impressive results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 11:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We introduced Amazon Bedrock to the world a little over a year ago, delivering an entirely new way to build generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications. With the broadest selection of first- and third-party foundation models (FMs) as well as user-friendly capabilities, Amazon Bedrock is the fastest and easiest way to build and scale secure generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-capabilities-make-it-easier-to-use-amazon-bedrock-to-build-and-scale-generative-ai-applications-and-deliver-impact/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building scalable, secure, and reliable RAG applications using Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 11:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the new enterprise-grade features for Knowledge Bases on Amazon Bedrock and how they align with the AWS Well-Architected Framework. With Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, you can quickly build applications using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) for use cases like question answering, contextual chatbots, and personalized search.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-scalable-secure-and-reliable-rag-applications-using-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate HyperPod clusters with Active Directory for seamless multi-user login</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker HyperPod is purpose-built to accelerate foundation model (FM) training, removing the undifferentiated heavy lifting involved in managing and optimizing a large training compute cluster. With SageMaker HyperPod, you can train FMs for weeks and months without disruption. Typically, HyperPod clusters are used by multiple users: machine learning (ML) researchers, software engineers, data scientists, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-hyperpod-clusters-with-active-directory-for-seamless-multi-user-login/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The executive’s guide to generative AI for sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are facing ever-increasing requirements for sustainability goals alongside environmental, social, and governance (ESG) practices. A Gartner, Inc. survey revealed that 87 percent of business leaders expect to increase their organization’s investment in sustainability over the next years. This post serves as a starting point for any executive seeking to navigate the intersection of generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-executives-guide-to-generative-ai-for-sustainability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
