<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:30:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Improve productivity when processing scanned PDFs using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2024/03_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a generative AI-powered assistant that can answer questions, provide summaries, generate content, and extract insights directly from the content in digital as well as scanned PDF documents in your enterprise data sources without needing to extract the text first. Customers across industries such as finance, insurance, healthcare life sciences, and more need […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-productivity-when-processing-scanned-pdfs-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated PyTorch inference with torch.compile on AWS Graviton processors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 17:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Originally PyTorch used an eager mode where each PyTorch operation that forms the model is run independently as soon as it’s reached. PyTorch 2.0 introduced torch.compile to speed up PyTorch code over the default eager mode. In contrast to eager mode, the torch.compile pre-compiles the entire model into a single graph in a manner that’s optimal for […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerated-pytorch-inference-with-torch-compile-on-aws-graviton-processors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access control for vector stores using metadata filtering with Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 17:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In November 2023, we announced Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock as generally available. Knowledge bases allow Amazon Bedrock users to unlock the full potential of Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) by seamlessly integrating their company data into the language model’s generation process. This feature allows organizations to harness the power of large language models (LLMs) while […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/access-control-for-vector-stores-using-metadata-filtering-with-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accenture creates a custom memory-persistent conversational user experience using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Traditionally, finding relevant information from documents has been a time-consuming and often frustrating process. Manually sifting through pages upon pages of text, searching for specific details, and synthesizing the information into coherent summaries can be a daunting task. This inefficiency not only hinders productivity but also increases the risk of overlooking critical insights buried within […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accenture-creates-a-custom-memory-persistent-conversational-user-experience-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an end-to-end serverless digital assistant for semantic search with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2024/02_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the rise of generative artificial intelligence (AI), an increasing number of organizations use digital assistants to have their end-users ask domain-specific questions, using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) over their enterprise data sources. As organizations transition from proofs of concept to production workloads, they establish objectives to run and scale their workloads with minimal operational […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-an-end-to-end-serverless-digital-assistant-for-semantic-search-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a self-service digital assistant using Amazon Lex and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations strive to implement efficient, scalable, cost-effective, and automated customer support solutions without compromising the customer experience. Generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered chatbots play a crucial role in delivering human-like interactions by providing responses from a knowledge base without the involvement of live agents. These chatbots can be efficiently utilized for handling generic inquiries, freeing up […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-self-service-digital-assistant-using-amazon-lex-and-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify idle endpoints in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker is a machine learning (ML) platform designed to simplify the process of building, training, deploying, and managing ML models at scale. With a comprehensive suite of tools and services, SageMaker offers developers and data scientists the resources they need to accelerate the development and deployment of ML solutions. In today’s fast-paced technological landscape, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/identify-idle-endpoints-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian language RAG with Cohere multilingual embeddings and Anthropic Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Media and entertainment companies serve multilingual audiences with a wide range of content catering to diverse audience segments. These enterprises have access to massive amounts of data collected over their many years of operations. Much of this data is unstructured text and images. Conventional approaches to analyzing unstructured data for generating new content rely on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/indian-language-rag-with-cohere-multilingual-embeddings-and-anthropic-claude-3-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of productivity agents with NinjaTech AI and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NinjaTech AI’s mission is to make everyone more productive by taking care of time-consuming complex tasks with fast and affordable artificial intelligence (AI) agents. We recently launched MyNinja.ai, one of the world’s first multi-agent personal AI assistants, to drive towards our mission. MyNinja.ai is built from the ground up using specialized agents that are capable of completing tasks on your behalf, including scheduling meetings, conducting deep research from the web, generating code, and helping with writing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications on Amazon Bedrock — the secure, compliant, and responsible foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has revolutionized industries by creating content, from text and images to audio and code. Although it can unlock numerous possibilities, integrating generative AI into applications demands meticulous planning. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that provides access to large language models (LLMs) and other foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies through a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-on-amazon-bedrock-the-secure-compliant-and-responsible-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational chatbot using different LLMs within single interface – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the advent of generative artificial intelligence (AI), foundation models (FMs) can generate content such as answering questions, summarizing text, and providing highlights from the sourced document. However, for model selection, there is a wide choice from model providers, like Amazon, Anthropic, AI21 Labs, Cohere, and Meta, coupled with discrete real-world data formats in PDF, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-conversational-chatbot-using-different-llms-within-single-interface-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate derivative confirms processing using AWS AI services for the capital markets industry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can automate and intelligently process derivative confirms at scale using AWS AI services. The solution combines Amazon Textract, a fully managed ML service to effortlessly extract text, handwriting, and data from scanned documents, and AWS Serverless technologies, a suite of fully managed event-driven services for running code, managing data, and integrating applications, all without managing servers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-derivative-confirms-processing-using-aws-ai-services-for-the-capital-markets-industry/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered assistants for investment research with multi-modal data: An application of Agents for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a follow-up to Generative AI and multi-modal agents in AWS: The key to unlocking new value in financial markets. This blog is part of the series, Generative AI and AI/ML in Capital Markets and Financial Services. Financial analysts and research analysts in capital markets distill business insights from financial and non-financial data, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-powered-assistants-for-investment-research-with-multi-modal-data-an-application-of-agents-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
