<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:50:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrate HyperPod clusters with Active Directory for seamless multi-user login</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker HyperPod is purpose-built to accelerate foundation model (FM) training, removing the undifferentiated heavy lifting involved in managing and optimizing a large training compute cluster. With SageMaker HyperPod, you can train FMs for weeks and months without disruption. Typically, HyperPod clusters are used by multiple users: machine learning (ML) researchers, software engineers, data scientists, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-hyperpod-clusters-with-active-directory-for-seamless-multi-user-login/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The executive’s guide to generative AI for sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are facing ever-increasing requirements for sustainability goals alongside environmental, social, and governance (ESG) practices. A Gartner, Inc. survey revealed that 87 percent of business leaders expect to increase their organization’s investment in sustainability over the next years. This post serves as a starting point for any executive seeking to navigate the intersection of generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-executives-guide-to-generative-ai-for-sustainability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing automatic training for solutions in Amazon Personalize</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Personalize is excited to announce automatic training for solutions. Solution training is fundamental to maintain the effectiveness of a model and make sure recommendations align with users’ evolving behaviors and preferences. As data patterns and trends change over time, retraining the solution with the latest relevant data enables the model to learn and adapt, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-automatic-training-for-solutions-in-amazon-personalize/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Kubernetes Operators for new inference capabilities in Amazon SageMaker that reduce LLM deployment costs by 50% on average</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 16:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce a new version of the Amazon SageMaker Operators for Kubernetes using the AWS Controllers for Kubernetes (ACK). ACK is a framework for building Kubernetes custom controllers, where each controller communicates with an AWS service API. These controllers allow Kubernetes users to provision AWS resources like buckets, databases, or message queues […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-kubernetes-operators-for-new-inference-capabilities-in-amazon-sagemaker-that-reduce-llm-deployment-costs-by-50-on-average/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to your slide deck using multimodal foundation models hosted on Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of this series, we presented a solution that used the Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings model to convert individual slides from a slide deck into embeddings. We stored the embeddings in a vector database and then used the Large Language-and-Vision Assistant (LLaVA 1.5-7b) model to generate text responses to user questions based on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/talk-to-your-slide-deck-using-multimodal-foundation-models-hosted-on-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-sagemaker-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale AI training and inference for drug discovery through Amazon EKS and Karpenter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with the leadership team of Iambic Therapeutics. Iambic Therapeutics is a drug discovery startup with a mission to create innovative AI-driven technologies to bring better medicines to cancer patients, faster. Our advanced generative and predictive artificial intelligence (AI) tools enable us to search the vast space of possible drug […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-ai-training-and-inference-for-drug-discovery-through-amazon-eks-and-karpenter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate customized, compliant application IaC scripts for AWS Landing Zone using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 17:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As you navigate the complexities of cloud migration, the need for a structured, secure, and compliant environment is paramount. AWS Landing Zone addresses this need by offering a standardized approach to deploying AWS resources. This makes sure your cloud foundation is built according to AWS best practices from the start. With AWS Landing Zone, you eliminate the guesswork in security configurations, resource provisioning, and account management. It’s particularly beneficial for organizations looking to scale without compromising on governance or control, providing a clear path to a robust and efficient cloud setup.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Meeting Assistant with Amazon Transcribe, Amazon Bedrock, and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 17:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve likely experienced the challenge of taking notes during a meeting while trying to pay attention to the conversation. You’ve probably also experienced the need to quickly fact-check something that’s been said, or look up information to answer a question that’s just been asked in the call. Or maybe you have a team member that always joins meetings late, and expects you to send them a quick summary over chat to catch them up.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Llama 3 models are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 16:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Meta Llama 3 foundation models are available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. The Llama 3 models are a collection of pre-trained and fine-tuned generative text models. In this post, we walk through how to discover and deploy Llama 3 models via SageMaker JumpStart. What is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/meta-llama-3-models-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack delivers native and secure generative AI powered by Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Slack, a Salesforce company, has collaborated with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to power Slack AI’s initial search and summarization features and provide safeguards for Slack to use large language models (LLMs) more securely. Slack worked with SageMaker JumpStart to host industry-leading third-party LLMs so that data is not shared with the infrastructure owned by third party model providers. This keeps customer data in Slack at all times and upholds the same security practices and compliance standards that customers expect from Slack itself.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncover hidden connections in unstructured financial data with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Neptune</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In asset management, portfolio managers need to closely monitor companies in their investment universe to identify risks and opportunities, and guide investment decisions. Tracking direct events like earnings reports or credit downgrades is straightforward—you can set up alerts to notify managers of news containing company names. However, detecting second and third-order impacts arising from events […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/uncover-hidden-connections-in-unstructured-financial-data-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-neptune/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open source observability for AWS Inferentia nodes within Amazon EKS clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks you through the Open Source Observability pattern for AWS Inferentia, which shows you how to monitor the performance of ML chips, used in an Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS) cluster, with data plane nodes based on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances of type Inf1 and Inf2.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/open-source-observability-for-aws-inferentia-nodes-within-amazon-eks-clusters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed training and efficient scaling with the Amazon SageMaker Model Parallel and Data Parallel Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the performance benefits of Amazon SageMaker (including SMP and SMDDP), and how you can use the library to train large models efficiently on SageMaker. We demonstrate the performance of SageMaker with benchmarks on ml.p4d.24xlarge clusters up to 128 instances, and FSDP mixed precision with bfloat16 for the Llama 2 model.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/distributed-training-and-efficient-scaling-with-the-amazon-sagemaker-model-parallel-and-data-parallel-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage your Amazon Lex bot via AWS CloudFormation templates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Lex is a fully managed artificial intelligence (AI) service with advanced natural language models to design, build, test, and deploy conversational interfaces in applications. It employs advanced deep learning technologies to understand user input, enabling developers to create chatbots, virtual assistants, and other applications that can interact with users in natural language. Managing your […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-your-amazon-lex-bot-via-aws-cloudformation-templates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A secure approach to generative AI with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative artificial intelligence (AI) is transforming the customer experience in industries across the globe. Customers are building generative AI applications using large language models (LLMs) and other foundation models (FMs), which enhance customer experiences, transform operations, improve employee productivity, and create new revenue channels. The biggest concern we hear from customers as they explore the advantages of generative AI is how to protect their highly sensitive data and investments. At AWS, our top priority is safeguarding the security and confidentiality of our customers&#39; workloads.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
