<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 15:00:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Uncover hidden connections in unstructured financial data with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Neptune</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In asset management, portfolio managers need to closely monitor companies in their investment universe to identify risks and opportunities, and guide investment decisions. Tracking direct events like earnings reports or credit downgrades is straightforward—you can set up alerts to notify managers of news containing company names. However, detecting second and third-order impacts arising from events […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/uncover-hidden-connections-in-unstructured-financial-data-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-neptune/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open source observability for AWS Inferentia nodes within Amazon EKS clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2024/17_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks you through the Open Source Observability pattern for AWS Inferentia, which shows you how to monitor the performance of ML chips, used in an Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS) cluster, with data plane nodes based on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances of type Inf1 and Inf2.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/open-source-observability-for-aws-inferentia-nodes-within-amazon-eks-clusters/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed training and efficient scaling with the Amazon SageMaker Model Parallel and Data Parallel Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the performance benefits of Amazon SageMaker (including SMP and SMDDP), and how you can use the library to train large models efficiently on SageMaker. We demonstrate the performance of SageMaker with benchmarks on ml.p4d.24xlarge clusters up to 128 instances, and FSDP mixed precision with bfloat16 for the Llama 2 model.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/distributed-training-and-efficient-scaling-with-the-amazon-sagemaker-model-parallel-and-data-parallel-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage your Amazon Lex bot via AWS CloudFormation templates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Lex is a fully managed artificial intelligence (AI) service with advanced natural language models to design, build, test, and deploy conversational interfaces in applications. It employs advanced deep learning technologies to understand user input, enabling developers to create chatbots, virtual assistants, and other applications that can interact with users in natural language. Managing your […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-your-amazon-lex-bot-via-aws-cloudformation-templates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A secure approach to generative AI with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative artificial intelligence (AI) is transforming the customer experience in industries across the globe. Customers are building generative AI applications using large language models (LLMs) and other foundation models (FMs), which enhance customer experiences, transform operations, improve employee productivity, and create new revenue channels. The biggest concern we hear from customers as they explore the advantages of generative AI is how to protect their highly sensitive data and investments. At AWS, our top priority is safeguarding the security and confidentiality of our customers&#39; workloads.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost-effective document classification using the Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings Model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2024/11_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 19:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2024/11_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations across industries want to categorize and extract insights from high volumes of documents of different formats. Manually processing these documents to classify and extract information remains expensive, error prone, and difficult to scale. Advances in generative artificial intelligence (AI) have given rise to intelligent document processing (IDP) solutions that can automate the document classification, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cost-effective-document-classification-using-the-amazon-titan-multimodal-embeddings-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS at NVIDIA GTC 2024: Accelerate innovation with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2024/11_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 16:14:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2024/11_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS was delighted to present to and connect with over 18,000 in-person and 267,000 virtual attendees at NVIDIA GTC, a global artificial intelligence (AI) conference that took place March 2024 in San Jose, California, returning to a hybrid, in-person experience for the first time since 2019. AWS has had a long-standing collaboration with NVIDIA for […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-at-nvidia-gtc-2024-accelerate-innovation-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an active learning pipeline for automatic annotation of images with AWS services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 16:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is co-written with Caroline Chung from Veoneer. Veoneer is a global automotive electronics company and a world leader in automotive electronic safety systems. They offer best-in-class restraint control systems and have delivered over 1 billion electronic control units and crash sensors to car manufacturers globally. The company continues to build on a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-active-learning-pipeline-for-automatic-annotation-of-images-with-aws-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
