<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Your complete guide to Amazon Quick Suite at AWS re:Invent 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, re:Invent will be held in Las Vegas, Nevada, from December 1 to December 5, 2025, and this guide will help you navigate our comprehensive session catalog and plan your week. The sessions cater to business and technology leaders, product and engineering teams, and data and analytics teams interested in incorporating agentic AI capabilities across their teams and organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/your-complete-guide-to-amazon-quick-suite-at-aws-reinvent-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate enterprise solutions with agentic AI-powered consulting: Introducing AWS Professional Service Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m excited to announce AWS Professional Services now offers specialized AI agents including the AWS Professional Services Delivery Agent. This represents a transformation to the consulting experience that embeds intelligent agents throughout the consulting life cycle to deliver better value for customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-enterprise-solutions-with-agentic-ai-powered-consulting-introducing-aws-professional-service-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Claude: Transforming business with agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Claude are enabling enterprises like Cox Automotive and Druva to deploy production-ready agentic AI systems that deliver measurable business value, with results including up to 63% autonomous issue resolution and 58% faster response times. We examine the technical foundation combining Claude&#39;s frontier AI capabilities with AgentCore&#39;s enterprise-grade infrastructure that allows organizations to focus on agent logic rather than building complex operational systems from scratch.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a biomedical research agent with Biomni tools and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a production-ready biomedical research agent by integrating Biomni&#39;s specialized tools with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, enabling researchers to access over 30 biomedical databases through a secure, scalable infrastructure. The implementation showcases how to transform research prototypes into enterprise-grade systems with persistent memory, semantic tool discovery, and comprehensive observability for scientific reproducibility .
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-biomedical-research-agent-with-biomni-tools-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your web apps hands-free with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Graphical user interfaces have carried the torch for decades, but today’s users increasingly expect to talk to their applications. In this post we show how we added a true voice-first experience to a reference application—the Smart Todo App—turning routine task management into a fluid, hands-free conversation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/make-your-web-apps-hands-free-with-amazon-nova-sonic/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the power of generative AI: Druva’s multi-agent copilot for streamlined data protection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI is transforming the way businesses interact with their customers and revolutionizing conversational interfaces for complex IT operations. Druva, a leading provider of data security solutions, is at the forefront of this transformation. In collaboration with Amazon Web Services (AWS), Druva is developing a cutting-edge generative AI-powered multi-agent copilot that aims to redefine the customer experience in data security and cyber resilience.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/harnessing-the-power-of-generative-ai-druvas-multi-agent-copilot-for-streamlined-data-protection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing agent-to-agent protocol support in Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use the A2A protocol for AI agents built with different frameworks to collaborate seamlessly. You&#39;ll learn how to deploy A2A servers on AgentCore Runtime, configure agent discovery and authentication, and build a real-world multi-agent system for incident response. We&#39;ll cover the complete A2A request lifecycle, from agent card discovery to task delegation, showing how standardized protocols eliminate the complexity of multi-agent coordination.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering enterprise search with the Cohere Embed 4 multimodal embeddings model in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Cohere Embed 4 multimodal embeddings model is now available as a fully managed, serverless option in Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we dive into the benefits and unique capabilities of Embed 4 for enterprise search use cases. We’ll show you how to quickly get started using Embed 4 on Amazon Bedrock, taking advantage of integrations with Strands Agents, S3 Vectors, and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to build powerful agentic retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to building AI agents in GxP environments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The regulatory landscape for GxP compliance is evolving to address the unique characteristics of AI. Traditional Computer System Validation (CSV) approaches, often with uniform validation strategies, are being supplemented by Computer Software Assurance (CSA) frameworks that emphasize flexible risk-based validation methods tailored to each system&#39;s actual impact and complexity (FDA latest guidance). In this post, we cover a risk-based implementation, practical implementation considerations across different risk levels, the AWS shared responsibility model for compliance, and concrete examples of risk mitigation strategies.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Agent collaboration patterns with Strands Agents and Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore four key collaboration patterns for multi-agent, multimodal AI systems – Agents as Tools, Swarms Agents, Agent Graphs, and Agent Workflows – and discuss when and how to apply each using the open-source AWS Strands Agents SDK with Amazon Nova models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multi-agent-collaboration-patterns-with-strands-agents-and-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
