<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:39:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Thomson Reuters built an Agentic Platform Engineering Hub with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post explains how TR&#39;s Platform Engineering team, a geographically distributed unit overseeing TR&#39;s service availability, boosted its operational productivity by transitioning from manual to an automated agentic system using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-thomson-reuters-built-an-agentic-platform-engineering-hub-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build agents to learn from experiences using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore episodic memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through the complete architecture to structure and store episodes, discuss the reflection module, and share compelling benchmarks that demonstrate significant improvements in agent task success rates.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-agents-to-learn-from-experiences-using-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-episodic-memory/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How bunq handles 97% of support with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how bunq upgraded Finn, its in-house generative AI assistant, using Amazon Bedrock to transform user support and banking operations to be seamless, in multiple languages and time zones.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-bunq-handles-97-of-support-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Strands Agents to create a multi-agent solution with Meta’s Llama 4 and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a multi-agent video processing workflow using Strands Agents, Meta&#39;s Llama 4 models, and Amazon Bedrock to automatically analyze and understand video content through specialized AI agents working in coordination. To showcase the solution, we will use Amazon SageMaker AI to walk you through the code.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-strands-agents-to-create-a-multi-agent-solution-with-metas-llama-4-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing multimodal retrieval for Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll guide you through building multimodal RAG applications. You&#39;ll learn how multimodal knowledge bases work, how to choose the right processing strategy based on your content type, and how to configure and implement multimodal retrieval using both the console and code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-multimodal-retrieval-for-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced fine-tuning techniques for multi-agent orchestration: Patterns from Amazon at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how fine-tuning enabled a 33% reduction in dangerous medication errors (Amazon Pharmacy), engineering 80% human effort reduction (Amazon Global Engineering Services), and content quality assessments improving 77% to 96% accuracy (Amazon A+). This post details the techniques behind these outcomes: from foundational methods like Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) (instruction tuning), and Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO), to Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) for human alignment, to cutting-edge reasoning optimizations such as Grouped-based Reinforcement Learning from Policy Optimization (GRPO), Direct Advantage Policy Optimization (DAPO), and Group Sequence Policy Optimization (GSPO) purpose-built for agentic systems.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Palo Alto Networks enhanced device security infra log analysis with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Palo Alto Networks’ Device Security team wanted to detect early warning signs of potential production issues to provide more time to SMEs to react to these emerging problems. They partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to develop an automated log classification pipeline powered by Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we discuss how Amazon Bedrock, through Anthropic’ s Claude Haiku model, and Amazon Titan Text Embeddings work together to automatically classify and analyze log data.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From beginner to champion: A student’s journey through the AWS AI League ASEAN finals</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS AI League, launched by Amazon Web Services (AWS), expanded its reach to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) last year, welcoming student participants from Singapore, Indonesia, Malaysia, Thailand, Vietnam, and the Philippines. In this blog post, you’ll hear directly from the AWS AI League champion, Blix D. Foryasen, as he shares his reflection on the challenges, breakthroughs, and key lessons discovered throughout the competition.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy AI agents on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore using GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use a GitHub Actions workflow to automate the deployment of AI agents on AgentCore Runtime. This approach delivers a scalable solution with enterprise-level security controls, providing complete continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) automation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-ai-agents-on-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-using-github-actions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Amazon AMET Payments team accelerates test case generation with Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how we overcame the limitations of single-agent AI systems through a human-centric approach, implemented structured outputs to significantly reduce hallucinations and built a scalable solution now positioned for expansion across the AMET QA team and later across other QA teams in International Emerging Stores and Payments (IESP) Org.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-the-amazon-amet-payments-team-accelerates-test-case-generation-with-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI-powered business reporting solution with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces generative AI guided business reporting—with a focus on writing achievements &amp;amp; challenges about your business—providing a smart, practical solution that helps simplify and accelerate internal communication and reporting.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-generative-ai-powered-business-reporting-solution-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguard generative AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can address these challenges by adding centralized safeguards to a custom multi-provider generative AI gateway using Amazon Bedrock Guardrails.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/safeguard-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale creative asset discovery with Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings unified vector search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we describe how you can use Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings to retrieve specific video segments. We also review a real-world use case in which Nova Multimodal Embeddings achieved a recall success rate of 96.7% and a high-precision recall of 73.3% (returning the target content in the top two results) when tested against a library of 170 gaming creative assets. The model also demonstrates strong cross-language capabilities with minimal performance degradation across multiple languages.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
