<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:31:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Agents observability using Arize AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce a new integration between Arize AI and Amazon Bedrock Agents that addresses one of the most significant challenges in AI development: observability. In this post, we demonstrate the Arize Phoenix system for tracing and evaluation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-agents-observability-using-arize-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How SkillShow automates youth sports video processing using Amazon Transcribe</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 15:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SkillShow, a leader in youth sports video production, films over 300 events yearly in the youth sports industry, creating content for over 20,000 young athletes annually. This post describes how SkillShow used Amazon Transcribe and other Amazon Web Services (AWS) machine learning (ML) services to automate their video processing workflow, reducing editing time and costs while scaling their operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-skillshow-automates-youth-sports-video-processing-using-amazon-transcribe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NewDay builds A Generative AI based Customer service Agent Assist with over 90% accuracy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 15:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Sergio Zavota and Amy Perring from NewDay. NewDay has a clear and defining purpose: to help people move forward with credit. NewDay provides around 4 million customers access to credit responsibly and delivers exceptional customer experiences, powered by their in-house technology system. NewDay’s contact center handles 2.5 million calls annually, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/newday-builds-a-generative-ai-based-customer-service-agent-assist-with-over-90-accuracy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No-code data preparation for time series forecasting using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Canvas offers no-code solutions that simplify data wrangling, making time series forecasting accessible to all users regardless of their technical background. In this post, we explore how SageMaker Canvas and SageMaker Data Wrangler provide no-code data preparation techniques that empower users of all backgrounds to prepare data and build time series forecasting models in a single interface with confidence.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/no-code-data-preparation-for-time-series-forecasting-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an agentic multimodal AI assistant with Amazon Nova and Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how agentic workflow patterns such as Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), multi-tool orchestration, and conditional routing with LangGraph enable end-to-end solutions that artificial intelligence and machine learning (AI/ML) developers and enterprise architects can adopt and extend. We walk through an example of a financial management AI assistant that can provide quantitative research and grounded financial advice by analyzing both the earnings call (audio) and the presentation slides (images), along with relevant financial data feeds.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a scalable AI video generator using Amazon SageMaker AI and CogVideoX</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In recent years, the rapid advancement of artificial intelligence and machine learning (AI/ML) technologies has revolutionized various aspects of digital content creation. One particularly exciting development is the emergence of video generation capabilities, which offer unprecedented opportunities for companies across diverse industries. This technology allows for the creation of short video clips that can be […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-scalable-ai-video-generator-using-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-cogvideox/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building trust in AI: The AWS approach to the EU AI Act</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The EU AI Act establishes comprehensive regulations for AI development and deployment within the EU. AWS is committed to building trust in AI through various initiatives including being among the first signatories of the EU&#39;s AI Pact, providing AI Service Cards and guardrails, and offering educational resources while helping customers understand their responsibilities under the new regulatory framework.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-trust-in-ai-the-aws-approach-to-the-eu-ai-act/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on the AWS DeepRacer Student Portal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting July 14, 2025, the AWS DeepRacer Student Portal will enter a maintenance phase where new registrations will be disabled. Until September 15, 2025, existing users will retain full access to their content and training materials, with updates limited to critical security fixes, after which the portal will no longer be available.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/update-on-the-aws-deepracer-student-portal/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate foundation model training and inference with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod and Amazon SageMaker Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how SageMaker HyperPod and SageMaker Studio can improve and speed up the development experience of data scientists by using IDEs and tooling of SageMaker Studio and the scalability and resiliency of SageMaker HyperPod with Amazon EKS. The solution simplifies the setup for the system administrator of the centralized system by using the governance and security capabilities offered by the AWS services.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-foundation-model-training-and-inference-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-and-amazon-sagemaker-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting summarization and action item extraction with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a benchmark of different understanding models from the Amazon Nova family available on Amazon Bedrock, to provide insights on how you can choose the best model for a meeting summarization task.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/meeting-summarization-and-action-item-extraction-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a custom text-to-SQL agent using Amazon Bedrock and Converse API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 16:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developing robust text-to-SQL capabilities is a critical challenge in the field of natural language processing (NLP) and database management. The complexity of NLP and database management increases in this field, particularly while dealing with complex queries and database structures. In this post, we introduce a straightforward but powerful solution with accompanying code to text-to-SQL using a custom agent implementation along with Amazon Bedrock and Converse API.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-custom-text-to-sql-agent-using-amazon-bedrock-and-converse-api/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate threat modeling with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 16:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how generative AI can revolutionize threat modeling practices by automating vulnerability identification, generating comprehensive attack scenarios, and providing contextual mitigation strategies.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-threat-modeling-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
