<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:38:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a FinOps agent using Amazon Bedrock with multi-agent capability and Amazon Nova as the foundation model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we use the multi-agent feature of Amazon Bedrock to demonstrate a powerful and innovative approach to AWS cost management. By using the advanced capabilities of Amazon Nova FMs, we’ve developed a solution that showcases how AI-driven agents can revolutionize the way organizations analyze, optimize, and manage their AWS costs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-finops-agent-using-amazon-bedrock-with-multi-agent-capability-and-amazon-nova-as-the-foundation-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stream ingest data from Kafka to Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases using custom connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2025/18_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For this post, we implement a RAG architecture with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases using a custom connector and topics built with Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (Amazon MSK) for a user who may be interested to understand stock price trends.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/stream-ingest-data-from-kafka-to-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-using-custom-connectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Zoom as a data accessor to your Amazon Q index</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 18:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how Zoom users can access their Amazon Q Business enterprise data directly within their Zoom interface, alleviating the need to switch between applications while maintaining enterprise security boundaries. Organizations can now configure Zoom as a data accessor in Amazon Q Business, enabling seamless integration between their Amazon Q index and Zoom AI Companion. This integration allows users to access their enterprise knowledge in a controlled manner directly within the Zoom platform.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of quality assurance: Shift-left testing with QyrusAI and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 16:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how QyrusAI and Amazon Bedrock are revolutionizing shift-left testing, enabling teams to deliver better software faster. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that allows businesses to build and scale generative AI applications using foundation models (FMs) from leading AI providers. It enables seamless integration with AWS services, offering customization, security, and scalability without managing infrastructure.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-future-of-quality-assurance-shift-left-testing-with-qyrusai-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate video insights for contextual advertising using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 16:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Data Automation (BDA) is a new managed feature powered by FMs in Amazon Bedrock. BDA extracts structured outputs from unstructured content—including documents, images, video, and audio—while alleviating the need for complex custom workflows. In this post, we demonstrate how BDA automatically extracts rich video insights such as chapter segments and audio segments, detects text in scenes, and classifies Interactive Advertising Bureau (IAB) taxonomies, and then uses these insights to build a nonlinear ads solution to enhance contextual advertising effectiveness.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Salesforce achieves high-performance model deployment with Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 16:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_04_2025/17_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a joint collaboration between Salesforce and AWS and is being cross-published on both the Salesforce Engineering Blog and the AWS Machine Learning Blog. The Salesforce AI Model Serving team is working to push the boundaries of natural language processing and AI capabilities for enterprise applications. Their key focus areas include optimizing large […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-salesforce-achieves-high-performance-model-deployment-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Amazon EKS troubleshooting using an Amazon Bedrock agentic workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 20:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to orchestrate multiple Amazon Bedrock agents to create a sophisticated Amazon EKS troubleshooting system. By enabling collaboration between specialized agents—deriving insights from K8sGPT and performing actions through the ArgoCD framework—you can build a comprehensive automation that identifies, analyzes, and resolves cluster issues with minimal human intervention.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-amazon-eks-troubleshooting-using-an-amazon-bedrock-agentic-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host concurrent LLMs with LoRAX</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 19:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) can be used to address these challenges effectively. Specifically, we discuss using LoRA serving with LoRA eXchange (LoRAX) and Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) GPU instances, allowing organizations to efficiently manage and serve their growing portfolio of fine-tuned models, optimize costs, and provide seamless performance for their customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/host-concurrent-llms-with-lorax/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a computer vision-based asset inventory application with low or no training</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 19:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2025/16_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a solution using generative AI and large language models (LLMs) to alleviate the time-consuming and labor-intensive tasks required to build a computer vision application, enabling you to immediately start taking pictures of your asset labels and extract the necessary information to update the inventory using AWS services
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-computer-vision-based-asset-inventory-application-with-low-or-no-training/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clario enhances the quality of the clinical trial documentation process with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The collaboration between Clario and AWS demonstrated the potential of AWS AI and machine learning (AI/ML) services and generative AI models, such as Anthropic’s Claude, to streamline document generation processes in the life sciences industry and, specifically, for complicated clinical trial processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/clario-enhances-the-quality-of-the-clinical-trial-documentation-process-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Mixtral 8x7B on Amazon SageMaker with AWS Inferentia2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 17:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to deploy and serve the Mixtral 8x7B language model on AWS Inferentia2 instances for cost-effective, high-performance inference. We&#39;ll walk through model compilation using Hugging Face Optimum Neuron, which provides a set of tools enabling straightforward model loading, training, and inference, and the Text Generation Inference (TGI) Container, which has the toolkit for deploying and serving LLMs with Hugging Face.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-mixtral-8x7b-on-amazon-sagemaker-with-aws-inferentia2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate business productivity with Amazon Q and Amazon Connect</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 17:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_04_2025/15_04_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to elevate business productivity by leveraging Amazon Q to provide insights that enable research, data analysis, and report potential fraud cases within Amazon Connect.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-business-productivity-with-amazon-q-and-amazon-connect/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build multi-agent systems with LangGraph and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to integrate open-source multi-agent framework, LangGraph, with Amazon Bedrock. It explains how to use LangGraph and Amazon Bedrock to build powerful, interactive multi-agent applications that use graph-based orchestration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-multi-agent-systems-with-langgraph-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic text-to-SQL for enterprise workloads with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_04_2025/14_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how enterprises can implement a scalable agentic text-to-SQL solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents, with advanced error-handling tools and automated schema discovery to enhance database query efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dynamic-text-to-sql-for-enterprise-workloads-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AIOps chatbot with Amazon Q Business custom plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use custom plugins for Amazon Q Business to build a chatbot that can interact with multiple APIs using natural language prompts. We showcase how to build an AIOps chatbot that enables users to interact with their AWS infrastructure through natural language queries and commands. The chatbot is capable of handling tasks such as querying the data about Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) ports and Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) buckets access settings.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How TransPerfect Improved Translation Quality and Efficiency Using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes how the AWS Customer Channel Technology – Localization Team worked with TransPerfect to integrate Amazon Bedrock into the GlobalLink translation management system, a cloud-based solution designed to help organizations manage their multilingual content and translation workflows. Organizations use TransPerfect’s solution to rapidly create and deploy content at scale in multiple languages using AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-transperfect-improved-translation-quality-and-efficiency-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racing beyond DeepRacer: Debut of the AWS LLM League</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 17:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_04_2025/11_04_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS LLM League was designed to lower the barriers to entry in generative AI model customization by providing an experience where participants, regardless of their prior data science experience, could engage in fine-tuning LLMs. Using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart, attendees were guided through the process of customizing LLMs to address real business challenges adaptable to their domain.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/racing-beyond-deepracer-debut-of-the-aws-llm-league/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
