<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:23:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How AWS delivers generative AI to the public sector in weeks, not years</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Experts at the Generative AI Innovation Center share several strategies to help organizations excel with generative AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-aws-delivers-generative-ai-to-the-public-sector-in-weeks-not-years/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S&amp;P Global Data integration expands Amazon Quick Research capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are pleased to announce a new integration between Amazon Quick Research and S&amp;amp;P Global. This integration brings both S&amp;amp;P Global Energy news, research, and insights and S&amp;amp;P Global Market Intelligence data to Quick Research customers in one deep research agent. In this post, we explore S&amp;amp;P Global’s data sets and the solution architecture of the integration with Quick Research.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/sp-global-data-integration-expands-amazon-quick-research-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline AI agent tool interactions: Connect API Gateway to AgentCore Gateway with MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AgentCore Gateway now supports API GatewayAs organizations explore the possibilities of agentic applications, they continue to navigate challenges of using enterprise data as context in invocation requests to large language models (LLMs) in a manner that is secure and aligned with enterprise policies. This post covers these new capabilities and shows how to implement them.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-ai-agent-tool-interactions-connect-api-gateway-to-agentcore-gateway-with-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an intelligent insurance underwriter agent powered by Amazon Nova 2 Lite and Amazon Quick Suite</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build an intelligent insurance underwriting agent that addresses three critical challenges: unifying siloed data across CRM systems and databases, providing explainable and auditable AI decisions for regulatory compliance, and enabling automated fraud detection with consistent underwriting rules. The solution combines Amazon Nova 2 Lite for transparent risk assessment, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore for managed MCP server infrastructure, and Amazon Quick Suite for natural language interactions—delivering a production-ready system that underwriters can deploy in under 30 minutes .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
