<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:31:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a multi-agent voice assistant with Amazon Nova Sonic and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Nova Sonic&#39;s speech-to-speech capabilities can be combined with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to create sophisticated multi-agent voice assistants that break complex tasks into specialized, manageable components. The approach demonstrates how to build modular, scalable voice applications using a banking assistant example with dedicated sub-agents for authentication, banking inquiries, and mortgage services, offering a more maintainable alternative to monolithic voice assistant designs.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate large-scale AI training with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training operator</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy and manage machine learning training workloads using the Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training operator, which enhances training resilience for Kubernetes workloads through pinpoint recovery and customizable monitoring capabilities. The Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training operator helps accelerate generative AI model development by efficiently managing distributed training across large GPU clusters, offering benefits like centralized training process monitoring, granular process recovery, and hanging job detection that can reduce recovery times from tens of minutes to seconds.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How TP ICAP transformed CRM data into real-time insights with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how TP ICAP used Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon Bedrock Evaluations to build ClientIQ, an enterprise-grade solution with enhanced security features for extracting CRM insights using AI, delivering immediate business value.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-tp-icap-transformed-crm-data-into-real-time-insights-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principal Financial Group accelerates build, test, and deployment of Amazon Lex V2 bots through automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the post Principal Financial Group increases Voice Virtual Assistant performance using Genesys, Amazon Lex, and Amazon QuickSight, we discussed the overall Principal Virtual Assistant solution using Genesys Cloud, Amazon Lex V2, multiple AWS services, and a custom reporting and analytics solution using Amazon QuickSight.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/principal-financial-group-accelerates-build-test-and-deployment-of-amazon-lex-v2-bots-through-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond vibes: How to properly select the right LLM for the right task</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss an approach that can guide you to build comprehensive and empirically driven evaluations that can help you make better decisions when selecting the right model for your task.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/beyond-vibes-how-to-properly-select-the-right-llm-for-the-right-task/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splash Music transforms music generation using AWS Trainium and Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Splash Music is setting a new standard for AI-powered music creation by using its advanced HummingLM model with AWS Trainium on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod. As a selected startup in the 2024 AWS Generative AI Accelerator, Splash Music collaborated closely with AWS Startups and the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to fast-track innovation and accelerate their music generation FM development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterative fine-tuning on Amazon Bedrock for strategic model improvement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 23:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations often face challenges when implementing single-shot fine-tuning approaches for their generative AI models. The single-shot fine-tuning method involves selecting training data, configuring hyperparameters, and hoping the results meet expectations without the ability to make incremental adjustments. Single-shot fine-tuning frequently leads to suboptimal results and requires starting the entire process from scratch when improvements are […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/iterative-fine-tuning-on-amazon-bedrock-for-strategic-model-improvement/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voice AI-powered drive-thru ordering with Amazon Nova Sonic and dynamic menu displays</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 18:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll demonstrate how to implement a Quick Service Restaurants (QSRs) drive-thru solution using Amazon Nova Sonic and AWS services. We&#39;ll walk through building an intelligent system that combines voice AI with interactive menu displays, providing technical insights and implementation guidance to help restaurants modernize their drive-thru operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/voice-ai-powered-drive-thru-ordering-with-amazon-nova-sonic-and-dynamic-menu-displays/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing document AI and structured outputs by fine-tuning Amazon Nova Models and on-demand inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 18:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides a comprehensive hands-on guide to fine-tune Amazon Nova Lite for document processing tasks, with a focus on tax form data extraction. Using our open-source GitHub repository code sample, we demonstrate the complete workflow from data preparation to model deployment. Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-document-ai-and-structured-outputs-by-fine-tuning-amazon-nova-models-and-on-demand-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming enterprise operations: Four high-impact use cases with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share four high-impact, widely adopted use cases built with Nova in Amazon Bedrock, supported by real-world customers deployments, offerings available from AWS partners, and experiences. These examples are ideal for organizations researching their own AI adoption strategies and use cases across industries.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transforming-enterprise-operations-four-high-impact-use-cases-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building smarter AI agents: AgentCore long-term memory deep dive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory transforms raw conversational data into persistent, actionable knowledge through sophisticated extraction, consolidation, and retrieval mechanisms that mirror human cognitive processes. The system tackles the complex challenge of building AI agents that don&#39;t just store conversations but extract meaningful insights, merge related information across time, and maintain coherent memory stores that enable truly context-aware interactions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-smarter-ai-agents-agentcore-long-term-memory-deep-dive/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure and verify a distributed training cluster with AWS Deep Learning Containers on Amazon EKS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Misconfiguration issues in distributed training with Amazon EKS can be prevented following a systematic approach to launch required components and verify their proper configuration. This post walks through the steps to set up and verify an EKS cluster for training large models using DLCs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/configure-and-verify-a-distributed-training-cluster-with-aws-deep-learning-containers-on-amazon-eks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala development in Amazon SageMaker Studio with Almond kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides a comprehensive guide on integrating the Almond kernel into SageMaker Studio, offering a solution for Scala development within the platform.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scala-development-in-amazon-sagemaker-studio-with-almond-kernel/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a device management agent with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a conversational device management system using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore. With this solution, users can manage their IoT devices through natural language, using a UI for tasks like checking device status, configuring WiFi networks, and monitoring user activity.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-device-management-agent-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import streamlined LLM deployment for Salesforce</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how Salesforce integrated Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import into their machine learning operations (MLOps) workflow, reused existing endpoints without application changes, and benchmarked scalability. We share key metrics on operational efficiency and cost optimization gains, and offer practical insights for simplifying your deployment strategy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import-streamlined-llm-deployment-for-salesforce/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
