<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:25:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Agents for Amazon Bedrock to interactively generate infrastructure as code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how Agents for Amazon Bedrock can be used to generate customized, organization standards-compliant IaC scripts directly from uploaded architecture diagrams. This will help accelerate deployments, reduce errors, and ensure adherence to security guidelines.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-agents-for-amazon-bedrock-to-interactively-generate-infrastructure-as-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve RAG accuracy with fine-tuned embedding models on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use Amazon SageMaker to fine tune a Sentence Transformer embedding model and deploy it with an Amazon SageMaker Endpoint. The code from this post and more examples are available in the GitHub repo.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-rag-accuracy-with-fine-tuned-embedding-models-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BRIA AI used distributed training in Amazon SageMaker to train latent diffusion foundation models for commercial use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Bar Fingerman from BRIA AI. This post explains how BRIA AI trained BRIA AI 2.0, a high-resolution (1024×1024) text-to-image diffusion model, on a dataset comprising petabytes of licensed images quickly and economically. Amazon SageMaker training jobs and Amazon SageMaker distributed training libraries took on the undifferentiated heavy lifting associated with infrastructure […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-bria-ai-used-distributed-training-in-amazon-sagemaker-to-train-latent-diffusion-foundation-models-for-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create custom images for geospatial analysis with Amazon SageMaker Distribution in Amazon SageMaker Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to extend Amazon SageMaker Distribution with additional dependencies to create a custom container image tailored for geospatial analysis. Although the example in this post focuses on geospatial data science, the methodology presented can be applied to any kind of custom image based on SageMaker Distribution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-custom-images-for-geospatial-analysis-with-amazon-sagemaker-distribution-in-amazon-sagemaker-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating model customization in Amazon Bedrock with AWS Step Functions workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models have become indispensable in generating intelligent and nuanced responses across a wide variety of business use cases. However, enterprises often have unique data and use cases that require customizing large language models beyond their out-of-the-box capabilities. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automating-model-customization-in-amazon-bedrock-with-aws-step-functions-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock now supports advanced parsing, chunking, and query reformulation giving greater control of accuracy in RAG based applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that helps you implement the entire Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) workflow from ingestion to retrieval and prompt augmentation without having to build custom integrations to data sources and manage data flows, pushing the boundaries for what you can do in your RAG workflows. However, it’s […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-now-supports-advanced-parsing-chunking-and-query-reformulation-giving-greater-control-of-accuracy-in-rag-based-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline generative AI development in Amazon Bedrock with Prompt Management and Prompt Flows (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to introduce two powerful new features for Amazon Bedrock: Prompt Management and Prompt Flows, in public preview. These features are designed to accelerate the development, testing, and deployment of generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications, enabling developers and business users to create more efficient and effective solutions that are easier to maintain. You […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-generative-ai-development-in-amazon-bedrock-with-prompt-management-and-prompt-flows-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering everyone with GenAI to rapidly build, customize, and deploy apps securely: Highlights from the AWS New York Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine this—all employees relying on generative artificial intelligence (AI) to get their work done faster, every task becoming less mundane and more innovative, and every application providing a more useful, personal, and engaging experience. To realize this future, organizations need more than a single, powerful large language model (LLM) or chat assistant. They need a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/empowering-everyone-with-genai-to-rapidly-build-customize-and-deploy-apps-securely-highlights-from-the-aws-new-york-summit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A progress update on our commitment to safe, responsible generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Responsible AI is a longstanding commitment at Amazon. From the outset, we have prioritized responsible AI innovation by embedding safety, fairness, robustness, security, and privacy into our development processes and educating our employees. We strive to make our customers’ lives better while also establishing and implementing the necessary safeguards to help protect them. Our practical […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-progress-update-on-our-commitment-to-safe-responsible-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Anthropic’s Claude 3 Haiku in Amazon Bedrock to boost model accuracy and quality</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 15:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2024/10_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Frontier large language models (LLMs) like Anthropic Claude on Amazon Bedrock are trained on vast amounts of data, allowing Anthropic Claude to understand and generate human-like text. Fine-tuning Anthropic Claude 3 Haiku on proprietary datasets can provide optimal performance on specific domains or tasks. The fine-tuning as a deep level of customization represents a key […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-anthropics-claude-3-haiku-in-amazon-bedrock-to-boost-model-accuracy-and-quality/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve up to ~2x higher throughput while reducing costs by up to ~50% for generative AI inference on Amazon SageMaker with the new inference optimization toolkit – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 21:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative artificial intelligence (AI) inference becomes increasingly critical for businesses, customers are seeking ways to scale their generative AI operations or integrate generative AI models into existing workflows. Model optimization has emerged as a crucial step, allowing organizations to balance cost-effectiveness and responsiveness, improving productivity. However, price-performance requirements vary widely across use cases. For […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-up-to-2x-higher-throughput-while-reducing-costs-by-up-to-50-for-generative-ai-inference-on-amazon-sagemaker-with-the-new-inference-optimization-toolkit-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve up to ~2x higher throughput while reducing costs by ~50% for generative AI inference on Amazon SageMaker with the new inference optimization toolkit – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 21:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, Amazon SageMaker announced a new inference optimization toolkit that helps you reduce the time it takes to optimize generative artificial intelligence (AI) models from months to hours, to achieve best-in-class performance for your use case. With this new capability, you can choose from a menu of optimization techniques, apply them to your generative AI […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-up-to-2x-higher-throughput-while-reducing-costs-by-50-for-generative-ai-inference-on-amazon-sagemaker-with-the-new-inference-optimization-toolkit-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet ranks number 1 for business and finance in S&amp;P AI Benchmarks by Kensho</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2024/09_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet currently ranks at the top of S&amp;amp;P AI Benchmarks by Kensho, which assesses large language models (LLMs) for finance and business. Kensho is the AI Innovation Hub for S&amp;amp;P Global. Using Amazon Bedrock, Kensho was able to quickly run Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet through a challenging suite of business and financial […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/anthropic-claude-3-5-sonnet-ranks-number-1-for-business-and-finance-in-sp-ai-benchmarks-by-kensho/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weather Company enhances MLOps with Amazon SageMaker, AWS CloudFormation, and Amazon CloudWatch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 19:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share the story of how The Weather Company (TWCo) enhanced its MLOps platform using services such as Amazon SageMaker, AWS CloudFormation, and Amazon CloudWatch. TWCo data scientists and ML engineers took advantage of automation, detailed experiment tracking, integrated training, and deployment pipelines to help scale MLOps effectively. TWCo reduced infrastructure management time by 90% while also reducing model deployment time by 20%.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-weather-company-enhances-mlops-with-amazon-sagemaker-aws-cloudformation-and-amazon-cloudwatch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eviden scales AWS DeepRacer Global League using AWS DeepRacer Event Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 18:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Eviden is a next-gen technology leader in data-driven, trusted, and sustainable digital transformation. With a strong portfolio of patented technologies and worldwide leading positions in advanced computing, security, AI, cloud, and digital platforms, Eviden provides deep expertise for a multitude of industries in more than 47 countries. Eviden is an AWS Premier partner, bringing together […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/eviden-scales-aws-deepracer-global-league-using-aws-deepracer-event-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate unique images by fine-tuning Stable Diffusion XL with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 18:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2024/08_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stable Diffusion XL by Stability AI is a high-quality text-to-image deep learning model that allows you to generate professional-looking images in various styles. Managed versions of Stable Diffusion XL are already available to you on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart (see Use Stable Diffusion XL with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart in Amazon SageMaker Studio) and Amazon Bedrock (see […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-unique-images-by-fine-tuning-stable-diffusion-xl-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
