<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 17:02:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a Multi-Agent System with LangGraph and Mistral on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 17:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use LangGraph and Mistral models on Amazon Bedrock to create a powerful multi-agent system that can handle sophisticated workflows through collaborative problem-solving. This integration enables the creation of AI agents that can work together to solve complex problems, mimicking humanlike reasoning and collaboration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-multi-agent-system-with-langgraph-and-mistral-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate RAG responses with Amazon Bedrock, LlamaIndex and RAGAS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 16:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_03_2025/06_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we’ll explore how to leverage Amazon Bedrock, LlamaIndex, and RAGAS to enhance your RAG implementations. You’ll learn practical techniques to evaluate and optimize your AI systems, enabling more accurate, context-aware responses that align with your organization’s specific needs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-rag-responses-with-amazon-bedrock-llamaindex-and-ragas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovating at speed: BMW’s generative AI solution for cloud incident analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how BMW uses generative AI to speed up the root cause analysis of incidents in complex and distributed systems in the cloud such as BMW’s Connected Vehicle backend serving 23 million vehicles. Read on to learn how the solution, collaboratively pioneered by AWS and BMW, uses Amazon Bedrock Agents and Amazon CloudWatch logs and metrics to find root causes quicker. This post is intended for cloud solution architects and developers interested in speeding up their incident workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series forecasting with LLM-based foundation models and scalable AIOps on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will guide you through the process of integrating Chronos into Amazon SageMaker Pipeline using a synthetic dataset that simulates a sales forecasting scenario, unlocking accurate and efficient predictions with minimal data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/time-series-forecasting-with-llm-based-foundation-models-and-scalable-aiops-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ground truth generation and review best practices for evaluating generative AI question-answering with FMEval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_03_2025/05_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss best practices for applying LLMs to generate ground truth for evaluating question-answering assistants with FMEval on an enterprise scale. FMEval is a comprehensive evaluation suite from Amazon SageMaker Clarify, and provides standardized implementations of metrics to assess quality and responsibility. To learn more about FMEval, see Evaluate large language models for quality and responsibility of LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ground-truth-generation-and-review-best-practices-for-evaluating-generative-ai-question-answering-with-fmeval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate AWS Well-Architected reviews with Generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 16:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a generative AI solution leveraging Amazon Bedrock to streamline the WAFR process. We demonstrate how to harness the power of LLMs to build an intelligent, scalable system that analyzes architecture documents and generates insightful recommendations based on AWS Well-Architected best practices. This solution automates portions of the WAFR report creation, helping solutions architects improve the efficiency and thoroughness of architectural assessments while supporting their decision-making process.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic metadata filtering for Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases with LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 16:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_03_2025/04_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases has a metadata filtering capability that allows you to refine search results based on specific attributes of the documents, improving retrieval accuracy and the relevance of responses. These metadata filters can be used in combination with the typical semantic (or hybrid) similarity search. In this post, we discuss using metadata filters with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dynamic-metadata-filtering-for-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-with-langchain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize DeepSeek-R1 distilled models using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod recipes – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 21:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this two-part series, we discuss how you can reduce the DeepSeek model customization complexity by using the pre-built fine-tuning workflows (also called “recipes”) for both DeepSeek-R1 model and its distilled variations, released as part of Amazon SageMaker HyperPod recipes. In this first post, we will build a solution architecture for fine-tuning DeepSeek-R1 distilled models and demonstrate the approach by providing a step-by-step example on customizing the DeepSeek-R1 Distill Qwen 7b model using recipes, achieving an average of 25% on all the Rouge scores, with a maximum of 49% on Rouge 2 score with both SageMaker HyperPod and SageMaker training jobs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce conversational AI response time through inference at the edge with AWS Local Zones</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 16:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide demonstrates how to deploy an open source foundation model from Hugging Face on Amazon EC2 instances across three locations: a commercial AWS Region and two AWS Local Zones. Through comparative benchmarking tests, we illustrate how deploying foundation models in Local Zones closer to end users can significantly reduce latency—a critical factor for real-time applications such as conversational AI assistants.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/reduce-conversational-ai-response-time-through-inference-at-the-edge-with-aws-local-zones/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixtral-12B-2409 is now available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 16:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_03_2025/03_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how to discover, deploy, and use the Mistral AI Pixtral 12B model for a variety of real-world vision use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pixtral-12b-2409-is-now-available-on-amazon-bedrock-marketplace/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline work insights with the Amazon Q Business connector for Smartsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explains how to integrate Smartsheet with Amazon Q Business to use natural language and generative AI capabilities for enhanced insights. Smartsheet, the AI-enhanced enterprise-grade work management platform, helps users manage projects, programs, and processes at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-work-insights-with-the-amazon-q-business-connector-for-smartsheet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level up your problem-solving and strategic thinking skills with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet in Amazon Bedrock can be used for a variety of business-related cognitive tasks, such as problem-solving, critical thinking and ideation—to help augment human thinking and improve decision-making among knowledge workers to accelerate innovation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/level-up-your-problem-solving-and-strategic-thinking-skills-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing AI implementation costs with Automat-it</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this guest post, we explain how AWS Partner Automat-it helped their customer achieve a more than twelvefold cost savings while keeping AI model performance within the required performance thresholds. This was accomplished through careful tuning of architecture, algorithm selection, and infrastructure management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-ai-implementation-costs-with-automat-it/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of an era: the final AWS DeepRacer League Championship at re:Invent 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_02_2025/28_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS DeepRacer League is the world&#39;s first global autonomous racing league powered by machine learning (ML). Over the past 6 years, a diverse community of over 560,000 builders from more than 150 countries worldwide have participated in the League to learn ML fundamentals hands-on through the fun of friendly autonomous racing. After an 8-month season of nail-biting virtual qualifiers, finalists convened in person at re:Invent in Las Vegas for one final showdown to compete for prizes and glory in the high-stakes, winner-take-all AWS DeepRacer League Championship.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate healthcare generative AI applications using LLM-as-a-judge on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 17:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to implement this evaluation framework using Amazon Bedrock, compare the performance of different generator models, including Anthropic’s Claude and Amazon Nova on Amazon Bedrock, and showcase how to use the new RAG evaluation feature to optimize knowledge base parameters and assess retrieval quality.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-healthcare-generative-ai-applications-using-llm-as-a-judge-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS DeepRacer: Closing time at AWS re:Invent 2024 –How did that physical racing go?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 17:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_02_2025/27_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In AWS DeepRacer: How to master physical racing?, I wrote in detail about some aspects relevant to racing AWS DeepRacer in the physical world. The previous post was left open-ended—with one last Championship Final left, it was too early to share all my secrets. Now that AWS re:Invent is over, it’s time to share my strategy, how I prepared, and how it went in the end.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-deepracer-closing-time-at-aws-reinvent-2024-how-did-that-physical-racing-go/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
