<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 15:50:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delight your customers with great conversational experiences via QnABot, a generative AI chatbot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 15:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            QnABot on AWS (an AWS Solution) now provides access to Amazon Bedrock foundational models (FMs) and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed end-to-end Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) workflow. You can now provide contextual information from your private data sources that can be used to create rich, contextual, conversational experiences. In this post, we discuss how to use QnABot on AWS to deploy a fully functional chatbot integrated with other AWS services, and delight your customers with human agent like conversational experiences.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing document-level sync reports: Enhanced data sync visibility in Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 19:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a fully managed, generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered assistant that helps enterprises unlock the value of their data and knowledge. With Amazon Q, you can quickly find answers to questions, generate summaries and content, and complete tasks by using the information and expertise stored across your company’s various data sources and enterprise […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-document-level-sync-reports-enhanced-data-sync-visibility-in-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derive generative AI-powered insights from ServiceNow with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 14:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to configure the Amazon Q ServiceNow connector to index your ServiceNow platform and take advantage of generative AI searches in Amazon Q. We use an example of an illustrative ServiceNow platform to discuss technical topics related to AWS services.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/derive-generative-ai-powered-insights-from-servicenow-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent healthcare forms analysis with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore using the Anthropic Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock large language model (LLM). Amazon Bedrock provides access to several LLMs, such as Anthropic Claude 3, which can be used to generate semi-structured data relevant to the healthcare industry. This can be particularly useful for creating various healthcare-related forms, such as patient intake forms, insurance claim forms, or medical history questionnaires.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/intelligent-healthcare-forms-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harness the power of AI and ML using Splunk and Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2024/12_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For organizations looking beyond the use of out-of-the-box Splunk AI/ML features, this post explores how Amazon SageMaker Canvas, a no-code ML development service, can be used in conjunction with data collected in Splunk to drive actionable insights. We also demonstrate how to use the generative AI capabilities of SageMaker Canvas to speed up your data exploration and help you build better ML models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/harness-the-power-of-ai-and-ml-using-splunk-and-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Deltek uses Amazon Bedrock for question and answering on government solicitation documents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2024/09_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides an overview of a custom solution developed by the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) for Deltek, a globally recognized standard for project-based businesses in both government contracting and professional services. Deltek serves over 30,000 clients with industry-specific software and information solutions. In this collaboration, the AWS GenAIIC team created a RAG-based solution for Deltek to enable Q&amp;amp;A on single and multiple government solicitation documents. The solution uses AWS services including Amazon Textract, Amazon OpenSearch Service, and Amazon Bedrock.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights from Box with the Amazon Q Box connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Seamless access to content and insights is crucial for delivering exceptional customer experiences and driving successful business outcomes. Box, a leading cloud content management platform, serves as a central repository for diverse digital assets and documents in many organizations. An enterprise Box account typically contains a wealth of materials, including documents, presentations, knowledge articles, and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-from-box-with-the-amazon-q-box-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Twilio generated SQL using Looker Modeling Language data with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2024/08_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As one of the largest AWS customers, Twilio engages with data, artificial intelligence (AI), and machine learning (ML) services to run their daily workloads. This post highlights how Twilio enabled natural language-driven data exploration of business intelligence (BI) data with RAG and Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-twilio-generated-sql-using-looker-modeling-language-data-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
