<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meet Boti: The AI assistant transforming how the citizens of Buenos Aires access government information with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes the agentic AI assistant built by the Government of the City of Buenos Aires and the GenAIIC to respond to citizens’ questions about government procedures. The solution consists of two primary components: an input guardrail system that helps prevent the system from responding to harmful user queries and a government procedures agent that retrieves relevant information and generates responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/meet-boti-the-ai-assistant-transforming-how-the-citizens-of-buenos-aires-access-government-information-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering air quality research with secure, ML-driven predictive analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a data imputation solution using Amazon SageMaker AI, AWS Lambda, and AWS Step Functions. This solution is designed for environmental analysts, public health officials, and business intelligence professionals who need reliable PM2.5 data for trend analysis, reporting, and decision-making. We sourced our sample training dataset from openAFRICA. Our solution predicts PM2.5 values using time-series forecasting.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/empowering-air-quality-research-with-secure-ml-driven-predictive-analytics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Finance built an AI assistant using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Kendra to support analysts for data discovery and business insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Amazon Finance technical team develops and manages comprehensive technology solutions that power financial decision-making and operational efficiency while standardizing across Amazon’s global operations. In this post, we explain how the team conceptualized and implemented a solution to these business challenges by harnessing the power of generative AI using Amazon Bedrock and intelligent search with Amazon Kendra.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-finance-built-an-ai-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-kendra-to-support-analysts-for-data-discovery-and-business-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercury foundation models from Inception Labs are now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 15:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we announce that Mercury and Mercury Coder foundation models from Inception Labs are now available through Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. We demonstrate how to deploy these ultra-fast diffusion-based language models that can generate up to 1,100 tokens per second on NVIDIA H100 GPUs, and showcase their capabilities in code generation and tool use scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mercury-foundation-models-from-inception-labs-are-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn how Amazon Health Services improved discovery in Amazon search using AWS ML and gen AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Amazon Health Services (AHS) solved discoverability challenges on Amazon.com search using AWS services such as Amazon SageMaker, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon EMR. By combining machine learning (ML), natural language processing, and vector search capabilities, we improved our ability to connect customers with relevant healthcare offerings.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/learn-how-amazon-health-services-improved-discovery-in-amazon-search-using-aws-ml-and-gen-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Geospatial Analysis and GIS Workflows with Amazon Bedrock Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applying emerging technologies to the geospatial domain offers a unique opportunity to create transformative user experiences and intuitive workstreams for users and organizations to deliver on their missions and responsibilities. In this post, we explore how you can integrate existing systems with Amazon Bedrock to create new workflows to unlock efficiencies insights. This integration can benefit technical, nontechnical, and leadership roles alike.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-geospatial-analysis-and-gis-workflows-with-amazon-bedrock-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the basics: A comprehensive foundation model selection framework for generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the model landscape expands, organizations face complex scenarios when selecting the right foundation model for their applications. In this blog post we present a systematic evaluation methodology for Amazon Bedrock users, combining theoretical frameworks with practical implementation strategies that empower data scientists and machine learning (ML) engineers to make optimal model selections.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/beyond-the-basics-a-comprehensive-foundation-model-selection-framework-for-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate intelligent document processing with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce our open source GenAI IDP Accelerator—a tested solution that we use to help customers across industries address their document processing challenges. Automated document processing workflows accurately extract structured information from documents, reducing manual effort. We will show you how this ready-to-deploy solution can help you build those workflows with generative AI on AWS in days instead of months.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-intelligent-document-processing-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker HyperPod enhances ML infrastructure with scalability and customizability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduced three features in SageMaker HyperPod that enhance scalability and customizability for ML infrastructure. Continuous provisioning offers flexible resource provisioning to help you start training and deploying your models faster and manage your cluster more efficiently. With custom AMIs, you can align your ML environments with organizational security standards and software requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-enhances-ml-infrastructure-with-scalability-and-customizability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune OpenAI GPT-OSS models using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod recipes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is the second part of the GPT-OSS series focusing on model customization with Amazon SageMaker AI. In Part 1, we demonstrated fine-tuning GPT-OSS models using open source Hugging Face libraries with SageMaker training jobs, which supports distributed multi-GPU and multi-node configurations, so you can spin up high-performance clusters on demand. In this post, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-openai-gpt-oss-models-using-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-recipes/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline code nodes now supported in Amazon Bedrock Flows in public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the public preview of support for inline code nodes in Amazon Bedrock Flows. With this powerful new capability, you can write Python scripts directly within your workflow, alleviating the need for separate AWS Lambda functions for simple logic. This feature streamlines preprocessing and postprocessing tasks (like data normalization and response formatting), simplifying generative AI application development and making it more accessible across organizations.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate enterprise AI implementations with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business offers AWS customers a scalable and comprehensive solution for enhancing business processes across their organization. By carefully evaluating your use cases, following implementation best practices, and using the architectural guidance provided in this post, you can deploy Amazon Q Business to transform your enterprise productivity. The key to success lies in starting small, proving value quickly, and scaling systematically across your organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-enterprise-ai-implementations-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up delivery of ML workloads using Code Editor in Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how you can use the new Code Editor and multiple spaces support in SageMaker Unified Studio. The sample solution shows how to develop an ML pipeline that automates the typical end-to-end ML activities to build, train, evaluate, and (optionally) deploy an ML model.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/speed-up-delivery-of-ml-workloads-using-code-editor-in-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Infosys Topaz leverages Amazon Bedrock to transform technical help desk operations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog, we examine the use case of a large energy supplier whose technical help desk agents answer customer calls and support field agents. We use Amazon Bedrock along with capabilities from Infosys Topaz™ to build a generative AI application that can reduce call handling times, automate tasks, and improve the overall quality of technical support.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-infosys-topaz-leverages-amazon-bedrock-to-transform-technical-help-desk-operations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
