<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 14:56:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Provide live agent assistance for your chatbot users with Amazon Lex and Talkdesk cloud contact center</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 14:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_03_2024/29_03_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Lex provides advanced conversational artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities to enable self-service support for your organization’s contact center. With Amazon Lex, you can implement an omnichannel strategy where customers engage via phone, websites, and messaging platforms. The bots can answer FAQs, provide self-service experiences, or triage customer requests before transferring to a human agent. Amazon Lex integrates […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/provide-live-agent-assistance-for-your-chatbot-users-with-amazon-lex-and-talkdesk-cloud-contact-center/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced RAG patterns on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 16:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, customers of all industries—whether it’s financial services, healthcare and life sciences, travel and hospitality, media and entertainment, telecommunications, software as a service (SaaS), and even proprietary model providers—are using large language models (LLMs) to build applications like question and answering (QnA) chatbots, search engines, and knowledge bases. These generative AI applications are not only […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advanced-rag-patterns-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient continual pre-training LLMs for financial domains</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 16:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2024/28_03_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) are generally trained on large publicly available datasets that are domain agnostic. For example, Meta’s Llama models are trained on datasets such as CommonCrawl, C4, Wikipedia, and ArXiv. These datasets encompass a broad range of topics and domains. Although the resulting models yield amazingly good results for general tasks, such as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/efficient-continual-pre-training-llms-for-financial-domains/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve DevOps maturity with BMC AMI zAdviser Enterprise and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post discusses how BMC Software added AWS Generative AI capabilities to its product BMC AMI zAdviser Enterprise. The zAdviser uses Amazon Bedrock to provide summarization, analysis, and recommendations for improvement based on the DORA metrics data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-devops-maturity-with-bmc-ami-zadviser-enterprise-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune your Amazon Titan Image Generator G1 model using Amazon Bedrock model customization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2024/27_03_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Titan lmage Generator G1 is a cutting-edge text-to-image model, available via Amazon Bedrock, that is able to understand prompts describing multiple objects in various contexts and captures these relevant details in the images it generates. It is available in US East (N. Virginia) and US West (Oregon) AWS Regions and can perform advanced image […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-your-amazon-titan-image-generator-g1-model-using-amazon-bedrock-model-customization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a receipt and invoice processing pipeline with Amazon Textract</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2024/26_03_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s business landscape, organizations are constantly seeking ways to optimize their financial processes, enhance efficiency, and drive cost savings. One area that holds significant potential for improvement is accounts payable. On a high level, the accounts payable process includes receiving and scanning invoices, extraction of the relevant data from scanned invoices, validation, approval, and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-receipt-and-invoice-processing-pipeline-with-amazon-textract/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
