<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:20:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhance video understanding with Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and open-set object detection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In real-world video and image analysis, businesses often face the challenge of detecting objects that weren’t part of a model’s original training set. This becomes especially difficult in dynamic environments where new, unknown, or user-defined objects frequently appear. In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock Data Automation uses OSOD to enhance video understanding.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-video-understanding-with-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-open-set-object-detection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Skello uses Amazon Bedrock to query data in a multi-tenant environment while keeping logical boundaries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Skello is a leading human resources (HR) software as a service (SaaS) solution focusing on employee scheduling and workforce management. Catering to diverse sectors such as hospitality, retail, healthcare, construction, and industry, Skello offers features including schedule creation, time tracking, and payroll preparation. We dive deep into the challenges of implementing large language models (LLMs) for data querying, particularly in the context of a French company operating under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a private workforce on Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth with the AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a complete solution for programmatically creating private workforces on Amazon SageMaker AI using the AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), including the setup of a dedicated, fully configured Amazon Cognito user pool.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-private-workforce-on-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-with-the-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TII Falcon-H1 models now available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of the Technology Innovation Institute (TII)’s Falcon-H1 models on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, developers and data scientists can now use six instruction-tuned Falcon-H1 models (0.5B, 1.5B, 1.5B-Deep, 3B, 7B, and 34B) on AWS, and have access to a comprehensive suite of hybrid architecture models that combine traditional attention mechanisms with State Space Models (SSMs) to deliver exceptional performance with unprecedented efficiency.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oldcastle accelerates document processing with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Oldcastle partnered with AWS to transform their document processing workflow using Amazon Bedrock with Amazon Textract. We discuss how Oldcastle overcame the limitations of their previous OCR solution to automate the processing of hundreds of thousands of POD documents each month, dramatically improving accuracy while reducing manual effort.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/oldcastle-accelerates-document-processing-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How London Stock Exchange Group is detecting market abuse with their AI-powered Surveillance Guide on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how London Stock Exchange Group (LSEG) used Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic&#39;s Claude foundation models to build an automated system that significantly improves the efficiency and accuracy of market surveillance operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-london-stock-exchange-group-is-detecting-market-abuse-with-their-ai-powered-surveillance-guide-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build trustworthy AI agents with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Observability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_09_2025/10_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through implementation options for both agents hosted on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime and agents hosted on other services like Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2), Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), AWS Lambda, or alternative cloud providers. We also share best practices for incorporating observability throughout the development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-trustworthy-ai-agents-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-observability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering innovation at scale: How AWS is tackling AI infrastructure challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative AI continues to transform how enterprises operate—and develop net new innovations—the infrastructure demands for training and deploying AI models have grown exponentially. Traditional infrastructure approaches are struggling to keep pace with today’s computational requirements, network demands, and resilience needs of modern AI workloads. At AWS, we’re also seeing a transformation across the technology […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/powering-innovation-at-scale-how-aws-is-tackling-ai-infrastructure-challenges/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your model training with managed tiered checkpointing on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_09_2025/09_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS announced managed tiered checkpointing in Amazon SageMaker HyperPod, a purpose-built infrastructure to scale and accelerate generative AI model development across thousands of AI accelerators. Managed tiered checkpointing uses CPU memory for high-performance checkpoint storage with automatic data replication across adjacent compute nodes for enhanced reliability. In this post, we dive deep into those concepts and understand how to use the managed tiered checkpointing feature.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-your-model-training-with-managed-tiered-checkpointing-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize HyperPod Cluster utilization with HyperPod task governance fine-grained quota allocation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the general availability of fine-grained compute and memory quota allocation with HyperPod task governance. With this capability, customers can optimize Amazon SageMaker HyperPod cluster utilization on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), distribute fair usage, and support efficient resource allocation across different teams or projects. For more information, see HyperPod task governance best […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maximize-hyperpod-cluster-utilization-with-hyperpod-task-governance-fine-grained-quota-allocation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and scale adoption of AI agents for education with Strands Agents, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and LibreChat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to quickly build sophisticated AI agents using Strands Agents, scale them reliably with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and make them accessible through LibreChat’s familiar interface to drive immediate user adoption across your institution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-and-scale-adoption-of-ai-agents-for-education-with-strands-agents-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-and-librechat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skai uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to significantly improve customer insights by revolutionized data access and analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Skai (formerly Kenshoo) is an AI-driven omnichannel advertising and analytics platform designed for brands and agencies to plan, launch, optimize, and measure paid media across search, social, retail media marketplaces and other “walled-garden” channels from a single interface. In this post, we share how Skai used Amazon Bedrock Agents to improve data access and analysis and improve customer insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/skai-uses-amazon-bedrock-agents-to-significantly-improve-customer-insights-by-revolutionized-data-access-and-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of AI in driving personalized product discovery at Snoonu</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Snoonu, a leading ecommerce platform in the Middle East, transformed their product discovery experience using AI-powered personalization. In this post, we share how Snoonu, a leading ecommerce platform in the Middle East, transformed their product discovery experience using AI-powered personalization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-power-of-ai-in-driving-personalized-product-discovery-at-snoonu/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating HPC and AI research in universities with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how a research university implemented SageMaker HyperPod to accelerate AI research by using dynamic SLURM partitions, fine-grained GPU resource management, budget-aware compute cost tracking, and multi-login node load balancing—all integrated seamlessly into the SageMaker HyperPod environment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-hpc-and-ai-research-in-universities-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Real-Time Race Track with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the Real-Time Race Track (RTRT), an interactive experience built using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock, that lets fans design, customize, and share their own racing circuits. We highlight how generative AI capabilities come together to deliver strategic racing insights such as pit timing and tire choices, and interactive features like an AI voice assistant and a retro-style racing poster.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/exploring-the-real-time-race-track-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build character consistent storyboards using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we take an animated short film, Picchu, produced by FuzzyPixel from Amazon Web Services (AWS), prepare training data by extracting key character frames, and fine-tune a character-consistent model for the main character Mayu and her mother, so we can quickly generate storyboard concepts for new sequels like the following images.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-character-consistent-storyboards-using-amazon-nova-in-amazon-bedrock-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build character consistent storyboards using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The art of storyboarding stands as the cornerstone of modern content creation, weaving its essential role through filmmaking, animation, advertising, and UX design. Though traditionally, creators have relied on hand-drawn sequential illustrations to map their narratives, today’s AI foundation models (FMs) are transforming this landscape. FMs like Amazon Nova Canvas and Amazon Nova Reel offer […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-character-consistent-storyboards-using-amazon-nova-in-amazon-bedrock-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
