<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:27:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Amazon SageMaker Projects with Terraform Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post you define, deploy, and provision a SageMaker Project custom template purely in Terraform. With no dependencies on other IaC tools, you can now enable SageMaker Projects strictly within your Terraform Enterprise infrastructure.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-amazon-sagemaker-projects-with-terraform-cloud/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How ZURU improved the accuracy of floor plan generation by 109% using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ZURU collaborated with AWS Generative AI Innovation Center and AWS Professional Services to implement a more accurate text-to-floor plan generator using generative AI. In this post, we show you why a solution using a large language model (LLM) was chosen. We explore how model selection, prompt engineering, and fine-tuning can be used to improve results.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-zuru-improved-the-accuracy-of-floor-plan-generation-by-109-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going beyond AI assistants: Examples from Amazon.com reinventing industries with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Non-conversational applications offer unique advantages such as higher latency tolerance, batch processing, and caching, but their autonomous nature requires stronger guardrails and exhaustive quality assurance compared to conversational applications, which benefit from real-time user feedback and supervision. This post examines four diverse Amazon.com examples of such generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/going-beyond-ai-assistants-examples-from-amazon-com-reinventing-industries-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architect a mature generative AI foundation on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we give an overview of a well-established generative AI foundation, dive into its components, and present an end-to-end perspective. We look at different operating models and explore how such a foundation can operate within those boundaries. Lastly, we present a maturity model that helps enterprises assess their evolution path.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/architect-a-mature-generative-ai-foundation-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon OpenSearch ML connector APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 15:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            OpenSearch offers a wide range of third-party machine learning (ML) connectors to support this augmentation. This post highlights two of these third-party ML connectors. The first connector we demonstrate is the Amazon Comprehend connector. In this post, we show you how to use this connector to invoke the LangDetect API to detect the languages of ingested documents. The second connector we demonstrate is the Amazon Bedrock connector to invoke the Amazon Titan Text Embeddings v2 model so that you can create embeddings from ingested documents and perform semantic search.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the gap between development and production: Seamless model lifecycle management with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 15:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Model Copy and Model Share features provide a powerful option for managing the lifecycle of an AI application from development to production. In this comprehensive blog post, we&#39;ll dive deep into the Model Share and Model Copy features, exploring their functionalities, benefits, and practical applications in a typical development-to-production scenario.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bridging-the-gap-between-development-and-production-seamless-model-lifecycle-management-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing earth observation with geospatial foundation models on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 21:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how a leading GeoFM (Clay Foundation’s Clay foundation model available on Hugging Face) can be deployed for large-scale inference and fine-tuning on Amazon SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-earth-observation-with-geospatial-foundation-models-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an agentic RAG application for advanced knowledge discovery with LlamaIndex, and Mistral in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 20:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate an example of building an agentic RAG application using the LlamaIndex framework. LlamaIndex is a framework that connects FMs with external data sources. It helps ingest, structure, and retrieve information from databases, APIs, PDFs, and more, enabling the agent and RAG for AI applications. This application serves as a research tool, using the Mistral Large 2 FM on Amazon Bedrock generate responses for the agent flow.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text-to-image basics with Amazon Nova Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 19:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus on the Amazon Nova Canvas image generation model. We then provide an overview of the image generation process (diffusion) and dive deep into the input parameters for text-to-image generation with Amazon Nova Canvas.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/text-to-image-basics-with-amazon-nova-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-world applications of Amazon Nova Canvas for interior design and product photography</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 19:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Nova Canvas can solve real-world business challenges through advanced image generation techniques. We focus on two specific use cases that demonstrate the power and flexibility of this technology: interior design and product photography.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/real-world-applications-of-amazon-nova-canvas-for-interior-design-and-product-photography/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Building an AI-powered assistant for investment research with multi-agent collaboration in Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 18:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how to build a multi-agent investment research assistant using the multi-agent collaboration capability of Amazon Bedrock. Our solution demonstrates how a team of specialized AI agents can work together to analyze financial news, evaluate stock performance, optimize portfolio allocations, and deliver comprehensive investment insights—all orchestrated through a unified, natural language interface.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/part-3-building-an-ai-powered-assistant-for-investment-research-with-multi-agent-collaboration-in-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-bedrock-data-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A generative AI prototype with Amazon Bedrock transforms life sciences and the genome analysis process</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 18:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores deploying a text-to-SQL pipeline using generative AI models and Amazon Bedrock to ask natural language questions to a genomics database. We demonstrate how to implement an AI assistant web interface with AWS Amplify and explain the prompt engineering strategies adopted to generate the SQL queries. Finally, we present instructions to deploy the service in your own AWS account.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-generative-ai-prototype-with-amazon-bedrock-transforms-life-sciences-and-the-genome-analysis-process/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemma 3 27B model now available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 18:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of Gemma 3 27B Instruct models through Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. In this post, we show you how to get started with Gemma 3 27B Instruct on both Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and SageMaker JumpStart, and how to use the model’s powerful instruction-following capabilities in your applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/gemma-3-27b-model-now-available-on-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a multimodal RAG based application using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 16:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through building a full-stack application that processes multimodal content using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation, stores the extracted information in an Amazon Bedrock knowledge base, and enables natural language querying through a RAG-based Q&amp;amp;A interface.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-multimodal-rag-based-application-using-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring foundation models for your business needs: A comprehensive guide to RAG, fine-tuning, and hybrid approaches</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 16:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to implement and evaluate three powerful techniques for tailoring FMs to your business needs: RAG, fine-tuning, and a hybrid approach combining both methods. We provid ready-to-use code to help you experiment with these approaches and make informed decisions based on your specific use case and dataset.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/tailoring-foundation-models-for-your-business-needs-a-comprehensive-guide-to-rag-fine-tuning-and-hybrid-approaches/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rufus doubled their inference speed and handled Prime Day traffic with AWS AI chips and parallel decoding</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Rufus, an AI-powered shopping assistant, relies on many components to deliver its customer experience including a foundation LLM (for response generation) and a query planner (QP) model for query classification and retrieval enhancement. This post focuses on how the QP model used draft centric speculative decoding (SD)—also called parallel decoding—with AWS AI chips to meet the demands of Prime Day. By combining parallel decoding with AWS Trainium and Inferentia chips, Rufus achieved two times faster response times, a 50% reduction in inference costs, and seamless scalability during peak traffic.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Amazon Bedrock Data Automation capabilities streamline video and audio analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 20:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Data Automation helps organizations streamline development and boost efficiency through customizable, multimodal analytics. It eliminates the heavy lifting of unstructured content processing at scale, whether for video or audio. The new capabilities make it faster to extract tailored, generative AI-powered insights like scene summaries, key topics, and customer intents from video and audio. This unlocks the value of unstructured content for use cases such as improving sales productivity and enhancing customer experience.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GuardianGamer scales family-safe cloud gaming with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 16:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how GuardianGamer uses AWS services including Amazon Nova and Amazon Bedrock to deliver a scalable and efficient supervision platform. The team uses Amazon Nova for intelligent narrative generation to provide parents with meaningful insights into their children’s gaming activities and social interactions, while maintaining a non-intrusive approach to monitoring.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/guardiangamer-scales-family-safe-cloud-gaming-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principal Financial Group increases Voice Virtual Assistant performance using Genesys, Amazon Lex, and Amazon QuickSight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 16:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Principal used this opportunity to build an integrated voice VA reporting and analytics solution using an Amazon QuickSight dashboard.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/principal-financial-group-increases-voice-virtual-assistant-performance-using-genesys-amazon-lex-and-amazon-quicksight/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
