<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:34:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon uses Amazon Nova models to automate operational readiness testing for new fulfillment centers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock can be used to implement an AI-powered image recognition solution that automates the detection and validation of module components, significantly reducing manual verification efforts and improving accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-uses-amazon-nova-models-to-automate-operational-readiness-testing-for-new-fulfillment-centers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iberdrola enhances IT operations using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Iberdrola, one of the world’s largest utility companies, has embraced cutting-edge AI technology to revolutionize its IT operations in ServiceNow. Through its partnership with AWS, Iberdrola implemented different agentic architectures using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, targeting three key areas: optimizing change request validation in the draft phase, enriching incident management with contextual intelligence, and simplifying change model selection using conversational AI. These innovations reduce bottlenecks, help teams accelerate ticket resolution, and deliver consistent and high-quality data handling throughout the organization.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building real-time voice assistants with Amazon Nova Sonic compared to cascading architectures</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Nova Sonic delivers real-time, human-like voice conversations through the bidirectional streaming interface. In this post, you learn how Amazon Nova Sonic can solve some of the challenges faced by cascaded approaches, simplify building voice AI agents, and provide natural conversational capabilities. We also provide guidance on when to choose each approach to help you make informed decisions for your voice AI projects.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-real-time-voice-assistants-with-amazon-nova-sonic-compared-to-cascading-architectures/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot reference implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post dives deeper into the implementation architecture for the Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automated-reasoning-checks-rewriting-chatbot-reference-implementation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale LLM fine-tuning with Hugging Face and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how this integrated approach transforms enterprise LLM fine-tuning from a complex, resource-intensive challenge into a streamlined, scalable solution for achieving better model performance in domain-specific applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-llm-fine-tuning-with-hugging-face-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Relic transforms productivity with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Working with the Generative AI Innovation Center, New Relic NOVA (New Relic Omnipresence Virtual Assistant) evolved from a knowledge assistant into a comprehensive productivity engine. We explore the technical architecture, development journey, and key lessons learned in building an enterprise-grade AI solution that delivers measurable productivity gains at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-relic-transforms-productivity-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate agentic application development with a full-stack starter template for Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to deploy Fullstack AgentCore Solution Template (FAST) to your Amazon Web Services (AWS) account, understand its architecture, and see how to extend it for your requirements. You will learn how to build your own agent while FAST handles authentication, infrastructure as code (IaC), deployment pipelines, and service integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-agentic-application-development-with-a-full-stack-starter-template-for-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent-to-agent collaboration: Using Amazon Nova 2 Lite and Amazon Nova Act for multi-agent systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how agent-to-agent collaboration on Amazon Bedrock works in practice, using Amazon Nova 2 Lite for planning and Amazon Nova Act for browser interaction, to turn a fragile single-agent setup into a predictable multi-agent system.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/agent-to-agent-collaboration-using-amazon-nova-2-lite-and-amazon-nova-act-for-multi-agent-systems/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured outputs on Amazon Bedrock: Schema-compliant AI responses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re announcing structured outputs on Amazon Bedrock—a capability that fundamentally transforms how you can obtain validated JSON responses from foundation models through constrained decoding for schema compliance. In this post, we explore the challenges of traditional JSON generation and how structured outputs solves them. We cover the two core mechanisms—JSON Schema output format and strict tool use—along with implementation details, best practices, and practical code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Amazon SageMaker HyperPod clusters using the HyperPod CLI and SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use the CLI and the SDK to create and manage SageMaker HyperPod clusters in your AWS account. We walk through a practical example and dive deeper into the user workflow and parameter choices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-clusters-using-the-hyperpod-cli-and-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate generative AI models with an Amazon Nova rubric-based LLM judge on Amazon SageMaker AI (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the Amazon Nova rubric-based judge feature: what a rubric-based judge is, how the judge is trained, what metrics to consider, and how to calibrate the judge. We chare notebook code of the Amazon Nova rubric-based LLM-as-a-judge methodology to evaluate and compare the outputs of two different LLMs using SageMaker training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-generative-ai-models-with-an-amazon-nova-rubric-based-llm-judge-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Associa transforms document classification with the GenAI IDP Accelerator and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Associa collaborated with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to build a generative AI-powered document classification system aligning with Associa’s long-term vision of using generative AI to achieve operational efficiencies in document management. The solution automatically categorizes incoming documents with high accuracy, processes documents efficiently, and provides substantial cost savings while maintaining operational excellence. The document classification system, developed using the Generative AI Intelligent Document Processing (GenAI IDP) Accelerator, is designed to integrate seamlessly into existing workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practical guide to Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2026/05_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to configure and use Amazon Nova Multimodal Embeddings for media asset search systems, product discovery experiences, and document retrieval applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-practical-guide-to-amazon-nova-multimodal-embeddings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating your marketing ideation with generative AI – Part 2: Generate custom marketing images from historical references</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building upon our earlier work of marketing campaign image generation using Amazon Nova foundation models, in this post, we demonstrate how to enhance image generation by learning from previous marketing campaigns. We explore how to integrate Amazon Bedrock, AWS Lambda, and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless to create an advanced image generation system that uses reference campaigns to maintain brand guidelines, deliver consistent content, and enhance the effectiveness and efficiency of new campaign creation.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratizing business intelligence: BGL’s journey with Claude Agent SDK and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BGL is a leading provider of self-managed superannuation fund (SMSF) administration solutions that help individuals manage the complex compliance and reporting of their own or a client’s retirement savings, serving over 12,700 businesses across 15 countries. In this blog post, we explore how BGL built its production-ready AI agent using Claude Agent SDK and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/democratizing-business-intelligence-bgls-journey-with-claude-agent-sdk-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon Quick Suite custom action connectors to upload text files to Google Drive using OpenAPI specification</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a secure file upload solution by integrating Google Drive with Amazon Quick Suite custom connectors using Amazon API Gateway and AWS Lambda.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-quick-suite-custom-action-connectors-to-upload-text-files-to-google-drive-using-openapi-specification/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI agents in enterprises: Best practices with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores nine essential best practices for building enterprise AI agents using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore. Amazon Bedrock AgentCore is an agentic platform that provides the services you need to create, deploy, and manage AI agents at scale. In this post, we cover everything from initial scoping to organizational scaling, with practical guidance that you can apply immediately.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-agents-in-enterprises-best-practices-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI for healthcare data analysis with Amazon SageMaker Data Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 21, 2025, Amazon SageMaker introduced a built-in data agent within Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio that transforms large-scale data analysis. In this post, we demonstrate, through a detailed case study of an epidemiologist conducting clinical cohort analysis, how SageMaker Data Agent can help reduce weeks of data preparation into days, and days of analysis development into hours—ultimately accelerating the path from clinical questions to research conclusions.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
