<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:57:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customize AI agent browsing with proxies, profiles, and extensions in Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_02_2026/13_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are announcing three new capabilities that address these requirements: proxy configuration, browser profiles, and browser extensions. Together, these features give you fine-grained control over how your AI agents interact with the web. This post will walk through each capability with configuration examples and practical use cases to help you get started.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/customize-ai-agent-browsing-with-proxies-profiles-and-extensions-in-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-browser/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI meets HR: Transforming talent acquisition with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to create an AI-powered recruitment system using Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, AWS Lambda, and other AWS services to enhance job description creation, candidate communication, and interview preparation while maintaining human oversight.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-meets-hr-transforming-talent-acquisition-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build long-running MCP servers on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore with Strands Agents integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_02_2026/12_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide you with a comprehensive approach to achieve this. First, we introduce a context message strategy that maintains continuous communication between servers and clients during extended operations. Next, we develop an asynchronous task management framework that allows your AI agents to initiate long-running processes without blocking other operations. Finally, we demonstrate how to bring these strategies together with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Strands Agents to build production-ready AI agents that can handle complex, time-intensive operations reliably.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Nemotron 3 Nano 30B MoE model is now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to announce that the NVIDIA Nemotron 3 Nano 30B model with 3B active parameters is now generally available in the Amazon SageMaker JumpStart model catalog. You can accelerate innovation and deliver tangible business value with Nemotron 3 Nano on Amazon Web Services (AWS) without having to manage model deployment complexities. You can power your generative AI applications with Nemotron capabilities using the managed deployment capabilities offered by SageMaker JumpStart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Amazon Bedrock throttling and service availability: A comprehensive guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to implement robust error handling strategies that can help improve application reliability and user experience when using Amazon Bedrock. We&#39;ll dive deep into strategies for optimizing performances for the application with these errors. Whether this is for a fairly new application or matured AI application, in this post you will be able to find the practical guidelines to operate with on these errors.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swann provides Generative AI to millions of IoT Devices using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to implement intelligent notification filtering using Amazon Bedrock and its gen-AI capabilities. You&#39;ll learn model selection strategies, cost optimization techniques, and architectural patterns for deploying gen-AI at IoT scale, based on Swann Communications deployment across millions of devices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/swann-provides-generative-ai-to-millions-of-iot-devices-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How LinqAlpha assesses investment theses using Devil’s Advocate on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_02_2026/11_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LinqAlpha is a Boston-based multi-agent AI system built specifically for institutional investors. The system supports and streamlines agentic workflows across company screening, primer generation, stock price catalyst mapping, and now, pressure-testing investment ideas through a new AI agent called Devil’s Advocate. In this post, we share how LinqAlpha uses Amazon Bedrock to build and scale Devil’s Advocate.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-linqalpha-assesses-investment-theses-using-devils-advocate-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon uses Amazon Nova models to automate operational readiness testing for new fulfillment centers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock can be used to implement an AI-powered image recognition solution that automates the detection and validation of module components, significantly reducing manual verification efforts and improving accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-uses-amazon-nova-models-to-automate-operational-readiness-testing-for-new-fulfillment-centers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iberdrola enhances IT operations using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Iberdrola, one of the world’s largest utility companies, has embraced cutting-edge AI technology to revolutionize its IT operations in ServiceNow. Through its partnership with AWS, Iberdrola implemented different agentic architectures using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, targeting three key areas: optimizing change request validation in the draft phase, enriching incident management with contextual intelligence, and simplifying change model selection using conversational AI. These innovations reduce bottlenecks, help teams accelerate ticket resolution, and deliver consistent and high-quality data handling throughout the organization.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building real-time voice assistants with Amazon Nova Sonic compared to cascading architectures</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_02_2026/10_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Nova Sonic delivers real-time, human-like voice conversations through the bidirectional streaming interface. In this post, you learn how Amazon Nova Sonic can solve some of the challenges faced by cascaded approaches, simplify building voice AI agents, and provide natural conversational capabilities. We also provide guidance on when to choose each approach to help you make informed decisions for your voice AI projects.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-real-time-voice-assistants-with-amazon-nova-sonic-compared-to-cascading-architectures/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot reference implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post dives deeper into the implementation architecture for the Automated Reasoning checks rewriting chatbot.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automated-reasoning-checks-rewriting-chatbot-reference-implementation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale LLM fine-tuning with Hugging Face and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how this integrated approach transforms enterprise LLM fine-tuning from a complex, resource-intensive challenge into a streamlined, scalable solution for achieving better model performance in domain-specific applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-llm-fine-tuning-with-hugging-face-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Relic transforms productivity with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Working with the Generative AI Innovation Center, New Relic NOVA (New Relic Omnipresence Virtual Assistant) evolved from a knowledge assistant into a comprehensive productivity engine. We explore the technical architecture, development journey, and key lessons learned in building an enterprise-grade AI solution that delivers measurable productivity gains at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-relic-transforms-productivity-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate agentic application development with a full-stack starter template for Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to deploy Fullstack AgentCore Solution Template (FAST) to your Amazon Web Services (AWS) account, understand its architecture, and see how to extend it for your requirements. You will learn how to build your own agent while FAST handles authentication, infrastructure as code (IaC), deployment pipelines, and service integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-agentic-application-development-with-a-full-stack-starter-template-for-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent-to-agent collaboration: Using Amazon Nova 2 Lite and Amazon Nova Act for multi-agent systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_02_2026/09_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how agent-to-agent collaboration on Amazon Bedrock works in practice, using Amazon Nova 2 Lite for planning and Amazon Nova Act for browser interaction, to turn a fragile single-agent setup into a predictable multi-agent system.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/agent-to-agent-collaboration-using-amazon-nova-2-lite-and-amazon-nova-act-for-multi-agent-systems/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured outputs on Amazon Bedrock: Schema-compliant AI responses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re announcing structured outputs on Amazon Bedrock—a capability that fundamentally transforms how you can obtain validated JSON responses from foundation models through constrained decoding for schema compliance. In this post, we explore the challenges of traditional JSON generation and how structured outputs solves them. We cover the two core mechanisms—JSON Schema output format and strict tool use—along with implementation details, best practices, and practical code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Amazon SageMaker HyperPod clusters using the HyperPod CLI and SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use the CLI and the SDK to create and manage SageMaker HyperPod clusters in your AWS account. We walk through a practical example and dive deeper into the user workflow and parameter choices.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-clusters-using-the-hyperpod-cli-and-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate generative AI models with an Amazon Nova rubric-based LLM judge on Amazon SageMaker AI (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_02_2026/06_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the Amazon Nova rubric-based judge feature: what a rubric-based judge is, how the judge is trained, what metrics to consider, and how to calibrate the judge. We chare notebook code of the Amazon Nova rubric-based LLM-as-a-judge methodology to evaluate and compare the outputs of two different LLMs using SageMaker training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-generative-ai-models-with-an-amazon-nova-rubric-based-llm-judge-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
