<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:29:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrate MLflow tracking servers to Amazon SageMaker AI with serverless MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to migrate your self-managed MLflow tracking server to a MLflow App – a serverless tracking server on SageMaker AI that automatically scales resources based on demand while removing server patching and storage management tasks at no cost. Learn how to use the MLflow Export Import tool to transfer your experiments, runs, models, and other MLflow resources, including instructions to validate your migration&#39;s success.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI-powered website assistant with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_12_2025/29_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to solve this challenge by building an AI-powered website assistant using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ai-powered-website-assistant-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmatically creating an IDP solution with Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to programmatically create an IDP solution that uses Strands SDK, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Base, and Bedrock Data Automation (BDA). This solution is provided through a Jupyter notebook that enables users to upload multi-modal business documents and extract insights using BDA as a parser to retrieve relevant chunks and augment a prompt to a foundational model (FM).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/programmatically-creating-an-idp-solution-with-amazon-bedrock-data-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI agent-driven browser automation for enterprise workflow management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Enterprise organizations increasingly rely on web-based applications for critical business processes, yet many workflows remain manually intensive, creating operational inefficiencies and compliance risks. Despite significant technology investments, knowledge workers routinely navigate between eight to twelve different web applications during standard workflows, constantly switching contexts and manually transferring information between systems. Data entry and validation tasks […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-agent-driven-browser-automation-for-enterprise-workflow-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic QA automation using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser and Amazon Nova Act</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how agentic QA automation addresses these challenges and walk through a practical example using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser and Amazon Nova Act to automate testing for a sample retail application.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/agentic-qa-automation-using-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-browser-and-amazon-nova-act/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing LLM inference on Amazon SageMaker AI with BentoML’s LLM- Optimizer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_12_2025/24_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to optimize large language model (LLM) inference on Amazon SageMaker AI using BentoML&#39;s LLM-Optimizer to systematically identify the best serving configurations for your workload.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-llm-inference-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-with-bentomls-llm-optimizer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
