<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:53:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate document processing with Amazon Bedrock Prompt Flows (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to build an IDP pipeline for automatically extracting and processing data from documents using Amazon Bedrock Prompt Flows, a fully managed service that enables you to build generative AI workflow using Amazon Bedrock and other services in an intuitive visual builder. Amazon Bedrock Prompt Flows allows you to quickly update your pipelines as your business changes, scaling your document processing workflows to help meet evolving demands.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governing the ML lifecycle at scale: Centralized observability with Amazon SageMaker and Amazon CloudWatch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2024/29_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is part of an ongoing series on governing the machine learning (ML) lifecycle at scale. To start from the beginning, refer to Governing the ML lifecycle at scale, Part 1: A framework for architecting ML workloads using Amazon SageMaker. A multi-account strategy is essential not only for improving governance but also for enhancing […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/governing-the-ml-lifecycle-at-scale-centralized-observability-with-amazon-sagemaker-and-amazon-cloudwatch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import data from Google Cloud Platform BigQuery for no-code machine learning with Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 18:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents an architectural approach to extract data from different cloud environments, such as Google Cloud Platform (GCP) BigQuery, without the need for data movement. This minimizes the complexity and overhead associated with moving data between cloud environments, enabling organizations to access and utilize their disparate data assets for ML projects. We highlight the process of using Amazon Athena Federated Query to extract data from GCP BigQuery, using Amazon SageMaker Data Wrangler to perform data preparation, and then using the prepared data to build ML models within Amazon SageMaker Canvas, a no-code ML interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized model monitoring for near real-time batch inference with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 17:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2024/28_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a framework to customize the use of Amazon SageMaker Model Monitor for handling multi-payload inference requests for near real-time inference scenarios. SageMaker Model Monitor monitors the quality of SageMaker ML models in production. Early and proactive detection of deviations in model quality enables you to take corrective actions, such as retraining models, auditing upstream systems, or fixing quality issues without having to monitor models manually or build additional tooling.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Planview built a scalable AI Assistant for portfolio and project management using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 16:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_10_2024/25_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Planview was able to develop a generative AI assistant to address complex work management process by adopting Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-planview-built-a-scalable-ai-assistant-for-portfolio-and-project-management-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super charge your LLMs with RAG at scale using AWS Glue for Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 18:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will explore building a reusable RAG data pipeline on LangChain—an open source framework for building applications based on LLMs—and integrating it with AWS Glue and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless. The end solution is a reference architecture for scalable RAG indexing and deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/super-charge-your-llms-with-rag-at-scale-using-aws-glue-for-apache-spark/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From RAG to fabric: Lessons learned from building real-world RAGs at GenAIIC – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 18:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we cover the core concepts behind RAG architectures and discuss strategies for evaluating RAG performance, both quantitatively through metrics and qualitatively by analyzing individual outputs. We outline several practical tips for improving text retrieval, including using hybrid search techniques, enhancing context through data preprocessing, and rewriting queries for better relevance.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/from-rag-to-fabric-lessons-learned-from-building-real-world-rags-at-genaiic-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance your Amazon Redshift cloud data warehouse with easier, simpler, and faster machine learning using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 17:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into a business use case for a banking institution. We will show you how a financial or business analyst at a bank can easily predict if a customer’s loan will be fully paid, charged off, or current using a machine learning model that is best for the business problem at hand.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-your-amazon-redshift-cloud-data-warehouse-with-easier-simpler-and-faster-machine-learning-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a generative AI-based application builder assistant using Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 17:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agentic workflows are a fresh new perspective in building dynamic and complex business use- case based workflows with the help of large language models (LLM) as their reasoning engine or brain. In this post, we set up an agent using Amazon Bedrock Agents to act as a software application builder assistant.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-generative-ai-based-application-builder-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from Amazon Rekognition people pathing: Exploring other alternatives</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 16:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2024/24_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After careful consideration, we made the decision to discontinue Rekognition people pathing on October 31, 2025. New customers will not be able to access the capability effective October 24, 2024, but existing customers will be able to use the capability as normal until October 31, 2025. This post discusses an alternative solution to Rekognition people pathing and how you can implement this solution in your applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transitioning-from-amazon-rekognition-people-pathing-exploring-other-alternatives/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking generative AI for enterprises: How SnapLogic powers their low-code Agent Creator using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we learn how SnapLogic&#39;s Agent Creator leverages Amazon Bedrock to provide a low-code platform that enables enterprises to quickly develop and deploy powerful generative AI applications without deep technical expertise.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-generative-ai-for-enterprises-how-snaplogic-powers-their-low-code-agent-creator-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-generation learning experience using Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude: Innovation from Classworks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 19:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how Classworks uses Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet to deliver next-generation differentiated learning with Wittly.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/next-generation-learning-experience-using-amazon-bedrock-and-anthropics-claude-innovation-from-classworks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune a BGE embedding model using synthetic data from Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 19:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock to create synthetic data, fine-tune a BAAI General Embeddings (BGE) model, and deploy it using Amazon SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-a-bge-embedding-model-using-synthetic-data-from-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost post-call analytics with Amazon Q in QuickSight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 18:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to unlock powerful post-call analytics and visualizations, empowering your organization to make data-driven decisions and drive continuous improvement.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-post-call-analytics-with-amazon-q-in-quicksight/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a next generation chat assistant with Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Connect, Amazon Lex, LangChain, and WhatsApp</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 18:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2024/23_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy a contextual AI assistant. We build a solution which provides users with a familiar and convenient interface using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Lex, and Amazon Connect, with WhatsApp as the channel.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-next-generation-chat-assistant-with-amazon-bedrock-amazon-connect-amazon-lex-langchain-and-whatsapp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI foundation model training on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how organizations can cost-effectively customize and adapt FMs using AWS managed services such as Amazon SageMaker training jobs and Amazon SageMaker HyperPod. We discuss how these powerful tools enable organizations to optimize compute resources and reduce the complexity of model training and fine-tuning. We explore how you can make an informed decision about which Amazon SageMaker service is most applicable to your business needs and requirements.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate fine-tuning of Llama 3.x models with the new visual designer for Amazon SageMaker Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will show you how to set up an automated LLM customization (fine-tuning) workflow so that the Llama 3.x models from Meta can provide a high-quality summary of SEC filings for financial applications. Fine-tuning allows you to configure LLMs to achieve improved performance on your domain-specific tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-fine-tuning-of-llama-3-x-models-with-the-new-visual-designer-for-amazon-sagemaker-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement Amazon SageMaker domain cross-Region disaster recovery using custom Amazon EFS instances</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2024/22_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we guide you through a step-by-step process to seamlessly migrate and safeguard your SageMaker domain from one active Region to another passive or active Region, including all associated user profiles and files.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-amazon-sagemaker-domain-cross-region-disaster-recovery-using-custom-amazon-efs-instances/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
