<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simplify access control and auditing for Amazon SageMaker Studio using trusted identity propagation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to enable and use trusted identity propagation in Amazon SageMaker Studio, which allows organizations to simplify access management by granting permissions to existing AWS IAM Identity Center identities. The solution demonstrates how to implement fine-grained access controls based on a physical user&#39;s identity, maintain detailed audit logs across supported AWS services, and support long-running user background sessions for training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simplify-access-control-and-auditing-for-amazon-sagemaker-studio-using-trusted-identity-propagation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking document information localization with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock, specifically Amazon Nova Pro, to achieve high-accuracy document field localization while dramatically simplifying implementation. We show how these models can precisely locate and interpret document fields with minimal frontend effort, reducing processing errors and manual intervention.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/benchmarking-document-information-localization-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Infosys built a generative AI solution to process oil and gas drilling data with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We built an advanced RAG solution using Amazon Bedrock leveraging Infosys Topaz™ AI capabilities, tailored for the oil and gas sector. This solution excels in handling multimodal data sources, seamlessly processing text, diagrams, and numerical data while maintaining context and relationships between different data elements. In this post, we provide insights on the solution and walk you through different approaches and architecture patterns explored, like different chunking, multi-vector retrieval, and hybrid search during the development.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline employee training with an intelligent chatbot powered by Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to design and implement custom plugins for Amazon Q Business to create an intelligent chatbot that streamlines employee training by retrieving answers from training materials. The solution implements secure API access using Amazon Cognito for user authentication and authorization, processes multiple document formats, and includes features like RAG-enhanced responses and email escalation capabilities through custom plugins.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-employee-training-with-an-intelligent-chatbot-powered-by-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a travel planning agentic workflow with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 20:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a travel planning solution using AI agents. The agent uses Amazon Nova, which offers an optimal balance of performance and cost compared to other commercial LLMs. By combining accurate but cost-efficient Amazon Nova models with LangGraph orchestration capabilities, we create a practical travel assistant that can handle complex planning tasks while keeping operational costs manageable for production deployments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-travel-planning-agentic-workflow-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway: Transforming enterprise AI agent tool development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, a fully managed service that revolutionizes how enterprises connect AI agents with tools and services by providing a centralized tool server with unified interface for agent-tool communication. The service offers key capabilities including Security Guard, Translation, Composition, Target extensibility, Infrastructure Manager, and Semantic Tool Selection, while implementing sophisticated dual-sided security architecture for both inbound and outbound connections.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway-transforming-enterprise-ai-agent-tool-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a scalable containerized web application on AWS using the MERN stack with Amazon Q Developer – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a traditional SDLC, a lot of time is spent in the different phases researching approaches that can deliver on requirements: iterating over design changes, writing, testing and reviewing code, and configuring infrastructure. In this post, you learned about the experience and saw productivity gains you can realize by using Amazon Q Developer as a coding assistant to build a scalable MERN stack web application on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Salesforce’s model endpoints with Amazon SageMaker AI inference components</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how the Salesforce AI Platform team optimized GPU utilization, improved resource efficiency and achieved cost savings using Amazon SageMaker AI, specifically inference components.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-salesforces-model-endpoints-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-inference-components/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a RAG chat-based assistant on Amazon EKS Auto Mode and NVIDIA NIMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the implementation of a practical RAG chat-based assistant using a comprehensive stack of modern technologies. The solution uses NVIDIA NIMs for both LLM inference and text embedding services, with the NIM Operator handling their deployment and management. The architecture incorporates Amazon OpenSearch Serverless to store and query high-dimensional vector embeddings for similarity search.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-rag-chat-based-assistant-on-amazon-eks-auto-mode-and-nvidia-nims/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Identity: Securing agentic AI at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Identity, a comprehensive identity and access management service purpose-built for AI agents that enables secure access to AWS resources and third-party tools. The service provides robust identity management features including agent identity directory, agent authorizer, resource credential provider, and resource token vault to help organizations deploy AI agents securely at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-identity-securing-agentic-ai-at-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the blog post Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock, we demonstrated how to build a scalable IDP pipeline using Anthropic foundation models on Amazon Bedrock. Although that approach delivered robust performance, the introduction of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation brings a new level of efficiency and flexibility to IDP solutions. This post explores how Amazon Bedrock Data Automation enhances document processing capabilities and streamlines the automation journey.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiteboard to cloud in minutes using Amazon Q, Amazon Bedrock Data Automation, and Model Context Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share the Amazon Bedrock Data Automation Model Context Protocol (MCP) server, for seamless integration between Amazon Q and your enterprise data. In this post, you will learn how to use the Amazon Bedrock Data Automation MCP server to securely integrate with AWS Services, use Bedrock Data Automation operations as callable MCP tools, and build a conversational development experience with Amazon Q.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/whiteboard-to-cloud-in-minutes-using-amazon-q-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-model-context-protocol/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing agentic Retrieval Augmented Generation to Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how Amazon Q Business is transforming enterprise data interaction through Agentic Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bringing-agentic-retrieval-augmented-generation-to-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering students with disabilities: University Startups’ generative AI solution for personalized student pathways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            University Startups, headquartered in Bethesda, MD, was founded in 2020 to empower high school students to expand their education beyond a traditional curriculum. University Startups is focused on special education and related services in school districts throughout the US. In this post, we explain how University Startups uses generative AI technology on AWS to enable students to design a specific plan for their future either in education or the work force.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations with Amazon Nova understanding models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to prompt Amazon Nova understanding models to cite sources in responses. Further, we will also walk through how we can evaluate the responses (and citations) for accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/citations-with-amazon-nova-understanding-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securely launch and scale your agents and tools on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 21:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime simplifies the deployment and management of AI agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/securely-launch-and-scale-your-agents-and-tools-on-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PwC and AWS Build Responsible AI with Automated Reasoning on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 19:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents how AWS and PwC are developing new reasoning checks that combine deep industry expertise with Automated Reasoning checks in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails to support innovation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pwc-and-aws-build-responsible-ai-with-automated-reasoning-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon scaled Rufus by building multi-node inference using AWS Trainium chips and vLLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, Amazon shares how they developed a multi-node inference solution for Rufus, their generative AI shopping assistant, using Amazon Trainium chips and vLLM to serve large language models at scale. The solution combines a leader/follower orchestration model, hybrid parallelism strategies, and a multi-node inference unit abstraction layer built on Amazon ECS to deploy models across multiple nodes while maintaining high performance and reliability.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-scaled-rufus-by-building-multi-node-inference-using-aws-trainium-chips-and-vllm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent financial analysis agent with LangGraph and Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes an approach of combining three powerful technologies to illustrate an architecture that you can adapt and build upon for your specific financial analysis needs: LangGraph for workflow orchestration, Strands Agents for structured reasoning, and Model Context Protocol (MCP) for tool integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-financial-analysis-agent-with-langgraph-and-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory: Building context-aware agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory, a fully managed service that enables AI agents to maintain both immediate and long-term knowledge, transforming one-off conversations into continuous, evolving relationships between users and AI agents. The service eliminates complex memory infrastructure management while providing full control over what AI agents remember, offering powerful capabilities for maintaining both short-term working memory and long-term intelligent memory across sessions.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational natural language interface for Amazon Athena queries using Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore an innovative solution that uses Amazon Bedrock Agents, powered by Amazon Nova Lite, to create a conversational interface for Athena queries. We use AWS Cost and Usage Reports (AWS CUR) as an example, but this solution can be adapted for other databases you query using Athena. This approach democratizes data access while preserving the powerful analytical capabilities of Athena, so you can interact with your data using natural language.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
