<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 18:21:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic Claude</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 18:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to develop an IDP solution using Anthropic Claude 3 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock. We demonstrate how to extract data from a scanned document and insert it into a database.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/intelligent-document-processing-using-amazon-bedrock-and-anthropic-claude/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata filtering for tabular data with Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 18:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading artificial intelligence (AI) companies like AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Mistral AI, Stability AI, and Amazon through a single API. To equip FMs with up-to-date and proprietary information, organizations use Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), a technique that […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/metadata-filtering-for-tabular-data-with-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure AccountantAI Chatbot: Lili’s journey with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 16:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was written in collaboration with Liran Zelkha and Eyal Solnik from Lili. Small business proprietors tend to prioritize the operational aspects of their enterprises over administrative tasks, such as maintaining financial records and accounting. While hiring a professional accountant can provide valuable guidance and expertise, it can be cost-prohibitive for many small businesses. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/secure-accountantai-chatbot-lilis-journey-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Mend.io unlocked hidden patterns in CVE data with Anthropic Claude on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 16:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2024/18_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Maciej Mensfeld from Mend.io. In the ever-evolving landscape of cybersecurity, the ability to effectively analyze and categorize Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVEs) is crucial. This post explores how Mend.io, a cybersecurity firm, used Anthropic Claude on Amazon Bedrock to classify and identify CVEs containing specific attack requirements details. By using […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-mend-io-unlocked-hidden-patterns-in-cve-data-with-anthropic-claude-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Deloitte Italy built a digital payments fraud detection solution using quantum machine learning and Amazon Braket</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 16:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As digital commerce expands, fraud detection has become critical in protecting businesses and consumers engaging in online transactions. Implementing machine learning (ML) algorithms enables real-time analysis of high-volume transactional data to rapidly identify fraudulent activity. This advanced capability helps mitigate financial risks and safeguard customer privacy within expanding digital markets. Deloitte is a strategic global […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-deloitte-italy-built-a-digital-payments-fraud-detection-solution-using-quantum-machine-learning-and-amazon-braket/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker unveils the Cohere Command R fine-tuning model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS announced the availability of the Cohere Command R fine-tuning model on Amazon SageMaker. This latest addition to the SageMaker suite of machine learning (ML) capabilities empowers enterprises to harness the power of large language models (LLMs) and unlock their full potential for a wide range of applications. Cohere Command R is a scalable, frontier […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-unveils-the-cohere-command-r-fine-tuning-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derive meaningful and actionable operational insights from AWS Using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 16:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2024/17_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a customer, you rely on Amazon Web Services (AWS) expertise to be available and understand your specific environment and operations. Today, you might implement manual processes to summarize lessons learned, obtain recommendations, or expedite the resolution of an incident. This can be time consuming, inconsistent, and not readily accessible. This post shows how to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/derive-meaningful-and-actionable-operational-insights-from-aws-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your generative AI distributed training workloads with the NVIDIA NeMo Framework on Amazon EKS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 19:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s rapidly evolving landscape of artificial intelligence (AI), training large language models (LLMs) poses significant challenges. These models often require enormous computational resources and sophisticated infrastructure to handle the vast amounts of data and complex algorithms involved. Without a structured framework, the process can become prohibitively time-consuming, costly, and complex. Enterprises struggle with managing […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-your-generative-ai-distributed-training-workloads-with-the-nvidia-nemo-framework-on-amazon-eks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governing the ML lifecycle at scale, Part 2: Multi-account foundations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 17:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2024/16_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Your multi-account strategy is the core of your foundational environment on AWS. Design decisions around your multi-account environment are critical for operating securely at scale. Grouping your workloads strategically into multiple AWS accounts enables you to apply different controls across workloads, track cost and usage, reduce the impact of account limits, and mitigate the complexity […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/governing-the-ml-lifecycle-at-scale-part-2-multi-account-foundations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video auto-dubbing using Amazon Translate, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon Polly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 17:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with MagellanTV and Mission Cloud. Video dubbing, or content localization, is the process of replacing the original spoken language in a video with another language while synchronizing audio and video. Video dubbing has emerged as a key tool in breaking down linguistic barriers, enhancing viewer engagement, and expanding market reach. However, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/video-auto-dubbing-using-amazon-translate-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-polly/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Mixbook used generative AI to offer personalized photo book experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 16:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2024/15_07_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Years ago, Mixbook undertook a strategic initiative to transition their operational workloads to Amazon Web Services (AWS), a move that has continually yielded significant advantages. This pivotal decision has been instrumental in propelling them towards fulfilling their mission, ensuring their system operations are characterized by reliability, superior performance, and operational efficiency. In this post we show you how Mixbook used generative artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities in AWS to personalize their photo book experiences—a step towards their mission.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Agents for Amazon Bedrock to interactively generate infrastructure as code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how Agents for Amazon Bedrock can be used to generate customized, organization standards-compliant IaC scripts directly from uploaded architecture diagrams. This will help accelerate deployments, reduce errors, and ensure adherence to security guidelines.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-agents-for-amazon-bedrock-to-interactively-generate-infrastructure-as-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve RAG accuracy with fine-tuned embedding models on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use Amazon SageMaker to fine tune a Sentence Transformer embedding model and deploy it with an Amazon SageMaker Endpoint. The code from this post and more examples are available in the GitHub repo.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-rag-accuracy-with-fine-tuned-embedding-models-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BRIA AI used distributed training in Amazon SageMaker to train latent diffusion foundation models for commercial use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Bar Fingerman from BRIA AI. This post explains how BRIA AI trained BRIA AI 2.0, a high-resolution (1024×1024) text-to-image diffusion model, on a dataset comprising petabytes of licensed images quickly and economically. Amazon SageMaker training jobs and Amazon SageMaker distributed training libraries took on the undifferentiated heavy lifting associated with infrastructure […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-bria-ai-used-distributed-training-in-amazon-sagemaker-to-train-latent-diffusion-foundation-models-for-commercial-use/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create custom images for geospatial analysis with Amazon SageMaker Distribution in Amazon SageMaker Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to extend Amazon SageMaker Distribution with additional dependencies to create a custom container image tailored for geospatial analysis. Although the example in this post focuses on geospatial data science, the methodology presented can be applied to any kind of custom image based on SageMaker Distribution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-custom-images-for-geospatial-analysis-with-amazon-sagemaker-distribution-in-amazon-sagemaker-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating model customization in Amazon Bedrock with AWS Step Functions workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models have become indispensable in generating intelligent and nuanced responses across a wide variety of business use cases. However, enterprises often have unique data and use cases that require customizing large language models beyond their out-of-the-box capabilities. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automating-model-customization-in-amazon-bedrock-with-aws-step-functions-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock now supports advanced parsing, chunking, and query reformulation giving greater control of accuracy in RAG based applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2024/11_07_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that helps you implement the entire Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) workflow from ingestion to retrieval and prompt augmentation without having to build custom integrations to data sources and manage data flows, pushing the boundaries for what you can do in your RAG workflows. However, it’s […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-now-supports-advanced-parsing-chunking-and-query-reformulation-giving-greater-control-of-accuracy-in-rag-based-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
