<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:08:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Answer questions from tables embedded in documents with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2024/12_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business launched support for tabular search, which you can use to extract answers from tables embedded in documents ingested in Amazon Q Business. Tabular search is a built-in feature in Amazon Q Business that works seamlessly across many domains, with no setup required from admin or end users. In this post, we ingest different types of documents that have tables and show you how Amazon Q Business responds to questions related to the data in the tables.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AWS sales uses Amazon Q Business for customer engagement</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In April 2024, we launched our AI sales assistant, which we call Field Advisor, making it available to AWS employees in the Sales, Marketing, and Global Services organization, powered by Amazon Q Business. Since that time, thousands of active users have asked hundreds of thousands of questions through Field Advisor, which we have embedded in our customer relationship management (CRM) system, as well as through a Slack application.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights from your Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL database using the Amazon Q Business connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through configuring and integrating Amazon Q for Business with Aurora PostgreSQL-Compatible to enable your database administrators, data analysts, application developers, leadership, and other teams to quickly get accurate answers to their questions related to the content stored in Aurora PostgreSQL databases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-from-your-amazon-aurora-postgresql-database-using-the-amazon-q-business-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tealium built a chatbot evaluation platform with Ragas and Auto-Instruct using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate the importance of generative AI in the collaboration between Tealium and the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) team by automating the following: 1/ Evaluating the retriever and the generated answer of a RAG system based on the Ragas Repository powered by Amazon Bedrock, 2/ Generating improved instructions for each question-and-answer pair using an automatic prompt engineering technique based on the Auto-Instruct Repository. An instruction refers to a general direction or command given to the model to guide generation of a response.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EBSCOlearning scales assessment generation for their online learning content with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate how EBSCOlearning partnered with AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to use the power of generative AI in revolutionizing their learning assessment process. We explore the challenges faced in traditional question-answer (QA) generation and the innovative AI-driven solution developed to address them.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ebscolearning-scales-assessment-generation-for-their-online-learning-content-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixtral 12B is now available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Pixtral 12B (pixtral-12b-2409), a state-of-the-art vision language model (VLM) from Mistral AI that excels in both text-only and multimodal tasks, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. You can try this model with SageMaker JumpStart, a machine learning (ML) hub that provides access to algorithms and models that can be deployed with one click for running inference. In this post, we walk through how to discover, deploy, and use the Pixtral 12B model for a variety of real-world vision use cases.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to your slide deck using multimodal foundation models on Amazon Bedrock – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Parts 1 and 2 of this series, we explored ways to use the power of multimodal FMs such as Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings, Amazon Titan Text Embeddings, and Anthropic’s Claude 3 Sonnet. In this post, we compared the approaches from an accuracy and pricing perspective.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/talk-to-your-slide-deck-using-multimodal-foundation-models-on-amazon-bedrock-part-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate actions across enterprise applications using Amazon Q Business plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a generative AI-powered assistant that enhances employee productivity by solving problems, generating content, and providing insights across enterprise data sources. Beyond searching indexed third-party services, employees need access to dynamic, near real-time data such as stock prices, vacation balances, and location tracking, which is made possible through Amazon Q Business plugins. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-actions-across-enterprise-applications-using-amazon-q-business-plugins/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating ML experimentation with enhanced security: AWS PrivateLink support for Amazon SageMaker with MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With access to a wide range of generative AI foundation models (FM) and the ability to build and train their own machine learning (ML) models in Amazon SageMaker, users want a seamless and secure way to experiment with and select the models that deliver the most value for their business. In the initial stages of an ML […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-ml-experimentation-with-enhanced-security-aws-privatelink-support-for-amazon-sagemaker-with-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistral-NeMo-Instruct-2407 and Mistral-NeMo-Base-2407 are now available on SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Mistral-NeMo-Base-2407 and Mistral-NeMo-Instruct-2407 large language models from Mistral AI that excel at text generation, are available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. In this post, we walk through how to discover, deploy and use the Mistral-NeMo-Instruct-2407 and Mistral-NeMo-Base-2407 models for a variety of real-world use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mistral-nemo-instruct-2407-and-mistral-nemo-base-2407-are-now-available-on-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing AI trust with new responsible AI tools, capabilities, and resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 23:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With trust as a cornerstone of AI adoption, we are excited to announce at AWS re:Invent 2024 new responsible AI tools, capabilities, and resources that enhance the safety, security, and transparency of our AI services and models and help support customers’ own responsible AI journeys.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advancing-ai-trust-with-new-responsible-ai-tools-capabilities-and-resources/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy RAG applications on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart using FAISS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 21:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build a RAG application on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart using Facebook AI Similarity Search (FAISS).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-rag-applications-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-using-faiss/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up your cluster procurement time with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use Amazon SageMaker HyperPod training plans, to bring down your training cluster procurement wait time. We guide you through a step-by-step implementation on how you can use the (AWS CLI) or the AWS Management Console to find, review, and create optimal training plans for your specific compute and timeline needs. We further guide you through using the training plan to submit SageMaker training jobs or create SageMaker HyperPod clusters.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
