<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 14:52:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Streamline deep learning environments with Amazon Q Developer and MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 14:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q Developer and Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers to streamline DLC workflows to automate creation, execution, and customization of DLC containers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-deep-learning-environments-with-amazon-q-developer-and-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI-powered automated summarization system with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Transcribe using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces a serverless meeting summarization system that harnesses the advanced capabilities of Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Transcribe to transform audio recordings into concise, structured, and actionable summaries. By automating this process, organizations can reclaim countless hours while making sure key insights, action items, and decisions are systematically captured and made accessible to stakeholders.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ai-powered-automated-summarization-system-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-transcribe-using-terraform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyruus builds a generative AI provider matching solution on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Kyruus Health uses AWS services to build Guide. We show how Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed service that provides access to foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies and Amazon through a single API, and Amazon OpenSearch Service, a managed search and analytics service, work together to understand everyday language about health concerns and connect members with the right providers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/kyruus-builds-a-generative-ai-provider-matching-solution-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use generative AI in Amazon Bedrock for enhanced recommendation generation in equipment maintenance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the manufacturing world, valuable insights from service reports often remain underutilized in document storage systems. This post explores how Amazon Web Services (AWS) customers can build a solution that automates the digitisation and extraction of crucial information from many reports using generative AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-generative-ai-in-amazon-bedrock-for-enhanced-recommendation-generation-in-equipment-maintenance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build real-time travel recommendations using AI agents on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build a generative AI solution using Amazon Bedrock that creates bespoke holiday packages by combining customer profiles and preferences with real-time pricing data. We demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases for travel information, Amazon Bedrock Agents for real-time flight details, and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless for efficient package search and retrieval.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-real-time-travel-recommendations-using-ai-agents-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a full stack voice AI agent with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to create an AI-powered call center agent for a fictional company called AnyTelco. The agent, named Telly, can handle customer inquiries about plans and services while accessing real-time customer data using custom tools implemented with the Model Context Protocol (MCP) framework.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-a-full-stack-voice-ai-agent-with-amazon-nova-sonic/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage multi-tenant Amazon Bedrock costs using application inference profiles</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how to implement a robust monitoring solution for multi-tenant AI deployments using a feature of Amazon Bedrock called application inference profiles. We demonstrate how to create a system that enables granular usage tracking, accurate cost allocation, and dynamic resource management across complex multi-tenant environments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-multi-tenant-amazon-bedrock-costs-using-application-inference-profiles/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating generative AI models with Amazon Nova LLM-as-a-Judge on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 22:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Evaluating the performance of large language models (LLMs) goes beyond statistical metrics like perplexity or bilingual evaluation understudy (BLEU) scores. For most real-world generative AI scenarios, it’s crucial to understand whether a model is producing better outputs than a baseline or an earlier iteration. This is especially important for applications such as summarization, content generation, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluating-generative-ai-models-with-amazon-nova-llm-as-a-judge-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building cost-effective RAG applications with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon S3 Vectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 22:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to integrate Amazon S3 Vectors with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases for RAG applications. You&#39;ll learn a practical approach to scale your knowledge bases to handle millions of documents while maintaining retrieval quality and using S3 Vectors cost-effective storage.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-cost-effective-rag-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-and-amazon-s3-vectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing on-demand deployment with customized Amazon Nova models on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 19:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through the custom model on-demand deployment workflow for Amazon Bedrock and provide step-by-step implementation guides using both the AWS Management Console and APIs or AWS SDKs. We also discuss best practices and considerations for deploying customized Amazon Nova models on Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implementing-on-demand-deployment-with-customized-amazon-nova-models-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building enterprise-scale RAG applications with Amazon S3 Vectors and DeepSeek R1 on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 12:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are adopting large language models (LLMs), such as DeepSeek R1, to transform business processes, enhance customer experiences, and drive innovation at unprecedented speed. However, standalone LLMs have key limitations such as hallucinations, outdated knowledge, and no access to proprietary data. Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) addresses these gaps by combining semantic search with generative AI, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-enterprise-scale-rag-applications-with-amazon-s3-vectors-and-deepseek-r1-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accenture scales video analysis with Amazon Nova and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 22:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was written with Ilan Geller, Kamal Mannar, Debasmita Ghosh, and Nakul Aggarwal of Accenture. Video highlights offer a powerful way to boost audience engagement and extend content value for content publishers. These short, high-impact clips capture key moments that drive viewer retention, amplify reach across social media, reinforce brand identity, and open new […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accenture-scales-video-analysis-with-amazon-nova-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy conversational agents with Vonage and Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 18:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how developers can integrate Amazon Nova Sonic with the Vonage communications service to build responsive, natural-sounding voice experiences in real time. By combining the Vonage Voice API with the low-latency and expressive speech capabilities of Amazon Nova Sonic, businesses can deploy AI voice agents that deliver more human-like interactions than traditional voice interfaces. These agents can be used as customer support, virtual assistants, and more.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling customers to deliver production-ready AI agents at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, I’m excited to share how we’re bringing this vision to life with new capabilities that address the fundamental aspects of building and deploying agents at scale. These innovations will help you move beyond experiments to production-ready agent systems that can be trusted with your most critical business processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enabling-customers-to-deliver-production-ready-ai-agents-at-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases now supports Amazon OpenSearch Service Managed Cluster as vector store</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 22:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases has extended its vector store options by enabling support for Amazon OpenSearch Service managed clusters, further strengthening its capabilities as a fully managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) solution. This enhancement builds on the core functionality of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases , which is designed to seamlessly connect foundation models (FMs) with internal data sources. This post provides a comprehensive, step-by-step guide on integrating an Amazon Bedrock knowledge base with an OpenSearch Service managed cluster as its vector store.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor agents built on Amazon Bedrock with Datadog LLM Observability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 22:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a new integration between Datadog LLM Observability and Amazon Bedrock Agents that helps monitor agentic applications built on Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we&#39;ll explore how Datadog&#39;s LLM Observability provides the visibility and control needed to successfully monitor, operate, and debug production-grade agentic applications built on Amazon Bedrock Agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/monitor-agents-built-on-amazon-bedrock-with-datadog-llm-observability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PayU built a secure enterprise AI assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 21:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PayU offers a full-stack digital financial services system that serves the financial needs of merchants, banks, and consumers through technology. In this post, we explain how we equipped the PayU team with an enterprise AI solution and democratized AI access using Amazon Bedrock, without compromising on data residency requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-payu-built-a-secure-enterprise-ai-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge generative AI workflows with NVIDIA DGX Cloud on AWS and Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 13:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Andrew Liu, Chelsea Isaac, Zoey Zhang, and Charlie Huang from NVIDIA. DGX Cloud on Amazon Web Services (AWS) represents a significant leap forward in democratizing access to high-performance AI infrastructure. By combining NVIDIA GPU expertise with AWS scalable cloud services, organizations can accelerate their time-to-train, reduce operational complexity, and unlock […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/supercharge-generative-ai-workflows-with-nvidia-dgx-cloud-on-aws-and-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate generative AI inference with NVIDIA Dynamo and Amazon EKS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 13:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces NVIDIA Dynamo and explains how to set it up on Amazon EKS for automated scaling and streamlined Kubernetes operations. We provide a hands-on walkthrough, which uses the NVIDIA Dynamo blueprint on the AI on EKS GitHub repo by AWS Labs to provision the infrastructure, configure monitoring, and install the NVIDIA Dynamo operator.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-generative-ai-inference-with-nvidia-dynamo-and-amazon-eks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS doubles investment in AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, marking two years of customer success</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 12:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, AWS announces a $100 million additional investment in its AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, marking two years of successful customer collaborations across industries from financial services to healthcare. The investment comes as AI evolves toward more autonomous, agentic systems, with the center already helping thousands of customers drive millions in productivity gains and transform customer experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-doubles-investment-in-aws-generative-ai-innovation-center-marking-two-years-of-customer-success/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
