<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:57:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications on Amazon Bedrock — the secure, compliant, and responsible foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has revolutionized industries by creating content, from text and images to audio and code. Although it can unlock numerous possibilities, integrating generative AI into applications demands meticulous planning. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that provides access to large language models (LLMs) and other foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies through a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-on-amazon-bedrock-the-secure-compliant-and-responsible-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational chatbot using different LLMs within single interface – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the advent of generative artificial intelligence (AI), foundation models (FMs) can generate content such as answering questions, summarizing text, and providing highlights from the sourced document. However, for model selection, there is a wide choice from model providers, like Amazon, Anthropic, AI21 Labs, Cohere, and Meta, coupled with discrete real-world data formats in PDF, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-conversational-chatbot-using-different-llms-within-single-interface-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate derivative confirms processing using AWS AI services for the capital markets industry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can automate and intelligently process derivative confirms at scale using AWS AI services. The solution combines Amazon Textract, a fully managed ML service to effortlessly extract text, handwriting, and data from scanned documents, and AWS Serverless technologies, a suite of fully managed event-driven services for running code, managing data, and integrating applications, all without managing servers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-derivative-confirms-processing-using-aws-ai-services-for-the-capital-markets-industry/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered assistants for investment research with multi-modal data: An application of Agents for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a follow-up to Generative AI and multi-modal agents in AWS: The key to unlocking new value in financial markets. This blog is part of the series, Generative AI and AI/ML in Capital Markets and Financial Services. Financial analysts and research analysts in capital markets distill business insights from financial and non-financial data, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-powered-assistants-for-investment-research-with-multi-modal-data-an-application-of-agents-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI21 Labs Jamba-Instruct model is now available in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of the Jamba-Instruct large language model (LLM) in Amazon Bedrock. Jamba-Instruct is built by AI21 Labs, and most notably supports a 256,000-token context window, making it especially useful for processing large documents and complex Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) applications. What is Jamba-Instruct Jamba-Instruct is an instruction-tuned version of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai21-labs-jamba-instruct-model-is-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale and simplify ML workload monitoring on Amazon EKS with AWS Neuron Monitor container</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Web Services is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Neuron Monitor container, an innovative tool designed to enhance the monitoring capabilities of AWS Inferentia and AWS Trainium chips on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS). This solution simplifies the integration of advanced monitoring tools such as Prometheus and Grafana, enabling you to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-and-simplify-ml-workload-monitoring-on-amazon-eks-with-aws-neuron-monitor-container/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an automated insight extraction framework for customer feedback analysis with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon QuickSight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to integrate LLMs into enterprise applications to harness their generative capabilities. We delve into the technical aspects of workflow implementation and provide code samples that you can quickly deploy or modify to suit your specific requirements. Whether you’re a developer seeking to incorporate LLMs into your existing systems or a business owner looking to take advantage of the power of NLP, this post can serve as a quick jumpstart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build safe and responsible generative AI applications with guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) enable remarkably human-like conversations, allowing builders to create novel applications. LLMs find use in chatbots for customer service, virtual assistants, content generation, and much more. However, the implementation of LLMs without proper caution can lead to the dissemination of misinformation, manipulation of individuals, and the generation of undesirable outputs such as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-safe-and-responsible-generative-ai-applications-with-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve visibility into Amazon Bedrock usage and performance with Amazon CloudWatch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will share some of capabilities to help you get quick and easy visibility into Amazon Bedrock workloads in context of your broader application. We will use the contextual conversational assistant example in the Amazon Bedrock GitHub repository to provide examples of how you can customize these views to further enhance visibility, tailored to your use case. Specifically, we will describe how you can use the new automatic dashboard in Amazon CloudWatch to get a single pane of glass visibility into the usage and performance of Amazon Bedrock models and gain end-to-end visibility by customizing dashboards with widgets that provide visibility and insights into components and operations such as Retrieval Augmented Generation in your application.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement exact match with Amazon Lex QnAIntent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 20:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a continuation of Creating Natural Conversations with Amazon Lex QnAIntent and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Base. In summary, we explored new capabilities available through Amazon Lex QnAIntent, powered by Amazon Bedrock, that enable you to harness natural language understanding and your own knowledge repositories to provide real-time, conversational experiences. In many cases, Amazon […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-exact-match-with-amazon-lex-qnaintent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Krikey AI harnessed the power of Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth to accelerate generative AI development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 17:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2024/24_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Jhanvi Shriram and Ketaki Shriram from Krikey. Krikey AI is revolutionizing the world of 3D animation with their innovative platform that allows anyone to generate high-quality 3D animations using just text or video inputs, without needing any prior animation experience. At the core of Krikey AI’s offering is their powerful […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-krikey-ai-harnessed-the-power-of-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-to-accelerate-generative-ai-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Amazon SageMaker JumpStart foundation model access with private hubs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 19:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker JumpStart is a machine learning (ML) hub offering pre-trained models and pre-built solutions. It provides access to hundreds of foundation models (FMs). A private hub is a feature in SageMaker JumpStart that allows an organization to share their models and notebooks so as to centralize model artifacts, facilitate discoverability, and increase the reuse […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/manage-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-foundation-model-access-with-private-hubs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eSentire delivers private and secure generative AI interactions to customers with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 14:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_06_2024/21_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            eSentire is an industry-leading provider of Managed Detection &amp;amp; Response (MDR) services protecting users, data, and applications of over 2,000 organizations globally across more than 35 industries. These security services help their customers anticipate, withstand, and recover from sophisticated cyber threats, prevent disruption from malicious attacks, and improve their security posture. In 2023, eSentire was […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/esentire-delivers-private-and-secure-generative-ai-interactions-to-customers-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperva optimizes SQL generation from natural language using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with Ori Nakar from Imperva. Imperva Cloud WAF protects hundreds of thousands of websites against cyber threats and blocks billions of security events every day. Counters and insights based on security events are calculated daily and used by users from multiple departments. Millions of counters are added daily, together […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/imperva-optimizes-sql-generation-from-natural-language-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create natural conversations with Amazon Lex QnAIntent and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customer service organizations today face an immense opportunity. As customer expectations grow, brands have a chance to creatively apply new innovations to transform the customer experience. Although meeting rising customer demands poses challenges, the latest breakthroughs in conversational artificial intelligence (AI) empowers companies to meet these expectations. Customers today expect timely responses to their questions […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-natural-conversations-with-amazon-lex-qnaintent-and-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate the reliability of Retrieval Augmented Generation applications using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to evaluate the performance, trustworthiness, and potential biases of your RAG pipelines and applications on Amazon Bedrock. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Mistral AI, Stability AI, and Amazon through a single API, along with a broad set of capabilities to build generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Amazon services using AWS PrivateLink in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 16:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a solution for configuring SageMaker notebook instances to connect to Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services with the use of AWS PrivateLink and Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) security groups.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/connect-to-amazon-services-using-aws-privatelink-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
