<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 20:35:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running deep research AI agents on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 20:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI agents are evolving beyond basic single-task helpers into more powerful systems that can plan, critique, and collaborate with other agents to solve complex problems. Deep Agents—a recently introduced framework built on LangGraph—bring these capabilities to life, enabling multi-agent workflows that mirror real-world team dynamics. The challenge, however, is not just building such agents but […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/running-deep-research-ai-agents-on-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate tokenization with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails for secure data handling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to integrate Amazon Bedrock Guardrails with third-party tokenization services to protect sensitive data while maintaining data reversibility. By combining these technologies, organizations can implement stronger privacy controls while preserving the functionality of their generative AI applications and related systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-tokenization-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails-for-secure-data-handling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid ML experimentation for enterprises with Amazon SageMaker AI and Comet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showed how to use SageMaker and Comet together to spin up fully managed ML environments with reproducibility and experiment tracking capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/rapid-ml-experimentation-for-enterprises-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-comet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move your AI agents from proof of concept to production with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore helps you transition your agentic applications from experimental proof of concept to production-ready systems. We follow the journey of a customer support agent that evolves from a simple local prototype to a comprehensive, enterprise-grade solution capable of handling multiple concurrent users while maintaining security and performance standards.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/move-your-ai-agents-from-proof-of-concept-to-production-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale visual production using Stability AI Image Services in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post was written with Alex Gnibus of Stability AI. Stability AI Image Services are now available in Amazon Bedrock, offering ready-to-use media editing capabilities delivered through the Amazon Bedrock API. These image editing tools expand on the capabilities of Stability AI’s Stable Diffusion 3.5 models (SD3.5) and Stable Image Core and Ultra models, which […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-visual-production-using-stability-ai-image-services-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompting for precision with Stability AI Image Services in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock now offers Stability AI Image Services: 9 tools that improve how businesses create and modify images. The technology extends Stable Diffusion and Stable Image models to give you precise control over image creation and editing. Clear prompts are critical—they provide art direction to the AI system. Strong prompts control specific elements like tone, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/prompting-for-precision-with-stability-ai-image-services-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Amazon Bedrock batch inference using Amazon CloudWatch metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to monitor and manage Amazon Bedrock batch inference jobs using Amazon CloudWatch metrics, alarms, and dashboards to optimize performance, cost, and operational efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/monitor-amazon-bedrock-batch-inference-using-amazon-cloudwatch-metrics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use AWS Deep Learning Containers with Amazon SageMaker AI managed MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to integrate AWS DLCs with MLflow to create a solution that balances infrastructure control with robust ML governance. We walk through a functional setup that your team can use to meet your specialized requirements while significantly reducing the time and resources needed for ML lifecycle management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-aws-deep-learning-containers-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-managed-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
