<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 22:41:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tailor responsible AI with new safeguard tiers in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 22:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the new safeguard tiers available in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails, explain their benefits and use cases, and provide guidance on how to implement and evaluate them in your AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/tailor-responsible-ai-with-new-safeguard-tiers-in-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured data response with Amazon Bedrock: Prompt Engineering and Tool Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We demonstrate two methods for generating structured responses with Amazon Bedrock: Prompt Engineering and Tool Use with the Converse API. Prompt Engineering is flexible, works with Bedrock models (including those without Tool Use support), and handles various schema types (e.g., Open API schemas), making it a great starting point. Tool Use offers greater reliability, consistent results, seamless API integration, and runtime validation of JSON schema for enhanced control.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon SageMaker AI Random Cut Forest for NASA’s Blue Origin spacecraft sensor data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use SageMaker AI to apply the Random Cut Forest (RCF) algorithm to detect anomalies in spacecraft position, velocity, and quaternion orientation data from NASA and Blue Origin’s demonstration of lunar Deorbit, Descent, and Landing Sensors (BODDL-TP).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-amazon-sagemaker-ai-random-cut-forest-for-nasas-blue-origin-spacecraft-sensor-data/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent multi-agent business expert using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 16:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a multi-agent system using multi-agent collaboration in Amazon Bedrock Agents to solve complex business questions in the biopharmaceutical industry. We show how specialized agents in research and development (R&amp;amp;D), legal, and finance domains can work together to provide comprehensive business insights by analyzing data from multiple sources.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-multi-agent-business-expert-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving cost-efficiency and speed in claims data processing with Amazon Nova Micro and Amazon Nova Lite</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we shared how an internal technology team at Amazon evaluated Amazon Nova models, resulting in notable improvements in inference speed and cost-efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/driving-cost-efficiency-and-speed-in-claims-data-processing-with-amazon-nova-micro-and-amazon-nova-lite/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Agents observability using Arize AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce a new integration between Arize AI and Amazon Bedrock Agents that addresses one of the most significant challenges in AI development: observability. In this post, we demonstrate the Arize Phoenix system for tracing and evaluation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-agents-observability-using-arize-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How SkillShow automates youth sports video processing using Amazon Transcribe</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 15:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            SkillShow, a leader in youth sports video production, films over 300 events yearly in the youth sports industry, creating content for over 20,000 young athletes annually. This post describes how SkillShow used Amazon Transcribe and other Amazon Web Services (AWS) machine learning (ML) services to automate their video processing workflow, reducing editing time and costs while scaling their operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-skillshow-automates-youth-sports-video-processing-using-amazon-transcribe/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NewDay builds A Generative AI based Customer service Agent Assist with over 90% accuracy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 15:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Sergio Zavota and Amy Perring from NewDay. NewDay has a clear and defining purpose: to help people move forward with credit. NewDay provides around 4 million customers access to credit responsibly and delivers exceptional customer experiences, powered by their in-house technology system. NewDay’s contact center handles 2.5 million calls annually, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/newday-builds-a-generative-ai-based-customer-service-agent-assist-with-over-90-accuracy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No-code data preparation for time series forecasting using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Canvas offers no-code solutions that simplify data wrangling, making time series forecasting accessible to all users regardless of their technical background. In this post, we explore how SageMaker Canvas and SageMaker Data Wrangler provide no-code data preparation techniques that empower users of all backgrounds to prepare data and build time series forecasting models in a single interface with confidence.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/no-code-data-preparation-for-time-series-forecasting-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an agentic multimodal AI assistant with Amazon Nova and Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how agentic workflow patterns such as Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), multi-tool orchestration, and conditional routing with LangGraph enable end-to-end solutions that artificial intelligence and machine learning (AI/ML) developers and enterprise architects can adopt and extend. We walk through an example of a financial management AI assistant that can provide quantitative research and grounded financial advice by analyzing both the earnings call (audio) and the presentation slides (images), along with relevant financial data feeds.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
