<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:57:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a self-service digital assistant using Amazon Lex and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations strive to implement efficient, scalable, cost-effective, and automated customer support solutions without compromising the customer experience. Generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered chatbots play a crucial role in delivering human-like interactions by providing responses from a knowledge base without the involvement of live agents. These chatbots can be efficiently utilized for handling generic inquiries, freeing up […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-self-service-digital-assistant-using-amazon-lex-and-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify idle endpoints in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker is a machine learning (ML) platform designed to simplify the process of building, training, deploying, and managing ML models at scale. With a comprehensive suite of tools and services, SageMaker offers developers and data scientists the resources they need to accelerate the development and deployment of ML solutions. In today’s fast-paced technological landscape, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/identify-idle-endpoints-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian language RAG with Cohere multilingual embeddings and Anthropic Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2024/01_07_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Media and entertainment companies serve multilingual audiences with a wide range of content catering to diverse audience segments. These enterprises have access to massive amounts of data collected over their many years of operations. Much of this data is unstructured text and images. Conventional approaches to analyzing unstructured data for generating new content rely on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/indian-language-rag-with-cohere-multilingual-embeddings-and-anthropic-claude-3-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of productivity agents with NinjaTech AI and AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NinjaTech AI’s mission is to make everyone more productive by taking care of time-consuming complex tasks with fast and affordable artificial intelligence (AI) agents. We recently launched MyNinja.ai, one of the world’s first multi-agent personal AI assistants, to drive towards our mission. MyNinja.ai is built from the ground up using specialized agents that are capable of completing tasks on your behalf, including scheduling meetings, conducting deep research from the web, generating code, and helping with writing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications on Amazon Bedrock — the secure, compliant, and responsible foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has revolutionized industries by creating content, from text and images to audio and code. Although it can unlock numerous possibilities, integrating generative AI into applications demands meticulous planning. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that provides access to large language models (LLMs) and other foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies through a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-on-amazon-bedrock-the-secure-compliant-and-responsible-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational chatbot using different LLMs within single interface – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2024/27_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the advent of generative artificial intelligence (AI), foundation models (FMs) can generate content such as answering questions, summarizing text, and providing highlights from the sourced document. However, for model selection, there is a wide choice from model providers, like Amazon, Anthropic, AI21 Labs, Cohere, and Meta, coupled with discrete real-world data formats in PDF, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-conversational-chatbot-using-different-llms-within-single-interface-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate derivative confirms processing using AWS AI services for the capital markets industry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can automate and intelligently process derivative confirms at scale using AWS AI services. The solution combines Amazon Textract, a fully managed ML service to effortlessly extract text, handwriting, and data from scanned documents, and AWS Serverless technologies, a suite of fully managed event-driven services for running code, managing data, and integrating applications, all without managing servers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-derivative-confirms-processing-using-aws-ai-services-for-the-capital-markets-industry/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered assistants for investment research with multi-modal data: An application of Agents for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2024/26_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a follow-up to Generative AI and multi-modal agents in AWS: The key to unlocking new value in financial markets. This blog is part of the series, Generative AI and AI/ML in Capital Markets and Financial Services. Financial analysts and research analysts in capital markets distill business insights from financial and non-financial data, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-powered-assistants-for-investment-research-with-multi-modal-data-an-application-of-agents-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI21 Labs Jamba-Instruct model is now available in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of the Jamba-Instruct large language model (LLM) in Amazon Bedrock. Jamba-Instruct is built by AI21 Labs, and most notably supports a 256,000-token context window, making it especially useful for processing large documents and complex Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) applications. What is Jamba-Instruct Jamba-Instruct is an instruction-tuned version of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai21-labs-jamba-instruct-model-is-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale and simplify ML workload monitoring on Amazon EKS with AWS Neuron Monitor container</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Web Services is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Neuron Monitor container, an innovative tool designed to enhance the monitoring capabilities of AWS Inferentia and AWS Trainium chips on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS). This solution simplifies the integration of advanced monitoring tools such as Prometheus and Grafana, enabling you to […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-and-simplify-ml-workload-monitoring-on-amazon-eks-with-aws-neuron-monitor-container/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an automated insight extraction framework for customer feedback analysis with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon QuickSight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to integrate LLMs into enterprise applications to harness their generative capabilities. We delve into the technical aspects of workflow implementation and provide code samples that you can quickly deploy or modify to suit your specific requirements. Whether you’re a developer seeking to incorporate LLMs into your existing systems or a business owner looking to take advantage of the power of NLP, this post can serve as a quick jumpstart.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build safe and responsible generative AI applications with guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) enable remarkably human-like conversations, allowing builders to create novel applications. LLMs find use in chatbots for customer service, virtual assistants, content generation, and much more. However, the implementation of LLMs without proper caution can lead to the dissemination of misinformation, manipulation of individuals, and the generation of undesirable outputs such as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-safe-and-responsible-generative-ai-applications-with-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve visibility into Amazon Bedrock usage and performance with Amazon CloudWatch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2024/25_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will share some of capabilities to help you get quick and easy visibility into Amazon Bedrock workloads in context of your broader application. We will use the contextual conversational assistant example in the Amazon Bedrock GitHub repository to provide examples of how you can customize these views to further enhance visibility, tailored to your use case. Specifically, we will describe how you can use the new automatic dashboard in Amazon CloudWatch to get a single pane of glass visibility into the usage and performance of Amazon Bedrock models and gain end-to-end visibility by customizing dashboards with widgets that provide visibility and insights into components and operations such as Retrieval Augmented Generation in your application.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
