<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 16:00:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune large multimodal models using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large multimodal models (LMMs) integrate multiple data types into a single model. By combining text data with images and other modalities during training, multimodal models such as Claude3, GPT-4V, and Gemini Pro Vision gain more comprehensive understanding and improved ability to process diverse data types. The multimodal approach allows models to handle a wider range […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-large-multimodal-models-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Mixtral 8x7B pre-training with expert parallelism on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 19:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2024/23_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mixture of Experts (MoE) architectures for large language models (LLMs) have recently gained popularity due to their ability to increase model capacity and computational efficiency compared to fully dense models. By utilizing sparse expert subnetworks that process different subsets of tokens, MoE models can effectively increase the number of parameters while requiring less computation per […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-mixtral-8x7b-pre-training-with-expert-parallelism-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating fashion product descriptions by fine-tuning a vision-language model with SageMaker and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 19:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2024/22_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows you how to predict domain-specific product attributes from product images by fine-tuning a VLM on a fashion dataset using Amazon SageMaker, and then using Amazon Bedrock to generate product descriptions using the predicted attributes as input. So you can follow along, we’re sharing the code in a GitHub repository.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generating-fashion-product-descriptions-by-fine-tuning-a-vision-language-model-with-sagemaker-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
