<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:47:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implement serverless semantic search of image and live video with Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-driven world, industries across various sectors are accumulating massive amounts of video data through cameras installed in their warehouses, clinics, roads, metro stations, stores, factories, or even private facilities. This video data holds immense potential for analysis and monitoring of incidents that may occur in these locations. From fire hazards to broken equipment, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-serverless-semantic-search-of-image-and-live-video-with-amazon-titan-multimodal-embeddings/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prioritizing employee well-being: An innovative approach with generative AI and Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 17:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2024/03_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced corporate landscape, employee mental health has become a crucial aspect that organizations can no longer overlook. Many companies recognize that their greatest asset lies in their dedicated workforce, and each employee plays a vital role in collective success. As such, promoting employee well-being by creating a safe, inclusive, and supportive environment is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/prioritizing-employee-well-being-an-innovative-approach-with-generative-ai-and-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-training genomic language models using AWS HealthOmics and Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Genomic language models are a new and exciting field in the application of large language models to challenges in genomics. In this blog post and open source project, we show you how you can pre-train a genomics language model, HyenaDNA, using your genomic data in the AWS Cloud. Here, we use AWS HealthOmics storage as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pre-training-genomic-language-models-using-aws-healthomics-and-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falcon 2 11B is now available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 15:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the first model in the next generation Falcon 2 family, the Falcon 2 11B foundation model (FM) from Technology Innovation Institute (TII), is available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. Falcon 2 11B is a trained dense decoder model on a 5.5 trillion token dataset […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/falcon-2-11b-is-now-available-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock in support of GDPR (right to be forgotten) requests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 15:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_05_2024/31_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) right to be forgotten, also known as the right to erasure, gives individuals the right to request the deletion of their personally identifiable information (PII) data held by organizations. This means that individuals can ask companies to erase their personal data from their systems and from the systems of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implementing-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-in-support-of-gdpr-right-to-be-forgotten-requests/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBRE and AWS perform natural language queries of structured data using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 19:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with CBRE. CBRE is the world’s largest commercial real estate services and investment firm, with 130,000 professionals serving clients in more than 100 countries. Services range from financing and investment to property management. CBRE is unlocking the potential of artificial intelligence (AI) to realize value across the entire commercial […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cbre-and-aws-perform-natural-language-queries-of-structured-data-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic video content moderation and policy evaluation using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations across media and entertainment, advertising, social media, education, and other sectors require efficient solutions to extract information from videos and apply flexible evaluations based on their policies. Generative artificial intelligence (AI) has unlocked fresh opportunities for these use cases. In this post, we introduce the Media Analysis and Policy Evaluation solution, which uses AWS […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dynamic-video-content-moderation-and-policy-evaluation-using-aws-generative-ai-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitech uses Amazon Bedrock to revolutionize information access with AI-powered chatbot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2024/30_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Murthy Palla and Madesh Subbanna from Vitech. Vitech is a global provider of cloud-centered benefit and investment administration software. Vitech helps group insurance, pension fund administration, and investment clients expand their offerings and capabilities, streamline their operations, and gain analytical insights. To serve their customers, Vitech maintains a repository of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/vitech-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-revolutionize-information-access-with-ai-powered-chatbot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance image search experiences with Amazon Personalize, Amazon OpenSearch Service, and Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 16:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A variety of different techniques have been used for returning images relevant to search queries. Historically, the idea of creating a joint embedding space to facilitate image captioning or text-to-image search has been of interest to machine learning (ML) practitioners and businesses for quite a while. Contrastive Language–Image Pre-training (CLIP) and Bootstrapping Language-Image Pre-training (BLIP) […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-image-search-experiences-with-amazon-personalize-amazon-opensearch-service-and-amazon-titan-multimodal-embeddings-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-end LLM training on instance clusters with over 100 nodes using AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to accelerate the full pre-training of LLM models by scaling up to 128 trn1.32xlarge nodes, using a Llama 2-7B model as an example. We share best practices for training LLMs on AWS Trainium, scaling the training on a cluster with over 100 nodes, improving efficiency of recovery from system and hardware failures, improving training stability, and achieving convergence.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/end-to-end-llm-training-on-instance-clusters-with-over-100-nodes-using-aws-trainium/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune large multimodal models using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2024/29_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large multimodal models (LMMs) integrate multiple data types into a single model. By combining text data with images and other modalities during training, multimodal models such as Claude3, GPT-4V, and Gemini Pro Vision gain more comprehensive understanding and improved ability to process diverse data types. The multimodal approach allows models to handle a wider range […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-large-multimodal-models-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
