<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:36:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inline code nodes now supported in Amazon Bedrock Flows in public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the public preview of support for inline code nodes in Amazon Bedrock Flows. With this powerful new capability, you can write Python scripts directly within your workflow, alleviating the need for separate AWS Lambda functions for simple logic. This feature streamlines preprocessing and postprocessing tasks (like data normalization and response formatting), simplifying generative AI application development and making it more accessible across organizations.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate enterprise AI implementations with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business offers AWS customers a scalable and comprehensive solution for enhancing business processes across their organization. By carefully evaluating your use cases, following implementation best practices, and using the architectural guidance provided in this post, you can deploy Amazon Q Business to transform your enterprise productivity. The key to success lies in starting small, proving value quickly, and scaling systematically across your organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-enterprise-ai-implementations-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up delivery of ML workloads using Code Editor in Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how you can use the new Code Editor and multiple spaces support in SageMaker Unified Studio. The sample solution shows how to develop an ML pipeline that automates the typical end-to-end ML activities to build, train, evaluate, and (optionally) deploy an ML model.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/speed-up-delivery-of-ml-workloads-using-code-editor-in-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Infosys Topaz leverages Amazon Bedrock to transform technical help desk operations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog, we examine the use case of a large energy supplier whose technical help desk agents answer customer calls and support field agents. We use Amazon Bedrock along with capabilities from Infosys Topaz™ to build a generative AI application that can reduce call handling times, automate tasks, and improve the overall quality of technical support.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-infosys-topaz-leverages-amazon-bedrock-to-transform-technical-help-desk-operations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create personalized products and marketing campaigns using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 21:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Built using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock, The Fragrance Lab represents a comprehensive end-to-end application that illustrates the transformative power of generative AI in retail, consumer goods, advertising, and marketing. In this post, we explore the development of The Fragrance Lab. Our vision was to craft a unique blend of physical and digital experiences that would celebrate creativity, advertising, and consumer goods while capturing the spirit of the French Riviera.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tyson Foods elevates customer search experience with an AI-powered conversational assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 21:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Tyson Foods collaborated with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center to revolutionize their customer interaction through an intuitive AI assistant integrated into their website. The AI assistant was built using Amazon Bedrock,
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/tyson-foods-elevates-customer-search-experience-with-an-ai-powered-conversational-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance AI agents using predictive ML models with Amazon SageMaker AI and Model Context Protocol (MCP)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 20:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to enhance AI agents’ capabilities by integrating predictive ML models using Amazon SageMaker AI and the MCP. By using the open source Strands Agents SDK and the flexible deployment options of SageMaker AI, developers can create sophisticated AI applications that combine conversational AI with powerful predictive analytics capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-ai-agents-using-predictive-ml-models-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-model-context-protocol-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify access control and auditing for Amazon SageMaker Studio using trusted identity propagation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to enable and use trusted identity propagation in Amazon SageMaker Studio, which allows organizations to simplify access management by granting permissions to existing AWS IAM Identity Center identities. The solution demonstrates how to implement fine-grained access controls based on a physical user&#39;s identity, maintain detailed audit logs across supported AWS services, and support long-running user background sessions for training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simplify-access-control-and-auditing-for-amazon-sagemaker-studio-using-trusted-identity-propagation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking document information localization with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to use foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock, specifically Amazon Nova Pro, to achieve high-accuracy document field localization while dramatically simplifying implementation. We show how these models can precisely locate and interpret document fields with minimal frontend effort, reducing processing errors and manual intervention.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/benchmarking-document-information-localization-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Infosys built a generative AI solution to process oil and gas drilling data with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We built an advanced RAG solution using Amazon Bedrock leveraging Infosys Topaz™ AI capabilities, tailored for the oil and gas sector. This solution excels in handling multimodal data sources, seamlessly processing text, diagrams, and numerical data while maintaining context and relationships between different data elements. In this post, we provide insights on the solution and walk you through different approaches and architecture patterns explored, like different chunking, multi-vector retrieval, and hybrid search during the development.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline employee training with an intelligent chatbot powered by Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to design and implement custom plugins for Amazon Q Business to create an intelligent chatbot that streamlines employee training by retrieving answers from training materials. The solution implements secure API access using Amazon Cognito for user authentication and authorization, processes multiple document formats, and includes features like RAG-enhanced responses and email escalation capabilities through custom plugins.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-employee-training-with-an-intelligent-chatbot-powered-by-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a travel planning agentic workflow with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 20:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_08_2025/18_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a travel planning solution using AI agents. The agent uses Amazon Nova, which offers an optimal balance of performance and cost compared to other commercial LLMs. By combining accurate but cost-efficient Amazon Nova models with LangGraph orchestration capabilities, we create a practical travel assistant that can handle complex planning tasks while keeping operational costs manageable for production deployments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-travel-planning-agentic-workflow-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway: Transforming enterprise AI agent tool development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, a fully managed service that revolutionizes how enterprises connect AI agents with tools and services by providing a centralized tool server with unified interface for agent-tool communication. The service offers key capabilities including Security Guard, Translation, Composition, Target extensibility, Infrastructure Manager, and Semantic Tool Selection, while implementing sophisticated dual-sided security architecture for both inbound and outbound connections.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway-transforming-enterprise-ai-agent-tool-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a scalable containerized web application on AWS using the MERN stack with Amazon Q Developer – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a traditional SDLC, a lot of time is spent in the different phases researching approaches that can deliver on requirements: iterating over design changes, writing, testing and reviewing code, and configuring infrastructure. In this post, you learned about the experience and saw productivity gains you can realize by using Amazon Q Developer as a coding assistant to build a scalable MERN stack web application on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Salesforce’s model endpoints with Amazon SageMaker AI inference components</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how the Salesforce AI Platform team optimized GPU utilization, improved resource efficiency and achieved cost savings using Amazon SageMaker AI, specifically inference components.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-salesforces-model-endpoints-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-inference-components/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a RAG chat-based assistant on Amazon EKS Auto Mode and NVIDIA NIMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the implementation of a practical RAG chat-based assistant using a comprehensive stack of modern technologies. The solution uses NVIDIA NIMs for both LLM inference and text embedding services, with the NIM Operator handling their deployment and management. The architecture incorporates Amazon OpenSearch Serverless to store and query high-dimensional vector embeddings for similarity search.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-a-rag-chat-based-assistant-on-amazon-eks-auto-mode-and-nvidia-nims/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Identity: Securing agentic AI at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Identity, a comprehensive identity and access management service purpose-built for AI agents that enables secure access to AWS resources and third-party tools. The service provides robust identity management features including agent identity directory, agent authorizer, resource credential provider, and resource token vault to help organizations deploy AI agents securely at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-identity-securing-agentic-ai-at-scale/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the blog post Scalable intelligent document processing using Amazon Bedrock, we demonstrated how to build a scalable IDP pipeline using Anthropic foundation models on Amazon Bedrock. Although that approach delivered robust performance, the introduction of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation brings a new level of efficiency and flexibility to IDP solutions. This post explores how Amazon Bedrock Data Automation enhances document processing capabilities and streamlines the automation journey.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiteboard to cloud in minutes using Amazon Q, Amazon Bedrock Data Automation, and Model Context Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share the Amazon Bedrock Data Automation Model Context Protocol (MCP) server, for seamless integration between Amazon Q and your enterprise data. In this post, you will learn how to use the Amazon Bedrock Data Automation MCP server to securely integrate with AWS Services, use Bedrock Data Automation operations as callable MCP tools, and build a conversational development experience with Amazon Q.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/whiteboard-to-cloud-in-minutes-using-amazon-q-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-model-context-protocol/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing agentic Retrieval Augmented Generation to Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how Amazon Q Business is transforming enterprise data interaction through Agentic Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bringing-agentic-retrieval-augmented-generation-to-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering students with disabilities: University Startups’ generative AI solution for personalized student pathways</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            University Startups, headquartered in Bethesda, MD, was founded in 2020 to empower high school students to expand their education beyond a traditional curriculum. University Startups is focused on special education and related services in school districts throughout the US. In this post, we explain how University Startups uses generative AI technology on AWS to enable students to design a specific plan for their future either in education or the work force.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations with Amazon Nova understanding models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to prompt Amazon Nova understanding models to cite sources in responses. Further, we will also walk through how we can evaluate the responses (and citations) for accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/citations-with-amazon-nova-understanding-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
