<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:39:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time series forecasting with Amazon SageMaker AutoML</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore a comprehensive approach to time series forecasting using the Amazon SageMaker AutoMLV2 Software Development Kit (SDK). SageMaker AutoMLV2 is part of the SageMaker Autopilot suite, which automates the end-to-end machine learning workflow from data preparation to model deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/time-series-forecasting-with-amazon-sagemaker-automl/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate user on-boarding for financial services with a digital assistant powered by Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2024/08_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a solution that harnesses the power of generative AI to streamline the user onboarding process for financial services through a digital assistant.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-user-on-boarding-for-financial-services-with-a-digital-assistant-powered-by-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI Slack chat assistant using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Kendra</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 20:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2024/07_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we describe the development of a generative AI Slack application powered by Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Kendra. This is designed to be an internal-facing Slack chat assistant that helps answer questions related to the indexed content.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-generative-ai-slack-chat-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-kendra/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create your fashion assistant application using Amazon Titan models and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 19:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_10_2024/04_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we implement a fashion assistant agent using Amazon Bedrock Agents and the Amazon Titan family models. The fashion assistant provides a personalized, multimodal conversational experience.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-your-fashion-assistant-application-using-amazon-titan-models-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Aviva built a scalable, secure, and reliable MLOps platform using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 18:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we describe how Aviva built a fully serverless MLOps platform based on the AWS Enterprise MLOps Framework and Amazon SageMaker to integrate DevOps best practices into the ML lifecycle. This solution establishes MLOps practices to standardize model development, streamline ML model deployment, and provide consistent monitoring.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-aviva-built-a-scalable-secure-and-reliable-mlops-platform-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visier’s data science team boosts their model output 10 times by migrating to Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we learn how Visier was able to boost their model output by 10 times, accelerate innovation cycles, and unlock new opportunities using Amazon SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/visiers-data-science-team-boosts-their-model-output-10-times-by-migrating-to-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement model-independent safety measures with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how you can use the ApplyGuardrail API in common generative AI architectures such as third-party or self-hosted large language models (LLMs), or in a self-managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) architecture.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-model-independent-safety-measures-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Schneider Electric uses Amazon Bedrock to identify high-potential business opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 20:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how the team at Schneider collaborated with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to build a generative AI solution on Amazon Bedrock to solve this problem. The solution processes and evaluates each requests for proposal (RFP) and then routes high-value RFPs to the microgrid subject matter expert (SME) for approval and recommendation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-schneider-electric-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-identify-high-potential-business-opportunities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve operational excellence with well-architected generative AI solutions using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss scaling up generative AI for different lines of businesses (LOBs) and address the challenges that come around legal, compliance, operational complexities, data privacy and security.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-operational-excellence-with-well-architected-generative-ai-solutions-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate workforce productivity through seamless personalization in Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Q Business uses personalization to improve the relevance of responses and how you can align your use cases and end-user data to take full advantage of this capability
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-workforce-productivity-through-seamless-personalization-in-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for building robust generative AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Agents – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to create accurate and reliable agents. Agents helps you accelerate generative AI application development by orchestrating multistep tasks. Agents use the reasoning capability of foundation models (FMs) to break down user-requested tasks into multiple steps.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-for-building-robust-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-agents-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS recognized as a first-time Leader in the 2024 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 18:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS has been recognized as a Leader in the 2024 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms. The post highlights how AWS&#39;s continued innovations in services like Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker have enabled organizations to unlock the transformative potential of generative AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-recognized-as-a-first-time-leader-in-the-2024-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-data-science-and-machine-learning-platforms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless voice-based contextual chatbot for people with disabilities using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we presented how to create a fully serverless voice-based contextual chatbot using Amazon Bedrock with Anthropic Claude.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-voice-based-contextual-chatbot-for-people-with-disabilities-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintain access and consider alternatives for Amazon Monitron</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses how customers can maintain access to Amazon Monitron after it is closed to new customers and what some alternatives are to Amazon Monitron.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maintain-access-and-consider-alternatives-for-amazon-monitron/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
