<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:50:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Kyndryl integrated ServiceNow and Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Kyndryl integrated Amazon Q Business with ServiceNow in a few simple steps. You will learn how to configure Amazon Q Business and ServiceNow, how to create a generative AI plugin for your ServiceNow incidents, and how to test and interact with ServiceNow using the Amazon Q Business web experience. This post will help you enhance your ServiceNow experience with Amazon Q Business and enjoy the benefits of a generative AI–powered interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HCLTech’s AWS powered AutoWise Companion: A seamless experience for informed automotive buyer decisions with data-driven design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces HCLTech’s AutoWise Companion, a transformative generative AI solution designed to enhance customers’ vehicle purchasing journey. In this post, we analyze the current industry challenges and guide readers through the AutoWise Companion solution functional flow and architecture design using built-in AWS services and open source tools. Additionally, we discuss the design from security and responsible AI perspectives, demonstrating how you can apply this solution to a wider range of industry scenarios.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating risk: AWS backbone network traffic prediction using GraphStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can use our enterprise graph machine learning (GML) framework GraphStorm to solve prediction challenges on large-scale complex networks inspired by our practices of exploring GML to mitigate the AWS backbone network congestion risk.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mitigating-risk-aws-backbone-network-traffic-prediction-using-graphstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement RAG while meeting data residency requirements using AWS hybrid and edge services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 18:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to extend Amazon Bedrock Agents to hybrid and edge services such as AWS Outposts and AWS Local Zones to build distributed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) applications with on-premises data for improved model outcomes. With Outposts, we also cover a reference pattern for a fully local RAG application that requires both the foundation model (FM) and data sources to reside on premises.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking complex problem-solving with multi-agent collaboration on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_01_2025/14_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The research team at AWS has worked extensively on building and evaluating the multi-agent collaboration (MAC) framework so customers can orchestrate multiple AI agents on Amazon Bedrock Agents. In this post, we explore the concept of multi-agent collaboration (MAC) and its benefits, as well as the key components of our MAC framework. We also go deeper into our evaluation methodology and present insights from our studies.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-complex-problem-solving-with-multi-agent-collaboration-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How BQA streamlines education quality reporting using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Education and Training Quality Authority (BQA) plays a critical role in improving the quality of education and training services in the Kingdom Bahrain. BQA reviews the performance of all education and training institutions, including schools, universities, and vocational institutes, thereby promoting the professional advancement of the nation’s human capital. In this post, we explore how BQA used the power of Amazon Bedrock, Amazon SageMaker JumpStart, and other AWS services to streamline the overall reporting workflow.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting team innovation, productivity, and knowledge sharing with Amazon Q Business – Web experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_01_2025/13_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how MuleSoft introduced a generative AI-powered assistant using Amazon Q Business to enhance their internal Cloud Central dashboard. This individualized portal shows assets owned, costs and usage, and well-architected recommendations to over 100 engineers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boosting-team-innovation-productivity-and-knowledge-sharing-with-amazon-q-business-web-experience/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an Amazon Bedrock based digital lending solution on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 20:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we propose a solution using DigitalDhan, a generative AI-based solution to automate customer onboarding and digital lending. The proposed solution uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to automate services related to KYC verification, credit and risk assessment, and notification. Financial institutions can use this solution to help automate the customer onboarding, KYC verification, credit decisioning, credit underwriting, and notification processes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-amazon-bedrock-based-digital-lending-solution-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI-powered malware analysis using Amazon Bedrock with Deep Instinct</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Deep Instinct’s generative AI-powered malware analysis tool, DIANNA, uses Amazon Bedrock to revolutionize cybersecurity by providing rapid, in-depth analysis of known and unknown threats, enhancing the capabilities of AWS System and Organization Controls (SOC) teams and addressing key challenges in the evolving threat landscape.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-ai-powered-malware-analysis-using-amazon-bedrock-with-deep-instinct/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email your conversations from Amazon Q</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_01_2025/09_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As organizations navigate the complexities of the digital realm, generative AI has emerged as a transformative force, empowering enterprises to enhance productivity, streamline workflows, and drive innovation. To maximize the value of insights generated by generative AI, it is crucial to provide simple ways for users to preserve and share these insights using commonly used tools such as email. This post explores how you can integrate Amazon Q Business with Amazon SES to email conversations to specified email addresses.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
