<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 17:35:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Cato Networks uses Amazon Bedrock to transform free text search into structured GraphQL queries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 17:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2025/22_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Accurately converting free text inputs into structured data is crucial for applications that involve data management and user interaction. In this post, we introduce a real business use case from Cato Networks that significantly improved user experience. By using Amazon Bedrock, we gained access to state-of-the-art generative language models with built-in support for JSON schemas and structured data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-cato-networks-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-transform-free-text-search-into-structured-graphql-queries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve forecasting challenges for the retail and CPG industry using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 20:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Amazon Web Services (AWS) helps in solving forecasting challenges by customizing machine learning (ML) models for forecasting. We dive into Amazon SageMaker Canvas and explain how SageMaker Canvas can solve forecasting challenges for retail and consumer packaged goods (CPG) enterprises.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/solve-forecasting-challenges-for-the-retail-and-cpg-industry-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling generative AI self-service using Amazon Lex, Amazon Bedrock, and ServiceNow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 20:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2025/21_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can integrate Amazon Lex with Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and ServiceNow to provide 24/7 automated support and self-service options.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enabling-generative-ai-self-service-using-amazon-lex-amazon-bedrock-and-servicenow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Kyndryl integrated ServiceNow and Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2025/16_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Kyndryl integrated Amazon Q Business with ServiceNow in a few simple steps. You will learn how to configure Amazon Q Business and ServiceNow, how to create a generative AI plugin for your ServiceNow incidents, and how to test and interact with ServiceNow using the Amazon Q Business web experience. This post will help you enhance your ServiceNow experience with Amazon Q Business and enjoy the benefits of a generative AI–powered interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HCLTech’s AWS powered AutoWise Companion: A seamless experience for informed automotive buyer decisions with data-driven design</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post introduces HCLTech’s AutoWise Companion, a transformative generative AI solution designed to enhance customers’ vehicle purchasing journey. In this post, we analyze the current industry challenges and guide readers through the AutoWise Companion solution functional flow and architecture design using built-in AWS services and open source tools. Additionally, we discuss the design from security and responsible AI perspectives, demonstrating how you can apply this solution to a wider range of industry scenarios.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating risk: AWS backbone network traffic prediction using GraphStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2025/15_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can use our enterprise graph machine learning (GML) framework GraphStorm to solve prediction challenges on large-scale complex networks inspired by our practices of exploring GML to mitigate the AWS backbone network congestion risk.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mitigating-risk-aws-backbone-network-traffic-prediction-using-graphstorm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
