<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 17:24:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Generate synthetic counterparty (CR) risk data with generative AI using Amazon Bedrock LLMs and RAG</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 17:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how you can use LLMs with advanced Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to generate high-quality synthetic data for a finance domain use case. You can use the same technique for synthetic data for other business domain use cases as well. For this post, we demonstrate how to generate counterparty risk (CR) data, which would be beneficial for over-the-counter (OTC) derivatives that are traded directly between two parties, without going through a formal exchange.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turbocharging premium audit capabilities with the power of generative AI: Verisk’s journey toward a sophisticated conversational chat platform to enhance customer support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 17:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_02_2025/20_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Verisk’s Premium Audit Advisory Service is the leading source of technical information and training for premium auditors and underwriters. In this post, we describe the development of the customer support process in PAAS, incorporating generative AI, the data, the architecture, and the evaluation of the results. Conversational AI assistants are rapidly transforming customer and employee support.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/turbocharging-premium-audit-capabilities-with-the-power-of-generative-ai-verisks-journey-toward-a-sophisticated-conversational-chat-platform-to-enhance-customer-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build verifiable explainability into financial services workflows with Automated Reasoning checks for Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 17:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Automated Reasoning checks work through various common FSI scenarios such as insurance legal triaging, underwriting rules validation, and claims processing.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-verifiable-explainability-into-financial-services-workflows-with-automated-reasoning-checks-for-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod task governance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 17:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_02_2025/19_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide best practices to maximize the value of SageMaker HyperPod task governance and make the administration and data science experiences seamless. We also discuss common governance scenarios when administering and running generative AI development tasks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-for-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-task-governance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Formula 1® uses generative AI to accelerate race-day issue resolution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 21:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_02_2025/18_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how F1 and AWS have developed a root cause analysis (RCA) assistant powered by Amazon Bedrock to reduce manual intervention and accelerate the resolution of recurrent operational issues during races from weeks to minutes. The RCA assistant enables the F1 team to spend more time on innovation and improving its services, ultimately delivering an exceptional experience for fans and partners. The successful collaboration between F1 and AWS showcases the transformative potential of generative AI in empowering teams to accomplish more in less time.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon Rekognition to improve bicycle safety</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 16:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_02_2025/17_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To better protect themselves, many cyclists are starting to ride with cameras mounted to the front or back of their bicycle. In this blog post, I will demonstrate a machine learning solution that cyclists can use to better identify close calls. The architecture of the solution uses Amazon Rekognition to detect vehicles in recorded bike ride videos. It then analyzes the video to determine if any vehicles are passing too close to the cyclist, within the 3-foot safe distance required by law.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
