<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 15:02:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Anomalo solves unstructured data quality issues to deliver trusted assets for AI with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 15:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how you can use Anomalo with Amazon Web Services (AWS) AI and machine learning (AI/ML) to profile, validate, and cleanse unstructured data collections to transform your data lake into a trusted source for production ready AI initiatives.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-anomalo-solves-unstructured-data-quality-issues-to-deliver-trusted-assets-for-ai-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An innovative financial services leader finds the right AI solution: Robinhood and Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Robinhood delivers democratized finance and real-time market insights using generative AI and Amazon Nova.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/an-innovative-financial-services-leader-finds-the-right-ai-solution-robinhood-and-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build conversational interfaces for structured data using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2025/17_06_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides instructions to configure a structured data retrieval solution, with practical code examples and templates. It covers implementation samples and additional considerations, empowering you to quickly build and scale your conversational data interfaces.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-conversational-interfaces-for-structured-data-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Apollo Tyres is unlocking machine insights using agentic AI-powered Manufacturing Reasoner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Apollo Tyres used generative AI with Amazon Bedrock to harness the insights from their machine data in a natural language interaction mode to gain a comprehensive view of its manufacturing processes, enabling data-driven decision-making and optimizing operational efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-apollo-tyres-is-unlocking-machine-insights-using-agentic-ai-powered-manufacturing-reasoner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extend your Amazon Q Business with PagerDuty Advance data accessor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how organizations can enhance their incident management capabilities by integrating PagerDuty Advance, an innovative set of agentic and generative AI capabilities that automate response workflows and provide real-time insights into operational health, with Amazon Q Business. We show how to configure PagerDuty Advance as a data accessor for Amazon Q indexes, so you can search and access enterprise knowledge across multiple systems during incident response.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovate business logic by implementing return of control in Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_06_2025/16_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the context of distributed systems and microservices architecture, orchestrating communication between diverse components presents significant challenges. However, with the launch of Amazon Bedrock Agents, the landscape is evolving, offering a simplified approach to agent creation and seamless integration of the return of control capability. In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock Agents revolutionizes agent creation and demonstrates the efficacy of the return of control capability in orchestrating complex interactions between multiple systems.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Qwen models with Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 17:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now import custom weights for Qwen2, Qwen2_VL, and Qwen2_5_VL architectures, including models like Qwen 2, 2.5 Coder, Qwen 2.5 VL, and QwQ 32B. In this post, we cover how to deploy Qwen 2.5 models with Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import, making them accessible to organizations looking to use state-of-the-art AI capabilities within the AWS infrastructure at an effective cost.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-qwen-models-with-amazon-bedrock-custom-model-import/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI solutions with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to build generative AI applications on Amazon Web Services (AWS) using the capabilities of Amazon Bedrock, highlighting how Amazon Bedrock can be used at each step of your generative AI journey. This guide is valuable for both experienced AI engineers and newcomers to the generative AI space, helping you use Amazon Bedrock to its fullest potential.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-solutions-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Netsertive built a scalable AI assistant to extract meaningful insights from real-time data using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how Netsertive introduced a generative AI-powered assistant into MLX, using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Nova, to bring their next generation of the platform to life.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-netsertive-built-a-scalable-ai-assistant-to-extract-meaningful-insights-from-real-time-data-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make videos accessible with automated audio descriptions using Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use services like Amazon Nova, Amazon Rekognition, and Amazon Polly to automate the creation of accessible audio descriptions for video content. This approach can significantly reduce the time and cost required to make videos accessible for visually impaired audiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/make-videos-accessible-with-automated-audio-descriptions-using-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Llama 3.3 Swallow: A Japanese sovereign LLM on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 15:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_06_2025/13_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Institute of Science Tokyo has successfully trained Llama 3.3 Swallow, a 70-billion-parameter large language model (LLM) with enhanced Japanese capabilities, using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod. The model demonstrates superior performance in Japanese language tasks, outperforming GPT-4o-mini and other leading models. This technical report details the training infrastructure, optimizations, and best practices developed during the project.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/training-llama-3-3-swallow-a-japanese-sovereign-llm-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Articul8’s domain-specific model development with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how Articul8 is redefining enterprise generative AI with domain-specific models that outperform general-purpose LLMs in real-world applications. In our latest blog post, we dive into how Amazon SageMaker HyperPod accelerated the development of Articul8’s industry-leading semiconductor model—achieving 2X higher accuracy that top open source models while slashing deployment time by 4X.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-articul8s-domain-specific-model-development-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How VideoAmp uses Amazon Bedrock to power their media analytics interface</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we illustrate how VideoAmp, a media measurement company, worked with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) team to develop a prototype of the VideoAmp Natural Language (NL) Analytics Chatbot to uncover meaningful insights at scale within media analytics data using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-videoamp-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-power-their-media-analytics-interface/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe enhances developer productivity using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Adobe partnered with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center, using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and the Vector Engine for Amazon OpenSearch Serverless. This solution dramatically improved their developer support system, resulting in a 20% increase in retrieval accuracy. In this post, we discuss the details of this solution and how Adobe enhances their developer productivity.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/adobe-enhances-developer-productivity-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Nova Lite enables Bito to offer a free tier option for its AI-powered code reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bito is an innovative startup that creates AI agents for a broad range of software developers. In this post, we share how Bito is able to offer a free tier option for its AI-powered code reviews using Amazon Nova.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-nova-lite-enables-bito-to-offer-a-free-tier-option-for-its-ai-powered-code-reviews/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Gardenia Technologies helps customers create ESG disclosure reports 75% faster using agentic generative AI on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Gardenia Technologies, a data analytics company, partnered with the AWS Prototyping and Cloud Engineering (PACE) team to develop Report GenAI, a fully automated ESG reporting solution powered by the latest generative AI models on Amazon Bedrock. This post dives deep into the technology behind an agentic search solution using tooling with Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and text-to-SQL capabilities to help customers reduce ESG reporting time by up to 75%. We demonstrate how AWS serverless technology, combined with agents in Amazon Bedrock, are used to build scalable and highly flexible agent-based document assistant applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Nemotron Super 49B and Nano 8B reasoning models now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Llama 3.3 Nemotron Super 49B V1 and Llama 3.1 Nemotron Nano 8B V1 are now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. With this launch, you can now deploy NVIDIA’s newest reasoning models to build, experiment, and responsibly scale your generative AI ideas on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/nvidia-nemotron-super-49b-and-nano-8b-reasoning-models-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate customer support with Amazon Bedrock, LangGraph, and Mistral models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock and LangGraph to build a personalized customer support experience for an ecommerce retailer. By integrating the Mistral Large 2 and Pixtral Large models, we guide you through automating key customer support workflows such as ticket categorization, order details extraction, damage assessment, and generating contextual responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-customer-support-with-amazon-bedrock-langgraph-and-mistral-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build responsible AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Bedrock Guardrails helps block harmful and undesirable multimodal content. Using a healthcare insurance call center scenario, we walk through the process of configuring and testing various guardrails.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-responsible-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective cost optimization strategies for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the increasing adoption of Amazon Bedrock, optimizing costs is a must to help keep the expenses associated with deploying and running generative AI applications manageable and aligned with your organization’s budget. In this post, you’ll learn about strategic cost optimization techniques while using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/effective-cost-optimization-strategies-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How E.ON saves £10 million annually with AI diagnostics for smart meters powered by Amazon Textract</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            E.ON’s story highlights how a creative application of Amazon Textract, combined with custom image analysis and pulse counting, can solve a real-world challenge at scale. By diagnosing smart meter errors through brief smartphone videos, E.ON aims to lower costs, improve customer satisfaction, and enhance overall energy service reliability. In this post, we dive into how this solution works and the impact it’s making.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-e-on-saves-10-million-annually-with-ai-diagnostics-for-smart-meters-powered-by-amazon-textract/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
