<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:55:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Detect Amazon Bedrock misconfigurations with Datadog Cloud Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce new security capabilities in Datadog Cloud Security that can help you detect and remediate Amazon Bedrock misconfigurations before they become security incidents. This integration helps organizations embed robust security controls and secure their use of the powerful capabilities of Amazon Bedrock by offering three critical advantages: holistic AI security by integrating AI security into your broader cloud security strategy, real-time risk detection through identifying potential AI-related security issues as they emerge, and simplified compliance to help meet evolving AI regulations with pre-built detections.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up custom domain names for Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to create custom domain names for your Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime agent endpoints using CloudFront as a reverse proxy. This solution provides several key benefits: simplified integration for development teams, custom domains that align with your organization, cleaner infrastructure abstraction, and straightforward maintenance when endpoints need updates.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/set-up-custom-domain-names-for-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing auto scaling on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we announce that Amazon SageMaker HyperPod now supports managed node automatic scaling with Karpenter, enabling efficient scaling of SageMaker HyperPod clusters to meet inference and training demands. We dive into the benefits of Karpenter and provide details on enabling and configuring Karpenter in SageMaker HyperPod EKS clusters.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-auto-scaling-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Boti: The AI assistant transforming how the citizens of Buenos Aires access government information with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes the agentic AI assistant built by the Government of the City of Buenos Aires and the GenAIIC to respond to citizens’ questions about government procedures. The solution consists of two primary components: an input guardrail system that helps prevent the system from responding to harmful user queries and a government procedures agent that retrieves relevant information and generates responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/meet-boti-the-ai-assistant-transforming-how-the-citizens-of-buenos-aires-access-government-information-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering air quality research with secure, ML-driven predictive analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a data imputation solution using Amazon SageMaker AI, AWS Lambda, and AWS Step Functions. This solution is designed for environmental analysts, public health officials, and business intelligence professionals who need reliable PM2.5 data for trend analysis, reporting, and decision-making. We sourced our sample training dataset from openAFRICA. Our solution predicts PM2.5 values using time-series forecasting.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/empowering-air-quality-research-with-secure-ml-driven-predictive-analytics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Finance built an AI assistant using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Kendra to support analysts for data discovery and business insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Amazon Finance technical team develops and manages comprehensive technology solutions that power financial decision-making and operational efficiency while standardizing across Amazon’s global operations. In this post, we explain how the team conceptualized and implemented a solution to these business challenges by harnessing the power of generative AI using Amazon Bedrock and intelligent search with Amazon Kendra.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-finance-built-an-ai-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-kendra-to-support-analysts-for-data-discovery-and-business-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercury foundation models from Inception Labs are now available in Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 15:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we announce that Mercury and Mercury Coder foundation models from Inception Labs are now available through Amazon Bedrock Marketplace and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. We demonstrate how to deploy these ultra-fast diffusion-based language models that can generate up to 1,100 tokens per second on NVIDIA H100 GPUs, and showcase their capabilities in code generation and tool use scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/mercury-foundation-models-from-inception-labs-are-now-available-in-amazon-bedrock-marketplace-and-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn how Amazon Health Services improved discovery in Amazon search using AWS ML and gen AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2025/26_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Amazon Health Services (AHS) solved discoverability challenges on Amazon.com search using AWS services such as Amazon SageMaker, Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon EMR. By combining machine learning (ML), natural language processing, and vector search capabilities, we improved our ability to connect customers with relevant healthcare offerings.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/learn-how-amazon-health-services-improved-discovery-in-amazon-search-using-aws-ml-and-gen-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Geospatial Analysis and GIS Workflows with Amazon Bedrock Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Applying emerging technologies to the geospatial domain offers a unique opportunity to create transformative user experiences and intuitive workstreams for users and organizations to deliver on their missions and responsibilities. In this post, we explore how you can integrate existing systems with Amazon Bedrock to create new workflows to unlock efficiencies insights. This integration can benefit technical, nontechnical, and leadership roles alike.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-geospatial-analysis-and-gis-workflows-with-amazon-bedrock-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the basics: A comprehensive foundation model selection framework for generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the model landscape expands, organizations face complex scenarios when selecting the right foundation model for their applications. In this blog post we present a systematic evaluation methodology for Amazon Bedrock users, combining theoretical frameworks with practical implementation strategies that empower data scientists and machine learning (ML) engineers to make optimal model selections.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/beyond-the-basics-a-comprehensive-foundation-model-selection-framework-for-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate intelligent document processing with generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce our open source GenAI IDP Accelerator—a tested solution that we use to help customers across industries address their document processing challenges. Automated document processing workflows accurately extract structured information from documents, reducing manual effort. We will show you how this ready-to-deploy solution can help you build those workflows with generative AI on AWS in days instead of months.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-intelligent-document-processing-with-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker HyperPod enhances ML infrastructure with scalability and customizability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_08_2025/22_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduced three features in SageMaker HyperPod that enhance scalability and customizability for ML infrastructure. Continuous provisioning offers flexible resource provisioning to help you start training and deploying your models faster and manage your cluster more efficiently. With custom AMIs, you can align your ML environments with organizational security standards and software requirements.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-enhances-ml-infrastructure-with-scalability-and-customizability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
