<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 19:01:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock now supports custom prompts for the RetrieveAndGenerate API and configuration of the maximum number of retrieved results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2024/09_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 19:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2024/09_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, you can securely connect foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock to your company data for Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). Access to additional data helps the model generate more relevant, context-specific, and accurate responses without retraining the FMs. In this post, we discuss two new features of Knowledge Bases for […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-now-supports-custom-prompts-for-the-retrieveandgenerate-api-and-configuration-of-the-maximum-number-of-retrieved-results/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock now supports metadata filtering to improve retrieval accuracy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 19:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At AWS re:Invent 2023, we announced the general availability of Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock. With Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, you can securely connect foundation models (FMs) in Amazon Bedrock to your company data using a fully managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) model. For RAG-based applications, the accuracy of the generated responses from FMs […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-now-supports-metadata-filtering-to-improve-retrieval-accuracy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build knowledge-powered conversational applications using LlamaIndex and Llama 2-Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 17:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unlocking accurate and insightful answers from vast amounts of text is an exciting capability enabled by large language models (LLMs). When building LLM applications, it is often necessary to connect and query external data sources to provide relevant context to the model. One popular approach is using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to create Q&amp;amp;A systems […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-knowledge-powered-conversational-applications-using-llamaindex-and-llama-2-chat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use everyday language to search and retrieve data with Mixtral 8x7B on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 16:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the widespread adoption of generative artificial intelligence (AI) solutions, organizations are trying to use these technologies to make their teams more productive. One exciting use case is enabling natural language interactions with relational databases. Rather than writing complex SQL queries, you can describe in plain language what data you want to retrieve or manipulate. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-everyday-language-to-search-and-retrieve-data-with-mixtral-8x7b-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost inference performance for Mixtral and Llama 2 models with new Amazon SageMaker containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 16:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_04_2024/08_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In January 2024, Amazon SageMaker launched a new version (0.26.0) of Large Model Inference (LMI) Deep Learning Containers (DLCs). This version offers support for new models (including Mixture of Experts), performance and usability improvements across inference backends, as well as new generation details for increased control and prediction explainability (such as reason for generation completion […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-inference-performance-for-mixtral-and-llama-2-models-with-new-amazon-sagemaker-containers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Content Moderation with Amazon Rekognition Bulk Analysis and Custom Moderation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 18:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Rekognition makes it easy to add image and video analysis to your applications. It’s based on the same proven, highly scalable, deep learning technology developed by Amazon’s computer vision scientists to analyze billions of images and videos daily. It requires no machine learning (ML) expertise to use and we’re continually adding new computer vision […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improving-content-moderation-with-amazon-rekognition-bulk-analysis-and-custom-moderation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and predicting urban heat islands at Gramener using Amazon SageMaker geospatial capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 16:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_04_2024/05_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-authored by Shravan Kumar and Avirat S from Gramener. Gramener, a Straive company, contributes to sustainable development by focusing on agriculture, forestry, water management, and renewable energy. By providing authorities with the tools and insights they need to make informed decisions about environmental and social impact, Gramener is playing a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/understanding-and-predicting-urban-heat-islands-at-gramener-using-amazon-sagemaker-geospatial-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a news recommender application with Amazon Personalize</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 17:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With a multitude of articles, videos, audio recordings, and other media created daily across news media companies, readers of all types—individual consumers, corporate subscribers, and more—often find it difficult to find news content that is most relevant to them. Delivering personalized news and experiences to readers can help solve this problem, and create more engaging […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-news-recommender-application-with-amazon-personalize/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nielsen Sports sees 75% cost reduction in video analysis with Amazon SageMaker multi-model endpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 16:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with Tamir Rubinsky and Aviad Aranias from Nielsen Sports. Nielsen Sports shapes the world’s media and content as a global leader in audience insights, data, and analytics. Through our understanding of people and their behaviors across all channels and platforms, we empower our clients with independent and actionable intelligence […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/nielsen-sports-sees-75-cost-reduction-in-video-analysis-with-amazon-sagemaker-multi-model-endpoints/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seamlessly transition between no-code and code-first machine learning with Amazon SageMaker Canvas and Amazon SageMaker Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 17:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Studio is a web-based, integrated development environment (IDE) for machine learning (ML) that lets you build, train, debug, deploy, and monitor your ML models. SageMaker Studio provides all the tools you need to take your models from data preparation to experimentation to production while boosting your productivity. Amazon SageMaker Canvas is a powerful […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/seamlessly-transition-between-no-code-and-code-first-machine-learning-with-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-and-amazon-sagemaker-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a contextual text and image search engine for product recommendations using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 15:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to build a contextual text and image search engine for product recommendations using the Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings model, available in Amazon Bedrock, with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-contextual-text-and-image-search-engine-for-product-recommendations-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-opensearch-serverless/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS and Mistral AI commit to democratizing generative AI with a strengthened collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 04:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_04_2024/03_04_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, Mistral AI is bringing its latest and most capable model, Mistral Large, to Amazon Bedrock, and is committed to making future models accessible to AWS customers. Mistral AI will also use AWS AI-optimized AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia to build and deploy its future foundation models on Amazon Bedrock, benefitting from the price, performance, scale, and security of AWS. Along with this announcement, starting today, customers can use Amazon Bedrock in the AWS Europe (Paris) Region.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient makes LLM benchmarking cost-effective and effortless with AWS Inferentia</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 16:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with Michael Feil at Gradient. Evaluating the performance of large language models (LLMs) is an important step of the pre-training and fine-tuning process before deployment. The faster and more frequent you’re able to validate performance, the higher the chances you’ll be able to improve the performance of the model. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/gradient-makes-llm-benchmarking-cost-effective-and-effortless-with-aws-inferentia/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable single sign-on access of Amazon SageMaker Canvas using AWS IAM Identity Center: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 16:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Canvas allows you to use machine learning (ML) to generate predictions without having to write any code. It does so by covering the end-to-end ML workflow: whether you’re looking for powerful data preparation and AutoML, managed endpoint deployment, simplified MLOps capabilities, or the ability to configure foundation models for generative AI, SageMaker Canvas […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enable-single-sign-on-access-of-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-using-aws-iam-identity-center-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar models from Upstage are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 15:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2024/02_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post is co-written with Hwalsuk Lee at Upstage. Today, we’re excited to announce that the Solar foundation model developed by Upstage is now available for customers using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. Solar is a large language model (LLM) 100% pre-trained with Amazon SageMaker that outperforms and uses its compact size and powerful track records […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/solar-models-from-upstage-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
