<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:20:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless AI Gateway architecture with AWS AppSync Events</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to use AppSync Events as the foundation of a capable, serverless, AI gateway architecture. We explore how it integrates with AWS services for comprehensive coverage of the capabilities offered in AI gateway architectures. Finally, we get you started on your journey with sample code you can launch in your account and begin building.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-ai-gateway-architecture-with-aws-appsync-events/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Totogi automated change request processing with Totogi BSS Magic and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post describes how Totogi automates change request processing by partnering with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center and using the rapid innovation capabilities of Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-totogi-automated-change-request-processing-with-totogi-bss-magic-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI agents with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore using AWS CloudFormation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock AgentCore services are now being supported by various IaC frameworks such as AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), Terraform and AWS CloudFormation Templates. This integration brings the power of IaC directly to AgentCore so developers can provision, configure, and manage their AI agent infrastructure. In this post, we use CloudFormation templates to build an end-to-end application for a weather activity planner.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-ai-agents-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-using-aws-cloudformation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Amazon.com Catalog Team built self-learning generative AI at scale with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how the Amazon Catalog Team built a self-learning system that continuously improves accuracy while reducing costs at scale using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-the-amazon-com-catalog-team-built-self-learning-generative-ai-at-scale-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PDI built an enterprise-grade RAG system for AI applications with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            PDI Technologies is a global leader in the convenience retail and petroleum wholesale industries. In this post, we walk through the PDI Intelligence Query (PDIQ) process flow and architecture, focusing on the implementation details and the business outcomes it has helped PDI achieve.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-pdi-built-an-enterprise-grade-rag-system-for-ai-applications-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How CLICKFORCE accelerates data-driven advertising with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how CLICKFORCE used AWS services to build Lumos and transform advertising industry analysis from weeks-long manual work into an automated, one-hour process.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-clickforce-accelerates-data-driven-advertising-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Thomson Reuters built an Agentic Platform Engineering Hub with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post explains how TR&#39;s Platform Engineering team, a geographically distributed unit overseeing TR&#39;s service availability, boosted its operational productivity by transitioning from manual to an automated agentic system using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-thomson-reuters-built-an-agentic-platform-engineering-hub-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build agents to learn from experiences using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore episodic memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through the complete architecture to structure and store episodes, discuss the reflection module, and share compelling benchmarks that demonstrate significant improvements in agent task success rates.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-agents-to-learn-from-experiences-using-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-episodic-memory/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How bunq handles 97% of support with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how bunq upgraded Finn, its in-house generative AI assistant, using Amazon Bedrock to transform user support and banking operations to be seamless, in multiple languages and time zones.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-bunq-handles-97-of-support-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Strands Agents to create a multi-agent solution with Meta’s Llama 4 and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to build a multi-agent video processing workflow using Strands Agents, Meta&#39;s Llama 4 models, and Amazon Bedrock to automatically analyze and understand video content through specialized AI agents working in coordination. To showcase the solution, we will use Amazon SageMaker AI to walk you through the code.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-strands-agents-to-create-a-multi-agent-solution-with-metas-llama-4-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing multimodal retrieval for Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll guide you through building multimodal RAG applications. You&#39;ll learn how multimodal knowledge bases work, how to choose the right processing strategy based on your content type, and how to configure and implement multimodal retrieval using both the console and code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-multimodal-retrieval-for-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
