<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 20:43:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Improve governance of models with Amazon SageMaker unified Model Cards and Model Registry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 20:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now register machine learning (ML) models in Amazon SageMaker Model Registry with Amazon SageMaker Model Cards, making it straightforward to manage governance information for specific model versions directly in SageMaker Model Registry in just a few clicks. In this post, we discuss a new feature that supports the integration of model cards with the model registry. We discuss the solution architecture and best practices for managing model cards with a registered model version, and walk through how to set up, operationalize, and govern your models using the integration in the model registry.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribe, translate, and summarize live streams in your browser with AWS AI and generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the approach behind building an AWS AI-powered Chrome extension that aims to revolutionize the live streaming experience by providing real-time transcription, translation, and summarization capabilities directly within your browser.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transcribe-translate-and-summarize-live-streams-in-your-browser-with-aws-ai-and-generative-ai-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your financial statement analysis with Amazon Bedrock and generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy a generative AI application that can accelerate your financial statement analysis on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-your-financial-statement-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock-and-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual content processing using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon A2I</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post outlines a custom multilingual document extraction and content assessment framework using a combination of Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock and Amazon A2I to incorporate human-in-the-loop capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multilingual-content-processing-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-a2i/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a reverse image search engine with Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings in Amazon Bedrock and AWS managed services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to extract key objects from image queries using Amazon Rekognition and build a reverse image search engine using Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings from Amazon Bedrock in combination with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless Service.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-reverse-image-search-engine-with-amazon-titan-multimodal-embeddings-in-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-managed-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI for agriculture: How Agmatix is improving agriculture with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes how Agmatix, a pioneering Agtech company powering R&amp;amp;D for input companies and digital agronomic solutions, uses Amazon Bedrock and AWS fully featured services to enhance the research process and development of higher-yielding seeds and sustainable molecules for global agriculture.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generative-ai-for-agriculture-how-agmatix-is-improving-agriculture-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate financial industry-specific insights using generative AI and in-context fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we demonstrate prompt engineering techniques to generate accurate and relevant analysis of tabular data using industry-specific language. This is done by providing large language models (LLMs) in-context sample data with features and labels in the prompt. The results are similar to fine-tuning LLMs without the complexities of fine-tuning models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-financial-industry-specific-insights-using-generative-ai-and-in-context-fine-tuning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliver personalized marketing with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Bedrock Developer Experience, and Amazon Personalize that allow marketers to save time and deliver efficient personalized advertising using a generative AI enhanced solution. Our solution is a marketing agent that shows how Amazon Personalize can effectively segment target customers based on relevant characteristics and behaviors. Additionally, by using Amazon Bedrock Agents and foundation models (FMs), our tool generates personalized creative content specifically tailored to each purpose.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Meta Llama 3.2 text generation models for generative AI inference using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 17:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to fine-tune Meta’s latest Llama 3.2 text generation models, Llama 3.2 1B and 3B, using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart for domain-specific applications. By using the pre-built solutions available in SageMaker JumpStart and the customizable Meta Llama 3.2 models, you can unlock the models’ enhanced reasoning, code generation, and instruction-following capabilities to tailor them for your unique use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-meta-llama-3-2-text-generation-models-for-generative-ai-inference-using-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights with the Amazon Q Business Microsoft Teams connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 17:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2024/11_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Teams is an enterprise collaboration tool that allows you to build a unified workspace for real-time collaboration and communication, meetings, and file and application sharing. You can exchange and store valuable organizational knowledge within Microsoft Teams. Microsoft Teams data is often siloed across different teams, channels, and chats, making it difficult to get a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-with-the-amazon-q-business-microsoft-teams-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Prompt Management is now available in GA</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 22:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Prompt Management, with new features that provide enhanced options for configuring your prompts and enabling seamless integration for invoking them in your generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-prompt-management-is-now-available-in-ga/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Zalando optimized large-scale inference and streamlined ML operations on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is cowritten with Mones Raslan, Ravi Sharma and Adele Gouttes from Zalando. Zalando SE is one of Europe’s largest ecommerce fashion retailers with around 50 million active customers. Zalando faces the challenge of regular (weekly or daily) discount steering for more than 1 million products, also referred to as markdown pricing. Markdown pricing is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-zalando-optimized-large-scale-inference-and-streamlined-ml-operations-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing Stability AI’s most advanced text-to-image models for media, marketing and advertising: Revolutionizing creative workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To stay competitive, media, advertising, and entertainment enterprises need to stay abreast of recent dramatic technological developments. Generative AI has emerged as a game-changer, offering unprecedented opportunities for creative professionals to push boundaries and unlock new realms of possibility. At the forefront of this revolution is Stability AI’s family of cutting-edge text-to-image AI models. These […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleashing-stability-ais-most-advanced-text-to-image-models-for-media-marketing-and-advertising-revolutionizing-creative-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a multi-tenant generative AI environment for your enterprise on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While organizations continue to discover the powerful applications of generative AI, adoption is often slowed down by team silos and bespoke workflows. To move faster, enterprises need robust operating models and a holistic approach that simplifies the generative AI lifecycle. In the first part of the series, we showed how AI administrators can build a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-multi-tenant-generative-ai-environment-for-your-enterprise-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance customer support with Amazon Bedrock Agents by integrating enterprise data APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2024/07_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has transformed customer support, offering businesses the ability to respond faster, more accurately, and with greater personalization. AI agents, powered by large language models (LLMs), can analyze complex customer inquiries, access multiple data sources, and deliver relevant, detailed responses. In this post, we guide you through integrating Amazon Bedrock Agents with enterprise data […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-customer-support-with-amazon-bedrock-agents-by-integrating-enterprise-data-apis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
