<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:31:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visier’s data science team boosts their model output 10 times by migrating to Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we learn how Visier was able to boost their model output by 10 times, accelerate innovation cycles, and unlock new opportunities using Amazon SageMaker.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/visiers-data-science-team-boosts-their-model-output-10-times-by-migrating-to-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement model-independent safety measures with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2024/03_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how you can use the ApplyGuardrail API in common generative AI architectures such as third-party or self-hosted large language models (LLMs), or in a self-managed Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) architecture.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/implement-model-independent-safety-measures-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Schneider Electric uses Amazon Bedrock to identify high-potential business opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 20:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how the team at Schneider collaborated with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center (GenAIIC) to build a generative AI solution on Amazon Bedrock to solve this problem. The solution processes and evaluates each requests for proposal (RFP) and then routes high-value RFPs to the microgrid subject matter expert (SME) for approval and recommendation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-schneider-electric-uses-amazon-bedrock-to-identify-high-potential-business-opportunities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieve operational excellence with well-architected generative AI solutions using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss scaling up generative AI for different lines of businesses (LOBs) and address the challenges that come around legal, compliance, operational complexities, data privacy and security.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/achieve-operational-excellence-with-well-architected-generative-ai-solutions-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate workforce productivity through seamless personalization in Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Q Business uses personalization to improve the relevance of responses and how you can align your use cases and end-user data to take full advantage of this capability
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-workforce-productivity-through-seamless-personalization-in-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for building robust generative AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Agents – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2024/02_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to create accurate and reliable agents. Agents helps you accelerate generative AI application development by orchestrating multistep tasks. Agents use the reasoning capability of foundation models (FMs) to break down user-requested tasks into multiple steps.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-practices-for-building-robust-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-agents-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS recognized as a first-time Leader in the 2024 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 18:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS has been recognized as a Leader in the 2024 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Data Science and Machine Learning Platforms. The post highlights how AWS&#39;s continued innovations in services like Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker have enabled organizations to unlock the transformative potential of generative AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-recognized-as-a-first-time-leader-in-the-2024-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-data-science-and-machine-learning-platforms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless voice-based contextual chatbot for people with disabilities using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we presented how to create a fully serverless voice-based contextual chatbot using Amazon Bedrock with Anthropic Claude.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-voice-based-contextual-chatbot-for-people-with-disabilities-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintain access and consider alternatives for Amazon Monitron</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2024/01_10_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses how customers can maintain access to Amazon Monitron after it is closed to new customers and what some alternatives are to Amazon Monitron.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maintain-access-and-consider-alternatives-for-amazon-monitron/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import a question answering fine-tuned model into Amazon Bedrock as a custom model</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a step-by-step approach of fine-tuning a Mistral model using SageMaker and import it into Amazon Bedrock using the Custom Import Model feature.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/import-a-question-answering-fine-tuned-model-into-amazon-bedrock-as-a-custom-model/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using task-specific models from AI21 Labs on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2024/30_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will show you how to leverage AI21 Labs’ Task-Specific Models (TSMs) on AWS to enhance your business operations. You will learn the steps to subscribe to AI21 Labs in the AWS Marketplace, set up a domain in Amazon SageMaker, and utilize AI21 TSMs via SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-task-specific-models-from-ai21-labs-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture to AWS CloudFormation code using Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 21:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore some ways you can use Anthropic’s Claude 3 Sonnet’s vision capabilities to accelerate the process of moving from architecture to the prototype stage of a solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/architecture-to-aws-cloudformation-code-using-anthropics-claude-3-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Northpower used computer vision with AWS to automate safety inspection risk assessments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 21:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_09_2024/27_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Northpower has worked with their technology partner Sculpt to reduce the effort and carbon required to identify and remediate public safety risks. Specifically, we cover the computer vision and artificial intelligence (AI) techniques used to combine datasets into a list of prioritized tasks for field teams to investigate and mitigate.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-northpower-used-computer-vision-with-aws-to-automate-safety-inspection-risk-assessments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenAI for Aerospace: Empowering the workforce with expert knowledge on Amazon Q and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 18:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we show how you can quickly launch generative AI-enabled expert chatbots, trained on your proprietary document sets, to empower your workforce across specific aerospace roles with Amazon Q and Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/genai-for-aerospace-empowering-the-workforce-with-expert-knowledge-on-amazon-q-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable training platform with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod for innovation: a video generation case study</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 18:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share an ML infrastructure architecture that uses SageMaker HyperPod to support research team innovation in video generation. We will discuss the advantages and pain points addressed by SageMaker HyperPod, provide a step-by-step setup guide, and demonstrate how to run a video generation algorithm on the cluster.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scalable-training-platform-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-for-innovation-a-video-generation-case-study/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control data access to Amazon S3 from Amazon SageMaker Studio with Amazon S3 Access Grants</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2024/26_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to simplify data access to Amazon S3 from SageMaker Studio using S3 Access Grants, specifically for different user personas using IAM principals.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/control-data-access-to-amazon-s3-from-amazon-sagemaker-studio-with-amazon-s3-access-grants/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
