<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:33:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Amazon Bedrock batch inference using Amazon CloudWatch metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to monitor and manage Amazon Bedrock batch inference jobs using Amazon CloudWatch metrics, alarms, and dashboards to optimize performance, cost, and operational efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/monitor-amazon-bedrock-batch-inference-using-amazon-cloudwatch-metrics/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use AWS Deep Learning Containers with Amazon SageMaker AI managed MLflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to integrate AWS DLCs with MLflow to create a solution that balances infrastructure control with robust ML governance. We walk through a functional setup that your team can use to meet your specialized requirements while significantly reducing the time and resources needed for ML lifecycle management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-aws-deep-learning-containers-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-managed-mlflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your organization’s productivity with the Amazon Q Business browser extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showed how to use the Amazon Q Business browser extension to give your team seamless access to AI-driven insights and assistance. The browser extension is now available in US East (N. Virginia) and US West (Oregon) AWS Regions for Mozilla, Google Chrome, and Microsoft Edge as part of the Lite Subscription.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/supercharge-your-organizations-productivity-with-the-amazon-q-business-browser-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Agentic Workflows with OpenAI GPT OSS on Amazon SageMaker AI and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2025/17_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to deploy gpt-oss-20b model to SageMaker managed endpoints and demonstrate a practical stock analyzer agent assistant example with LangGraph, a powerful graph-based framework that handles state management, coordinated workflows, and persistent memory systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-agentic-workflows-with-openai-gpt-oss-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline access to ISO-rating content changes with Verisk rating insights and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into how Verisk Rating Insights, powered by Amazon Bedrock, large language models (LLM), and Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), is transforming the way customers interact with and access ISO ERC changes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-access-to-iso-rating-content-changes-with-verisk-rating-insights-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unified multimodal access layer for Quora’s Poe using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2025/16_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center and Quora collaborated to build a unified wrapper API framework that dramatically accelerates the deployment of Amazon Bedrock FMs on Quora’s Poe system. We detail the technical architecture that bridges Poe’s event-driven ServerSentEvents protocol with Amazon Bedrock REST-based APIs, demonstrate how a template-based configuration system reduced deployment time from days to 15 minutes, and share implementation patterns for protocol translation, error handling, and multi-modal capabilities.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule topology-aware workloads using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod task governance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce topology-aware scheduling with SageMaker HyperPod task governance by submitting jobs that represent hierarchical network information. We provide details about how to use SageMaker HyperPod task governance to optimize your job efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/schedule-topology-aware-workloads-using-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-task-governance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How msg enhanced HR workforce transformation with Amazon Bedrock and msg.ProfileMap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_09_2025/15_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how msg automated data harmonization for msg.ProfileMap, using Amazon Bedrock to power its large language model (LLM)-driven data enrichment workflows, resulting in higher accuracy in HR concept matching, reduced manual workload, and improved alignment with compliance requirements under the EU AI Act and GDPR.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-msg-enhanced-hr-workforce-transformation-with-amazon-bedrock-and-msg-profilemap/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate advanced agentic RAG pipeline with Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how to streamline your RAG development lifecycle from experimentation to automation, helping you operationalize your RAG solution for production deployments with Amazon SageMaker AI, helping your team experiment efficiently, collaborate effectively, and drive continuous improvement.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-advanced-agentic-rag-pipeline-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock model insights with log probability support for Amazon Bedrock Custom Model Import</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how log probabilities work with imported models in Amazon Bedrock. You will learn what log probabilities are, how to enable them in your API calls, and how to interpret the returned data. We also highlight practical applications—from detecting potential hallucinations to optimizing RAG systems and evaluating fine-tuned models—that demonstrate how these insights can improve your AI applications, helping you build more trustworthy solutions with your custom models.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet to Claude 4 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2025/12_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post provides a systematic approach to migrating from Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet to Claude 4 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock. We examine the key model differences, highlight essential migration considerations, and deliver proven best practices to transform this necessary transition into a strategic advantage that drives measurable value for your organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/migrate-from-anthropics-claude-3-5-sonnet-to-claude-4-sonnet-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance video understanding with Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and open-set object detection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In real-world video and image analysis, businesses often face the challenge of detecting objects that weren’t part of a model’s original training set. This becomes especially difficult in dynamic environments where new, unknown, or user-defined objects frequently appear. In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock Data Automation uses OSOD to enhance video understanding.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-video-understanding-with-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-open-set-object-detection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Skello uses Amazon Bedrock to query data in a multi-tenant environment while keeping logical boundaries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Skello is a leading human resources (HR) software as a service (SaaS) solution focusing on employee scheduling and workforce management. Catering to diverse sectors such as hospitality, retail, healthcare, construction, and industry, Skello offers features including schedule creation, time tracking, and payroll preparation. We dive deep into the challenges of implementing large language models (LLMs) for data querying, particularly in the context of a French company operating under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a private workforce on Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth with the AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2025/11_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a complete solution for programmatically creating private workforces on Amazon SageMaker AI using the AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), including the setup of a dedicated, fully configured Amazon Cognito user pool.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-private-workforce-on-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-with-the-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
