<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 15:03:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enable Amazon Bedrock cross-Region inference in multi-account environments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 15:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to modify your Regional access controls to specifically allow Amazon Bedrock cross-Region inference while maintaining broader Regional restrictions for other AWS services. We provide practical examples for both SCP modifications and AWS Control Tower implementations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enable-amazon-bedrock-cross-region-inference-in-multi-account-environments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker JumpStart adds fine-tuning support for models in a private model hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 16:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are announcing an enhanced private hub feature with several new capabilities that give organizations greater control over their ML assets. These enhancements include the ability to fine-tune SageMaker JumpStart models directly within the private hub, support for adding and managing custom-trained models, deep linking capabilities for associated notebooks, and improved model version management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-adds-fine-tuning-support-for-models-in-a-private-model-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI-powered game design: Accelerating early development with Stability AI models on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 14:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has emerged as a game changer, offering unprecedented opportunities for game designers to push boundaries and create immersive virtual worlds. At the forefront of this revolution is Stability AI’s cutting-edge text-to-image AI model, Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large (SD3.5 Large), which is transforming the way we approach game environment creation. In this post, we explore how you can use SD3.5 Large to address practical gaming needs such as early concept art and character design.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock launches Session Management APIs for generative AI applications (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 22:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock announces the preview launch of Session Management APIs, a new capability that enables developers to simplify state and context management for generative AI applications built with popular open source frameworks such as LangGraph and LlamaIndex. Session Management APIs provide an out-of-the-box solution that enables developers to securely manage state and conversation context across […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-launches-session-management-apis-for-generative-ai-applications-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance deployment guardrails with inference component rolling updates for Amazon SageMaker AI inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 21:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss the challenges faced by organizations when updating models in production. Then we deep dive into the new rolling update feature for inference components and provide practical examples using DeepSeek distilled models to demonstrate this feature. Finally, we explore how to set up rolling updates in different scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-deployment-guardrails-with-inference-component-rolling-updates-for-amazon-sagemaker-ai-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate and improve performance of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to evaluate the performance of your knowledge base, including the metrics and data to use for evaluation. We also address some of the tactics and configuration changes that can improve specific metrics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-and-improve-performance-of-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance enterprise productivity for your LLM solution by becoming an Amazon Q Business data accessor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to enhance enterprise productivity for your large language model (LLM) solution by using the Amazon Q index for ISVs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-enterprise-productivity-for-your-llm-solution-by-becoming-an-amazon-q-business-data-accessor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI enabled virtual IT troubleshooting assistant using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how to build a GenAI powered virtual IT troubleshooting assistant using Amazon Q Business. This innovative solution integrates with popular ITSM tools like ServiceNow, Atlassian Jira, and Confluence to streamline information retrieval and enhance collaboration across your organization. By harnessing the power of generative AI, this assistant can significantly boost operational efficiency and provide 24/7 support tailored to individual needs. Learn how to set up, configure, and leverage this solution to transform your enterprise information management.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process formulas and charts with Anthropic’s Claude on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how you can use these multi-modal generative AI models to streamline the management of technical documents. By extracting and structuring the key information from the source materials, the models can create a searchable knowledge base that allows you to quickly locate the data, formulas, and visualizations you need to support your work.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/process-formulas-and-charts-with-anthropics-claude-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate IT operations with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a comprehensive AIOps solution that combines various AWS services such as Amazon Bedrock, AWS Lambda, and Amazon CloudWatch to create an AI assistant for effective incident management. This solution also uses Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon Bedrock Agents. The solution uses the power of Amazon Bedrock to enable the deployment of intelligent agents capable of monitoring IT systems, analyzing logs and metrics, and invoking automated remediation processes.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline AWS resource troubleshooting with Amazon Bedrock Agents and AWS Support Automation Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS provides a powerful tool called AWS Support Automation Workflows, which is a collection of curated AWS Systems Manager self-service automation runbooks. These runbooks are created by AWS Support Engineering with best practices learned from solving customer issues. They enable AWS customers to troubleshoot, diagnose, and remediate common issues with their AWS resources. In this post, we explore how to use the power of Amazon Bedrock Agents and AWS Support Automation Workflows to create an intelligent agent capable of troubleshooting issues with AWS resources.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create generative AI agents that interact with your companies’ systems in a few clicks using Amazon Bedrock in Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock in SageMaker Unified Studio to build a generative AI application to integrate with an existing endpoint and database.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-generative-ai-agents-that-interact-with-your-companies-systems-in-a-few-clicks-using-amazon-bedrock-in-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asure’s approach to enhancing their call center experience using generative AI and Amazon Q in Quicksight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore why Asure used the Amazon Web Services (AWS) post-call analytics (PCA) pipeline that generated insights across call centers at scale with the advanced capabilities of generative AI-powered services such as Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Q in QuickSight. Asure chose this approach because it provided in-depth consumer analytics, categorized call transcripts around common themes, and empowered contact center leaders to use natural language to answer queries. This ultimately allowed Asure to provide its customers with improvements in product and customer experiences.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the multimodal power of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation to transform unstructured data into actionable insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we&#39;re excited to announce the general availability of Amazon Bedrock Data Automation, a powerful, fully managed capability within Amazon Bedrock that seamlessly transforms unstructured multimodal data into structured, application-ready insights with high accuracy, cost efficiency, and scalability.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleashing-the-multimodal-power-of-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-to-transform-unstructured-data-into-actionable-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
