<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 20:22:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Amazon Bedrock Data Automation capabilities streamline video and audio analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 20:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Data Automation helps organizations streamline development and boost efficiency through customizable, multimodal analytics. It eliminates the heavy lifting of unstructured content processing at scale, whether for video or audio. The new capabilities make it faster to extract tailored, generative AI-powered insights like scene summaries, key topics, and customer intents from video and audio. This unlocks the value of unstructured content for use cases such as improving sales productivity and enhancing customer experience.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GuardianGamer scales family-safe cloud gaming with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 16:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how GuardianGamer uses AWS services including Amazon Nova and Amazon Bedrock to deliver a scalable and efficient supervision platform. The team uses Amazon Nova for intelligent narrative generation to provide parents with meaningful insights into their children’s gaming activities and social interactions, while maintaining a non-intrusive approach to monitoring.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/guardiangamer-scales-family-safe-cloud-gaming-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principal Financial Group increases Voice Virtual Assistant performance using Genesys, Amazon Lex, and Amazon QuickSight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 16:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Principal used this opportunity to build an integrated voice VA reporting and analytics solution using an Amazon QuickSight dashboard.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/principal-financial-group-increases-voice-virtual-assistant-performance-using-genesys-amazon-lex-and-amazon-quicksight/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize query responses with user feedback using Amazon Bedrock embedding and few-shot prompting</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 16:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how Amazon Bedrock, combined with a user feedback dataset and few-shot prompting, can refine responses for higher user satisfaction. By using Amazon Titan Text Embeddings v2, we demonstrate a statistically significant improvement in response quality, making it a valuable tool for applications seeking accurate and personalized responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimize-query-responses-with-user-feedback-using-amazon-bedrock-embedding-and-few-shot-prompting/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting team productivity with Amazon Q Business Microsoft 365 integrations for Microsoft 365 Outlook and Word</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 15:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business integration with Microsoft 365 applications offers powerful AI assistance directly within the tools that your team already uses daily. In this post, we explore how these integrations for Outlook and Word can transform your workflow.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boosting-team-productivity-with-amazon-q-business-microsoft-365-integrations-for-microsoft-365-outlook-and-word/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Amazon Bedrock Agents with Slack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a solution to incorporate Amazon Bedrock Agents in your Slack workspace. We guide you through configuring a Slack workspace, deploying integration components in Amazon Web Services, and using this solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-amazon-bedrock-agents-with-slack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure distributed logging in scalable multi-account deployments using Amazon Bedrock and LangChain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 16:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_05_2025/21_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a solution for securing distributed logging multi-account deployments using Amazon Bedrock and LangChain.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/secure-distributed-logging-in-scalable-multi-account-deployments-using-amazon-bedrock-and-langchain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a domain‐aware data preprocessing pipeline: A multi‐agent collaboration approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce a multi-agent collaboration pipeline for processing unstructured insurance data using Amazon Bedrock, featuring specialized agents for classification, conversion, and metadata extraction. We demonstrate how this domain-aware approach transforms diverse data formats like claims documents, videos, and audio files into metadata-rich outputs that enable fraud detection, customer 360-degree views, and advanced analytics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-domain%E2%80%90aware-data-preprocessing-pipeline-a-multi%E2%80%90agent-collaboration-approach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating complex document processing: How Onity Group built an intelligent solution using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Onity Group, a financial services company specializing in mortgage servicing and origination, transformed their document processing capabilities using Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services. The solution helped Onity achieve a 50% reduction in document extraction costs while improving overall accuracy by 20% compared to their previous OCR and AI/ML solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automating-complex-document-processing-how-onity-group-built-an-intelligent-solution-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
