<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 22:26:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Generative AI Inference with NVIDIA NIM Microservices on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 22:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a walkthrough of how customers can use generative artificial intelligence (AI) models and LLMs using NVIDIA NIM integration with SageMaker. We demonstrate how this integration works and how you can deploy these state-of-the-art models on SageMaker, optimizing their performance and cost.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-started-with-nvidia-nim-inference-microservices-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the final AWS DeepRacer  League championship and road ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 19:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AWS DeepRacer League is the world’s first autonomous racing league, open to everyone and powered by machine learning (ML). AWS DeepRacer brings builders together from around the world, creating a community where you learn ML hands-on through friendly autonomous racing competitions. As we celebrate the achievements of over 560,000 participants from more than 150 countries who sharpened their skills through the AWS DeepRacer League over the last 6 years, we also prepare to close this chapter with a final season that serves as both a victory lap and a launching point for what’s next in the world of AWS DeepRacer.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide a personalized experience for news readers using Amazon Personalize and Amazon Titan Text Embeddings on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2024/29_08_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how you can recommend breaking news to a user using AWS AI/ML services. By taking advantage of the power of Amazon Personalize and Amazon Titan Text Embeddings on Amazon Bedrock, you can show articles to interested users within seconds of them being published.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/provide-a-personalized-experience-for-news-readers-using-amazon-personalize-and-amazon-titan-text-embeddings-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing tenant isolation using Agents for Amazon Bedrock in a multi-tenant environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will show you how to implement tenant isolation using Amazon Bedrock agents within a multi-tenant environment. We’ll demonstrate this using a sample multi-tenant e-commerce application that provides a service for various tenants to create online stores. This application will use Amazon Bedrock agents to develop an AI assistant or chatbot capable of providing tenant-specific information, such as return policies and user-specific information like order counts and status updates.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect the Amazon Q Business generative AI coding companion to your GitHub repositories with Amazon Q GitHub (Cloud) connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to perform natural language queries over the indexed GitHub (Cloud) data using the AI-powered chat interface provided by Amazon Q Business. We also cover how Amazon Q Business applies access control lists (ACLs) associated with the indexed documents to provide permissions-filtered responses.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/connect-the-amazon-q-business-generative-ai-coding-companion-to-your-github-repositories-with-amazon-q-github-cloud-connector/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate customer experience through an intelligent email automation solution using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use Amazon Bedrock to automate email responses to customer queries. With our solution, you can identify the intent of customer emails and send an automated response if the intent matches your existing knowledge base or data sources. If the intent doesn’t have a match, the email goes to the support team for a manual response.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-customer-experience-through-an-intelligent-email-automation-solution-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an end-to-end RAG solution using Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock and the AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2024/28_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to seamlessly automate the deployment of an end-to-end RAG solution using Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock and the AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), enabling organizations to quickly set up a powerful question answering system.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-end-to-end-rag-solution-using-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock-and-the-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index website contents using the Amazon Q Web Crawler connector for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 22:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to create an Amazon Q Business application and index website contents using the Amazon Q Web Crawler connector for Amazon Q Business. We use two data sources (websites) here. The first data source is an employee onboarding guide from a fictitious company, which requires basic authentication. We demonstrate how to set up authentication for the Web Crawler. The second data source is the official documentation for Amazon Q Business.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with cross-region inference in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are happy to announce the general availability of cross-region inference, a powerful feature allowing automatic cross-region inference routing for requests coming to Amazon Bedrock. This offers developers using on-demand inference mode, a seamless solution for managing optimal availability, performance, and resiliency while managing incoming traffic spikes of applications powered by Amazon Bedrock. By opting in, developers no longer have to spend time and effort predicting demand fluctuations.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building automations to accelerate remediation of AWS Security Hub control findings using Amazon Bedrock and AWS Systems Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 18:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2024/27_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we will harness the power of generative artificial intelligence (AI) and Amazon Bedrock to help organizations simplify and effectively manage remediations of AWS Security Hub control findings.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-automations-to-accelerate-remediation-of-aws-security-hub-control-findings-using-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-systems-manager/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure RAG applications using prompt engineering on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 20:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss existing prompt-level threats and outline several security guardrails for mitigating prompt-level threats. For our example, we work with Anthropic Claude on Amazon Bedrock, implementing prompt templates that allow us to enforce guardrails against common security threats such as prompt injection. These templates are compatible with and can be modified for other LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/secure-rag-applications-using-prompt-engineering-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get the most from Amazon Titan Text Premier</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 20:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the new Amazon Titan Text Premier model, specifically optimized for enterprise use cases, such as building Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and agent-based applications. Such integrations enable advanced applications like building interactive AI assistants that use enterprise APIs and interact with your propriety documents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-the-most-from-amazon-titan-text-premier/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenASL: Generative AI-powered American Sign Language avatars</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 19:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into the architecture and implementation details of GenASL, which uses AWS generative AI capabilities to create human-like ASL avatar videos. GenASL is a solution that translates speech or text into expressive ASL avatar animations, bridging the gap between spoken and written language and sign language.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/genasl-generative-ai-powered-american-sign-language-avatars/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS empowers sales teams using generative AI solution built on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_08_2024/26_08_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Through this series of posts, we share our generative AI journey and use cases, detailing the architecture, AWS services used, lessons learned, and the impact of these solutions on our teams and customers. In this first post, we explore Account Summaries, one of our initial production use cases built on Amazon Bedrock. Account Summaries equips our teams to be better prepared for customer engagements. It combines information from various sources into comprehensive, on-demand summaries available in our CRM or proactively delivered based on upcoming meetings.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build private and secure enterprise generative AI applications with Amazon Q Business using IAM Federation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 01:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_08_2024/23_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a conversational assistant powered by generative artificial intelligence (AI) that enhances workforce productivity by answering questions and completing tasks based on information in your enterprise systems, which each user is authorized to access. In an earlier post, we discussed how you can build private and secure enterprise generative AI applications with Amazon Q Business and AWS IAM Identity Center. If you want to use Amazon Q Business to build enterprise generative AI applications, and have yet to adopt organization-wide use of AWS IAM Identity Center, you can use Amazon Q Business IAM Federation to directly manage user access to Amazon Q Business applications from your enterprise identity provider (IdP), such as Okta or Ping Identity.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
