<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:30:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhance conversational AI with advanced routing techniques with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Conversational artificial intelligence (AI) assistants are engineered to provide precise, real-time responses through intelligent routing of queries to the most suitable AI functions. With AWS generative AI services like Amazon Bedrock, developers can create systems that expertly manage and respond to user requests. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-conversational-ai-with-advanced-routing-techniques-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve LLM performance with human and AI feedback on Amazon SageMaker for Amazon Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Amazon EU Design and Construction (Amazon D&amp;amp;C) team is the engineering team designing and constructing Amazon warehouses. The team navigates a large volume of documents and locates the right information to make sure the warehouse design meets the highest standards. In the post A generative AI-powered solution on Amazon SageMaker to help Amazon EU […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-llm-performance-with-human-and-ai-feedback-on-amazon-sagemaker-for-amazon-engineering/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve accuracy of Amazon Rekognition Face Search with user vectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_04_2024/24_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In various industries, such as financial services, telecommunications, and healthcare, customers use a digital identity process, which usually involves several steps to verify end-users during online onboarding or step-up authentication. An example of one step that can be used is face search, which can help determine whether a new end-user’s face matches those associated with […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-accuracy-of-amazon-rekognition-face-search-with-user-vectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate ML workflows with Amazon SageMaker Studio Local Mode and Docker support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 19:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce two new capabilities in Amazon SageMaker Studio that will accelerate iterative development for machine learning (ML) practitioners: Local Mode and Docker support. ML model development often involves slow iteration cycles as developers switch between coding, training, and deployment. Each step requires waiting for remote compute resources to start up, which […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-ml-workflows-with-amazon-sagemaker-studio-local-mode-and-docker-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significant new capabilities make it easier to use Amazon Bedrock to build and scale generative AI applications – and achieve impressive results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 11:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We introduced Amazon Bedrock to the world a little over a year ago, delivering an entirely new way to build generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications. With the broadest selection of first- and third-party foundation models (FMs) as well as user-friendly capabilities, Amazon Bedrock is the fastest and easiest way to build and scale secure generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/new-capabilities-make-it-easier-to-use-amazon-bedrock-to-build-and-scale-generative-ai-applications-and-deliver-impact/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building scalable, secure, and reliable RAG applications using Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 11:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_04_2024/23_04_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the new enterprise-grade features for Knowledge Bases on Amazon Bedrock and how they align with the AWS Well-Architected Framework. With Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, you can quickly build applications using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) for use cases like question answering, contextual chatbots, and personalized search.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-scalable-secure-and-reliable-rag-applications-using-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate HyperPod clusters with Active Directory for seamless multi-user login</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker HyperPod is purpose-built to accelerate foundation model (FM) training, removing the undifferentiated heavy lifting involved in managing and optimizing a large training compute cluster. With SageMaker HyperPod, you can train FMs for weeks and months without disruption. Typically, HyperPod clusters are used by multiple users: machine learning (ML) researchers, software engineers, data scientists, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-hyperpod-clusters-with-active-directory-for-seamless-multi-user-login/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The executive’s guide to generative AI for sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_04_2024/22_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are facing ever-increasing requirements for sustainability goals alongside environmental, social, and governance (ESG) practices. A Gartner, Inc. survey revealed that 87 percent of business leaders expect to increase their organization’s investment in sustainability over the next years. This post serves as a starting point for any executive seeking to navigate the intersection of generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-executives-guide-to-generative-ai-for-sustainability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing automatic training for solutions in Amazon Personalize</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_04_2024/20_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Personalize is excited to announce automatic training for solutions. Solution training is fundamental to maintain the effectiveness of a model and make sure recommendations align with users’ evolving behaviors and preferences. As data patterns and trends change over time, retraining the solution with the latest relevant data enables the model to learn and adapt, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-automatic-training-for-solutions-in-amazon-personalize/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Kubernetes Operators for new inference capabilities in Amazon SageMaker that reduce LLM deployment costs by 50% on average</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 16:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce a new version of the Amazon SageMaker Operators for Kubernetes using the AWS Controllers for Kubernetes (ACK). ACK is a framework for building Kubernetes custom controllers, where each controller communicates with an AWS service API. These controllers allow Kubernetes users to provision AWS resources like buckets, databases, or message queues […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-kubernetes-operators-for-new-inference-capabilities-in-amazon-sagemaker-that-reduce-llm-deployment-costs-by-50-on-average/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to your slide deck using multimodal foundation models hosted on Amazon Bedrock and Amazon SageMaker – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of this series, we presented a solution that used the Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings model to convert individual slides from a slide deck into embeddings. We stored the embeddings in a vector database and then used the Large Language-and-Vision Assistant (LLaVA 1.5-7b) model to generate text responses to user questions based on […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/talk-to-your-slide-deck-using-multimodal-foundation-models-hosted-on-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-sagemaker-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale AI training and inference for drug discovery through Amazon EKS and Karpenter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_04_2024/19_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with the leadership team of Iambic Therapeutics. Iambic Therapeutics is a drug discovery startup with a mission to create innovative AI-driven technologies to bring better medicines to cancer patients, faster. Our advanced generative and predictive artificial intelligence (AI) tools enable us to search the vast space of possible drug […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scale-ai-training-and-inference-for-drug-discovery-through-amazon-eks-and-karpenter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate customized, compliant application IaC scripts for AWS Landing Zone using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 17:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As you navigate the complexities of cloud migration, the need for a structured, secure, and compliant environment is paramount. AWS Landing Zone addresses this need by offering a standardized approach to deploying AWS resources. This makes sure your cloud foundation is built according to AWS best practices from the start. With AWS Landing Zone, you eliminate the guesswork in security configurations, resource provisioning, and account management. It’s particularly beneficial for organizations looking to scale without compromising on governance or control, providing a clear path to a robust and efficient cloud setup.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Meeting Assistant with Amazon Transcribe, Amazon Bedrock, and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 17:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You’ve likely experienced the challenge of taking notes during a meeting while trying to pay attention to the conversation. You’ve probably also experienced the need to quickly fact-check something that’s been said, or look up information to answer a question that’s just been asked in the call. Or maybe you have a team member that always joins meetings late, and expects you to send them a quick summary over chat to catch them up.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Llama 3 models are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 16:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that Meta Llama 3 foundation models are available through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy and run inference. The Llama 3 models are a collection of pre-trained and fine-tuned generative text models. In this post, we walk through how to discover and deploy Llama 3 models via SageMaker JumpStart. What is […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/meta-llama-3-models-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack delivers native and secure generative AI powered by Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_04_2024/18_04_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Slack, a Salesforce company, has collaborated with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to power Slack AI’s initial search and summarization features and provide safeguards for Slack to use large language models (LLMs) more securely. Slack worked with SageMaker JumpStart to host industry-leading third-party LLMs so that data is not shared with the infrastructure owned by third party model providers. This keeps customer data in Slack at all times and upholds the same security practices and compliance standards that customers expect from Slack itself.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
