<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 20:42:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio to build complex AI workflows using Amazon Bedrock Flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 20:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use SageMaker Unified Studio to create complex AI workflows using Amazon Bedrock Flows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio-to-build-complex-ai-workflows-using-amazon-bedrock-flows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating AI innovation: Scale MCP servers for enterprise workloads with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a centralized Model Context Protocol (MCP) server implementation using Amazon Bedrock that provides shared access to tools and resources for enterprise AI workloads. The solution enables organizations to accelerate AI innovation by standardizing access to resources and tools through MCP, while maintaining security and governance through a centralized approach.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-ai-innovation-scale-mcp-servers-for-enterprise-workloads-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the right approach for generative AI-powered structured data retrieval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore five different patterns for implementing LLM-powered structured data query capabilities in AWS, including direct conversational interfaces, BI tool enhancements, and custom text-to-SQL solutions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/choosing-the-right-approach-for-generative-ai-powered-structured-data-retrieval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing drug data analysis using Amazon Bedrock multimodal RAG capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock&#39;s multimodal RAG capabilities revolutionize drug data analysis by efficiently processing complex medical documentation containing text, images, graphs, and tables.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-drug-data-analysis-using-amazon-bedrock-multimodal-rag-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and deploy AI inference workflows with new enhancements to the Amazon SageMaker Python SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 21:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide an overview of the user experience, detailing how to set up and deploy these workflows with multiple models using the SageMaker Python SDK. We walk through examples of building complex inference workflows, deploying them to SageMaker endpoints, and invoking them for real-time inference.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-and-deploy-ai-inference-workflows-with-new-enhancements-to-the-amazon-sagemaker-python-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context extraction from image files in Amazon Q Business using LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we look at a step-by-step implementation for using the custom document enrichment (CDE) feature within an Amazon Q Business application to process standalone image files. We walk you through an AWS Lambda function configured within CDE to process various image file types, and showcase an example scenario of how this integration enhances Amazon Q Business&#39;s ability to provide comprehensive insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/context-extraction-from-image-files-in-amazon-q-business-using-llms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AWS architecture diagrams using Amazon Q CLI and MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q Developer CLI with the AWS Diagram MCP and the AWS Documentation MCP servers to create sophisticated architecture diagrams that follow AWS best practices. We discuss techniques for basic diagrams and real-world diagrams, with detailed examples and step-by-step instructions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-aws-architecture-diagrams-using-amazon-q-cli-and-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS costs estimation using Amazon Q CLI and AWS Cost Analysis MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q CLI with the AWS Cost Analysis MCP server to perform sophisticated cost analysis that follows AWS best practices. We discuss basic setup and advanced techniques, with detailed examples and step-by-step instructions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-costs-estimation-using-amazon-q-cli-and-aws-cost-analysis-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailor responsible AI with new safeguard tiers in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 22:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the new safeguard tiers available in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails, explain their benefits and use cases, and provide guidance on how to implement and evaluate them in your AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/tailor-responsible-ai-with-new-safeguard-tiers-in-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured data response with Amazon Bedrock: Prompt Engineering and Tool Use</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We demonstrate two methods for generating structured responses with Amazon Bedrock: Prompt Engineering and Tool Use with the Converse API. Prompt Engineering is flexible, works with Bedrock models (including those without Tool Use support), and handles various schema types (e.g., Open API schemas), making it a great starting point. Tool Use offers greater reliability, consistent results, seamless API integration, and runtime validation of JSON schema for enhanced control.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon SageMaker AI Random Cut Forest for NASA’s Blue Origin spacecraft sensor data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use SageMaker AI to apply the Random Cut Forest (RCF) algorithm to detect anomalies in spacecraft position, velocity, and quaternion orientation data from NASA and Blue Origin’s demonstration of lunar Deorbit, Descent, and Landing Sensors (BODDL-TP).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-amazon-sagemaker-ai-random-cut-forest-for-nasas-blue-origin-spacecraft-sensor-data/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent multi-agent business expert using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 16:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a multi-agent system using multi-agent collaboration in Amazon Bedrock Agents to solve complex business questions in the biopharmaceutical industry. We show how specialized agents in research and development (R&amp;amp;D), legal, and finance domains can work together to provide comprehensive business insights by analyzing data from multiple sources.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-multi-agent-business-expert-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving cost-efficiency and speed in claims data processing with Amazon Nova Micro and Amazon Nova Lite</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we shared how an internal technology team at Amazon evaluated Amazon Nova models, resulting in notable improvements in inference speed and cost-efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/driving-cost-efficiency-and-speed-in-claims-data-processing-with-amazon-nova-micro-and-amazon-nova-lite/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
