<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:59:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Powering enterprise search with the Cohere Embed 4 multimodal embeddings model in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Cohere Embed 4 multimodal embeddings model is now available as a fully managed, serverless option in Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we dive into the benefits and unique capabilities of Embed 4 for enterprise search use cases. We’ll show you how to quickly get started using Embed 4 on Amazon Bedrock, taking advantage of integrations with Strands Agents, S3 Vectors, and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore to build powerful agentic retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to building AI agents in GxP environments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The regulatory landscape for GxP compliance is evolving to address the unique characteristics of AI. Traditional Computer System Validation (CSV) approaches, often with uniform validation strategies, are being supplemented by Computer Software Assurance (CSA) frameworks that emphasize flexible risk-based validation methods tailored to each system&#39;s actual impact and complexity (FDA latest guidance). In this post, we cover a risk-based implementation, practical implementation considerations across different risk levels, the AWS shared responsibility model for compliance, and concrete examples of risk mitigation strategies.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Agent collaboration patterns with Strands Agents and Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore four key collaboration patterns for multi-agent, multimodal AI systems – Agents as Tools, Swarms Agents, Agent Graphs, and Agent Workflows – and discuss when and how to apply each using the open-source AWS Strands Agents SDK with Amazon Nova models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multi-agent-collaboration-patterns-with-strands-agents-and-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune VLMs for multipage document-to-JSON with SageMaker AI and SWIFT</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate that fine-tuning VLMs provides a powerful and flexible approach to automate and significantly enhance document understanding capabilities. We also demonstrate that using focused fine-tuning allows smaller, multi-modal models to compete effectively with much larger counterparts (98% accuracy with Qwen2.5 VL 3B).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-vlms-for-multipage-document-to-json-with-sagemaker-ai-and-swift/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Clario automates clinical research analysis using generative AI on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Clario has used Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services to build an AI-powered solution that automates and improves the analysis of COA interviews.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-clario-automates-clinical-research-analysis-using-generative-ai-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratizing AI: How Thomson Reuters Open Arena supports no-code AI for every professional with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how TR addressed key business use cases with Open Arena, a highly scalable and flexible no-code AI solution powered by Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services such as Amazon OpenSearch Service, Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3), Amazon DynamoDB, and AWS Lambda. We&#39;ll explain how TR used AWS services to build this solution, including how the architecture was designed, the use cases it solves, and the business profiles that use it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing structured output for Custom Model Import in Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the addition of structured output to Custom Model Import. Structured output constrains a model&#39;s generation process in real time so that every token it produces conforms to a schema you define. Rather than relying on prompt-engineering tricks or brittle post-processing scripts, you can now generate structured outputs directly at inference time.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-structured-output-for-custom-model-import-in-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform your MCP architecture: Unite MCP servers through AgentCore Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this year, we introduced Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, a fully managed service that serves as a centralized MCP tool server, providing a unified interface where agents can discover, access, and invoke tools. Today, we&#39;re extending support for existing MCP servers as a new target type in AgentCore Gateway. With this capability, you can group multiple task-specific MCP servers aligned to agent goals behind a single, manageable MCP gateway interface. This reduces the operational complexity of maintaining separate gateways, while providing the same centralized tool and authentication management that existed for REST APIs and AWS Lambda functions.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Search increased ML training twofold using AWS Batch for Amazon SageMaker Training jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Amazon Search optimized GPU instance utilization by leveraging AWS Batch for SageMaker Training jobs. This managed solution enabled us to orchestrate machine learning (ML) training workloads on GPU-accelerated instance families like P5, P4, and others. We will also provide a step-by-step walkthrough of the use case implementation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-search-increased-ml-training-twofold-using-aws-batch-for-amazon-sagemaker-training-jobs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterate faster with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime direct code deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock AgentCore is an agentic platform for building, deploying, and operating effective agents securely at scale. Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Runtime is a fully managed service of Bedrock AgentCore, which provides low latency serverless environments to deploy agents and tools. It provides session isolation, supports multiple agent frameworks including popular open-source frameworks, and handles multimodal […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/iterate-faster-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-runtime-direct-code-deployment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
