<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:24:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use IP-restricted presigned URLs to enhance security in Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While presigned URLs offer a convenient way to grant temporary access to S3 objects, sharing these URLs with people outside of the workteam can lead to unintended access of those objects. To mitigate this risk and enhance the security of SageMaker Ground Truth labeling tasks, we have introduced a new feature that adds an additional layer of security by restricting access to the presigned URLs to the worker’s IP address or virtual private cloud (VPC) endpoint from which they access the labeling task.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the power of structured data for enterprises using natural language with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2024/20_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss an architecture to query structured data using Amazon Q Business, and build out an application to query cost and usage data in Amazon Athena with Amazon Q Business. Amazon Q Business can create SQL queries to your data sources when provided with the database schema, additional metadata describing the columns and tables, and prompting instructions. You can extend this architecture to use additional data sources, query validation, and prompting techniques to cover a wider range of use cases.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Rerank 3 Nimble now generally available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 16:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2024/19_08_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Cohere Rerank 3 Nimble foundation model (FM) is now generally available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. This model is the newest FM in Cohere’s Rerank model series, built to enhance enterprise search and Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) systems. In this post, we discuss the benefits and capabilities of this new model with some examples. Overview […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cohere-rerank-3-nimble-now-generally-available-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perform generative AI-powered data prep and no-code ML over any size of data using Amazon SageMaker Canvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 03:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_08_2024/16_08_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Canvas now empowers enterprises to harness the full potential of their data by enabling support of petabyte-scale datasets. Starting today, you can interactively prepare large datasets, create end-to-end data flows, and invoke automated machine learning (AutoML) experiments on petabytes of data—a substantial leap from the previous 5 GB limit. With over 50 connectors, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/perform-generative-ai-powered-data-prep-and-no-code-ml-over-any-size-of-data-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delight your customers with great conversational experiences via QnABot, a generative AI chatbot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 15:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2024/15_08_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            QnABot on AWS (an AWS Solution) now provides access to Amazon Bedrock foundational models (FMs) and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed end-to-end Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) workflow. You can now provide contextual information from your private data sources that can be used to create rich, contextual, conversational experiences. In this post, we discuss how to use QnABot on AWS to deploy a fully functional chatbot integrated with other AWS services, and delight your customers with human agent like conversational experiences.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing document-level sync reports: Enhanced data sync visibility in Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 19:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a fully managed, generative artificial intelligence (AI)-powered assistant that helps enterprises unlock the value of their data and knowledge. With Amazon Q, you can quickly find answers to questions, generate summaries and content, and complete tasks by using the information and expertise stored across your company’s various data sources and enterprise […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-document-level-sync-reports-enhanced-data-sync-visibility-in-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derive generative AI-powered insights from ServiceNow with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 14:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2024/14_08_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shows how to configure the Amazon Q ServiceNow connector to index your ServiceNow platform and take advantage of generative AI searches in Amazon Q. We use an example of an illustrative ServiceNow platform to discuss technical topics related to AWS services.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/derive-generative-ai-powered-insights-from-servicenow-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent healthcare forms analysis with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2024/13_08_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore using the Anthropic Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock large language model (LLM). Amazon Bedrock provides access to several LLMs, such as Anthropic Claude 3, which can be used to generate semi-structured data relevant to the healthcare industry. This can be particularly useful for creating various healthcare-related forms, such as patient intake forms, insurance claim forms, or medical history questionnaires.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/intelligent-healthcare-forms-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
