<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 15:16:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build agentic systems with CrewAI and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 15:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how CrewAI’s open source agentic framework, combined with Amazon Bedrock, enables the creation of sophisticated multi-agent systems that can transform how businesses operate. Through practical examples and implementation details, we demonstrate how to build, deploy, and orchestrate AI agents that can tackle complex tasks with minimal human oversight.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-agentic-systems-with-crewai-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Guardrails image content filters provide industry-leading safeguards, helping customer block up to 88% of harmful multimodal content: Generally available today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 20:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Guardrails announces the general availability of image content filters, enabling you to moderate both image and text content in your generative AI applications. In this post, we discuss how to get started with image content filters in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-guardrails-image-content-filters-provide-industry-leading-safeguards-helping-customer-block-up-to-88-of-harmful-multimodal-content-generally-available-today/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating custom dependencies in Amazon SageMaker Canvas workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 19:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When implementing machine learning workflows in Amazon SageMaker Canvas, organizations might need to consider external dependencies required for their specific use cases. Although SageMaker Canvas provides powerful no-code and low-code capabilities for rapid experimentation, some projects might require specialized dependencies and libraries that aren’t included by default in SageMaker Canvas. This post provides an example of how to incorporate code that relies on external dependencies into your SageMaker Canvas workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate training data and cost-effectively train categorical models with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 18:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how you can use Amazon Bedrock to generate high-quality categorical ground truth data, which is crucial for training machine learning (ML) models in a cost-sensitive environment. Generative AI solutions can play an invaluable role during the model development phase by simplifying training and test data creation for multiclass classification supervised learning use cases. We dive deep into this process on how to use XML tags to structure the prompt and guide Amazon Bedrock in generating a balanced label dataset with high accuracy.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Amazon Bedrock cross-Region inference in multi-account environments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 15:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to modify your Regional access controls to specifically allow Amazon Bedrock cross-Region inference while maintaining broader Regional restrictions for other AWS services. We provide practical examples for both SCP modifications and AWS Control Tower implementations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enable-amazon-bedrock-cross-region-inference-in-multi-account-environments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker JumpStart adds fine-tuning support for models in a private model hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 16:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are announcing an enhanced private hub feature with several new capabilities that give organizations greater control over their ML assets. These enhancements include the ability to fine-tune SageMaker JumpStart models directly within the private hub, support for adding and managing custom-trained models, deep linking capabilities for associated notebooks, and improved model version management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-adds-fine-tuning-support-for-models-in-a-private-model-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI-powered game design: Accelerating early development with Stability AI models on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 14:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has emerged as a game changer, offering unprecedented opportunities for game designers to push boundaries and create immersive virtual worlds. At the forefront of this revolution is Stability AI’s cutting-edge text-to-image AI model, Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large (SD3.5 Large), which is transforming the way we approach game environment creation. In this post, we explore how you can use SD3.5 Large to address practical gaming needs such as early concept art and character design.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock launches Session Management APIs for generative AI applications (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 22:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock announces the preview launch of Session Management APIs, a new capability that enables developers to simplify state and context management for generative AI applications built with popular open source frameworks such as LangGraph and LlamaIndex. Session Management APIs provide an out-of-the-box solution that enables developers to securely manage state and conversation context across […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-launches-session-management-apis-for-generative-ai-applications-preview/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance deployment guardrails with inference component rolling updates for Amazon SageMaker AI inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 21:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss the challenges faced by organizations when updating models in production. Then we deep dive into the new rolling update feature for inference components and provide practical examples using DeepSeek distilled models to demonstrate this feature. Finally, we explore how to set up rolling updates in different scenarios.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-deployment-guardrails-with-inference-component-rolling-updates-for-amazon-sagemaker-ai-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate and improve performance of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to evaluate the performance of your knowledge base, including the metrics and data to use for evaluation. We also address some of the tactics and configuration changes that can improve specific metrics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluate-and-improve-performance-of-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance enterprise productivity for your LLM solution by becoming an Amazon Q Business data accessor</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_03_2025/25_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to enhance enterprise productivity for your large language model (LLM) solution by using the Amazon Q index for ISVs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-enterprise-productivity-for-your-llm-solution-by-becoming-an-amazon-q-business-data-accessor/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
